<string id="mervin_start_dialog_0">
    <text>O-o-oh, what was that?.. And who are You?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Look at that, alive! Well wow, first time I see someone survive falling into a "Whirligig" anomaly. You, dear, were truly born with a silver spoon in your mouth. You could at least say thank you for pulling you out of the anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you, but I don't remember anything... Something flashed, then a total blackout. Oh my, how my head hurts...</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I see you came to your senses. And now lay it out, who are you, what is your name and what were you doing here in Pripyat. Just don't lie, or I'll shoot.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_4">
    <text>But I'm telling you, I don't remember anything. I can't even remember my name. I'm not lying. I remember I had things in my backpack. And weapons, it seems. But why I came here and what my name is, I can't recall.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, let it be so. And your things and protective suit, which, it seems, saved you - are bye-bye. The anomaly tore all your junk into small pieces and scattered it around. Your money, seemingly, also gone... Check it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_6">
    <text>So that's how it is... And who are You and why did you save me? After all, as I understand, it was an extremely dangerous undertaking.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_7">
    <text>My name is Mervin. I collect "lost souls" like you and convert them to the greatest faith. Faith in the almighty "Monolith". So, you came across me very handily. You are a tough guy, I see, and the "Monolith" brotherhood really needs new fighters right now. Show yourself brave and obedient, and you will become one of us.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_8">
    <text>And if I refuse?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Such an option is impossible. We'll do this with you now: if you prove that you are good for something, then I will grant you life and help you. But if not, if you chicken out, then death will relieve you of suffering.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_10">
    <text>And how will I prove what I'm capable of and that I'm not a coward?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_11">
    <text>It's simple. You will undergo a small test: in the center of Pripyat there is an old ferris wheel. A pack of mutants lives in this place, snorks they call them. There should be about five or six of them there. Go there and destroy the beasts. Then return to me. For this task I will give you my personal "Colt" system pistol and two packs of ammo for it. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, it seems I have no other choice... Give me the gun and I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="snork_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Snorks destroyed!</text>
</string>
<string id="snork_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Well done, handled the test. And now you will come with me. You proved that you are brave and agile, we need such fighters. Everything is decided, you will serve the great brotherhood - the "Monolith" brotherhood. Later you will thank me!</text>
</string>
<string id="snork_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Let's go, I have nowhere else to go anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>What kind of tasks must I fulfill?</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>The tasks will be uneasy. I will move you, with the help of the great power of teleportation, granted to us by the powerful "Monolith", to different places, from which you must get out alive and unharmed and return to me. But most importantly, in each of these places one of the manuscripts with our main commandments will be lying. You will have to take it, read and remember what is written there, and then, as you return, give it to me. Only in this case will the task be considered completed.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Everything is clear to me. What is the first task?</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>For a start, a not particularly difficult "walk" to CNPP-2. Then straight to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>Well then, I am ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I completed the first task.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done! Give me the manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>What will be the second task?</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Now the task will be harder. I will send you to the roof of the Sarcophagus, where the radar is. Conditions are the same. You take the manuscript and bring it to me. And also: be careful on the way back.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood everything. Come on, teleport me.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I completed the second task.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, good job! Returned quickly. Give the scroll here.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, take the second manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So, good. Other tasks you will receive later. Now we will have to interrupt for a short while, Charon is waiting for you - something urgent. Then, as you fulfill his errand, Charon will tell you how we will proceed with training.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll go to Charon.</text>
</string>
<string id="new_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, should I go to Mervin now?</text>
</string>
<string id="new_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, now you can calmly continue training. Mervin awaits you in Pripyat, in the hotel. Now I will teleport you into this very hotel. You will find Mervin on the second floor, to the left of room #26. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="new_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I am ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Mervin! I am back to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, let's continue the lessons. Here is the third task for you, a warm-up: did you like riding carousels in childhood?</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Liked it in childhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>Well so you will remember childhood now!</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>Didn't understand, how is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>You are a bastard, Mervin, the wind almost blew me off the wheel!</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hard in training - easy in battle!</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, take it, adversary, the third manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>What, liked it? Don't get angry - learn to control your emotions. This will be useful to you in the future.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, don't stall, what else did you come up with for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>Loved climbing attics in childhood I bet, huh? Well so come on, plunge into childhood one more time!</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>What is this again?</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I have a feeling that you and Charon conspired to kill me.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>No one wishes you death. If you complete all tasks and be obedient and brave, then Charon will subsequently make you a mentor. So everything that is done - is all for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Alright, understood. Here is the fourth manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_3">
    <text>That is good. And now we will move together to one place.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Where to now?</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow! You do this great.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>If you serve "Monolith" faithfully and truly, then I will teach you this science too.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks for that. Well, what about the last test?</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>Liked jumping in childhood? There's a five-story building behind me. You need to jump from this roof to the balcony of the fifth floor, then from the balcony to another balcony and so on to the end, on the last balcony there will be a manuscript. I don't need to return it to, let it remain as a souvenir. Just make sure you don't lose it, no matter what happens to you... Keep it safe, it will come in handy... That will be the end of your training. As soon as you complete the last task, go straight to Charon. He has an important and responsible job for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, now that's business!</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_5">
    <text>Well that's it, go jump. Good luck, hope to see you again. Send regards to Charon from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Borov.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_2">
    <text>How do you know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_3">
    <text>You've made such a "ruckus" in the Zone that everyone is talking only about you. As soon as you entered the Bar territory, I was immediately reported that Strelok had paid us a visit... Well, let's get acquainted. And now to business: In short, a difficult man has appeared here, called Count. He is sort of a chief of intelligence here for us. Go to him, he has some important business.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_4">
    <text>And where do I look for this Count?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_5">
    <text>He is right here, on the Bar territory, in the brick annex opposite the entrance to the "100 Rads" Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I'll go find Count.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello! Are you Count?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. And who might you be?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Borov sent me to you, says you need help.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_3">
    <text>A-a-ah, Strelok! Heard a lot about you. Behind your back they call you "Werewolf". You are from the former Monolithians, isn't that right?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes, that's right. Well, let's consider we are introduced.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_0">
    <text>What business do you have with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok, we haven't managed to chat about life, so to speak, and you are already about business...</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I have no time to chat. If I'm needed, say why, and if not, I'm leaving - many things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay-okay, don't boil over... People say that you are a risky man and walk "in an embrace" with fortune. There is a job, just for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Listening carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I and my partners Prince and Caesar recently picked up the trail of a mercenary group that was trying to organize the import of a large batch of modern weapons and supplies into the Zone to create a powerful base somewhere on the Rostok territory, to then storm the Bar, or maybe the Warehouses, well, I don't know exactly... And as a result control the passage further into the Zone. We managed, with the help of Knyaz's people, to track and shoot down three choppers carrying the cargo. Then we ran into a cover squad... Had to split into three groups. Barely escaped alive... The mercenaries battered us badly back then. There was a chase after me, so I had to lay low. That's why I headed to the Bar. Prince and his group went to the Warehouses, to look for the place where one of the downed choppers could have fallen. And Caesar intended to move to Yantar, to find the crash site of another helicopter. And then to the scientists, to lick his wounds.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_6">
    <text>So, and what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_7">
    <text>To start, here is the first task for you. Not far from here, behind the Bar territory. As you go out towards the Garbage. Not long ago a chopper crashed. Where the chopper itself crashed is unknown. To hell with it. So, there, somewhere at the end of this road, they just dropped crates from it. The crates with weapons, I think, survived and remained lying somewhere there.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Interesting things you are telling, Count.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_9">
    <text>You need to hurry! Find this place and bring me everything valuable that survived from there, so the mercenaries don't get it. The military should have accompanying documents with them. Search for them, they should be in a fireproof case. By these documents we will be able to find out who on the "Big Land" sponsors these weapon deliveries. And then through our people, so to speak, "influence the process". And a request: shoot the mutants, please, who are coming here in crowds, otherwise they keep striving to penetrate the Bar, and this can turn into very dangerous consequences. Here, take a few F-1 grenades, they'll come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood everything. Moving out already. Will deal with the mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Count!</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, what's there? Tell me, don't torment.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I was there. What a place! Still break into cold sweat as I recall... Here is what I found and brought the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well done, Strelok! I didn't doubt you. Give here what you brought. Keep one gun and ammo for it, as agreed, for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here, hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Count, how else can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_1">
    <text>So. While you were absent, Prince contacted me. He is currently hiding temporarily on the Radar. Says that he found the place where the second helicopter crashed at the Warehouses after all, but ran into mercenaries there. They laid down all his guys, bitches, but they mowed down those scum gloriously too. You need to find Prince. And also he was left practically without weapons and ammo. Therefore, before going to the Radar, pick up the gun and ammo from his stash at the Warehouses near the old helicopter, which is rusting somewhere in a ravine, and take it to Prince. You'll give the gun, and then act according to the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_2">
    <text>But where on the Radar should I look for Prince?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_3">
    <text>He is hiding somewhere in an abandoned tunnel, where the blocked entrance to the old bunker is. There was also a small military base there before. And now it seems quiet there, according to his words. That's it, go. Find the gun for Prince definitely, and I will warn him now that I sent a "guest".</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything. I'll go find the gun and to Prince on the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Prince?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. And you, apparently, are Strelok. Let's be acquainted.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Count asked to pass you the gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Aha, thanks! Give it here, very handy! Or mercenaries are preparing a roundup on me here. Tracked me down it seems, and I remained, consider it, without a weapon. So, just one "peashooter".</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here, hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_0">
    <text>How can I be of use further?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Count probably told you that I found the place where the second mercenary helicopter crashed after all. Well so, you can help us very much if you go and pick up documents from the fireproof case. I definitely saw, a metal case was lying there among crates with weapons, but couldn't reach it. Mercs squeezed in a vice, laid down all guys, only I alone barely left. Four remaining mercenaries chased me through all Warehouses, until they ran into Freedomers. Don't know how the matter ended there for them, but I managed to bolt to the Radar. Although a couple of these freaks, in my opinion, broke through the Barrier after all. I sensed someone behind my back...</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_2">
    <text>So, and where is this place you are sending me to?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Means, this place is at the old checkpoint, practically behind the territory of the Warehouses. There not far from the bloodsucker village. In general, you'll figure it out. Take the docs and immediately to the Bar to Count. But just be careful. There is some spatial devilry there: that downed chopper lost its cargo and as if dissolved... Mysticism of some kind. In short, be on "alert".</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Is that all?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, and also a few crates survived there. I think some weapons remained intact there. Mercs didn't have time to take it after all. Rushed after me in pursuit. If you find anything, take it for yourself. Main thing, so they don't get it. And be careful, suddenly those who pursued me are hanging around somewhere nearby here... Well that's it, go with God.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Already going.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Count!</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>O-o-oh, Strelok! With what news did you come?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I was in that place where Prince detected the lost cargo.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>And what, found anything there? Were there any documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes, brought the docs safe and sound. Picked up several serious guns in crates. Prince said that if I find any weapons there, to take them for myself as a reward. Want me to sell to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Well, I can buy, of course. You, mainly, give the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_net_work_0">
    <text>Well, Count, is there more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_net_work_1">
    <text>Nothing for now. Come by later, maybe Caesar will appear after all... Without him it's impossible to decipher the information you obtained.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Count! Barman said you were looking for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, was looking. Good that you came. Caesar contacted me recently. He is now sitting out at scientists' on Yantar in the bunker, licking wounds. Need to take something to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>What needs to be taken to him? Especially since I need to go to Yantar too.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>In short, he had three stashes here not far, in the vicinity of the Bar. Well, somewhere in the inner courtyard. So, need to pick up three flash drives from these three stashes, in which Caesar had mercenary cipher codes written down, and take them to him. He is very literate in these matters for us, so he will be able to assemble a single code for decryption.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_4">
    <text>Damn. Where approximately did he make his stashes?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_5">
    <text>Well.... Know for sure that on the Bar territory. Not in particularly crowded places, I think.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, we'll deal with this. And how do I get to Yantar then? Especially since I have my own interest there too.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_7">
    <text>And I completely forgot! Of course, the road to Yantar lies through the Rostok factory. It's not easy to pass there, but you can. You have a gift for such things. As you find Caesar's three flash drives, I will send the transition from the Bar to Rostok to your PDA. My people are clearing it just right now. We blocked it some time ago, because all sorts of mutated junk climbed from Rostok into the Bar. But now safety aside, there are more important matters. Need to go to Yantar, so we'll clear the road. Come on, find Caesar's stashes, and we meanwhile will open the transition to Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, you will help me with the transition to Rostok, but how further? How to get to Yantar from there?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, Strelok, what questions you ask! There you'll figure it out by situation. Search for "Secret Trails", they are there. As you cross through the tunnel with "Fryers" on Rostok, search around there. There is a transition to Yantar. Not always obvious, but exists, telling you for sure. And what interest do you have there, on Yantar?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, regarding transition to Yantar understood everything. Not the first time searching for secret paths blindly. I'll find it. And my interest is such that I am looking for one person. And this person should be in the Dead City. And the road there is unknown to me. But scientists on Yantar might know it. So I was told. Such are the affairs.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_11">
    <text>So that's it... Well, eggheads from Yantar, of course, are brainy guys, but right now they are unlikely to help you... Too much changed in the Zone after the last blowout, including needed paths changed their location. In short, do the business with Caesar, return and we'll ponder how to get you to the Dead City. I will help.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright, understood everything. I'll try faster.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello. Are you Caesar?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_2">
    <text>And I am Strelok. Count sent me. I brought you your flash drives with mercenary cipher codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Ah, Strelok! Glad to meet you. Count informed me about you. I've been waiting. Well, give the flash drives here. And I, in turn, prepared a reward for you for the work. Rare artifact. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thanks for the artifact! Here are your three flash drives, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well? Can I be free?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>No, Strelok, wait... There is one business here, uneasy. Count told you about three mercenary choppers that we shot down?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I am aware of the matter. Already visited the crash sites of two. And brought docs to Count from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Aha, good. Now to business. The third helicopter crashed somewhere here, on Yantar, behind the lake. Mercs reached it faster than us. And tried to carry out the surviving cargo to a safe place on Rostok. But were afraid to go through the scientist base. Dan and the guys guard everything here after all. So they went around the X-16 laboratory complex. But on the way, apparently, fell into a spatial anomaly. Well, you probably know about such one for sure. Or maybe a controller took them, don't know exactly... So, those mercenaries vanished, but the cargo remained lying. Sakharov helped me track the signal. Signal is weak, but stable. Comes from somewhere in the complex territory...</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Can you be more precise?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't interrupt me. The place where the signal comes from is in the outer courtyard of the X-16 complex. Behind the gates, opposite the entrance to the laboratory itself. There must be metal cases, at least one for sure. Can get there straight from the factory territory. Passing without protection is unreal, brains boil at once. I'll give you a couple of stimulants, with them you can walk holding hands even with a controller. Help out, bring secret documents. They must be there, I know for sure. It is very important. I would go myself, but can't yet. Wounds haven't healed yet. And I meanwhile will deal with cipher codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, agreed. I'll go.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Found the documents, Caesar.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done, Strelok! And I just dealt with the codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>And what now?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Give the docs, I'll take a quick look at them. And you don't leave. Wait a couple of minutes.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, what's there?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Again the same cipher... Need to take these documents to Count. I will also give you a PDA with a unified base code, which I assembled while you were absent. Give it to Count too. He will decipher the data, and then we'll see what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well okay. Give the docs and PDA. I'll go to Count.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Count!</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Caesar already informed me about everything. Thank you, helped out. Give the PDA with the base code and the documents. Let's see what information is hidden there.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Aha. Let's have a look what we have here... so-so... schedule of weapon deliveries to the Zone... lists of agents... some data about secret experiments... Oops! Now this is interesting!.. So, Strelok, don't go anywhere! Wait a little. I think very serious matters are twisting here. Need to read everything carefully and draw conclusions.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll wait... Count. I think something is due to me for such risky work?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Ah yes, of course. Sorry. Here is SR-2 Veresk SMG and a little ammo for it from me and my friends in gratitude. Take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Wow, thanks!</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_0">
    <text>Well? What is in the documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_1">
    <text>In short, Strelok. It turns out that weapon and supplies deliveries are carried out to prepare a very large mercenary operation. It speaks of some installation affecting the psyche. With the help of this installation one can sort of "burn out the brain" within a radius of several kilometers. Mercenaries are preparing a massive attack with the aim to capture the Radar territory, install this installation there and thereby block the path to Pripyat and CNPP. It is unclear what the ultimate goal in all this is, but one thing is clear: behind all this stands some group of scientists. Moreover they act not from the "Big Land", but right from here, from the Zone! Who they are and where to look for them - is unclear. But if they succeed in what is planned, then it will be bad for all of us. The Zone will split into two parts, and no one will know anymore what will be happening there, at the CNPP...</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_2">
    <text>What things! And what to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_3">
    <text>You need to find one person, his name is Fang. And pass him this PDA. I uploaded all decrypted information there. Maybe he can clarify something. Well or at least advise what to do. He knows a lot of things and people.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, Fang! So I know him. Met him somehow in Pripyat... And moreover, I am looking for him myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_5">
    <text>Well that's good. Find him, pass him my PDA with decrypted information.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. Give the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Count. So what about my question?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>And for your case there is a solution. My intelligence works sharply.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, don't stall, speak, time is pressing. I need to find Mahomet.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen carefully: you need to get to the Dead City, right? There is no simple known path there, but there are experienced diggers who know the way. Just like that, of course, they won't open the secret path to anyone. Most likely, they will even say they don't know about such. But one can say that you are very lucky right now. A problem has arisen for them: A very important person disappeared. Went to the Dead City and didn't return. And they desperately need to find him. And there is no one to send right now. And you just appeared handily, can offer them your services, and at the same time gain your own interest.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>Aha, understood. And who are these diggers, and where to look for them?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>You might even know them. It's the Clear Sky guys on the Radar: Sviblov and his guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>So that's it... Interesting, why do Clear Sky members go to the Dead City? The Wanderers seem to control everything there now.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright, I'll tell you more: few know about this, but the Wanderers and Clear Sky used to be one whole. A special Clear Sky group, consisting of scientific staff and their security, which carried out some closed project funded by a large pharmaceutical corporation. What project that was, no one knows. Everything is kept secret to this day. It is only known that they were based on Yantar, on the territory of Sakharov's scientific base, who helped them in their business. Then something went wrong, and an internal conflict occurred. \n\nIt was rumored that it all started because of women. There were two sisters there: Leila and Karina. Either they didn't share men, or men didn't share them, or some other disagreements on ideological grounds occurred, don't know exactly... But still, I always said: women have no place in the Zone, only troubles from them. So, this detachment split into two groups then: One remained with scientists on Yantar led by Dan, and the second, under the leadership of Leila, left the camp and went deep into the Zone, calling themselves Wanderers. Leila's sister, Karina, remained with Dan on Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>I was at Yantar, but I didn't see any girl there.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>And here the most interesting part begins: They said that Dan had an affair with this Karina. And then she hooked up with Sviblov. So Dan got angry and sent Sviblov into exile on the Radar, and Karina left with him too. In short, Clear Sky stepped on the same rake twice... Soon the sisters somehow reconciled, and Karina started visiting Leila from time to time. So this time she went to the Dead City to the Wanderers and disappeared. Sviblov sent his people to search, but they didn't return either. Such are the affairs.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>That's how twisted it all is.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_11">
    <text>And don't say. Straight up Santa Barbara. In short, go to Sviblov on the Radar and hint to him that you accidentally learned about his problem and that you can help. From whom you learned, it is not necessary to say. Well, you understand. Promise him to find out where Karina disappeared, and he will show you the path to the Dead City. Comprende? This is the only way for you to get to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, understood everything. I'm going to the Radar to Sviblov. Thank you, Count, and see you!</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Sviblov!</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>What brought you to me, stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>I accidentally learned that you need help in searching for a missing person. Is that so?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, actually yes. We have a problem here... But how did you find out about this?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>Where I found out - doesn't matter. The main thing is, I can help you. Well, I'll try, at least. Only I need full information about this case and the transition to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>You are a brisk fellow, however. Well okay, we have no choice now. I understand you already know the main essence of the problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, in general terms.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>In short, a girl disappeared, our "sister". Called Karina. Dark-haired, short, dressed in a blue Clear Sky protective suit. Left five days ago to the Dead City, let's say, to visit and didn't return, although she should have already the next day. I sent a man to search, but he disappeared too.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>Do I understand correctly that I need to find Karina or find out what happened to her?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>Let's say this: find and if necessary, save and deliver here. Well or at least bring to Yantar into the bunker to the scientists. I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, I understood everything. I don't need anything as a reward. Just show where to find the transition to the Dead City. I won't lie, I have my own interest there too.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, agreed. We never showed the transition to the Dead City to anyone, but now is a special case. Therefore I will send the transition point to your PDA right now. It is located not far from here, practically behind the wall of this complex where we are with you now. \nJust hurry, this path is not constant. Can disappear at any moment. That's it, go. In the city you will find the Wanderers. Talk to Leila, Karina's sister, she went to her. Just I beg you, find Karina.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_12">
    <text>Clear, I'll try. Give the transition mark, and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Fang, I have a business from Count for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_1">
    <text>From Count? Haven't heard about him for a long time... What business?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here is a PDA with information about the mercenary assault on the Radar being prepared. Look, maybe you can advise what to do next.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So... (reads PDA) interesting-interesting... Well wow! I heard about this from Ghost, but didn't really believe it. And now I don't know what to think. So many events and problems piled up at once here, and they are all somehow connected. Let's do this: I need to think everything over thoroughly, consult with Ghost and Doctor. And you solve priority tasks for now. Then come to me, we'll definitely come up with something.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Understood everything, Fang. Will definitely drop by later.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, what news, Fang?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_1">
    <text>I talked with Ghost and Doctor. Information that you brought me was confirmed. Indeed, a group of some insane scientists is plotting something very serious and dangerous. The first step planned is to turn on the installation on the Radar and cut off Pripyat and CNPP from the rest of the Zone. For this they hired mercenaries and are trying to arm them to the teeth, and then, after capturing the Radar, turn them into "watchdogs". Then, when no one will disturb them at the CNPP itself, somewhere in the Sarcophagus, deploy secret experiments related to this damn stone, with the Monolith... Well and for protection of the CNPP territory and Pripyat they already have a guard - Monolithians. They have cleared their brains long ago... Well and lastly: seems, preparation has already begun in full swing in the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_2">
    <text>And what to do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, Barman already told you that you need to find the Doctor at the Swamps. So Doctor will say what to undertake next. Just hurry!</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Everything is clear. Means, as planned, going first to Doctor at the Swamps.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Skinflint. Lukash said that you have some business for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Strelok. There is one request for you. Fulfill it, I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak, what needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_3">
    <text>We now, as you see, firmly entrenched at this base. Everything would be fine: weapons, ammo, canned food and vodka with rusks remaining from the military are plenty, but just want, you know, freshly baked soft rye bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_4">
    <text>You're kidding! Where did you see rye bread in the Zone, and fresh at that?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_5">
    <text>And here you are wrong. There is one person, called Baker. So he bakes real rye bread right here, in the Zone. And his bread turns out not simple... Baker came up with some tricky recipe. Bread baked by him doesn't go stale for about a month and tastes like fresh, even if you carry it in a backpack for a week or two. From what and how he makes his bread, no one knows, but the fact remains a fact. In short, bring me 10 loaves of this bread from Baker, and I will thank you very decently. Well what, deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Deal. Only where do I look for this Baker? Haven't heard anything about him before.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Well here, now you will know. Before he had a bakery at Agroprom in the southern complex, and then mercs came, and he had to get out of there. Now, they say, he went to trader Sidorovich, will make a new bakery there. Well, Sidorovich you surely know or heard about him. On the territory of Deep Station in the village he dwells. So ask him. He will suggest where to find Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright. I'll talk to Sidorovich when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Skinflint. I brought you ten loaves of bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, you helped out! Well, huge thanks to you!</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here. Take the goods.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Aha, give it here. And here is a special present from me to you. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Wow! Dreamed about such one for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Be healthy, Skinflint. Is there any more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Why yes, of course there is. A personal matter, and therefore doubly responsible. Wouldn't trust just anyone. Therefore listen carefully. I will speak quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak, I am listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_3">
    <text>In short, there is a stalker in the Zone. Called Shuttle. He engages in constantly going to the "Big Land" and passing parcels there or from there for those who hire him. Mostly his clients are scientists from Yantar and experienced loner stalkers. But recently I also had to turn to him on an important question.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, his job is serious...</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Agree with you, but he receives big money for it too. Well so, he carried a small suitcase with very important things for me. Which ones - won't say, it doesn't concern the matter. And, in short, he disappeared... Most likely, the poor guy perished in an anomaly or ran into monsters. Although the man is very experienced. If the contents of the case he carried for me fall into "wrong" hands, then I won't be well. I would go searching myself, but can't leave the base right now. Well what, will you help me?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_6">
    <text>No question. I'll help, of course. You pay well. Give details, and I'm off.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_7">
    <text>And here just the complexity of the situation appears... Shuttle contacted last time three days ago. Since then neither hide nor hair of him. I beg you, find Shuttle or what remains of him. And most importantly, return the case with the parcel to me. Last time Shuttle contacted from Rostok. Well, you know, it's unpopulated Wild Territory, people disappear there constantly. Said that he looked after a place for a halt for the night in some secluded place and that's it. After that disappeared. Dig through the whole Rostok, but find my case and some information about Shuttle, I beg you very much. I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Yeah... What a task you gave me... Well okay. I'll try to help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Skinflint. Found I your case.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Oh and good fellow are you, Strelok! And what happened to Shuttle?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I didn't find Shuttle. Apparently, nothing remained of him, except his PDA and diplomat. In the underpass on Rostok was his last shelter among anomalies and monsters. Seems he fell into a trap there.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well okay. He knew what he was going for. Rest in peace. Give me my parcel and Shuttle's PDA quickly. And here is a present from me not worse than last time.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you. Decent payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Sidorovich! I am looking for one person. Called Baker. They say he went to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's correct. A baker appeared here recently. A good man, by the way. And what bread he bakes - simply delicious.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_2">
    <text>Exactly! I am just looking for him for this. So where did he settle?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_3">
    <text>He is right here not far, located in the abandoned village. I'll send a marker to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_4">
    <text>Aha, understood. Thank you. I'll go meet Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What did the dear man come with?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Skinflint asked me to bring him ten loaves of rye bread, which only you bake. How much do I owe you?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>A-a-ah, Skinflint. Remember this freedomer. Not a bad guy. I don't really need money right now. You better help me in one matter, and I will give you ten loaves.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_5">
    <text>To bake bread, I need, as you understand, flour. Well and something else. "Something else" I will find myself. But with flour it is tight now. Before I had a bakery at Agroprom, and Freedomers supplied me with flour. And then these cutthroats - mercenaries appeared and everything changed. Lukash and his guys went to Army Warehouses, and I had to look for a new quiet place. Well so, when I decided to move from Agroprom, I initially wanted to settle at the warehouses, closer to Freedomers. \n\nI asked five stalkers then to help me carry bags with flour. And already on the very approach to the Freedom base, in the village at Army Warehouses bloodsuckers attacked us. Tore all my kids to shreds. I barely managed to crawl to the transition to the Bar. Had to abandon the bags. Five bags there were, twenty-five kilograms each. Such a pity... I asked Lukash to find these bags after that, but Freedomers are afraid to poke into that village. Then, being in the Bar, I decided not to risk like that anymore and came here. Here seems to be the quietest place, although far from the center of the Zone. But soon I'll establish direct flour supplies, and business will go.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_6">
    <text>So how can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_7">
    <text>The matter is simple. Bloodsuckers don't eat flour after all. So somewhere there in the village these bags must be. True, most likely these beasts scattered them. You go to this village at the Warehouses, find and bring me these five bags of flour. And so you don't run five times, I will give you a unique anti-gravity suit. Wearing it, you can easily carry about a hundred and eighty kilograms. Then you will return it to me. I bartered it from master Lefty for thirty loaves. Look, don't lose it!</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Ye-eah... That's quite a distance to trudge.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_9">
    <text>And here I will help you. Listen to me carefully: from here, from the Peacekeepers territory, you can get to the "Bar" itself by one very tricky secret path bypassing the Cordon, Dark Valley and Forest. Yes-yes, don't be surprised. There is such a path. I came here from the Bar by it. Pathfinder showed me this path for twenty loaves of my bread. Under other circumstances I wouldn't open this secret path to anyone, but now the situation is exceptional. I can't go for the bags myself, old already, legs refuse to walk completely... So, if you don't want to go back through posts, cordons and garbage dumps, then use my path.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_10">
    <text>So, interesting. This changes things completely! If from here one can get to the Bar, then it's a stone's throw to the Warehouses. Speak, where does your path start?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_11">
    <text>From here go to the north-west of the territory. There, not far from the path, is a railway with an anomaly walking along the wires. This path will lead you to the southern entrance to the Bar. Well if you don't find it, you'll have to go to the Warehouses and back. Same way as you came here. Well what, agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright, Baker, agreed. Give the suit and see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Baker, here are your bags. All five. Barely found them.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok! Can say, you are saving small business in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Come on, don't talk nonsense. Here, take the bags and your gravisuit. By the way, the suit is a thing!</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Give it. And here are your ten loaves, as agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Aha. That's nice.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_0">
    <text>Baker, listen. Sell me your gravisuit. I liked it very much. Can carry so much stuff with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_1">
    <text>Sorry, Strelok, can't. No way without it for me, understand yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, understand, of course. But liked it painfully much...</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_3">
    <text>So. If you want the same for yourself, then listen here: at Cordon at the Military base there are more anti-gravity suits, I know for sure. Here is my advice to you: Acquire this body armor from them and take it to Lefty. He will modernize it for you into the same one as mine. I on my part will warn Lefty that Strelok will come with this question... Lefty won't refuse, don't doubt! True, will have to do something for him too, but that's the rule of the Zone, understand yourself...</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you, Baker, for the advice. Will definitely use it.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Lefty!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_1">
    <text>O-oh, Strelok, what brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_2">
    <text>Well I have an anti-gravity military body armor here...</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_3">
    <text>Everything is clear. Want to modernize? Is that so?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_4">
    <text>Absolutely correct.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, this can be arranged... From you, only out of respect to you of course, just one mesomodificate - "Fire Soul".</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood everything, here is the anti-gravity vest for you, and as I have "Fire Soul" - I'll be right back to you, and you engage meanwhile, I'll be quick.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Lefty!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_1">
    <text>O-oh, Strelok, brought me "Fire Soul"?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Sure! Here it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Come on, come on, let's see...</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_4">
    <text>What, don't trust?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Come on, don't get heated, everything is normal. Here, hold the new thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Thank you! Hope this is what I need.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I do anything else for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, actually, there is one more business.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak, don't torment.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, strictly speaking, simple matter: I am trying to organize a small bakery here, and for this need to fix the stove. It is completely good for nothing. Missing something for repair. When I left Agroprom hastily, left a lot there. Now I regret.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand that you need to bring something from Agroprom?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, absolutely correct. I hid the most valuable in a secluded spot. Boarded up in a wooden crate and hid reliably. You will need to find this place and bring me the crate with spare parts for the stove from there. Well, various iron pieces inside: burners, pipes, manometer.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. And where to look for this place?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, you see, it was night... Was making my way along the edge of the swamp, through reeds in northern direction. Then reached an island and put the crate in some rusty pipe. Thought, I'll return and pick it up later. And look how it all turned out. Where I ended up from Agroprom now. In short, need to search in the area of this island. Can't say more precisely. Only hope is on you, Strelok. Or my assistant drank himself away completely, can't trust him with anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_8">
    <text>And what assistant do you have? I understood you live here alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_9">
    <text>What assistant is he. Drunkard. Vano is his name. So, helps around the house sometimes. But serious business can't be trusted to him. Found a "Freedom" suit somewhere, put it on. Says that he is now "Freedomer" and will leave to them soon. Went completely crazy, the small one. Wandered somewhere for a week, now appeared. Sleeping in the back room on the couch. If you want, can look at this "miracle of nature". Maybe, reason with him with a strong man's word. Pity him, honestly speaking, the guy. Perishing...</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, Baker, agreed. Will be at Agroprom, try to find your crate. And now I'll go look at your Vano.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Baker. I found your little crate with iron pieces.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok! Now we'll fix the stove, and business will go deftly.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well, that's glorious. Take your crate.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wait. Let me thank you. Here, take a flamethrower, fully charged. Made it with my own hands from improvised means. Against bloodsuckers and other filth will be just the thing. If later, when you use all combustible mixture and want to charge it again, then turn to Screw, "Freedom" mechanic. He will help.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you for the flamethrower. Well all, I went. Many things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Borov. Mercenaries destroyed.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok, well done! Helped out! Can say, saved life.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on. Today I helped you, tomorrow you me. In the Zone no other way.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait. Let me thank you. Here, take. Twenty thousand rubles won't be extra.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, Borov. I have a proposal for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_1">
    <text>What proposal?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_2">
    <text>Well I, in connection with today's situation with mercenaries at southern checkpoint, looked closer at your fortifications and want to say that they are good for nothing. One more such sudden attack and you are done for. Especially weak looks the northern checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes I see it myself. Well and what exactly do you propose?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_4">
    <text>I have guys familiar, free stalkers. Used to work as military builders. Good specialists in various fort structures. Could agree for a reasonable fee with them, so they strengthen or redo both checkpoints.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_5">
    <text>And what to think here? Proposal is good. Or the gang that lives here, can't do a damn thing, only guzzle vodka and swear eternally. What is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I think, to start need to determine the front of work and make an estimate. Agree on money and then start work. For me, to start talking with them, need to clearly outline the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_7">
    <text>Well lead them to me, we'll chat.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_8">
    <text>No, they won't go like that. Let me first outline the situation to them in detail, and they already come with proposal and estimate. But for this I need a detailed map of the Bar and adjacent territories, not to explain on fingers to them. Is there such map?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, I have such map. Want - take. Only return definitely.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_10">
    <text>That is good. Means, agreed. Give the map and I went to the guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_0">
    <text>Borov, I am looking for one person here.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_1">
    <text>What person?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_2">
    <text>Called Antiquarian. Say, one can acquire rare ammo from him.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_3">
    <text>There is such speculator - rubs in all sorts of old stuff for triple price, acquired somewhere at Army Warehouses rarity arsenal of past century, fixed guns, cleaned and now passes for antiques... He is just here right now. Search him on the territory of the prison, in the house, that to the right from passage and slightly in depth.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you, going find Antiquarian.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Good health, are you Antiquarian?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes it's me. Need something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, Noodle told me that you have ammo for revolver, can you sell?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Sell won't sell, but can exchange. Change one pack of ammo for 3 bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Well then, deal, going find 3 bottles for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Here, hold three bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>O, that is business! Give it here the darling. And here is for you, as agreed, your pack.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Give. And do you have more ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yes, I have more ammo for revolver. Bring three more bottles and another pack is yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Alright, agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Antiquarian, I have more vodka for exchange.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>That is good, give three bottles of vodka and take pack of ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_0">
    <text>And hello to you. Who might you be?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_1">
    <text>My name is Pathfinder, but unlikely it will tell you anything. And I wait here, actually for you, Strelok. But first let's have a glass, don't mind? Just no one to talk heart to heart here... understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Understand. But only one glass, no more. I have no time.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Well that is good. Cheers...</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, went well... And now say, why did you need me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Ye-eah, good vodka in the Bar nowadays... Well so, Strelok, one very respected person wants to meet you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Who is such?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_7">
    <text>He asked not to name him, for safety.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, alright. And where does he wait for me, this respected incognito?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_9">
    <text>There is one secret place. At Agroprom, in underground catacombs. Entrance there knows only he alone. And he told me so: "Tell Strelok to go urgently to Agroprom. There, near the northern building will find blocked entrance to catacombs. Well and further I will open passage for him..."</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, you intrigued me... Alright, going find stranger, since I am so needed to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Here, turns out, who waits for me here! Greetings to you, Doctor! And why such conspiracy?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hush, hush, Strelok. Don't rejoice particularly. Not everything is so simple now. You, probably, already know or heard that something huge is plotted in the Zone. In Pripyat now uneasy, mercenaries activated. My heart feels that hard times are coming.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>So what, you moved here from Swamps now?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>No, not everything is so dramatic yet. I am here, so to speak, "passing through". Went to Agroprom, for some herbs. Now going back to Swamps, and dropped here to rest. Here quiet, hidden from strangers eyes place, as you see yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Clear. And Pathfinder, who is he?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Pathfinder - he is my old friend and guide. So don't worry, proven man, more than once rescued me from trouble. Better guide than him in whole Zone not find. He finds such paths that sometimes you marvel at his flair and intuition. You stop by him later, talk, maybe, mutual interest will be found.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Understood. Will stop by Pathfinder when possible. And why did you search for me? Have business for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_7">
    <text>Listen, Strelok, possibly, Feldsher with Ghost and Fang will have to move here from Pripyat in near future, and, possibly, me too. Therefore will need reliable place where one can hide for long time, understand? Yes and to you it will be useful too. We are now one team... I beg you, organize a stash here, about which only we four will know. Except you now no one else will be to look after this stash. Collect here just in case supply of provisions and weapons, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_8">
    <text>Alright, Doctor, agreed. Especially since place is gorgeous. Not a single beast will poke here.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_9">
    <text>Well, that is glorious. Use this place for yourself as you deem necessary. Entrance here for now will be from top, from Agroprom, but then will need to block it for good. Unreliable it is... Teleport, that blocks entrance from bottom from catacombs, already aged. It will stop functioning soon itself. Therefore you, Strelok, somehow later must secure this stash from strangers and monsters...</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_10">
    <text>Alright, I in bottom, in dungeon, will place tripwire at entrance to hole, as soon as blocking teleport stops acting. So that, Doctor, careful there, if come without me. And pass to your Feldsher, Ghost and Fang, let be more careful. From top, from Agroprom, entrance to stash will block tightly later, can not worry. Entrance will remain only from bottom, from catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_11">
    <text>Agreed. Let be so. Exit teleport from this stash to Agroprom I installed in hole. Use it for now. Later, when lower teleport, blocking entrance to hole, disappears, then this one, working for exit, also will disappear.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_12">
    <text>Everything clear. Well, I went, see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Pathfinder. Met I with your incognito.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well that is excellent. Names here aloud won't pronounce.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Listen, he told me that you are best guide in Zone and know many secret paths, unknown to others. Is it true?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, it is so. Many secret paths known to me. But not everything is so simple, as you think. If you really interested in possibility to secretly move around Zone, cross from one territory to another where others can't, then I can assist you in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_4">
    <text>You ask! Of course, interests me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, then listen: Secret paths in Zone open not often and remain available for movement for small period of time, on average about a week. To find such paths, need very rare artifact. Called "Guide". Appears very rarely and in places deaf and unpopulated. And, as rule, not far from that place, where it was born, will be path located. True, one but - by such paths can go only in one direction. Return have to either by known to all routes, or search new artifact on that territory, from which want to find secret path.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Interesting. Didn't hear about this before. And what is needed to find this path for sure?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_7">
    <text>If find artifact "Guide", then carry it to me. I will be able to determine exact location of path on that territory where you found artifact and where this path will lead you. Well and then, put mark on PDA for you, so that path you could for sure find. Well and as payment for my services will take from you this very artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Labs, agreed. And how does it look at least, this artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes you won't confuse it with any other. "Guide" has unearthly beauty burgundy glow and rays. Most often "Guide" can be found on Rostok, on Cordon, on Agroprom and on Army Warehouses. In other places it is great rarity.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood everything. As find artifact "Guide", then straight to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Strelok. There is one more difficult matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_2">
    <text>Difficult matters - that's exactly for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, then listen carefully: I must soon move out to Pripyat, but I have to go through Yantar, and then through the Pripyat underground bypassing the Radar. The road is calm on one hand, deserted, and few mutants. But on the other hand, there is an impassable multitude of anomalies. And I need one artifact for my journey, a very rare one. It is called "Liquidator". Its only and main property is that when thrown on the ground, it destroys all known anomalies within a radius of 15 meters. That's what I need. And you will help very much if you obtain one such artifact for me. More than one is not needed, as it is of reusable action.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_4">
    <text>Very interesting. Never heard of such an art.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_5">
    <text>And here is the most important part. There is a small group of stalkers in the Zone, about ten people. They call themselves "Railroaders". Very strange guys, I tell you. Their main stalker is nicknamed "Lector". And the rest, rumor has it, are sort of like twin brothers all. And there are rumors that they are cannibals... So this group lives somewhere behind the Rostok factory territory. They are the best artifact seekers and mutant hunters in the Zone. They look severe of course, strongly resemble zombies, but they say it's because long ago they got under a strong blowout and didn't die, but sort of mutated. Adapted to the effects of radiation and psi-emission, and also began to sense places where rare artifacts are born with their gut. And they sense monsters a mile away. So they definitely must have a "Liquidator". Find the Railroaders, talk to Lector. Maybe you'll manage to agree with him and obtain the needed art.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. But how do I find these guys? Can you tell more precisely?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_7">
    <text>Means, as I already told you, they dwell somewhere on the territory of the Rostok factory construction site. If you bring me the "Liquidator" artifact, I won't remain in debt. I will thank you royally.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood everything. Moving out to the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Pathfinder, I brought you the "Liquidator" artifact. Oh and strange are those Railroaders!</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, thank you, Strelok, helped out. I won't remain in debt either. Here, take this.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Give it, won't refuse! And here, hold your artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good afternoon. Are you Lector?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. What brought you, stalker, to these wild places? Decided to hunt monsters?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>No. I have business with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, then lay out why you came.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_0">
    <text>They say you are the best artifact seekers and monster hunters in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_1">
    <text>We don't think about it much. Who is better, who is worse. We simply try to survive, that's all. But actually it is quite flattering to hear such things about ourselves always. So what exactly brought you to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_2">
    <text>One good person needed a very rare artifact - "Liquidator". And finding it, as they say, can only be done by such experienced stalkers as you. That's why I came to you for help. By the way, my name is Strelok. Well what, will you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_3">
    <text>You know, Strelok, if you came at another time, then, despite even your flattering speeches in our address, I would have sent you far away. But now we also need some help. Help us, and we will help you. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Of course. And what is required to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_5">
    <text>So: One of our brothers nicknamed Sledgehammer and two of his assistants left three days ago to Yantar to the scientists for "Antizombie". As you see, we are not quite healthy... These are consequences of a powerful blowout we got under a year ago. And we need this preparation to survive and not turn into walking zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_6">
    <text>I understand... And?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_7">
    <text>And that Sledgehammer and the guys should have returned yesterday before lunch... We have very little time, need to take preparations urgently, and there are none. People are in critical condition. Look, Alex can't be helped anymore... Had to shoot the poor guy so he wouldn't suffer. In short, I have no one to send to search for the missing group now. And you appeared just handily. Go, find the missing guys. If they are dead, take the Antizombie from them. Should be ten boxes and also one device, determining the date and exact time of the next blowout. Sledgehammer was carrying it to us. This device is also extremely necessary for us. Therefore the task is such: find the missing group or what remains of them and bring ten boxes of Antizombie and the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright. But where should I look for them?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, from Yantar they definitely crossed to the Wild Territory, as the last time they contacted they were already on the road, further than the transition to Yantar. Worth searching there, it's not far from here: As you find yourself on the road, after the tunnel with burners, just go further. Scour every bush there, but find the guys or what remains of them, and most importantly, bring what I ask.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Everything is clear. I'll go, try to find the missing group and bring what is required.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found the bodies of all three couriers. Apparently, they ran into mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Eh, losses again... Lost six people already lately. Well okay, this is the Zone... Did you bring what we are waiting for?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes. I brought ten Antizombies and the device. Is my artifact ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Here is the thing... I don't have the artifact you need. But we have one person who knows exactly where it can be found. He is the best among us in searching for rare artifacts and shooting mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>And who is this?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>His name is Zveroboy, my right hand. Yes, actually, there he appeared, talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Alright. Take your loot, and I'll go talk to Zveroboy.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. Are you Zveroboy?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Lector told me you are searching.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Well so speak, where do I find the "Liquidator" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen, I will tell you where to find "Liquidator". Just help us one more time, I beg you very much. A new type of mutants appeared here recently. Very similar to boars, but just painfully tenacious. These beasts gave us no peace for a whole month. Mauled two of our brothers to death. We arranged a roundup on them then, from ten barrels barely laid down two: turned out to be a male and female, but didn't find their brood. And now the offspring of these beasts appeared, even more insidious and angry... We can't arrange a roundup on them now, need to patch up wounds. And you, I see, are a capable fellow. Surely can outwit and destroy the mutants. Yes and moreover it will be on your way. And to handle them more deftly, I will give you an M320 handheld grenade launcher and a dozen charges for it. And three F-1 grenades.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, persuaded. Now give details, where to look for the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_5">
    <text>As I understand, you will have to give this "Anomaly Liquidator" to the customer, right? And it is a very valuable and necessary thing. And surely you wouldn't mind having one for yourself. So, you are helping us greatly, therefore listen here: "Liquidators" are born only in one place - at Rostok. Look inside the boarded-up house. Radiation is high there, but I think it won't scare you off. Try to get into this house through a hole in the roof. Just be careful, there is a deep pit under the hole. If you fall, you won't get out yourself. And there should be at least two artifacts there. I feel it with my spinal cord, and my flair never failed me in this matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Good, deal. I help you one more time. Where were the piglet-boars seen last time?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Piglets, you say... You should have seen them! These will be larger than a chimera. And last time we saw them near the tunnel, which is not far from the transition to Yantar. Three of them were there. Destroy the superboars, definitely take their hooves. Bring three pieces as proof of completed work.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Ok. Give the grenade launcher and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>And insidious beasts they turned out to be! Barely managed.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, you are well done! Rid us of danger. Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Don't mention it. And the grenade launcher is really good. Liked it very much: light, doesn't take much space, and at the same time quite powerful. Cool toy.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Give the hooves. And take this grenade launcher for yourself as a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you. Here, hold the hooves.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I be of use in anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, you can. We caught one mercenary here recently, armed to the teeth. He lagged behind his own and, apparently, got lost. So, he had a unique helmet with him, protecting from harmful impact of blowouts, and also a very fancy gun. Well, when we started torturing him, who is he and why he was hanging around here, he spilled everything to us. Mercs plotted some operation in the Zone: Transported weapons and gear on choppers, and someone shot down their choppers. And now they pursue the offenders and try to save their gear and weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_2">
    <text>So, interesting. And what?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_3">
    <text>We tortured out of him that they hid three more protective helmets, same as he had, on Yantar not far from the main entrance to the X-16 complex territory. In the area of garages worth searching. And also, probably, slightly further, where the pipe was laid. We really need these very helmets. True, they need to be tuned individually, but we will solve this later with the eggheads.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_4">
    <text>By the way, and where is this mercenary now?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Where-where... Doesn't matter where. He is no more... In short, will you undertake finding and bringing us three protective helmets on Yantar? And I will give you that mercenary's unique assault rifle for the work. Notable thing, won't regret. Well how?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Labs, agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Well and lastly: from here to Yantar one can get only through Rostok, somewhere must be a path to Yantar, don't know exactly where. Surely only experienced guys, that are in the Bar, can know. Count, for example.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood everything, moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Zveroboy, I barely found these three protective helmets.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well and well done! Give them here, and I prepared the mercenary's gun for you, as promised. Fully cleaned, oiled. In short, like new. Yes, and also Lector wanted to talk to you very much. Approach him.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well that's glorious. Hold the helmets and give the gun. Can't wait already to see what mercenaries fight with nowadays. I'll talk to Lector now.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Pathfinder! I found the "Guide" artifact on Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_1">
    <text>You are lucky. Let's see where your path is hiding and where it will lead you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold the artifact. Just careful, it is very hot.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so... Aha, here we clarified the situation. The path leads from Rostok straight to Army Warehouses. Sent the mark of the beginning of the path to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_4">
    <text>Grasped. Thank you, I'll check this path when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder. I found the "Guide" artifact at Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, let's look what kind of path we have here.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so... Aha, everything is clear. The path leads from Army Warehouses to the Dark Valley. Sent the mark of the beginning of the path to your PDA. Look later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_4">
    <text>That is good. Thank you, I'll check this path when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder. I found the "Guide" artifact at the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_1">
    <text>Let's take a look what secret path will open to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so... Aha, understood. The path leads from the Cordon to Agroprom, bypassing the Garbage. Sent the mark of the beginning of the path to your PDA, look later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything. Thank you, I'll check this path when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder. I found the "Guide" artifact at Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_1">
    <text>You are a lucky one, Strelok. Let's see what path opens its "embrace" before you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so... Aha, interesting. The path leads from Agroprom to the Cordon. Sent the mark of the beginning of the path to your PDA. Look later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything. Thank you, I'll check this path when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, did you want something?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I can offer you, Strelok, a mutually beneficial deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_2">
    <text>O-oh, so you know me too! Well, speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I have been waiting for such an experienced stalker as you, Strelok, for a very responsible and secret task. So, the matter is this: the military at the Checkpoint, which is at the Cordon, had a manual for assembling Item 62, aka "Gauss Rifle". Well, I think there is no need to explain what kind of thing this is. So, there were seven parts in the manual in total, each in a separate folder. I say "were", because two months ago some daredevil stalkers caught a soldier from the Checkpoint, and he "bought" his life for information about the location of the manual parts and led the stalkers secretly to the Checkpoint at night. They managed to steal six parts of the manual, but one part remained on the territory of the Checkpoint in some stash, which they didn't have time to reach. The military raised the alarm for the whole garrison then.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Interesting topic. And what happened next?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Next, these daredevils, there were exactly six of them, split up. And everyone took one part of the manual. The military arranged a roundup for these stalkers throughout the Zone. Searched for them for a long time, but couldn't catch them. But, nevertheless, none of this six survived. \n\nOne, having met a small group of familiar stalkers, ran into a pack of hungry pseudodogs together with them somewhere at the Garbage. \nThe second decided to hide in the Agroprom undergrounds, and perished there. \nThe third climbed for some reason into the X-18 laboratory, which is in the "Dark Valley". He didn't come out of there. \nThe fourth disappeared somewhere in the forest on the Radar. He contacted us, apparently, before his death. Said he was hiding in some rocks. \nThe fifth, their leader, an experienced Digger, reached as far as Pripyat. His trail is lost somewhere in the area of the hotel. \nThe sixth... They chased him longer than others. Wounded him. He then sat out at the scientists' on Yantar for some time. Then, as he patched up his wounds, went to perform some task for the scientists in gratitude for the treatment in laboratory X-16. But, as you guess, he didn't return from there, disappeared somewhere in the labyrinths of X-16...</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Wow, things! And how do you know so many details about this case?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Because before going to the Checkpoint for the manual, these very stalkers came to me... And we agreed with them then that they bring the manual "obtained" from the military, and I in return make the "Item". Spare parts are not a problem for me. We were constantly in touch with them, that's why I know approximately where each of them ended his path. In short, it is required to find the bodies of all six stalkers and take all six parts of the manual from them. Besides this, it is necessary to find that very stash on the territory of the Checkpoint at the Cordon, which the guys didn't reach, and pick up the seventh part, and then bring all seven parts of the assembly manual to me. In return, I will assemble a rifle for you according to the brought schematics and give batteries for it. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, deal. As I find all seven parts, I'll come straight to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>That's it, Potapov! I found all seven parts of the assembly manual.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hush, hush! Why are you making noise?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>What, what... Look how many eyes and ears are around. And the matter is secret. For the information you obtained, anyone is ready to gnaw a throat.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Alright, understood everything. And what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>And next is this: you give me all seven parts of the manual now, and I, as agreed, will assemble the rifle and you will receive the first specimen. Got it? But I need some time... In short, it's a delicate matter. Therefore come to me at three in the morning, not earlier. Just look, I will wait for you exactly from three at night to five in the morning. Got it? Only two hours at your disposal. While everything here, in the Bar, is quiet. At other times don't even come, there will be no conversation.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Ok! Agreed. Hold the seven parts of the manual. And after three at night I'm straight to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_0">
    <text>Well? Is everything ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_1">
    <text>Hush-hush! Yes, everything is ready. Here, take the first specimen and batteries. As charges run out, come to me, I'll give new ones. More precisely, sell, understood? Can buy immediately if you want.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, understood everything. Give it here.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow! Don't believe my eyes! Semetsky in person.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, it's me. And you, I understand, are Strelok? Yeah, in an interesting place and at an interesting moment we met with you... I know why you are here.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I am looking for my brother. And you are my last hope. And how did you get here? And what happened to you generally? Everyone has considered you a legend for a long time, one of the mysteries of the Zone. Where are these constant messages about your death from? And what is known to you about the fate of the Captain?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I came here for the sake of this stone, damn it!.. I have been in the Zone from the very beginning. There were few of us then, twenty people, maybe thirty. And everyone strove here, to the center of the Zone. Someone wanted to get rich at the expense of artifacts, someone to learn the secret of the Sarcophagus and the Monolith, and someone simply fled here from worldly cares and problems. And I... I was just young and hot then... Wanted to save the whole world... I had my reasons for that. It was the Captain who pulled me into that insane scam with the hike to the Sarcophagus. I hate him for that! He was stubborn and fearless, but crazy. He liked the Zone, now I know it for sure. He almost "merged" with it, fell in love with it. And I... I wanted just...</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_4">
    <text>So what happened to you then after all? And is my brother still alive?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I wanted to find a way to destroy the Zone. Too much it took from me... Rumors circulated then that in the very heart of the Zone, in the Sarcophagus, there is a magic crystal - the Monolith, which can fulfill one most cherished wish. I naively assumed that I could put an end to the growing Zone in such a way. Believed in a miracle. Fool! Thought that there is no connection between the Zone and the Monolith, and that this is an "Artifact of Fate" that can help... And we and the Captain managed then with the help of our partners to penetrate inside the Sarcophagus and find this cherished stone. Only I and he penetrated the Sarcophagus. I thought that we had one goal with him, but I was mistaken... I made my wish... Captain too.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_6">
    <text>And what happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_7">
    <text>...The Monolith threw me out, like a blind kitten, somewhere in the region of the Red Forest. And the Zone after that expanded even more. What happened later to our friends, with whom we came to the Sarcophagus, I don't know. But the Captain...</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_8">
    <text>What happened to him? And what wish did he make?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_9">
    <text>He wished for the Zone to share its great power with him. He was ready for the sake of this even to "dissolve" in it. He knew exactly that the Monolith and the Zone - are one whole. So he "became related" to the Zone...</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_10">
    <text>How is that? I didn't understand... So is my brother alive or dead?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_11">
    <text>Hard to understand... He is neither alive, nor dead. He is now part of the Zone, as he wanted. Only don't know if he is glad about it... He became the most powerful artifact with such properties and power that no one even dreamed of. In short, I cannot explain this to you. You need to see and understand everything yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, but for this first need to find him! Where do I look for my brother? Well or that, who or what he is now?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_13">
    <text>Getting to him is not simple... You are going to the Control Bunker right now, right? You were sort of sent to find out what is happening there. There you will receive all answers, including about your brother. Only I don't advise you to poke in there. Forget about it and while there is still time, get away from this place! You are unlikely to be able to help your brother with anything anymore, only will ruin your life in vain or just like us, turn into some "original" unmanufactured creation of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_14">
    <text>No! I must walk my path to the end! I believe in luck. It was always with me while I walked here. I swore to myself that I would find my brother or know for sure that he is dead. So, until I received all answers and confirmations, I won't turn from the path.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_15">
    <text>Well, as you know. You, apparently, are as stubborn and crazy as your brother... I'll give you a last piece of advice: in the Bunker, where you are heading now, great danger awaits you. Try not to lose reason and self-control. Your own mind will be the best weapon there. While your will is strong, you will have at least some chance.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_16">
    <text>Alright, I understood you. Tell me, and what happened to you next?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_17">
    <text>The Zone and this damn shard played a cruel joke on me. Turned into the one you see before yourself now... Instead of fulfilling my wish, the Monolith blinded me, plunging into eternal darkness, endowed with sharpened animal senses and gave immortality... Hundreds of times after that I died and rose from the dead, wandering in eternal darkness, having no opportunity to change anything anymore. There are so many holes and scars on my body that no living patch of skin remains at all... Monsters killed me, bullets "caught up", tore apart in anomalies. I have long been not a human at all, but simply another "Miracle of the Zone", like your brother. And the Zone doesn't let me go, its "favorite Zombie".</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_18">
    <text>And why did you come here again, to the Monolith?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_19">
    <text>I must destroy it... Or let it destroy me. I don't care anymore. I waited for this moment for a very long time. And you helped me get here, clearing the path to the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_20">
    <text>Wait. Maybe you have some other way out?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_21">
    <text>I have no other way out. And you go, maybe, you will be lucky. And I am here alone... This is my war... Yes, and also here, take. This is a gift to you from me. In gratitude that you helped me get here, into the Sarcophagus, faster.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_22">
    <text>What is this?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_23">
    <text>This is "Wind Rose" - a rarest artifact, possessing magical power. Not a single human ever found such, and unlikely will ever be able to find, because "Wind Rose" appears in such places, where only a mutant can get... If you still manage to find your brother, or rather what he is now, then this artifact can help. It will lower the power of "shackles of the mind" for some time. And if the Captain is still able to think and make decisions, if he wants to free himself from his "captivity", then possibly something will work out... And now go... Go away from here, I say!</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_24">
    <text>Alright. I am leaving to the Control Bunker. Thank you and good luck to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Solomon! Long time no see!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok. Have urgent business for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes too much evil spirits bred here lately, especially near generators and in the eastern part of CNPP-2. Yesterday I went for reconnaissance of the area, ran into monsters and accidentally dropped my PDA exactly in the eastern part. Need to return it. There is a lot of important information... Won't be hard to find. It lies somewhere on the asphalt path. Will you take it? And I will give you an exoskeleton, powerful machine gun and ammo for it for this business. With such gear it will be pure entertainment for you to mow down mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, deal. Give the gun and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I brought your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Strelok! And I didn't doubt you, well done!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Machine gun is a thing! Returning...</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_3">
    <text>No, keep it for yourself, as a reward. Thank you for everything! Yes, and also. You are going to the bunker now, right? Be careful. The "eggheads" are plotting something serious there with their experiments. Be more attentive. Personally I don't really trust them. Where did they even get there from? Don't understand... Apparently, cleared the entrance from inside the sarcophagus... Well, good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you too. And see you... Well, or just in case, farewell!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_0">
    <text>And who are You?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_1">
    <text>And we, Strelok, are those who have been waiting for you for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_2">
    <text>How do you know me? Did we meet before?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_3">
    <text>No, we haven't had the honor to meet you before, but we know everything about you! In some sense we are Gods... Well or almost... We can make people happy, or vice versa. Everything will depend on behavioral instincts and... on the readiness of consciousness to perceive impulses given to it... But this is long to explain.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Everything somehow fits very intricately with you... And why do you, Gods, need me?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, you received a task from the Doctor to sneak into the Bunker and find out all secrets and mysteries. Welcome! Come in. We don't bite, will show and tell you everything. We have no secrets for those who came to us themselves. Or, maybe, you changed your mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_6">
    <text>No, didn't change mind. I always bring what started to the end!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Well then, then for a start I will show you the first truth. Are you ready to see what is in reality, and not what we allow to see?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, I said that I am ready! I came here for answers!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Is this some kind of prank?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_1">
    <text>And do we, Strelok, look like clowns?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_2">
    <text>So it means, all this time you created an illusion in the heads of everyone who tried to find out the truth about your designs?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I already told you that we are almost Gods and can do things that neither you, nor anyone else even guess about.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_4">
    <text>And what is your goal?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_5">
    <text>The goal is only one - this is our Zone and we are its masters. And humans, these talking monkeys, have no place here. Together we will never get along. Therefore we will close access for humanity to the center of the Zone and stop any encroachments on our Shrines! And whoever dares and dares to disturb us, will be destroyed.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_6">
    <text>And why haven't you killed me yet? After all I am a human!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_7">
    <text>And you still don't understand? Listen to yourself. You are the same as us, "Child of the Zone". Remember how you got into the Zone, what happened to you after the Big Blow. Where, when and most importantly how, you ended up where you were found. You just decided not to think about it and drive away any thoughts about what happened to you. Did you ever wonder why the Zone left you alive then? But in vain. It "created" you, like all of us. You are another new "Form" of life, capable of surviving in the Zone. Let the appearance of a human remain with you, but your essence - is the essence of a mutant! \n\nExcept you no one would have been able to reach here, into the Bunker. And you reached not only because you were sent here, but to a greater extent because you are drawn here, into the very heart of the Zone, like by a magnet. You see, hear and feel not as a human anymore, but as a mutant. Your instincts are sharpened, you are agile, hardy and fearless, like a beast. Your mind is sharp, like a razor blade. You are just afraid to admit this to yourself. Fool! You are trying to fight with yourself, trying to remain human, stifling new abilities granted to you by the Zone. Let yourself go, be who you have long become. Don't torment yourself, but live in harmony with your new home, with the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I don't believe you. I am a human! Human by appearance and by my essence!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_9">
    <text>And you are just as stubborn and stupid as your brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_10">
    <text>What?.. You know my brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Your brother is no longer your brother. He is part of us, part of the Zone. His inner power and mind serve us now. Want to join him? We can easily arrange this. Only there is no sense in this, believe me. Still everything will be as we want.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_12">
    <text>What are you talking about! I came here to save him.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_13">
    <text>Alright, don't worry so much. Anyway you will understand and realize everything yourself soon. And now there is no time. Soon there will be a blowout and an explosion, very powerful and dangerous for everyone. After it a lot in the Zone will change, a lot will fall into its rightful places. Then it will become clear to you too who you really are... And now need to take cover and wait out. We will help you. There is no way back from here anyway. We blocked all exits from the Sarcophagus and Control Bunker. Therefore choose: you go with us into shelter, and we will protect you from the approaching blowout, and you will be saved. Or you will go straight to your brother. You walked here for so long for this after all? But what can happen to your split mind there, when you meet with "brother" - is a complete mystery even for us. Honestly speaking, we are afraid to approach "him" ourselves... Yes and you have no time left for rescue already. Well, what do you choose?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_14">
    <text>Apparently, I have no other choice... I am going with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_15">
    <text>Go to hell, degenerates, together with your Zone! I am going to my brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_0">
    <text>Sakharov told me that one of your employees disappeared and help is needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Strelok, help is needed. Here is what happened: we sent one of our lab technicians, Lazarev, to Agroprom, to the swamp, so he would conduct tests of a new device there, fixing the level and dynamics of growth of anomalous activity. Well and so he didn't return. Last time he contacted us when he was already there, at the swamp. And then some crackling, and silence on the air...</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_2">
    <text>So, understood. And how can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_3">
    <text>Need to find out what happened to Lazarev. At least some information is needed. Go to Agroprom, find out what happened there and report the results to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_4">
    <text>Everything is clear, moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well what, I was at Agroprom, at the swamp. Found the body of lab technician Lazarev. Some strange beasts appeared there, similar to snorks, but excessively tenacious, swamp crawlers. They worked him over...</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Ay-ay-ay... And the device? Did you bring the device back?</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, here it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Very good that you brought us the device. Here is a reward for this. A very rare artifact "Moon Dummy". Does it suit you? Yes, and also... Talk to Dan, please. We have one important matter here, can't be resolved somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_4">
    <text>"Moon Dummy", of course, suits. Rare artifact. Give it. And I'll talk to Dan definitely.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I be of use?</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_1">
    <text>You can. Here not far, on the swamp, which is under the bridge, beasts started living. Very similar to snorks, but only very tenacious, scum. Crawl in circles around our base at night. Any moment, will attack in a pack, we won't fight them off. Swamp Crawlers they call them.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you suggesting I shoot these mutants?</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_3">
    <text>Quick-witted. Exactly. Destroy the beasts to the root. Can you handle it? We won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_4">
    <text>Of course, I'll handle it. Prepare the reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_0">
    <text>That's it. Dealt with Swamp Crawlers. They won't disturb you anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well and good job. Hold your fee.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_2">
    <text>O-oh, give it.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_0">
    <text>Something else?</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Strelok. There is a little business, true, dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_2">
    <text>Dangers - are for me. Lay out, what business.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_3">
    <text>Here nearby, at the abandoned military checkpoint, which is in the western part of Army Warehouses, not far from the bloodsucker village, a family of Izloms started living. Insidious beasts, I tell you. They strive to sneak onto our base. Need to clear this place of Izloms. I'll pay with loot. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll take it. Hope payment will be appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_est_0">
    <text>That's it, Izloms destroyed.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You are a risky man, Strelok. Alone against Izloms... Hardly anyone of my guys is capable of such. Here, hold your reward - AKMN assault rifle. Great thing! Well and a pack of ammo, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Give it, thank you. And I went, many things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_0">
    <text>What is it again?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_1">
    <text>One person was looking for you here recently. Introduced himself as Magician. Says, if Strelok appears, let him find him.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_2">
    <text>Magician, you say... Don't know such one. And what did he want? And where to look for him?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_3">
    <text>What he wanted from you, he didn't say. Said that he wants to see you very much. Will wait here, in Pripyat, in the hotel. Says to search in one of the rooms.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_4">
    <text>Clear. Alright, I'll go try to find this Magician. Especially since I, seem to know, who it might be.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_0">
    <text>O-oh, Mervin? And I thought that it is you looking for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, hello, student. I've been waiting for you for a long time to return a debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_2">
    <text>What debt?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_3">
    <text>And this one!</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Mervin! What did you hit me so heartily for and took all things?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_1">
    <text>For your betrayal before the Monolith brotherhood should have killed you altogether. This I still pitied you. Like you, despite everything. Think that it is Doctor, bastard, led you astray from the true path... Well okay, let's consider that we are even.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, even. And what next?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_3">
    <text>And next... If you want to return your things and weapon, then you'll have to perform something for me. Not the first time for you to walk around Pripyat in one sweater and with a knife? As in our first meeting, I'll give you a pistol and two packs of ammo for it one more time.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Stop mocking! What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_5">
    <text>KILL FELDSHER!</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Feldsher, hi. Such matter here...</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>What matter, Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>In short, Mervin lured me to himself, stunned and took all things and weapons. Sent me to kill you. Promised to return everything for this. But don't worry! Of course, I won't do this. I came to you for advice on how to get rid of Mervin and his curses. And return my things and weapons. After all Mervin - he is a sorcerer. Killing him by simple means doesn't seem possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok, for loyalty. And regarding that Mervin cannot be killed, I will tell you this: "There is no defense against a crowbar, if there is no other crowbar". And I just have something that will help you defeat the sorcerer. As they say: "I am not a magician, I am just learning, but good helps create miracles.".</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>And what is this mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>My sawed-off shotgun, modified for a unique special round of crushing power against any evil spirits and devilry, by the way, also made by me. Just for such a case I saved this weapon. Here I see, this hour has come. Well so, I give you the sawed-off shotgun with two rounds, although, think, even one will be enough. And you go and kill Mervin, and rid all of us of one more danger. And regarding your things and weapons don't worry: Ghost knows where Mervin has a stash. I will ask him to go there and pick up all loot and weapons stolen from you. Well, and you as you finish off Mervin, go to Ghost for your things. Well, what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Give the sawed-off shotgun, Feldsher. I'll waste this wizard.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Ghost! Feldsher said that you will pick up my things and weapons stolen by him from Mervin's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes everything is already with me. Feldsher informed me about your problem, and I wasn't lazy, went and picked up your loot and weapons from Mervin's stash. Good thing I spotted where this creep made himself a stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_2">
    <text>That is good! Well, give then my things and weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I will give, of course. But only you do one more business for us. Okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_4">
    <text>What is this! I already crawled the whole Zone at your whim! And again, to simply return my things, need to do something! Got me already, honestly.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_5">
    <text>Come on, don't boil over. Simple matter. Find a crate with dynamite in the Palace of Culture, which mercenaries hid there when they ran things here in Pripyat, and bring it to me. Something I myself couldn't find this crate there, and you are a sharp-eyed man, surely will find. Well and I will say where I hid your things. Yes, here, take a suit for now, two F-1 grenades, a kalash and a pack of ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. Give, I'll do everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found the crate with dynamite.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_1">
    <text>That is glorious. Give it here. Your things are in the hotel, in a closed room. Key from it I don't know where, look for another way to climb inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, hold the crate.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Dan. Can I be of use further?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_1">
    <text>There is one task, very important. Sakharov gave it to me, and I can't send anyone right now. And can't leave myself. It's uneasy here now. Need to find three laser disks with information that represents great value for scientists. These disks are about five years old, but information recorded on them is of very great importance right now. I am not really in the know, but Sakharov says that he got old archival records, and he read there that many years ago, after the second explosion and powerful blowout occurred at the CNPP, a group of military scientists accompanied by a special forces detachment was sent to the Zone. \n\nTheir task was to study strange phenomena that started immediately after that blowout. This group stayed then in the closed Zone for about three months, and then something happened and connection with them was interrupted. A week later two special forces soldiers from that security detachment came, or rather crawled to the Checkpoint. They were in terrible condition, said something incoherent and implausible. They were considered insane and sent to a mental hospital. No one else returned from the group and no one was found, although a search operation was organized immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_2">
    <text>Meaning we are talking about the very first expedition to study the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, this is that very first expedition... So, listen further: Those two soldiers died in the hospital from an excessively high dose of radiation, which they caught in a week while getting out to the Checkpoint. One doctor who observed them in the hospital wrote down everything they told about their misadventures in his diary. This doctor was a friend of Sakharov and when he learned that he was going to work in the Zone, gave him his diary. Among other things, there was information that those first scientists conducted observations of strange metamorphoses occurring with animals. \n\nJudging by records from the diary, under the supervision of scientists in their field laboratory were several caught specimens of dogs, one pig and a dozen rats, which were kept in cages and constantly taken some tests. These animals changed literally before eyes, mutation process went at furious pace in them, and they turned into terrible beasts.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, this is all interesting. And what do disks with information have to do with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't interrupt! Further it says that a month after observations of mutants began, an emergency occurred: Somehow the beasts managed to break out, and they smashed the entire laboratory and damaged most of the scientific equipment, including computers on which all research archives were stored. Mauled three guards and one scientist. Managed to shoot two dogs, all others hid in the forest not far from the camp. As those soldiers said, after this a decision was immediately made to curtail work and urgently return, as delaying and waiting for help became very dangerous. \n\nAll test results and all observations that were conducted, it seemed, were lost. But it turned out that one of the scientists the day before the tragedy recorded all data on three laser disks, which these two special forces soldiers were instructed to take with them and move out as soon as possible to deliver information to the Big Land. The remaining members of the group planned to pack equipment, dismantle the camp and move out a day after them. But, as we know now, none of the remaining survived. And those two on the way fell into a trap to mutants. Escaping, they had to dump all their gear, including the backpack in which the disks lay along with provisions.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_6">
    <text>What things! And where to find that backpack with disks now, lost five years ago? And, by the way, why is five-year-old information so important right now?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_7">
    <text>Those research results. They are priceless, and should reveal the secret and primary cause of mutations of living organisms in the Zone, as they were conducted at the very first stages, immediately after that blowout in two thousand six. Finding disks will be uneasy, but possible. The backpack in whose pocket they lay has already either rotted or mutants tore it apart. But nothing should have happened to the disks. They were in special high-strength plastic cases. Animals don't eat plastic, and if any of the stalkers found them, it would have been known long ago. The place where special forces soldiers dumped their things, according to their description most resembles the territory we now call the Garbage. A landmark on the terrain where to search - is somewhere in ravines, behind one of the garbage heaps. Well what, will you undertake finding those three disks? I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I'll try to help.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Dan! Well what, found I the disks.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>That is great! What, all three?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, all three. Oh and had to climb ravines at the Garbage. A reward is due from you!</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Of course! Here, take in reward "SKS Carbine" and a couple of packs of ammo for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Won't refuse a good carbine, give. And here are your disks. Take and see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Lector. Zveroboy said that you have business for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, there is something interesting for you here. You are a stalker and surely heard that there is a place, where a real Klondike of artifacts is. But, probably, don't really believe in this, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_2">
    <text>Well yes, heard something similar. There were talks that such place exists, but hard to believe in it.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_3">
    <text>And you believe, this place really exists. And rare artifacts are dirt cheap there. Only discovering them is not given to everyone. Something is needed for this. I can tell you how to find that Klondike and stock up on arts nicely. Want?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_4">
    <text>Won't refuse such offer. And what is required from me in return?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_5">
    <text>And in return for this information you bring me one artifact - "Controller's Heart". Bring, and I open the secret to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_6">
    <text>Agreed. Will bring I you "Controller's Heart".</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well here, look, brought I you "Controller's Heart". Tell, how find Klondike of artifacts and your heart.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Brisk you fellow! Well, listen here: this place, as you, probably, know by hearsay, is located in Dark Valley not far from X-18 laboratory complex. There is a lowland behind the hill, here in it is the Klondike. Only far not everyone destined to see artifacts there, because for this need to have something with oneself.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>And what is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Need, that you have with oneself one artifact. Called "Snake Eye". It as if is catalyst for that place. Actually, from it all started. Exactly "Snake Eye" turned out in that place where formed immediately several anomalies and began process of unseen before transmutations. Finding this art is very hard. Had I one. I gave it to one brother named Nut for bringing us very needed medicines. Well so, I know, where can find one more such artifact. And then will open before you "Magic Valley".</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Don't torment, tell faster.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_5">
    <text>What impatient you are! Well, listen here: can find it in forest on Radar near small gap in fencing from barbed wire between two boulders. As find "Snake Eye", so go to Dark Valley. Search cherished lowland and collect artifacts. Understood all?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Yes, everything clear. Thank you for valuable information. Going search "Snake Eye" in forest on Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Wanderer! Sviblov said that you can suggest about one curious little thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_1">
    <text>And good health to you, stalker. What thing? Show.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_2">
    <text>Here look, some Amulet. Emits radiation a little, true.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_3">
    <text>Very rare thing, I tell you. And very valuable. And I even know what it is and for what.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, speak, don't torment.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_5">
    <text>So: this is one of six ancient magic Amulets. I saw similar at one old digger in Pripyat. He told me story about these Amulets. In short, as I already said, there are six in total. That, which you have - is Amulet of first order. And that, which saw I at Digger was of third order. Digger that sly man was, with some young stalkers hunted for various unusual and rare things and mysteries of Zone. So they just at that time searched through whole Zone these very Amulets. He showed me one Amulet and drawings of others, scanned from some ancient book. Asked, if discover such, then carry to him. And he promised pay well. Where these ancient pagan Amulets appeared in Zone, he didn't say...</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_6">
    <text>So-so, interesting. And why are these Amulets so valuable?</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_7">
    <text>Each by itself special value doesn't represent. But if collect all six, then will happen process of catalyzation, and these six Amulets turn into Talisman, which doubles protective properties of all six taken together, and besides this adds something its own. And also, it is absolutely not radioactive. Five ordinal Amulets have various protective properties, and sixth is exactly that very catalyst which will put in action ancient magic. In short, if collect all six ordinal amulets, then can get unique protective Amulet. If hang it on belt, owner will receive very big protection from damages of various character.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_8">
    <text>Wow things, mysticism some. Somehow weakly believed in all this.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_9">
    <text>And you try find all six and check. I look, you fellow sly and curious. Especially since Digger that from Pripyat. Say, died recently under strange circumstances. Where exactly don't know, but say, that last time him somewhere in center of Pripyat saw. So that no one more secrets of Zone scout. Maybe and find him when. More precisely, what from him remained, of course. Suddenly and Amulet that at him turns out. \n\nBy the way, people said, that one of his partners one more Amulet seemingly found. But and he, poor guy, also perished somewhere on Yantar, in laboratory X-16, when already almost left from it by underground catacombs. Either on monster some ran there, or something else. \n\nOne more owner of amulet, by rumors, was dishonest on hand. Traded he that offered service on search of rare artifacts. Took from stalkers prepayment, and work often didn't do. Scammer, in short, was. For this and paid. Him himself later "scammed" - ordered bring something from village of bloodsuckers and gave specially spoiled kalash. Jammed barrel not weakly after five shots. Here there, in Bloodsucker Village, he and couldn't fight off ghouls. Tore him to pieces. And man brave, say, was. So that, possibly, in that village, on Army warehouses lies one more amulet. Places there unpopulated, therefore chance find exists. Where other amulets search, I don't know. In short, dare, Strelok! And I to you on PDA descriptions of all six Amulets send, just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_10">
    <text>Intrigued you me, Wanderer! Thanks for valuable information. Now won't be me peace, until all six Amulets not collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder?! And what you here doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_1">
    <text>Doctor me sent cover you. I sneaked on CNPP from north through Limansk. There is path one there, secret.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_2">
    <text>Glad you see, buddy! What will do?</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_3">
    <text>Someone blocked entrance to Bunker from CNPP. Now there so simply not get. But exists one option.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_4">
    <text>Which? Speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, you know about my abilities open "Secret Trails". Well so, Solomon gave me one artifact - "Guide", found by him long ago in Sarcophagus. "Guide" quite old, but, nevertheless, it shows, that transition from Sarcophagus to Bunker still works, but back already no. Mark I you send on PDA. You need hurry. Return to Sarcophagus, Strelok, find there entrance to Bunker. I can't with you go, as by "Secret Trail" can pass only one. Therefore I will wait here. Hope, you manage open from inside passage to Bunker from CNPP, and then we together figure out, what to what.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood all. Going to Sarcophagus, wait.</text>
</string>
