<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101">
    <text>Thank you... er-r-r... Marked One, right? You helped my colleague Kruglov escape, and as a sign of gratitude I would like to give you our work suit... a very convenient thing, you know... Perhaps I could be of some other use to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1011">
    <text>I'm looking for laboratory X-16. Barman said you might know its location.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1012">
    <text>We've been interested in laboratory X-16 for quite some time... Or rather, that device inside that generates radiation directly affecting people's consciousness. I must disappoint you: it's impossible to get there without special psi-protection. The result will be tragically inevitable - even if you manage to avoid the hordes of zombies around the laboratory entrance, you risk turning into one of them. All this is very serious. True, we've developed a device that helps shield the radiation, but for more precise tuning we need to conduct a series of additional measurements. If you help us with this, in some time we'll probably be able to provide a prototype for field testing.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1013">
    <text>Measurements?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1014">
    <text>If you, together with our employee, make all the necessary measurements, I'll prepare the protective device prototype for work and give it to you. It will most likely allow penetration into the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10141">
    <text>Alright, I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101411">
    <text>Well, that's excellent! Talk to Kruglov and head out. He's already equipped with everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101412">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10142">
    <text>Alright, I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101421">
    <text>Well, that's excellent! Talk to Semenov and head out. He already has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101422">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10143">
    <text>No... I don't want to take this on yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101431">
    <text>A pity, a real pity... I don't even know when we ourselves will be able to send an expedition for measurements.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11">
    <text>Yes-yes? What interests you?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_111">
    <text>I'm looking for laboratory X-16. Barman said you might know its location.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12">
    <text>Thank you, Marked One, for helping Kruglov escape. Take this suit as a reward for your help. And, I suspect, you didn't just come for the reward, am I right?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121">
    <text>I'm looking for laboratory X-16. Barman said you might know its location.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1211">
    <text>We've been studying the radiation from laboratory X-16 for a long time, you won't get through there without special protection. We've developed an appropriate device, but for its tuning we need to conduct a series of measurements. If you help us make these measurements, I'll give you a tuned prototype with which you'll be able to break through to the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12111">
    <text>I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121111">
    <text>Well, that's excellent, talk to Kruglov and head out. He has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12112">
    <text>No, I don't agree yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121122">
    <text>A real pity. We also can't arrange things yet and send an expedition for measurements.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21">
    <text>Yes-yes? What interests you?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211">
    <text>Yes, we know about this laboratory, however we don't know its exact coordinates. Moreover, trying to get there is too dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111">
    <text>Continue.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21111">
    <text>We've been interested in laboratory X-16 for quite some time... Or rather, that device inside that generates radiation directly affecting people's consciousness. I must disappoint you: it's impossible to get there without special psi-protection. The result will be tragically inevitable - even if you manage to avoid the hordes of zombies around the laboratory entrance, you risk turning into one of them. All this is very serious. True, we've developed a device that helps shield the radiation, but for more precise tuning we need to conduct a series of additional measurements. If you help us with this, in some time we'll probably be able to provide a prototype for field testing.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21112">
    <text>Alright, I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211121">
    <text>Well, that's excellent! Talk to Kruglov and head out. He's already equipped with everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111211">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21113">
    <text>Alright, I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211131">
    <text>Well, that's excellent! Talk to Semenov and head out. He already has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211132">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211141">
    <text>You don't understand, there's radiation there. No one could get closer than half a kilometer, it zombifies everyone. It's real suicide to go there without protection, understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111411">
    <text>Hm. That changes things.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111412">
    <text>Then make your measurements, and I'll get the prototype.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21114121">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and head out. He's already equipped with everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21114122">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111413">
    <text>Then make your measurements, and I'll get the prototype.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21114131">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and head out. He already has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21114132">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111414">
    <text>I'll think about your offer.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21114">
    <text>Anyway, come back when you're ready, and we'll organize the measurements.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2112">
    <text>Got it. And if I decide to go there, I'll let you know.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311">
    <text>I'm looking for laboratory X-16. You can help me.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_3111">
    <text>Yes, our team is working on creating psi-protection. However, I can't give you the prototype yet, we need to tune it. If you help us make measurements with one of my assistants, I'll give you the prototype, and you'll be able to get into the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31111">
    <text>I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311111">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and head out. He's already equipped with everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31112">
    <text>I don't agree yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311121">
    <text>Very well. Come back when you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_312">
    <text>I'm looking for laboratory X-16. You can help me.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_3121">
    <text>Yes, our team is working on creating psi-protection. However, I can't give you the prototype yet, we need to tune it. If you help us make measurements with one of my assistants, I'll give you the prototype, and you'll be able to get into the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31211">
    <text>I agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_312111">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and head out. He already has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31212">
    <text>I don't agree yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_312121">
    <text>Very well. Come back when you change your mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41">
    <text>Hello, Marked One! Did you get my message?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411">
    <text>Yes, I'm here.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111">
    <text>Excellent! Then let's get started right away. Are you ready to escort our employee to conduct measurements in the anomalous field?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111">
    <text>Yes, ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411111">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and head out. He's already equipped with everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41112">
    <text>Yes, ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411121">
    <text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and head out. He already has everything necessary.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41113">
    <text>Not yet ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411131">
    <text>Very well. Come back when you're ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11">
    <text>Hello, Marked One. Thank you for agreeing to help. I'm a bit worried, to be honest... So listen, we need to go to the anomalous field not far from here and make several measurements. It's not so far, but to get there we'll have to go through zombie territory, so be careful. You'll go first, and I'll follow you. If anything happens to me, return to the bunker and report to the professor. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111">
    <text>Got it. Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_21">
    <text>Hello, Marked One. Thank you for agreeing to help. I'm a bit worried, to be honest... So listen, we need to go to the anomalous field not far from here and make several measurements. It's not so far, but to get there we'll have to go through zombie territory, so be careful. I'll go first, and you follow me. If anything happens to me, return to the bunker and report to the professor. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_211">
    <text>Got it. Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_31">
    <text>Marked One, wait! We haven't finished our conversation yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_41">
    <text>What? Yes-yes! Got it! I'm ready! Let's go!</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_51">
    <text>Marked One, we're here! It'll take me about twenty minutes to make the measurements... Please, just don't go far. We have to return together and through the same route. Is that clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_511">
    <text>Got it, take your measurements.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_512">
    <text>You know what... probably go first. You have tons of experience - not like me, and the corpses got stirred up again.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_513">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_514">
    <text>You know what... probably go first. You have tons of experience - not like me, and the corpses got stirred up again.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_515">
    <text>Alright.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_61">
    <text>Sorry, I'm really pressed for time right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_71">
    <text>Hello, Marked One! How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_81">
    <text>Wait a bit... we need to finish our conversation.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_help_scientist_91">
    <text>Wait! I'm not done with the measurements yet!</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_11">
    <text>Oh, mama... Oh... m-m-m...</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_111">
    <text>Alive? Well get up... get up slowly. It's over now. All over.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_21">
    <text>Hello, Marked One. How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_211">
    <text>Done! Measurements are packed, time to head back!</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_31">
    <text>Hello, Marked One! How are you doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_0">
    <text>I heard about a foreign expedition that died in the Zone...</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_1">
    <text>Everyone's already heard about that, my dear. Did Sidorovich tell you?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_2">
    <text>Yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_22">
    <text>So what do you want to know?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_23">
    <text>Did you participate in that expedition?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_24">
    <text>I was supposed to, but didn't participate... It's hard for me to talk about this terrible tragedy. Many of my friends and colleagues died then... On the other hand, two years have passed since then... But since you're so interested, I'll probably begin my story. As I already said, this happened two years ago. And it all started with a scientific congress in Berlin, the main theme of which was the Zone, as well as its impact on the environment. As a result, it was decided to equip a scientific expedition to the Zone, led by leading specialists, for the purpose of collecting information and studying the nature of the Zone. Soon sponsors were found, everything was coordinated with the Ukrainian government, and three months later preparations for the expedition began at a military base on the edge of Chernobyl. Ah, the cream of the scientific world came here then, the most famous foreign and domestic scientists: physicists, chemists, biologists, ecologists.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_25">
    <text>I know this in general terms. What happened next?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_26">
    <text>A mass of equipment was purchased: various devices, special equipment, a mobile laboratory, protective suits and so on. As security, the government allocated two special forces units and special armored personnel carriers. Stalker guides, translators and even journalists were also supposed to participate in the expedition. In general, after two weeks of preparation and briefing, the expedition headed into the Zone, to City-32. And this had to happen! The day before departure I got sick and was forced to lie in the infirmary for four days, which, in theory, saved my life. And how I regretted then that I couldn't go on the expedition, how I envied my colleagues... They promised me then that after recovery they'd send me by helicopter to the scientific camp. Meanwhile, the expedition reached City-32. A mobile scientific camp similar to the one you're in now was delivered there by helicopter, communication with the base was established and they set to work on the research. At first everything went as well as possible. They began measuring radiation levels, studying the features of different anomalies, the chemical composition of artifacts. Every day we received regular messages from the camp about new finds and discoveries - no one doubted the success of the expedition anymore. And I meanwhile lay on a cot in the infirmary biting my elbows...</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_27">
    <text>Go on.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_28">
    <text>But soon strange things began happening in the camp. First we noticed excessive aggressiveness and irritability in voices over the radio, but didn't attach much importance to it, not everyone's nerves are iron. Then two special forces soldiers disappeared somewhere. Three days after the expedition started, we received a message that one of the scientists, Professor Rosenberg, being in an extremely agitated state, committed suicide by shooting himself. This news shocked us! And two days later radio communication with the camp was cut off. We were completely perplexed, it was decided to send a helicopter to the camp, but due to a strong hurricane this was not possible. All we could do was wait. Another day later we received a message from two stalkers who saw at night a group of people in an armored personnel carrier at the Rotten Forest, ambushed by bandits. The military immediately sent a special squad there. What happened there, Sidorovich already told you, I can only add that three expedition participants survived the ambush by hiding in the forest. When we found them, they looked more like animals than people - wild, frightened, tattered. These people at first resembled patients of a psychiatric hospital, it was hard to believe that a week ago they were still normal. It took about a month of intensive treatment to at least partially restore their psyche.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_29">
    <text>And what's the result?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_291">
    <text>After analyzing what happened and the stories of the survivors, the commission came to the conclusion that the cause of the expedition's death was psychotropic radiation of unprecedented power, which in the Zone was called the "Brain Scorcher." As a result of prolonged exposure to this radiation, people's psyche began to break down: unprecedented aggressiveness, rage and savagery appeared. Some couldn't cope with such mental stress and killed themselves, like poor Professor Rosenberg. Others vented aggression on others - attacked and killed them like rabid animals. A massacre began in the camp. And then mutants arrived too, taking advantage of the absence of guards. Those who hadn't completely lost their minds tried to return in the armored personnel carrier, but halfway fell into a bandit ambush and were killed in the shootout. That's how the expedition to City-32 died... Since then I swore not to leave the Zone until I study this damn radiation and find protection from it... Well, dear friend, I've been talking with you here, it's time to get to work.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_292">
    <text>Yes-yes. I won't keep you, professor...</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_3">
    <text>No.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_33">
    <text>Then better ask him. I don't have time for stories right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_0">
    <text>Professor. Do you have any useful information about mutants?</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_1">
    <text>Yes, of course. Here's Kruglov's latest report on poltergeists.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_2">
    <text>Very interesting to learn something new. I've heard different things about them before.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_3">
    <text>So, what do we know about poltergeists:\n1. These are presumably people who got into an enormously powerful Emission. They are supreme telepaths, can subjugate people, animals, mutants, controllers (not fully controlled by poltergeists).\n2. Invisible in physical form. According to stalkers who went mad, insubstantial storm or fire formations. It's unknown what happens after the soul's death... It's also unknown if they can be killed at all.\n3. Telekinetic abilities vary. Can throw objects from small to heavy iron doors.\n4. A reproductive link between telepaths has been established. First a poltergeist must appear. From it comes a controller. The type of transformation is not exactly known. Presumably a controller is a person who was under the influence of a poltergeist for a long time, where the poltergeist's mind and the human mind are closely intertwined. At some point the controller rejects the poltergeist from its consciousness. Then it regresses into a burer. Information obtained from scientists at the Zone's center, with whom contact was lost 2 years ago.\n5. Most likely, they inhabit underground areas, although signs of presence are detected throughout the Zone, including on the surface.\n6. Energy analysis of a controller revealed its connection with a higher intelligence. Apparently, a poltergeist. Consequently, a poltergeist can be killed by disrupting the energy balance of its essence...</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_4">
    <text>U-u-uh... Professor. Can you repeat that last phrase more slowly?..</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_5">
    <text>In short, dear friend, you need to shoot them more.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_6">
    <text>A-ah! Now it's clear. Thank you very much for the information!</text>
</string>
