<string id="vas1_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Vasiliev!</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you and how do you know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_2">
    <text>Forester sent me instead of himself to find Associate Professor Vasiliev and help him get to the place, I assume that is you. Forester has a bad heart, he couldn't come himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, now it's clear. Only here is bad luck. Forester probably told you that I was carrying medicines and food for him, and was supposed to take prepared roots and artifacts in return, but didn't make it, as I got under a blowout, and ran into monsters too? Well so, while I was running through the forest and looking for shelter, I dropped the backpack with the parcel for Forester somewhere. Where I lost it, I don't know now. And on top of everything smashed the PDA where the map of the Forest was. So I am sitting here, don't know what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_4">
    <text>So, and what shall we do? Forester needs medicines very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_5">
    <text>Need to return to our base, on Yantar. Professor Sakharov has more medicines there. You will take them and carry to Forester yourself, and at the same time it won't be so scary for me to walk through the Forest with you. You have a map, right? Using it I will quickly orient myself how to get to the transition to Yantar. I see you only have a shotgun with you. Here, take my pistol, a couple of packs of ammo for it and a scientific medkit with bandages - it is unrestful on Yantar now. Well, let's go? I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, agreed. Well, are we moving out?</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_0">
    <text>How can I help, father?</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to find one rare root in the Forest for ecologists, I promised them. And I've been feeling unwell in recent days. And even now my heart seized a bit. If only you could help, go find the needed root.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I will help you with joy. Tell me, what kind of root is this and where to look for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Firstly, it is the root of a plant called Mandrake. Secondly, when pulling out of the ground, Mandrake emits a wild scream, which can lead to insanity or even death of the one who tries to do it. I will mark on the map the approximate place where Mandrake can be found, but be careful. Although the place is quiet there, nothing terrible should happen, just don't forget to plug your ears before you extract the root.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Clear with this. And will you give a double-barreled shotgun and buckshot just in case? Or it is a bit scary to walk in the Forest with just a knife.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Of course I will give. I will also give you four packs of buckshot for it, take the leather jacket and here are a couple more medkits and bandages just in case. And I will wait for you here, prepare tea and something to eat meanwhile.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I'll try to find this Mandrake root.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_0">
    <text>I found the Mandrake.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Well done, you are a good helper!</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Only you said that the place is quiet there... Not quiet at all! A herd of some insidious monsters was grazing nearby, looking like pigs, and also, as I took the mandrake out of the ground, boars came running. I shot them, only they tore my jacket, the beasts.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_3">
    <text>Strange, it seemed it was always calm in those places. Well you are doubly well done, didn't fear mutants! Here, take food, refresh yourself a little. By the way, take a couple more anti-radiation drugs - will help very much if you accidentally "swallow" radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you! Was glad to help.</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog1_0">
    <text>Are we there?</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog1_1">
    <text>Practically, yes. Further along the road is the transition, on Yantar be extremely careful, zombies bred, oh boy. Well that's it, let's go, don't lag behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog1_2">
    <text>Understood everything, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog2_0">
    <text>Well, where to next?</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog2_1">
    <text>That's it, we are at the place, at the entrance to the underwater cave. There is the transition to Yantar, need to dive and penetrate into the opening. That's it, go dive first, I am after you. Careful there and be on alert, it is unknown in what part of Yantar it will throw us out, and places there are dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog2_2">
    <text>Alright, I am going first.</text>
</string>