<string id="sar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, brother! Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="sar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings to you too! Do you have business with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother, the Leader awaits you. He will tell you about our rules and commandments. Listen to him and delve into everything. Here, take this, it is prepared specially for you: weapons and equipment. May the power of the Monolith be with you!</text>
</string>
<string id="sar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you. I'm coming, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_0">
    <text>Mentor, I need to repair something. %c[orange][Repair]</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_1">
    <text>Indeed. Our enemies do not sleep. Let me see.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the primary weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the secondary weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_4">
    <text>Repair the armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_5">
    <text>Mentor, I don't have enough money.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_6">
    <text>Here is your weapon, brother. Let our enemies tremble.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_7">
    <text>Armor patched up. Glory to the Monolith! To the spite of our enemies, another brother is ready to defend our truth.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_8">
    <text>Thank you, Mentor.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_9">
    <text>I am ready to carry faith and truth to those deaf and blind ones again. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_10">
    <text>Mentor, there is something else.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_repair_11">
    <text>Oh, you took quite a beating! Let me have a look:</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_trade_speak_0">
    <text>Hello, Mentor.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_trade_speak_1">
    <text>Greetings, brother! It is good that you came. You have been with us recently, so I want to give you some instructions.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_trade_speak_2">
    <text>I am all ears, Mentor.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_trade_speak_3">
    <text>Like anyone who has stepped onto the true path, you must work. Killing the infidels is the duty of everyone who is with us. But still, the community must live. We need, like everyone else, food, water, medicine, ammo, and so on. To get all this, we need artifacts. The Big World, alas, is not with us. Chaos and disbelief reign there. They are ready to sell anything to anyone, but they need the spawn of the Zone - artifacts. Every member of the community is obliged to bring artifacts they find. For them, this brother will receive a ration consisting of ammo, food, and medkits. The better the artifact, the better the ration.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_0">
    <text>Greetings, Mentor. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_1">
    <text>Come closer, my brother. I am listening to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_trade_speak_4">
    <text>I understand, Mentor, I will try my best.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_2">
    <text>Mentor. I brought something, take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_3">
    <text>Artifacts?</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_31">
    <text>I have a "Stone Flower".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_32">
    <text>I have a "Stone Blood".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_33">
    <text>I have a "Night Star".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_34">
    <text>I have a "Soul".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_35">
    <text>I have a "Spring".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_36">
    <text>I have a "Crystal".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_37">
    <text>I have a "Goldfish".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_38">
    <text>I have a "Meat Chunk".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_39">
    <text>I have a "Gravi".</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_390">
    <text>Oh, forgive me Mentor, I was mistaken.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_311">
    <text>Not much... Well, here are three packs of ammo for the Kalash, standard, one medkit, and one antirad.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_321">
    <text>You work poorly. But okay, take two standard medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_331">
    <text>O-o-oh, "Night Star"! Let me look at it... An infrequent guest with us. Well done, here is ammo: five packs of armor-piercing for the Groza, two scientific medkits, and two antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_341">
    <text>A rare artifact, you earned a reward! Here, NATO ammo, five packs, improved, plus three scientific medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_351">
    <text>No one has brought a "Spring" for a long time. Here, five packs of armor-piercing for the SVU, plus two antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_361">
    <text>You brought a "Crystal"? You pleased me! Take five packs of ammo for the Val, no, not armor-piercing - standard. But instead, here are two more army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_371">
    <text>For the "Goldfish" you are entitled to this: ammo for the Kalash, armor-piercing, five packs, plus two army medkits. Yes, and also canned meat. Take four cans.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_381">
    <text>For "Meat Chunk" I will give You ammo for the Kalash, three boxes, standard, plus simple medkits and four sticks of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_change_391">
    <text>For "Gravi", here is NATO ammo, three packs, standard, plus two simple medkits and four sticks of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_0">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_1">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith! Greetings to our new brother! As you already know, we have only recently controlled the Sarcophagus territory. After the accident, there wasn't a single person here besides us, only monsters. So, too many of them have bred. Here is your first task: below us, on the territory of the Sarcophagus, a family of burers has settled in, about 5-6 of them. We don't need such neighbors. Therefore, soldier, listen to the order: go there and clear the territory. Also, these creatures stole a device from us - a Decoder, which we really need. Therefore, soldier, besides destroying these dwarfs, you also need to find the Decoder. Dig through all their burrows, but find the device.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_2">
    <text>I will gladly fulfill this task, Leader. I will not let you down.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Leader!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_est_1">
    <text>Oh, our new brother. Did you complete my task?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_first_speak_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I did what you asked. The dwarfs are destroyed, and here is your device.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_0">
    <text>Brother... do you have it?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_1">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_2">
    <text>You know what. Do you have anything to drink?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_3">
    <text>Brother, are you crazy? Someone might hear us.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_4">
    <text>I really need it, I haven't had a drop in three months, and here... It's somehow... anyway, I can't... Bring me and my buddy five bottles, and for that, I'll give you my brand new pistol - a Glock. Took it from one "infidel".</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_5">
    <text>Sorry brother, but I don't have any vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_6">
    <text>Here, take it. Just keep it quiet so Solomon doesn't see.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_0">
    <text>Brother, do you have any extra food?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_1">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_2">
    <text>I could use some canned food, about five cans. I'm hungry, and Makhon won't give credit.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_3">
    <text>Alright, if I get some, I'll bring it.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_0">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_1">
    <text>Hello to you too. Here, take this, found exactly five cans.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_2">
    <text>Brother, thank you, and I have nothing to thank you with... Although, listen, I have a transmutation recipe here, record it to your PDA. It will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_3">
    <text>Thanks for the recipe. Good luck, brother. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_0">
    <text>Brother, any batteries for the PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_1">
    <text>No, where from?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_2">
    <text>Well, there isn't a shop nearby, of course, but there is a way. Bring me five of any PDAs, and I'll dig the batteries out of them somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_3">
    <text>Alright brother. If I collect five PDAs, I'll bring them.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_0">
    <text>Hello brother, did you collect them?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_1">
    <text>Yes, here, take them!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_2">
    <text>Thank you! Wait, let me thank you. I have a "Vog" grenade launcher here, brand new, and some ammo for the Kalash. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_0">
    <text>Did you call, Charon?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_1">
    <text>Yes, brother. I have business for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_2">
    <text>I am listening to you, Leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_3">
    <text>Solomon's group spotted several stalkers at CNPP-2. It turns out that an enemy is roaming in our rear. These infidels not only refuse to step on the true path, but also defile the "Holy Places" with their presence.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_4">
    <text>Give me permission, I will grind them into dust. These infidels will get what they deserve!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_5">
    <text>Do not rush. You will not go alone. Solomon's group awaits you. Find them. Note, I need Solomon alive. You answer for him with your head! Here is a little ammo and a couple of medkits for you. You will find the transition to CNPP-2 in the room with the Monolith, to the left of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_need_6">
    <text>Thank you, Leader, for the trust. I will not let you down. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_aes_need_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_aes_need_1">
    <text>You are on time, brother, everything is ready, we are waiting only for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_aes_need_2">
    <text>What are the plans?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_aes_need_3">
    <text>We move out slowly, we go as a group, you are slightly ahead... That's it, let's move out!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_aes_need_4">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith! May his strength and power be with us!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_est_0">
    <text>Leader, you are teaching me the same thing again... But alright... I listen and obey... Leader, I brought joyful news.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_aes_est_1">
    <text>It is good that you are patient and obedient. I have already been reported about your exploits. Well done! Glory to the Monolith! He does not abandon his children and helps them in difficult times.</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_0">
    <text>Well, infidel, shall I shoot you like a dog?</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_1">
    <text>Don't, I beg you, don't! Don't kill me!</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_2">
    <text>You and your people defiled the Holy Places, there is no mercy for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_3">
    <text>Brother.... Brother, don't kill me... I... I sincerely want to believe. I am ready to reunite with You. But now, I beg you, give, give me a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_4">
    <text>Fine, here is a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_5">
    <text>I don't have a medkit. Die, infidel!</text>
</string>
<string id="chaes_mamai_master_6">
    <text>Thank you, brother! Listen, I have a transmutation recipe. Record it in your PDA, it will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_dialog_0">
    <text>I am listening to you, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_dialog_1">
    <text>Brother, you showed your good side, I see - you are a smart guy. There is a special task for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak Solomon. I am glad to be trusted, especially by such a master as you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_dialog_3">
    <text>So, brother. When we first arrived here, it wasn't so deserted. Here and there one could meet squads of military stalkers. Somehow we managed to escort them out of here. Oh, we lost many brothers back then! But, Glory to the Monolith, we survived and the enemies are defeated. From one of our brothers, by the way, a former special forces soldier who participated in the special operation, we learned that they were looking for documentation that one scientist, who worked before the Big Blow (Dorodin seems to be his surname), carefully collected and put into 3 fireproof cases. They never managed to find the documents... We managed to track the location of 2 cases. I sent the coordinates to your PDA, but the third one vanished into thin air. Well, soldier, listen to the order: dig through the entire western part of CNPP-2, but find the 3 cases. The only thing else I can say is that a weak signal, possibly from the third case, is coming from somewhere on the outer upper levels of the Sarcophagus. I will mark the approximate place on your PDA. But, the thing is, you can only get to the upper levels through a teleport anomaly, and my fighters are afraid to climb into it.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_dialog_4">
    <text>Solomon. I will do everything I can, and even more. May the strength and mind of the Monolith be with me. May my faith help me! I am ready!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_est_0">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith, I did not let you down, Solomon.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_est_1">
    <text>Did you find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_est_2">
    <text>Yes Solomon, here they are - all three.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_case_est_3">
    <text>Your merits before the flock are great! You are an example of a good brother. Your humility and diligence will not go unnoticed, brother. The Monolith sees and hears everything. A great honor is prepared for you. But for now, allow me to reward you. Here, take five F-1 grenades. Let the enemies fear you even more!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_0">
    <text>Brother, I have business.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_1">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_2">
    <text>Brother, help me out. Solomon gave me and my partner a task to clear the CNPP-2 territory of monsters. But disaster struck. Snorks dragged my partner away and... devoured him. I told him not to drink, there is only sin in it... So the Monolith got angry. Anyway, I have two days left, and I'm afraid to go alone... But what will I tell Solomon then? I need to present him with proof. And where will I get it if I didn't go anywhere. Please, get 8 snork feet. Help me out, huh? And in return, I'll give you six packs of buckshot. But be careful. Snorks jump on roofs like mad horses! They live not far from here, slightly west of our camp. But, I repeat, be careful! Watch the roofs, lure them out from there...</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_3">
    <text>I will try to get the snork feet for you. Just don't drink anymore, brother. For us, who have stepped on the path of "Truth", drinking is a sin.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_0">
    <text>Well, how is it there, brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_1">
    <text>I got the snork feet for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_2">
    <text>Eight pieces? Oh, thank you brother, you really helped me out! Here, take the buckshot, as I promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Charon! Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_1">
    <text>Soldier, one floor above us is the Monolith Control Bunker. We want to create a control and coordination center in this place over time. But right now it's... gloom. Basically, just monsters...</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_2">
    <text>Leader, what must I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_3">
    <text>The task on one hand is simple - clear the bunker of filth. But on the other hand... who knows how many of them are there. The passage through the Sarcophagus is blocked, so for now the only way there is through CNPP-2. Look, I sent a marker to your PDA. The entrance to the control bunker is in this place. Look at the map in your PDA. Yes, and here are a couple of medkits and some ammo for the Kalash, just in case. And I'll also give you a shotgun, an MP-133, which helped me out more than once in difficult times. Take care of it, it will be handier to complete the task with it. Let this be a reward from me for your agility and loyalty.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_0">
    <text>I was in the Bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_1">
    <text>And what is there?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_2">
    <text>Just zombies and burers. But, strictly speaking, there were also several bloodsuckers, I had to tinker with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_3">
    <text>Well done. As always, I was not mistaken when I chose you specifically for this task.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_0">
    <text>Master, is there serious work?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you really ready for serious work?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_2">
    <text>I think so. I want to earn your trust even more.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_3">
    <text>You are a young fighter showing great promise, therefore, you now need to undergo additional training. Go to your savior - to Mervin, he will conduct several lessons with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_4">
    <text>Where should I look for him?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_5">
    <text>Mervin is a keeper of the Monolith. You will find him here, in the Sarcophagus, next to our "Treasure".</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, I will go find Mervin.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Mervin. Charon sent me to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, Charon already warned me. He says he is generally pleased with you, sees great prospects in you. But you have a lot of audacity and freethinking. In connection with all this, it is required to teach you strength of spirit, courage, as well as humility and tolerance. Just don't take this as punishment. This is special training that every new fighter who has earned the Leader's trust undergoes.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Charon. Mervin told me that you have some urgent business for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, soldier. An urgent matter has appeared: there is a healer, called the Swamp Doctor. He lives in the Swamps, not far from Pripyat. Well, it doesn't matter. He makes medicines for us, and we don't touch him for that. In addition, we supply him with artifacts, valuable and rare ones, which can only be found here, on the CNPP territory. Right now we have many sick, especially at CNPP-2. So: you need to go to Pripyat urgently, meet with the Doctor or his courier and pick up some medicines. The Doctor rarely comes himself, usually sends his student. Called Feldsher. A persistent fellow... But anyway, closer to the point: I have no one else to send right now but you, so get ready for the road.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_2">
    <text>Clear. Where do I look for the meeting place in Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_3">
    <text>Look at the stadium. The Doctor or his student usually hang out there when they come to Pripyat. I will place a marker on this spot in your PDA. You will go to Pripyat through the CNPP. Here, look, I will send you the coordinates of the transition from the Sarcophagus to the CNPP. And there, I hope, you will find how to get to Pripyat.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_est_0">
    <text>Master, here are the medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_est_1">
    <text>Let me take a look, so... so, seems like everything is here. How did you find the Doctor?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_est_2">
    <text>The Doctor wasn't there, his student was - Feldsher. A normal guy, pity he's not one of us. True, he said that we owed him and demanded payment: either artifacts or mutant parts. Had to run around a bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_est_3">
    <text>I see. And regarding these healers: I don't like them, oh, I don't like them. We would have shot them long ago, but the Swamp Doctor... In short, he is the only doctor in the area, so we have to tolerate it. Last time, when the Doctor himself brought medicines, he shot my courier, said that he treated him rudely. And I do not forgive anyone for such things... Everything has its time.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_doctor_est_4">
    <text>Alright, Charon, I understood everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, are you Dyak?</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Brother. You can't pass further alone. We noticed a squad of military, clearly not conscripts. They laid down two of my scouts, they didn't even have time to make a sound.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother, I am in a hurry. I have an urgent errand from Charon. By the way, why do you have such a bandit-like mug? Are you from the former ones?</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_start_dialog_3">
    <text>The mug is normal, you don't choose it! Yes, I was a bandit. In one skirmish in Pripyat with a Monolith squad I was wounded. Solomon found me, but didn't finish me off, instead he healed me, then enlightened me and directed me to the true path. So I am in his debt. Now I serve the Monolith faithfully and truly! That's it, enough philosophy, it is restless here... Help me out, brother! I am personally responsible to Charon for this sector. He will tear my head off for the fact that soldiers are on my territory. I have a gun here - PP-19 "Bizon". If you help, it's yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, brother, you speak sense, I will help. Later I have another question for you... But first let's get the job done. Moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, how are you, Dyak?</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>Those bitches! They laid down many of our brothers. But I am intact, Glory to the Monolith. Although it seems I got grazed a little.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, okay brother, I am in a hurry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait. Here, as promised. Take the gun, a little ammo for it, and a scope. May the strength and spirit of the Monolith be with you!</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Dyak, I am performing a task for Solomon here, and only you can help.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak, what is the essence of the question. I will help however I can. You really helped me out, and I am in debt to Solomon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Solomon asked me to bring him something, specifically: a crate of canned food from Pripyat and also a container with medicines, which, he says, Makhon hid somewhere on the CNPP territory. And apparently, you know where exactly, and can give a hint. Solomon trusts you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_3">
    <text>So that's it... Well, I won't tell you the exact place, because I don't know it myself. Makhon hid that container alone in secret. But I saw out of the corner of my eye which way he went then.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Alright, searching for who knows what and who knows where is nothing new to me, speak the approximate landmarks.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_5">
    <text>He, meaning Makhon, when he came here to the CNPP two months ago, was very secretive and taciturn. He only asked me to send a patrol to the eastern part of the CNPP to clear the area of mutants if discovered. My guys did everything, returned and reported. And then he went alone, asked not to be accompanied. He had a metal container with medicines with him, I definitely spied that. He returned later without it. I saw that he went out through the eastern gates, well these ones, behind you, not far from where we are now, and then walked around the locomotive and went towards the old freight train. That's where you should search. Maybe you'll find his stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood everything. I'll try to find the container in the eastern part of the CNPP.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Charon sent me.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>What does he want?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Medicines, as always.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>So tell him that he will receive nothing. We gave on credit several times, but this time patience has run out. Let him pay up first.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_4">
    <text>M-m-m... Feldsher, I cannot return without medicines, we have many sick people.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Want to get medicines? Well then you pay! Why can't he understand that I need artifacts and monster parts so that I can produce medicines. No artifacts - no medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Feldsher, what is needed? I will try to get it.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Two "Night Star" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, Feldsher, I have exactly two, found them on the way here.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I don't have a "Night Star". Maybe bring something else?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Then bring ten dog tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I have tails. Here, take them.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_6">
    <text>I don't have that many tails either, I'll go look.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Well done! I look at you and don't understand, what have you forgotten among fanatics?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_12">
    <text>Well done, how quick! I look at you and don't understand, what have you forgotten among fanatics?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_8">
    <text>We are not fanatics, we believe in the truth, in... Although honestly speaking, I've confused myself...</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_9">
    <text>That's empty talk, guy. You don't believe what you are saying yourself... I've heard similar words from your predecessors more than once. I am used to looking people in the eye. So, everyone who was before you had empty eyes, but yours... Yours are burning! Not my business, of course, but think, why and for what do you believe in this... stone. Yes, the stone is not simple, there is a lot of mysterious and incomprehensible in it, but whatever you say, it is just a stone.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Respectable one, I do not advise you to utter such words in my presence.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, guy, I won't detain you anymore. Just listen to your heart more often, trust it, and it will give you the right advice - so the Doctor taught.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_0">
    <text>Respectable one, do you happen to do repairs? %c[orange][Repair]</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_1">
    <text>A little bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the first weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the second weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_4">
    <text>Repair the armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_5">
    <text>Yeah, at such prices I am not ready to repair yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_6">
    <text>Well, look, good as new.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_7">
    <text>Yeah, who do you have to be to bring a suit to such a state... Alright, have to change all the plates.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_8">
    <text>Hey, not bad, thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_9">
    <text>Listen, I think it's even better now than when it was new.</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_10">
    <text>There is something else here, won't you take a look?</text>
</string>
<string id="digger_repair_11">
    <text>Yes, please, what do we have:</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_0">
    <text>Greetings, Mentor. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_1">
    <text>Come closer, my brother, I am listening to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_2">
    <text>Mentor, I brought something - take a look.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_3">
    <text>Artifacts?</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_31">
    <text>I have a "Stone Flower".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_32">
    <text>I have a "Stone Blood".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_33">
    <text>I have a "Night Star".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_34">
    <text>I have a "Soul".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_35">
    <text>I have a "Spring".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_36">
    <text>I have a "Crystal".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_37">
    <text>I have a "Goldfish".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_38">
    <text>I have a "Meat Chunk".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_39">
    <text>I have a "Gravi".</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_390">
    <text>Oh, forgive me Mentor, I was mistaken.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_311">
    <text>Not much, well then, here are three packs of ammo for the Kalash, standard, one medkit and one antirad.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_321">
    <text>You work poorly, but okay - take two standard medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_331">
    <text>O-o-oh, "Night Star"! Let me look at it... Not a frequent guest with us, well done, here is ammo for you, five packs for the Groza, armor-piercing, two scientific medkits and two antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_341">
    <text>A rare artifact! You earned a reward. Here, NATO ammo, five packs, improved, plus three scientific medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_351">
    <text>No one has brought a "Spring" for a long time. Here, five packs of armor-piercing for the SVU, plus two antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_361">
    <text>You brought a "Crystal"? You pleased me, take five packs of ammo for the Vintorez, no, not armor-piercing, standard, but instead, here are two more army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_371">
    <text>For the "Goldfish" you are entitled to this: ammo for the Kalash, armor-piercing, five packs, plus two army medkits, yes, and here take four cans of stew.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_381">
    <text>For "Meat Chunk" I will give you ammo for the Kalash, three packs, standard, plus two simple medkits and four sticks of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_change_391">
    <text>For "Gravi" - here is NATO ammo, three packs, standard, plus two simple medkits and four sticks of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_0">
    <text>Mentor, I need to repair something. %c[orange][Repair]</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_1">
    <text>Indeed, our enemies do not sleep, let me see.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the first weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the second weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_4">
    <text>Repair the armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_5">
    <text>Leader, I don't have enough money.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_6">
    <text>Here is your weapon, brother, let our enemies tremble.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_7">
    <text>Armor patched up. Glory to the Monolith! To spite our enemies, another brother is ready to defend our truth.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_8">
    <text>Thank you, Mentor.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_9">
    <text>I am ready to carry the truth to those deaf and blind ones again. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_10">
    <text>Mentor, there is something else.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_repair_11">
    <text>Oh, you took quite a beating, let me have a look:</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Master, I heard that mercenaries captured our base in Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>There is such a matter. We chase them out of Pripyat, and they keep coming and coming.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, maybe it's time for us to show who is the master of Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>I think so too. Listen, soldier, Makhon is already there with his guys. You get ready too. Talk to him, he will explain everything to you. But note: Makhon is my right hand. I will hold you personally responsible if he dies during the assault. And then, when you return, you will continue your special training with Mervin.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Master. Victory! Makhon is alive and well.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_est_1">
    <text>Makhon already reported. You did well! Glory to the Monolith! He does not abandon us in difficult times. Now I think they won't meddle with us for a long time. Although we shouldn't relax either. We have many enemies, many...</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_baza_est_2">
    <text>I serve the Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Mentor, are you already in position?</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>For a long time already. See the guys with me... These are the best of the best! Maybe you will become one of them someday too. Heard about the "Inner Circle"? In short, it is our guard. No fear, no mercy, no pain and no compassion.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>I hope I will become one of them someday. Well, Makhon, shall we move out slowly?</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go brother, indeed, we've been sitting too long.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_0">
    <text>Mentor, did you call?</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait... let me catch my breath.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_2">
    <text>Makhon, I'm not rushing, everyone had a hard time.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_3">
    <text>That's not all. We still need to clear the central square, take the guys and go towards the Lenin monument.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_4">
    <text>Executing already.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_est_0">
    <text>Whew... I'm tired somehow. What a day.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_est_1">
    <text>Yes, we had to work. But the result is positive. We liberated our base and the city center. Now mercenaries hold only the outskirts. But it's nothing, we'll get to them too.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_est_2">
    <text>Alright, Makhon, I'm off. Need to report to Charon.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_lenin_est_3">
    <text>Brother. Here, take this anomaly detector. Well, of course, not the best one, but it will save your life a couple of times, that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_about_change_0">
    <text>Respectable one, do you have anything for sale?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_about_change_1">
    <text>I have something for sale, besides trading I can offer an exchange: you give me monster parts, just note: I take parts in bulk, ten pieces each, and I will give you medkits and ammo for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_about_change_2">
    <text>Alright, when I find them - I'll bring them.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_0">
    <text>Here, I have something here. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_1">
    <text>What do you have there?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_2">
    <text>I have ten flesh eyes.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_3">
    <text>I have ten boar hooves.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_4">
    <text>I have ten blind dog tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_5">
    <text>I have ten pseudodog tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_6">
    <text>I have ten bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_7">
    <text>I have ten burer hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_8">
    <text>I have ten zombie hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_9">
    <text>I have ten snork feet.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_10">
    <text>I have ten tushkano heads.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_11">
    <text>I have ten controller hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_12">
    <text>I have ten pseudogiant paws.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_13">
    <text>I have ten chimera claws.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_14">
    <text>Unfortunately, I am empty today.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_21">
    <text>Give them here, they make decent medicines! Here, I give you four scientific medkits for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_31">
    <text>For ten hooves I will give you four army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_41">
    <text>How did you get them? Well done! Here are four packs of buckshot.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_51">
    <text>Pseudodogs are very dangerous. Didn't think you were capable of such a thing. Here are F1 grenades, four pieces.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_61">
    <text>10 bloodsucker tentacles? You are a dangerous man! Here are four packs of ammo for the Val and Vintorez, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_71">
    <text>10 burer hands? Where did you find them? Well okay, here are four packs of NATO ammo, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_81">
    <text>For civilian zombie hands I will give you... I'll give you five packs of buckshot.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_91">
    <text>Snorks, br-r-r... I don't like them. I had an unpleasant story with them once... Here are four standard medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_101">
    <text>Tushkanos. And how did you catch them? They are so nimble. Here are five packs of 9x18 ammo, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_111">
    <text>Controllers. Wow, damn it! You are... alright, here are five antirads for that.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_121">
    <text>Pseudogiants? Pseudogiants - yes, huge beasts... Here are seven packs of NATO ammo, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_131">
    <text>A Chimera is a dangerous monster, here are five packs of ammo for the Kalash, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_change_141">
    <text>If you find anything, come back.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_need_0">
    <text>What do you want, brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_need_1">
    <text>Brother, I have business for you. We are here, consider it the edge of the earth, there are no shops, you understand yourself, but we are still people, and we need to eat and need medicines. Charon is resolving this issue, but until everything settles down, we will swell from hunger here or kick the bucket from some cholera.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_need_2">
    <text>How can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_need_3">
    <text>Charon will sooner or later send you to Pripyat... So, there is a store there. It is of course not working, some former grocery store, but I am practically 100% sure there must be products there. I don't know, canned food... maybe something else. Brother, help out, if you find something, bring it. But that is not all yet... One Doctor prepares and supplies medicines for our brotherhood, but Makhon is holding them back for my guys, with whom we guard the inner territory of the CNPP here. This is all because we once argued with him on the topic of our faith, so he is taking revenge slowly. But I know that Makhon has a stash with medicines on the CNPP territory. One of our brothers told me about this. He is called Dyak. You can get to Pripyat from the Sarcophagus only through the outer territory of the CNPP, and Dyak is currently in charge there. You must talk to him. Say that at my request you are looking for what I am asking you to bring. He will help, he is in some debt to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_need_4">
    <text>Alright, brother, I will help. When I am in Pripyat, I will look for something for you. I will look into the grocery store and on the CNPP territory I will try to find the container with medicines. I hope Dyak helps.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_0">
    <text>Well, brother, I brought joyful news.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_1">
    <text>What is the news?</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_2">
    <text>I was in Pripyat, I found this grocery store - it's empty there. Apparently, someone had already been there before me, and probably more than once. But still, after searching, I found one crate with canned food. And at the CNPP I finally found the place where the container with medicines was hidden. It wasn't simple, I want to tell you, it was very not simple.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_3">
    <text>Canned food - that is good, there is less radiation in it. Well, give it here, what you brought. I want to thank you. Here, choose:</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_31">
    <text>Eotech sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_32">
    <text>PSO sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_33">
    <text>SMG MP5A3.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_311">
    <text>Take the sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_321">
    <text>Take the sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_food_est_331">
    <text>Take the SMG.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_0">
    <text>My training is finished, Master. How else can I be useful?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_1">
    <text>Soldier, there is a task for you. Dyak's people caught a stalker. He is currently on the CNPP territory. Your task is to interrogate him, find out everything and... eliminate him. We don't need spies. But don't get your hands dirty yourself - Dyak will do everything independently - he knows how to solve such issues without unnecessary pathos. Your task is to interrogate the spy, find out everything and report to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_2">
    <text>Obey, executing already.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_0">
    <text>Well, speak, who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_1">
    <text>Friend, don't kill me, I'll say everything!</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_2">
    <text>Stop whining, you knew what you were getting into. Now, perhaps, only a frank confession will save you.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_3">
    <text>Brother, brother, I'll say everything, please, don't kill me!</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_4">
    <text>That's it, you've driven me to the edge, for the last time... Who are you and what were you looking for here?</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_5">
    <text>Serga... My name is Serga. Ghost sent me... Or rather, there were three of us, but these guys... laid down two of us. Ghost... it's all him! He sent us here, we were looking for how to sneak into the control bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_6">
    <text>Why did you need the bunker? And who is Ghost?</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_7">
    <text>Docu... documents, brother, have mercy... that's... that's it, I'm silent. I don't know exactly, some important documents. Seems to be a map of the underground communications of Pripyat and the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_8">
    <text>Who is Ghost?</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_9">
    <text>He seems to be former military, maybe KGB. He... He... I... We worked together lately. He was looking for a way to sneak into the Sarcophagus, bypassing the posts. Why? I don't know myself, Ghost never spoke about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_10">
    <text>Where can he be found?</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_11">
    <text>I don't know exactly, lately we were either in Pripyat or on the Radar, but where his base is - I don't know.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_12">
    <text>Interrogation finished.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_13">
    <text>No, brother! Brother, don't kill me. Don't... I beg you, tell this Dyak to let me go, I told you everything I knew.</text>
</string>
<string id="shpion_dopross_14">
    <text>I said - interrogation finished.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Master. May the power of the Monolith be with us!</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_est_1">
    <text>What news did you bring, soldier?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_est_2">
    <text>I interrogated the spy. His name was Serga. He and two other stalkers were looking for some documents, a map of the Pripyat undergrounds. Maybe he's lying, although unlikely. And Dyak is truly a "beast"... Yes, the spy also mentioned a stalker by the nickname Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_dopross_est_3">
    <text>Ghost... Something familiar. I'm sure it's somehow connected to this Swamp Doctor and his Feldsher. But anyway. Soldier, rest for now. If needed - I will call.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_net_work_0">
    <text>Master, are there tasks? I've been sitting too long. Starting to get nervous...</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_net_work_1">
    <text>Well done, soldier! Soon I will recommend you for a serious reward and promotion. But for now, there is no work. If needed - I will call. That is All. Rest, pray and strengthen your faith!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Feldsher, you asked me to come by.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes, I need you very - very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_2">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_3">
    <text>I don't know if you've heard of a man named Ghost or not, and if you have, probably bad things. But I need your help.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Of course, I heard about him, quite recently. I would talk to this Ghost with pleasure.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, so you will talk. But there is just a small hitch.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_6">
    <text>Getting interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_7">
    <text>In order to talk to him, he must first be freed. Mercenaries captured him, they are holding him in Pripyat. I will send you the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_8">
    <text>Strange that they didn't shoot him.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_9">
    <text>Nothing strange. There is nothing to take from your brother. You are fanatics. It is easier to kill you than try to squeeze something out of you. But from him, one can. Especially since I suspect the real reason is me and the Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_10">
    <text>Why did you decide that?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_11">
    <text>Because the Swamp Doctor is the only doctor in the district, and I am his faithful student. They came several times already, but both the Doctor and I refused them, so they hold a grudge.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_12">
    <text>Strange scruples... As I understand, you and the Doctor are not thrilled with us either. But you supply us with medicines. Are we better than them by your standards?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_13">
    <text>You are fanatics. At least half of you, and I think even more, do not control yourselves. I don't know what controls you and how, but I hope to find out. Even you... yes, yes... even you yourself do not notice that you have not been your own master for a long time. So I feel sorry for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_14">
    <text>Interesting theory. Worst of all is that I, unfortunately, do not remember who I was before, before I got here. I don't remember what my name was before, how I got into the Zone. I don't remember why I ended up in Pripyat. I remember nothing. Memories start only from the moment Mervin saved me. Pulled me out of an anomaly... Alright, send Ghost's coordinates. I'll go do what I do best - kill!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_dialog_15">
    <text>Give me your PDA... So, here, marked the place. If everything goes well, drop by on the way back. I have something for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you Ghost?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_1">
    <text>A minute ago I was, but now I don't even know... First time I see a Monolithian helping me. Usually, one can expect nothing but a bullet from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_2">
    <text>Jokes later, Feldsher sent me. That's it, moving out. Follow me.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_3">
    <text>Attaboy Feldsher, I underestimated him! Thought he only blindly carried out the Doctor's errands.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_4">
    <text>Let's go, I said.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, you are free.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_1">
    <text>Freedom is a conditional concept. You freed me from the mercenaries so that I became dependent on you.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_2">
    <text>How I am sick of you smart alecks. Feldsher, now you... His theory about some device or whatever, that controls us. Let's talk about what is certain. What documents are you looking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_3">
    <text>What are you talking about? A-a-ah... understood. Did they get caught after all? Yes, but there were no other people at hand, and the documents were needed. Rather, I understood that this trio wouldn't find the documents. All that was required of them was to conduct, so to speak, reconnaissance at the CNPP and check how many of your brothers are there and where.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_4">
    <text>And what kind of documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_5">
    <text>Documents... You don't believe that there is some device that controls you, do you? But I and the Doctor believe. That is exactly what we are looking for. And it is located somewhere in the Sarcophagus. But where exactly is unknown to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_6">
    <text>What is happening to me... Just half a day ago I wanted to shoot you, and now... now I don't even know. But note, if you get caught again, I won't have pity.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_est_0">
    <text>Feldsher, here I am. Ghost is free.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_est_1">
    <text>Thank you. Still, I understand more and more that I was not mistaken in you. You definitely need to meet with the Doctor and talk to him. He will explain everything to you better than I can. He can surely help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_est_2">
    <text>You are at it again. I don't need any help. Stop it. This is my conscious path. Yes, and warn your Ghost that if he pokes his nose into our place again, I won't let him leave alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_est_3">
    <text>You are stubborn, but okay. Here, I have a transmutation recipe. Write it down, might be needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>Leader, did you call me?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I called. We calculated Ghost, he is in Pripyat.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>I learned something about him. He must be eliminated urgently, before he causes trouble here. Yes, I thought that no one would cope better than you. So the honor of killing the little reptile fell to you. I believe that you will succeed. You haven't let me down once yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_finish_dialog_4">
    <text>I won't let you down now either, Charon!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_0">
    <text>Feldsher, what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_1">
    <text>You seem to have received a task to kill Ghost?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_2">
    <text>Once again I am amazed by your awareness. In my opinion, you know more about me than I do myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_3">
    <text>I am the assistant and associate of the Doctor, don't forget that. And some patients, let's say, out of gratitude... Well, further, I hope, is clear to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_4">
    <text>Alright, Feldsher, let's get closer to the point.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_5">
    <text>You must not kill Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_6">
    <text>I have an order! I must, and Ghost himself I don't like. He is shady somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_7">
    <text>M-m-m-m... I didn't want to, but... Apparently I have to.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_set_actor_8">
    <text>Didn't want what?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_0">
    <text>Oh... what's wrong with me? I feel sick, I feel so crappy.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_1">
    <text>It's okay, it will pass. Endure a little. I injected you with a potent sedative. This is, so to say, the aftereffect of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_2">
    <text>There is something wrong with my head, I can't remember anything...</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_3">
    <text>Don't worry, your memory will return, but gradually. I hope this will help you remember who you really are and how you ended up in Pripyat. I don't even know what to call you. You there in your "Brotherhood" are almost all nameless. Brothers, in a word. Yes, I put a helmet there for you. Under no circumstances throw it away. It will be able to protect you from psi-radiation. If you take it off, the Monolith will start controlling you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_4">
    <text>Guy, give me time to come to my senses... Me... My name is Strelok. I remembered! I remembered why I came to Pripyat! I am looking for my brother! Do you... Do you happen to know anything about a stalker nicknamed "Captain" and about a raid of stalkers to the Sarcophagus two years and a bit ago?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_5">
    <text>Well, hello, Strelok! I congratulate you on "returning" to yourself. I don't know a stalker nicknamed Captain. And I haven't heard about a raid to the Sarcophagus two years ago either. I'm new to the Zone... And just in case, I'll tell you: don't forget, your former friends are no longer your friends. So I don't advise you to go back. At the CNPP, they are unlikely to be happy about your arrival. I would advise you to get away from Pripyat altogether. You definitely need to get to the Swamp Doctor. With him, you can find answers to many of your questions. Perhaps he knows something about your brother. Ghost can help you get to the "Swamps". Speaking of Ghost. He is in danger, I'm sure. This Charon always insures himself. Probably, besides you, he sent someone else in case you fail. You need Ghost. Don't let him die.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_6">
    <text>Feldsher, or whatever your name is, I don't remember who Ghost, Charon and others are. Why can't you take me to the Doctor yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_7">
    <text>See, your memory is returning gradually. We are stuck here a bit in Pripyat... The old path to the Swamps through the Radar is currently inaccessible, and there is no other one yet... But, as I said, Ghost can help find a path to the "Swamps", and I still have some business in Pripyat. Okay, to start with, I will drop a marker on Ghost's location. You need to find him urgently. Perhaps Charon's people are already there. I hope you haven't forgotten how to hold a weapon?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_neytral_8">
    <text>I think it's innate... Alright, I'll go find Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_need_0">
    <text>Are you Ghost? I feel like I've seen you before.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_need_1">
    <text>That happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_need_2">
    <text>No... no, I don't recall.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_need_3">
    <text>Recently... Alright, you don't remember anything anyway. Listen to me. Feldsher said to lead you out of Pripyat to the Swamps to the Doctor. But there is a problem. The passage to the Radar is controlled by mercenaries. And even if you pass, further on, a rather strong psi-radiation has formed recently. No protection will help you against it, you will die quickly and painfully. When it will change location is unknown, and there is no time to wait. There is another secret path to the Swamps from Pripyat. But where is it? There is information that somewhere in the Sarcophagus, in the control bunker, there are secret documents. If you find them, the transition should be displayed on them. Bring the documents to me, I will try to decipher them. Can you find the way to the Control Bunker?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_need_4">
    <text>I will try.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_est_0">
    <text>Ghost, here are the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_est_1">
    <text>Found them? Well done! Let me have a look. Aha... so... That's it, figured it out. Alright, now go to Fang, he will escort you to the place. I will send him the coordinates of the transition, and he will show you the path on the spot, it's not far, but safer together.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_est_2">
    <text>Understood, coming already. Yes, by the way, I remembered practically everything! I remembered, for example, that I saved you recently from mercenary captivity.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_est_3">
    <text>Your memory is recovering quickly. Alright, go. There is no time, good luck and thank you!</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_doc_est_4">
    <text>You take care too, Ghost, hope to see you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you Fang?</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_1">
    <text>The very same, Ghost informed me. Ready to go?</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, ready! I have nothing else to do here.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We walk carefully, no rushing, the main thing is not to run into a Monolith patrol. That's it, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Are we there?</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, look here: the transition to the Swamps is just behind me, I sent a marker to your PDA. Well that's it, brother, farewell. Good luck to you, see you again. Give my regards to the Doctor!</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>All the best to you too, see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait-wait... Ghost wants something from us here. Aha, here... sent a message. In short, he asks to return to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Damn it! I already had one foot, so to speak, stepping from Pripyat to the "Swamps", and now returning again...</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry, it's quick, Ghost writes that he forgot to personally hand you something very important from the Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_6">
    <text>Ah, well then alright, let's return to Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="suvenir_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello again. What do you have for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="suvenir_dialog_1">
    <text>My memory is useless, I completely forgot, Feldsher passed something here for you as a gift: three army medkits and his MP5, it saved his life more than once, he says you need it more. Here, take it and, as they say, break a leg, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="suvenir_dialog_2">
    <text>Same to you. Big thanks to Feldsher from me. You know, it's a little scary... what awaits me there?</text>
</string>
<string id="suvenir_dialog_3">
    <text>Don't chicken out! You are a sensible guy, everything will be fine! If anything, you know where to find us. And now go, the Doctor is waiting for you. Yes, and here is my advice: don't think about touching the Doctor's "patients" - he won't like it, understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="suvenir_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood, okay. That's it, I'm going to the Swamps to the Doctor, we'll surely see each other again somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_0">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't recognize me, scum?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_2">
    <text>You won't believe it - I really don't recognize you. Feldsher in Pripyat cleared my brains thoroughly.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_3">
    <text>You know Feldsher?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_4">
    <text>Do I know Feldsher? He cleared my whole head. I am clean as a baby. Consider it a second life.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_5">
    <text>Feldsher is the assistant of the Swamp Doctor, but neither he nor the Doctor told me anything about you... Hmmm.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_6">
    <text>Believe me, I'm not lying, haven't learned how yet. I just haven't met the Swamp Doctor yet, but I've heard a lot about him, including from Feldsher.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_7">
    <text>Listen, what's your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_8">
    <text>My name is Strelok! You took all my weapons, equipment, loot and money! Give it all back to me!</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_9">
    <text>Don't yell like that. I didn't take your things or your money. I don't do such things. I found you here already lying unconscious, as they say, in just your underwear. Apparently, those who robbed you decided that you had already kicked the bucket, otherwise they wouldn't have left you alive. So, consider yourself lucky.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_10">
    <text>If not you, then who knocked me out and robbed me?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_11">
    <text>That is unknown to me. I can only assume it was one of your "old friends" from the Sarcophagus. And now listen here, Strelok. You don't move right now, and I slowly... very slowly hand you a gun and ammo. Got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_12">
    <text>Although I am a "baby", I am quick-witted.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Listen, why did you help me?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>It's all the Doctor. Say thank you to him if you see him. He and Feldsher once saved me. I now consider myself indebted to them for life, especially to the Doctor. And they cleared my brains, just like yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>Why didn't you leave here?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>Where to? And why? I was in good standing with Charon, he sent me to command at CNPP-2. I am practically my own master here. Well, sometimes I have to do dirty work. And besides, you don't know how many enemies I have on the other side. I wouldn't last a day there. And I am old already...</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>Listen, I am planning to bolt to the other side. Maybe you have a request?</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>M-m-m... Yes, perhaps there is one. I need to send a parcel there, to the big world. My daughter is there, true, she is grown up already. I haven't seen her for about ten years.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Unlikely to succeed.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_7">
    <text>There is one person at the Cordon, a trader. They call him Barman. He will help. Back when I was a loner, I was always amazed at the deals he pulled off. Yes, and to interest you, I will give you a transmutation recipe. How to make the "Hide" modification from the "Film" artifact, if you help.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_8">
    <text>No need, I'll take it anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_9">
    <text>It's necessary, brother, necessary. Times are like that. So. As soon as you agree, don't come to me. Let the Barman write me a note. Perhaps he even remembers me. And I will then send the recipe to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Barman, I have business with you, all the way from the CNPP.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>What business?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>Need to send a parcel there, to the "Big World".</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>D-damn... Are you crazy?! You form the CNPP are all like that. You come, rest a week or two at the Cordon, drink umpteen liters of vodka. Spouting such utter nonsense. Or maybe you want a woman? There you go! Don't bother me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>Barman, my dear friend! I want a woman, and vodka, but most of all, for you to send the parcel. What do you want in return?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>Do you think it's that simple? Over there (points head towards the checkpoint) people also want to eat and drink.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Alright, Barman, don't stall. How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_7">
    <text>Two "Crystal" artifacts, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_8">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_9">
    <text>I don't have them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_10">
    <text>Then two "Film" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_11">
    <text>I have these, take them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_12">
    <text>I don't have those either.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_13">
    <text>Then come when you have them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_14">
    <text>Give me the "Crystals". And don't worry, the channel is reliable, everything will be tip-top.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_15">
    <text>Give me the "Films". And don't worry, the channel is reliable, everything will be tip-top.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Barman, hello! How about the parcel?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>Brought them?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>Yes, here, I have exactly two "Crystal" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>Yes, here, I have exactly two "Film" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>No, I just dropped by. Alright, I'll go look.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>Give me the "Crystals". And don't worry, the channel is reliable, everything will be tip-top.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Give me the "Films". And don't worry, the channel is reliable, everything will be tip-top.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_0">
    <text>Have anything for sale? %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_1">
    <text>I can offer buckshot, standard medkits or simple ammo for the Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_2">
    <text>Need buckshot.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_3">
    <text>Need medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_4">
    <text>Need ammo for the Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_21">
    <text>I exchange five packs of buckshot for:\n
	- 8 blind dog tails,\n
	- 6 boar hooves,\n
	- 6 chimera claws,\n
	- 2 "Twist" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_211">
    <text>Zahar, I have tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_212">
    <text>Zahar, I have hooves.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_213">
    <text>Zahar, I have claws.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_214">
    <text>Zahar, I have "Twists".</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_215">
    <text>I am empty today.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_31">
    <text>I exchange three medkits for:\n
	- 8 pseudodog tails,\n
	- 1 "Slug" artifact,\n
	- 1 "Stone Flower" artifact,\n
	- 1 "Gravi" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_311">
    <text>Zahar, I have pseudodog tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_312">
    <text>Zahar, I have a "Slug" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_313">
    <text>Zahar, I have a "Stone Flower" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_314">
    <text>Zahar, I have a "Gravi" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_41">
    <text>I exchange five packs of simple ammo for the Kalash for:\n
	- 6 bloodsucker tentacles,\n
	- 1 "Meat Chunk" artifact,\n
	- 2 "Slime" artifacts,\n
	- 2 "Jellyfish" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_411">
    <text>Zahar, I have tentacles.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_412">
    <text>Zahar, I have a "Meat Chunk" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_413">
    <text>Zahar, I have 2 "Slime" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_zahar_change_414">
    <text>Zahar, I have 2 "Jellyfish" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_0">
    <text>Completely forgot... Seems I have something for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_1">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_2">
    <text>A message from your friend... From Zahar. Do you know him?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_3">
    <text>Zahar? Haven't heard about him for a long time. Thought he was long dead. Where did you meet him? How is he, my old friend, doing?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_4">
    <text>Zahar is fine. He has been wandering through forests and fields with "Hunters" for a long time. Here, he asked to pass you a personal letter. Says he wants to make peace.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_5">
    <text>That old fart! I never held a grudge against him. I think he didn't either. We argued out of stupidity back then. Well okay, what's past is past... You brought me good news, guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_6">
    <text>Here, take the letter.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello guys, who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_1">
    <text>We are Freedomers, and who are you yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_2">
    <text>They call me Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_3">
    <text>Strelok, desire to earn some money? You help us at the same time, we won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_4">
    <text>What is the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_5">
    <text>There is a military base behind the hills. Their commander is Belchuk, a rare bastard. Caught three of ours yesterday and immediately put them against the wall. That scumbag! Wait, I'll get to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_6">
    <text>I see. What next?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_7">
    <text>We need this base desperately. Until we kick the soldiers out of there, the passage to the center of the Zone is closed for stalkers. So we are looking for free stalkers who are not afraid and will go with us. As you can see, there aren't many of us. So an extra gun wouldn't hurt. Will you come with us? Don't worry, I'll pay well. Brother, think for yourself, the Zone is our home, yours and mine. And it's not for soldiers to tell us where and why to go. We risk every day here without them. Every other day we lose a friend. And this Belchuk implies total lawlessness. Seized power and wastes our brothers. Whoever gets caught - is shot on the spot.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay-okay brother, you persuaded me, so, when are we moving out?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_9">
    <text>Right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_10">
    <text>Well then, let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Lukash, the base is ours! Belchuk is dead.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, half the job is done.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you mean half? You seemed to say that we needed to capture the base and that's it - job done.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>We still need to kick the soldiers out from the Barrier, and only then that's it. The path to the center is relatively free.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_4">
    <text>Why didn't you say so immediately?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_5">
    <text>Come on, we are doing a necessary deed. As soon as we capture the Barrier, I'll pay, don't worry. Come on, brother, hurry, before the soldiers realize.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_6">
    <text>Am I going alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_7">
    <text>No, of course not. Look, Cap and the guys will go too. Protect Cap, he must remain alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, convinced.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Lukash, the Barrier is ours!</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_1">
    <text>Glory to the heroes! You did a great job. Here, hold this, earned by blood and sweat.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_2">
    <text>Lukash, listen, I need to get to the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_3">
    <text>To the Bar? Why do you need to go there?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_4">
    <text>I have business there.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, business is business. But I don't know the way to the Bar. We don't go there. We have a war with Duty, you know. But there is one guy at the farm, the Informer. Maybe he knows, he roams everywhere. Ask him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_baryer_dialog_6">
    <text>Thanks for the tip.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. Are you the Informer?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, suppose it's me. What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_2">
    <text>I need to find a way to the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_3">
    <text>To the Bar? Heh... It costs money.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_4">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_5">
    <text>I'm not interested in money. Bring me a "Mama's Beads" artifact, then we'll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_6">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_7">
    <text>Informer, here is the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_8">
    <text>Excellent! So, listen. Go straight along the road, past the Barrier, there will be a turn to the right. That's the road to the Bar. But be careful, there are plenty of dogs there.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedomitel_dialog_9">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_0">
    <text>Stand back! Access to the base is closed for outsiders!</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to see General Voronin. I have important information.</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_2">
    <text>What information can a stalker have? Get out of here while you're still intact.</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_3">
    <text>Tell the General that I helped capture the Freedom base. I think he will be interested.</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_4">
    <text>You? Helped Freedom? Hah! And you came here to brag about it? Guys, fire!</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait! You misunderstood. I helped DEAL with the Freedom base. I can help you too.</text>
</string>
<string id="plichko_propusk_dialog_6">
    <text>Is that so? Hmm... Alright. But if you're lying, we'll hang you on the nearest tree. Go, the General is in the bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, General.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you and how did you get in here?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Your man Plichko let me through.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Strelok? Haven't heard of you. What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm looking for work. And information.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Work... There is always work for brave people. But trust must be earned. I have a task. Our scouts reported that bandits in the Dark Valley have some documents. They concern our safety. You need to get them.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Where exactly in the Dark Valley?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_7">
    <text>At the base. Borov is in charge there. The documents are likely in his safe.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I'll take the job.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_docs_est_0">
    <text>General, I have the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_docs_est_1">
    <text>Let me see... Yes, this is it. Good job, stalker. You have proven your loyalty. Here is your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_prince_dialog_0">
    <text>General, is there any more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_prince_dialog_1">
    <text>There is one delicate matter. A stalker named Prince owes us a lot. But the problem is, he disappeared. Rumor has it he went to the Radar. He had a unique weapon with him - a modified Winchester. I want that weapon. Find Prince, or his body, and bring me the gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_prince_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood. I'll search.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_prince_est_0">
    <text>Here is the Winchester, General.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_prince_est_1">
    <text>Excellent weapon! A pity about Prince, he was a good fighter once... Here, take this money.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Colonel.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings, stalker. Came to trade or just looking?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I want to trade.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Look at the goods. We have the best equipment in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_quest_0">
    <text>Colonel, do you have any tasks?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_quest_1">
    <text>There is one thing. I need a "Goldfish" artifact. But not a simple one, a special one. It was seen in the Dark Valley, near the fuel tanks. Bring it, and I'll give you a good suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_quest_2">
    <text>I'll try to find it.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_quest_est_0">
    <text>Here is the "Goldfish", Colonel.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_quest_est_1">
    <text>Great! As promised, here is a PSZ-9d suit. It will serve you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_0">
    <text>Colonel, interested in an exchange? %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_1">
    <text>Depends on what you offer. I need medkits and ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_2">
    <text>I have artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_3">
    <text>I have mutant parts.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_21">
    <text>For a "Soul" artifact I will give 3 army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_22">
    <text>For a "Mica" artifact I will give 5 packs of 9x39 ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_31">
    <text>For 5 bloodsucker tentacles I will give a scientific medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_32">
    <text>For 10 dog tails I will give 2 packs of buckshot.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_do_0">
    <text>Deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_change_do_1">
    <text>I'll pass for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey you, come here.</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_start_dialog_1">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Ivancov. The General asked me to keep an eye on you. Don't cause trouble, understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Understood, Captain.</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Captain Ivancov, help is needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_task_dialog_1">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Mutants attacked the checkpoint. We need support.</text>
</string>
<string id="ivancov_task_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll send a squad immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I am Count. A free shooter, like you. But I prefer to work alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_task_dialog_0">
    <text>Count, do you know anything about the Prince?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_task_dialog_1">
    <text>Prince? Yes, I knew him. A reckless guy. He went to the Radar and didn't come back. If you're looking for him, look near the helicopter crash site.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_task_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks for the info.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Lukash, the job is done.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, we worked gloriously! You really are a master, you know your stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, what about the payment?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, that goes without saying, I promised. By the way, Strelok, I look at you... you don't look like the other vagrants who roam the Zone in search of profit... You have a different "fire" in your eyes. What are you doing in the Zone, if it's not a secret, of course?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_4">
    <text>You are right, I am not here for profit. I am looking for my brother. We got lost under very strange and inexplicable circumstances. So I am trying to find my brother's trail. Or maybe, if I'm lucky, him himself. Have you heard anything about a man nicknamed "Captain", who went to the Sarcophagus with a group of other stalkers two years and a bit ago?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_5">
    <text>No, I don't know such a stalker personally. I heard about that raid into the "heart" of the Zone, of course, like everyone else. But I can't say anything more. So don't blame me. Alright, here, take your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_after_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you anyway, Lukash. Come on, give me what you prepared for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_0">
    <text>Halt.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_1">
    <text>Greetings.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_2">
    <text>Listen, man, this territory is ours and you can't pass for free.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_3">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_4">
    <text>2000 for a one-time pass through our territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_5">
    <text>Damn, left my checkbook at home.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_6">
    <text>Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_koha_prohod_7">
    <text>There, I see immediately - a business man. When you go back, towards the exit, or want to come to us again, don't forget to come to me! And I'll tell you if you need to pay again or not. Knyaz is the boss here. Whatever he says, goes. But for now, don't even poke your nose without the dough!</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_0">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_1">
    <text>Greetings, I have a business proposal for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_2">
    <text>What kind of proposal?</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_3">
    <text>I buy PDAs of dead stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_4">
    <text>Why do you need them?</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_5">
    <text>Well, I am an Informer, so I must know as much as possible, the profession obliges. Listen, for 10 PDAs I will give you one modified artifact. Well, and if you bring 20 PDAs, I will share information about a stash with you. True, it's luck here: if it's a master's stash, the loot is corresponding. But if it's a rookie's... you understand yourself what awaits you there.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_buy_pda_6">
    <text>Alright, if I have PDAs - I will bring them.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_0">
    <text>Hello, how is life, rumor trader?</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_1">
    <text>Well, not only rumors, let's get to business, what did you bring?</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_2">
    <text>Here, gathered 10 PDAs for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_3">
    <text>I have a rich catch today. Here are 20 PDAs.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_4">
    <text>Up to my neck in business, no time to collect PDAs, I'll bring them next time.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_5">
    <text>Well since you brought 10 PDAs, here, take this, as promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_6">
    <text>20 PDAs - that's so much information! Give me your PDA, I'll send you information about a stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_beret_pda_7">
    <text>Well then, until next time.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_0">
    <text>Borov, I want to buy something. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_2">
    <text>I have ammo and weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_3">
    <text>Ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_4">
    <text>Weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5">
    <text>What ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6">
    <text>I have Saiga and AKMN.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5111">
    <text>For AKM, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_51">
    <text>7.62x39mm, 3 packs for 5 cans of food.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5211">
    <text>For AKM, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_52">
    <text>7.62x39mm armor-piercing, 3 packs for 4 bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5311">
    <text>For Kalash, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_53">
    <text>5.45x39mm 3 packs, for 5 loaves of bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5411">
    <text>For Kalash, improved.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_54">
    <text>5.45x39mm BP, 3 packs for 4 bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5511">
    <text>For LR-300, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_55">
    <text>5.56x45mm SS109, 3 packs for 5 sticks of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5611">
    <text>For LR-300, improved.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_56">
    <text>5.56x45mm AP, 3 packs for 4 bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5711">
    <text>For SVD, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_57">
    <text>7.62x54R 7N1, three packs for 1 "Stone Flower" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5811">
    <text>For Vintorez, Val or Groza, standard.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_58">
    <text>9x39 PAB-9, three packs for 1 "Slug" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6111">
    <text>AKMN.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_61">
    <text>AKMN - for 2 "Mica" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6211">
    <text>Saiga.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_62">
    <text>Saiga - for 2 "Meat Chunk" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_611">
    <text>AKMN is my favorite weapon, give it here.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_612">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_613">
    <text>Too expensive.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_621">
    <text>Saiga? That's it, snorks, watch out! Here, take 2 "Chunks".</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_623">
    <text>Nah, not today, I'm empty.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_511">
    <text>Give me standard, I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_512">
    <text>I ate the canned food, I was hungry.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_521">
    <text>For AKM - armor-piercing? Give me.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_522">
    <text>Don't have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_531">
    <text>Give me standard, I have a Kalash but running low on ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_532">
    <text>Don't have it, gave it all to crows.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_541">
    <text>Armor-piercing? Give me.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_542">
    <text>Don't have it, we partied a bit in the village yesterday.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_551">
    <text>Need for LR-300.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_552">
    <text>Ran out.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_561">
    <text>NATO ones, and armor-piercing too? Give me.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_562">
    <text>Yeah, everyone needs vodka, I don't have it - ran out.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_571">
    <text>Give me, I happen to have a "Stone Flower" with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_572">
    <text>Yeah, everyone needs vodka, don't have it - ran out.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_581">
    <text>Just for Groza, give me.</text>
</string>
<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_582">
    <text>Don't have it, I'm broke today.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_1">
    <text>What brought you to me, Stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_2">
    <text>Lukash told me that you can show me how to get from here, the Army Warehouses territory, to the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I can show the path to the Bar, but only if you help me too. You came just in time. There is an urgent matter: at that base you and the Freedomers captured from the military, there should be some documents left after them. I won't say exactly where, but definitely on the territory of the base. If Freedomers find them before you... In short, I wouldn't want Lukash's people to find these documents. Let's say, for ethical reasons.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_4">
    <text>Need to find some documents at the Freedom base. Do I understand you correctly?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_5">
    <text>Exactly. Find the documents, and I'll show you how to get to the Bar for that.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_6">
    <text>And how do you imagine that? There are piles of these documents there, my whole life will go into searching for them. And I need to go further.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_7">
    <text>Wait, brother, don't get excited. This folder is special, I assure you. It is probably hidden, but not among other documents, (lowering voice heavily, whispering) on the folder should be written: agents and case number. And also, this folder is in a protective, waterproof and fireproof transparent cover. So it can lie anywhere, even under the open sky. Got it? I very... very much desire to receive it, stalker. So, besides the transition to the "Bar", I'll throw in an artifact transmutation recipe for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_8">
    <text>Well alright, deal. I'll try to find this secret folder at the Freedom base, I have nowhere else to go, need to get out of the Warehouses somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, I was at the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_1">
    <text>Well, what's there? Found it?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_2">
    <text>Yes, found it. Interesting folder. I peeked in there out of the corner of my eye and found something very important for myself... I didn't come here just for nothing. I am looking for a brother, with whom we parted ways quite a long time ago. His nickname is Captain. In that secret folder I found a mention of him. And these records are quite fresh. At most half a year old, judging by some dates. Do you know anything about this man?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_3">
    <text>Actually, sticking your nose into other people's papers is somewhat indecent. But okay, let it pass. And regarding your Captain: consider that you already found him. He recently joined the Duty faction, serves as a guide for them, he is a seasoned stalker after all, crawled the Zone far and wide in his time. So I wish you to find him as soon as possible. That's the situation. Hope I helped you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_4">
    <text>This is the best news for all the time I've been in the Zone! Thank you so much for such important information about my brother. And where should I look for this Duty faction?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_5">
    <text>As far as I know, Dutyers have now settled in the Dark Valley. So you will get there exactly through the Bar territory. True, then you'll have to pass through the Garbage, but that's trifles. And now I will mark the transition to the Bar territory on your PDA and, as promised, give you a transmutation recipe, will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_6">
    <text>Thank you, you truly are the "Information Service" of the Zone. Maybe you can advise something else useful?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_7">
    <text>Well, okay, I'll give you one piece of valuable information for free. A man lives in the Zone in a tunnel at Agroprom - Sorcerer. He practices "black magic". And the most interesting thing is that he can resurrect the dead. So if you suddenly need to bring someone back to life, look for the Sorcerer at Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_8">
    <text>Well, thanks for the info! I hope I won't have to use "black magic" services.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_0">
    <text>Can I do anything else for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_1">
    <text>Yes, you can. There is another urgent matter. Diggers on the Radar are in trouble. Someone robbed their stash. Now they are sitting there completely without food and without medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_2">
    <text>What is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_3">
    <text>It's quite simple really. I will collect what they need. It will be enough for the start. Your task is to take the package to them. I'll send you the group's coordinates. At the same time, I'll show you the transition from the Army Warehouses to the Radar. Might come in handy later.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_4">
    <text>Alright, send the coordinates, and I'm off. Need to hurry. I'll go to the Radar to help the guys. At the same time, I'll collect some artifacts for myself on the way. They say there are many of them there, like a "Klondike". Well, and after that I'll rush to the Bar. Maybe I'll manage to rest a bit there. And then I'll go meet the Dutyers and hope to meet my brother there.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_0">
    <text>Who did this to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_1">
    <text>Better not ask. I've seen things, but this... A bloodsucker, but so powerful. We shot at it from six barrels, but it didn't care. Good thing it was full, didn't kill us - just tormented us a little. That bastard! What the Zone does to them, these aren't monsters, but some kind of terminators... Anyway, what are you doing here, stalker?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_2">
    <text>Ah, yes, completely forgot. I am here on behalf of the Informer. He collected some things for you here. Says you were robbed the other day. Well, there's a little: food, medkits, vodka. And generally, I am looking for a brother in the Zone, they call him "Captain". We got lost a long time ago. Have you heard anything about a stalker nicknamed "Captain" and his team?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_3">
    <text>No, I haven't heard of such a stalker, so sorry... And thank you. You helped us out greatly. How can I thank you? Ah, here, there is something! Take this, we found someone's weapon stash here, got hold of some ammo. Which ones should I give you? NATO or ours?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_4">
    <text>Give me NATO ones.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_5">
    <text>Give me ours.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, since I wandered into such a wilderness, maybe there is a job for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_1">
    <text>How about hunting?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_2">
    <text>Is it for that bloodsucker that almost tore you to shreds?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_3">
    <text>For him, the darling! Or are you afraid? I want to make a stuffed trophy out of him for memory.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I'm not afraid. Where do I look for him?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_5">
    <text>He hangs around here, not far. Let me drop a marker on him for you. Kill the beast - drag the carcass of this mutated cattle to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_0">
    <text>D-damn! What a beast. Barely managed.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_1">
    <text>Exactly, that's what I'm saying. How did you handle him? I still don't understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_2">
    <text>Yeah, had to tinker with it. Anyway, here is the carcass, accept the work.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_3">
    <text>A huge buffalo. And it stinks, the bastard. Well okay. Here, take a few medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_0">
    <text>What next?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_1">
    <text>I think we need to catch that bastard who stole things from our stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_2">
    <text>How?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_3">
    <text>Very simple. Look, I put a little loot in our stash, and you, when you get there, hide nearby. Since there is no one to steal but our own, I will gather all my people and tell them about this stash. Since the "Rat" is among us, he will surely go stealing again, and there... there I rely on you, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_4">
    <text>Sviblov, I won't let you down.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_5">
    <text>Just this, don't fire prematurely there. Wait until he reaches the stash, otherwise who knows, maybe a person is just walking. And don't catch his eye, understand yourself, it's a delicate matter. We don't need noise.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_1">
    <text>Oh, our savior! By the way, what is your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_3">
    <text>Strelok, so be it Strelok. How is our business?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_4">
    <text>Handled everything quietly. Certain Fedya the Robber.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_5">
    <text>Ah, you devil! I suspected him too, but there was no proof. Alright, thank you for the service. Yes, here is your reward - a sniper rifle. The guys dug it up somewhere. Look, a good thing. I'll give you a pack of sniper ammo too.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_6">
    <text>Thanks for the carbine! Yes, by the way, I took some ancient Amulet from the neck of this Fedya the Robber. A very strange thing, I want to tell you. Here, look... Do you know what this thing is?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_7">
    <text>Yes, a curious little thing... It emits some radiation, but clearly has some protective property. You know what? Show this Amulet to the Wanderer. He is standing over there by the wall, recently returned from a raid. He surely knows what kind of thing this is.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_8">
    <text>Okay, give me my reward and I'll go show the Amulet to the Wanderer.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Sviblov, is there more work, otherwise I'm leaving.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_1">
    <text>There is, of course, where would we be without work. Will need to go down into the Bunker and drag from there... Yes, basically, drag everything that can be dragged.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_2">
    <text>M-m-m, the task is a bit vague. Can you clarify what exactly, otherwise maybe tables and chairs are needed too.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_3">
    <text>Ideally, all we need is the system unit from the computer. But... but possibly, there will also be some paper documents. So, if there are any, drag them here too.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything, executing already.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_0">
    <text>Well, Sviblov, you found a place to send me! There are monsters like cockroaches and just as many mercenaries, how did they even pass by you?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_1">
    <text>They probably found some other entrance, considering it's a laboratory. These are very important documents. Did you find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_2">
    <text>Yes, here is the system unit, and here are the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_3">
    <text>Well done! For this I'll throw you a transmutation recipe. My guys took this recipe from one mercenary's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Lukash, how about work?</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Work? Well, there is no work for now, but there is a request.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_2">
    <text>What request?</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Need to find one person.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_4">
    <text>Kill him, you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_5">
    <text>You misunderstood me. There is one person, Lefty, a jack of all trades. We recaptured the base from the military. There is a lot of work: paint there, hammer here, saw more. Well, you understand yourself. I worry Dutyers might lure him to themselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_6">
    <text>Dutyers? And who is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_7">
    <text>Ah, soldiers with a delusional idea - "to cleanse the Zone". Well, let's not talk about them. Find Lefty and persuade him. I need him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright. If I find Lefty, I'll try to negotiate.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_9">
    <text>I won't be in debt either. You see, I pay well for work. Yes, and one more thing: here on the "Army Warehouses" territory, in the village not far from the abandoned checkpoint, there is a person. Called the Informer. A shady type. You be careful with him, but you'll have to go to him. To leave the "Army Warehouses" territory you need to know where the transition is located. As far as I know, right now you can only get to the Bar from the Warehouses, but only the Informer knows the way there. So, go to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood, I'll go talk to the Informer.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Are you Lefty?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_2">
    <text>They say you are a jack of all trades?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I can do a lot of things. And what did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_4">
    <text>I have a request from one person. He would like you to come to his base. And, well, various repairs there. In short, everything you know how to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_5">
    <text>Nah, I won't set foot near Voronin anymore. Subordination, discipline, br-r-r. Screw it, I'd better live free.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_6">
    <text>No, no. Not to Voronin, but to Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_7">
    <text>Ah, well I can go to Freedomers. But how will I go to them? Look at me, all in rags, no normal weapon, and the path is not short. Basically like this. Bring me a "Groza" and a suit. For example, here, "Mercenary Scientific Suit". A good suit, better than "Seva". Naturally, everything must be new. And then, consider it a deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_8">
    <text>Eh, damn, why did I get involved with you? Well okay, I'll look for a new "Mercenary Scientific Suit" and a new "Groza" for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_0">
    <text>Well, Lefty, hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_1">
    <text>Hello to you too. Well, found the new gear for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_2">
    <text>Yes, found it. Here, take everything as you asked: "Mercenary Scientific Suit" and "Groza" - everything in excellent condition.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_3">
    <text>Well, man, thank you! If you need anything repaired, come to me immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_4">
    <text>Alright, agreed. Good luck to you!</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_est_levsha_0">
    <text>Hello, Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_est_levsha_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, come in. How will you please me?</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_est_levsha_2">
    <text>I found Lefty. He, of course, was a bit stubborn, but in the end agreed. So, expect guests.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_est_levsha_3">
    <text>You didn't let me down, as always. Thank you. My treat, as we agreed. Yes, by the way, Skinflint has a matter for you. Definitely visit him later.</text>
</string>
<string id="lukash_est_levsha_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll go visit Skinflint.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_0">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_1">
    <text>Brother, help me out.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_2">
    <text>Explain properly. What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_3">
    <text>Bandits grabbed my pals and are holding them in the local prison.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_4">
    <text>Is there a prison here?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, sort of. They simply converted an old bunker into a prison and put everyone who owes them in there.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, how can I help? Give you money or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_7">
    <text>You see, the local boss, Knyaz, doesn't want to talk to me, I'm just a pawn to him. But you, immediately visible, are a solid man. He will definitely talk to you. Help free the guys, persuade Knyaz to let them go. And I... and I will give you a transmutation recipe.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_need_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, I'll talk to Knyaz, but I promise nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello to the gang.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_1">
    <text>Greetings, fraer. Where did you pop up from? To chat or strictly for business?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_2">
    <text>Came from afar. I have business with you, no time for chatting.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, come on, spill it, what business do you have.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_4">
    <text>They say you are holding a couple of stalkers for debts in your prison?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_5">
    <text>So-o-o, Sakhatiy is involved again. Damn! He already buzzed all my ears off, I should kick him out of the camp territory completely. Sick of him already, for real.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, so what about the guys?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_7">
    <text>They are shameful bitches! They stole my personal unique shotgun. Lefty gave it to me for my birthday. I went against a pseudogiant alone with it... And these rats... The matter was like this: I drop into the bar, and put the gun on the counter so it doesn't get in the way, because I know: everyone here is one of us, they won't touch it. And I went into the rest room. Snoozed for an hour or two, went out into the hall, there were only a couple of my guys and Borov. Looked, and the gun is gone! For real GONE! Well, naturally, I started an investigation, this and that, hit my own guys, scolded Borov. It turned out in the end that these two bastards entered the bar shortly before that. \n\nSo I organized a chase after them. Caught them. Started to crack them. These devils decided to play innocent: "Us? Never, Knyaz! We respect you, life is dearer to us!". Well, in general, same old story, damn. Well, my guys conducted educational work, but all they managed to beat out of them is that they saw one ugly mug of bandit appearance, who flew out of the bar like a bullet and almost knocked them off their feet. Look at that - "bandit appearance", everyone here has bandit appearance (laughs). So I had to put them in jail. I told them this: Until they confess and return the gun plus a penalty, they sure as hell won't get out of there.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_8">
    <text>If I find the gun for you, will you let the guys go?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_9">
    <text>The gun and the penalty. Let's say, fifteen grand.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_10">
    <text>Ten thousand and the gun, can't do more.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, deal, fraer. Hope your words are worth something. And press Sakhatiy. He, the sly mug, clearly didn't tell you everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well? Do you want me to help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course. Why would I ask you then?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, then stop feeding me bullshit and tell everything as it was.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_3">
    <text>You see, someone stole Knyaz's shotgun, and Cat and Vovan were in the bar at about that time. Well, now everyone thinks it's them. Especially since everyone knows that Cat is an avid gambler and constantly loses. He owes half the bar already. Agree, with such a reputation it is not difficult to suspect him? Only it's not him.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Then who?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_5">
    <text>The guys, when they entered the bar, saw a man. They met him and he almost knocked them down. They suspect him.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_6">
    <text>And where am I supposed to look for the man who almost knocked them down?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_7">
    <text>In short, here is what I will tell you: when Cat and Vovan were being led to prison, and I walked nearby and heard briefly from the bandits that the man is from Kocherga's gang, his nickname is Nut. He and two others, well the very same ones who led the guys, went for very rare and valuable artifacts. They said that somewhere in a secluded corner a strange phenomenon happened. All known anomalies formed in one place, and a monstrous haze raged for three days. And imagine, about a dozen rarest artifacts formed there after that. \n\nThey were cooked in this very mess. Where this place is, I didn't hear clearly, but it was definitely said that somewhere in the Dark Valley. And that the artifacts that formed there appear and disappear, as if falling through the ground. And whoever is lucky will be able to find and collect them. So, these three decided to hit the jackpot and went there on luck. But there were so many monsters in that place, oh boy! Well, then those two pissed themselves and ran away. And Nut, as he saw the arts, blew his top. He went straight ahead. But managed to take only one art, then chimeras tore him up badly. Well, he also ran away then. Ran for a long time, but still couldn't get away... Was wounded badly.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Why did you keep silent before?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_9">
    <text>I wasn't silent, but no one wanted to listen to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_10">
    <text>So, alright, everything is clear with this. You better tell me, where should I look for Knyaz's personal shotgun now?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Don't get hot! I think Knyaz's gun lies where chimeras finished Nut off. After all, beasts don't need weapons... And the bandits just said that the matter was in the Dark Valley. And that dude ran to a small two-story building, which is at the gas station next to the unfinished factory building. He tried to hide in it, but not fate, apparently... There, in the house at the gas station, you should search.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_0">
    <text>Well, Knyaz? I found your personal shotgun.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_1">
    <text>And the money, did you bring the money?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_2">
    <text>Yes, money is with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_3">
    <text>No, no money.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_4">
    <text>Clean work! That hits the spot, damn! You greased me well, bro! Alright, I'll tell my guys to release those two bastards.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, are you satisfied? I found Knyaz's gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you, you helped out. And the guys? Will the guys be released?</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, Knyaz already gave the order.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I... Well... Here, write down the recipe. Thank you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_dialog_0">
    <text>What did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Man, need your help. Mercenaries captured our brother Lefty. There are only six of us, and heaps of them. Every gun is important to us now. Help out, brother, come with us. We won't let our comrade be hurt.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, Lefty! He is exactly who I need.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_dialog_3">
    <text>Follow us.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_est_0">
    <text>Bes, can you spare some ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_est_1">
    <text>I can give some for the Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_est_2">
    <text>Well, give me at least for the Kalash. I spent all mine on these scums.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_0">
    <text>What was that?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_1">
    <text>Bandits, marauders, damn them. We declared war on them here, cleared almost the entire Dark Valley of them, otherwise they didn't let anyone pass. Well, in revenge they decided to cover us all at once. Alright, we'll show them who's the boss in the house.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_2">
    <text>Understood. You chose a not entirely successful place for a base.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_3">
    <text>Well, we are a relatively young faction... Just wait, we'll gain strength and take the Bar. It's high time to kick the bandits out of there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_4">
    <text>You'll have a hard time. They are entrenched there painfully well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_5">
    <text>Give it time, and we will be there. I, General Voronin, promise you this. By the way, thanks for the help. Here, take this from me, will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_0">
    <text>Health to you, Comrade Colonel. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_1">
    <text>Greetings, stalker, what did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_2">
    <text>Well, want to buy something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_3">
    <text>There are ammo, medkits and weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4">
    <text>Ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5">
    <text>Weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_6">
    <text>Medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41">
    <text>What ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51">
    <text>What weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_61">
    <text>I have army ones.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_411">
    <text>Ammo 5.45x39mm BP, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4111">
    <text>3 packs - for "Jellyfish" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41111">
    <text>I have a "Jellyfish" - here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41112">
    <text>Oh well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_412">
    <text>Ammo 7.62x54R 7N1, sniper.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4121">
    <text>3 packs - for "Meat Chunk" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41211">
    <text>Give me, the sniper rifle is idle in the backpack.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41212">
    <text>Nah, don't have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_413">
    <text>Ammo 7.62x54R 7N14, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4131">
    <text>3 packs - for "Flash" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41311">
    <text>Give me armor-piercing - just the thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41312">
    <text>Nah, don't have a "Flash".</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_414">
    <text>Ammo 9x39 SP-5, sniper.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4141">
    <text>3 packs - for "Gravi" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41411">
    <text>Give me, just the thing for Groza.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41412">
    <text>Where will I get you a "Gravi"?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_415">
    <text>Ammo 9x39 SP-6, armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_4151">
    <text>3 packs - for 2 "Sparkler" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41511">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have 2 "Sparkler" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_41512">
    <text>You went too far.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_511">
    <text>AN-94 "Abakan".</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5111">
    <text>AN-94 "Abakan" - for 2 "Gravi" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51111">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have 2 "Gravi" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51112">
    <text>You went too far.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_512">
    <text>Assault "Abakan".</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5121">
    <text>Assault "Abakan" - for 2 "Urchin" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51211">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have 2 "Urchin" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51212">
    <text>Prices! Prices! I better run with a Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_513">
    <text>Kalashnikov Machine Gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5131">
    <text>Kalashnikov Machine Gun - for 2 "Ruby Spring" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51311">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have two "Ruby Springs" with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51312">
    <text>Didn't need it anyway, just asking.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_514">
    <text>VSS "Vintorez".</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5141">
    <text>VSS "Vintorez" - for 2 "Ruby Battery" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51411">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have a couple of "Ruby Batteries" with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51412">
    <text>Didn't need it anyway, just asking.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_515">
    <text>RPG-7V.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_5151">
    <text>RPG-7V - for 2 "Stone Flower" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51511">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have two "Stone Flower" artifacts with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_51512">
    <text>Too expensive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_611">
    <text>How much for army ones?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_6111">
    <text>3 army medkits - for one "Slug" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_61111">
    <text>Give me, I just happen to have one "Slug" artifact with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_changhe_61112">
    <text>Too expensive.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_0">
    <text>Is there work, Knyaz?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_1">
    <text>What, fraer, not scared to work with us? You understand yourself, our work is "special", mostly by the concepts.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_2">
    <text>I understand, spill it.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_3">
    <text>Here is a task for you, simple for starters: There is one fraer, called Jeka. So he owes us money, shameful nit. He is hanging around somewhere at the Garbage now.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_4">
    <text>What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_5">
    <text>Two options: either let him cough up the dough, the little bitch, 15 grand, or... you understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_6">
    <text>Alright, I'll talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_0">
    <text>Are you Jeka?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_1">
    <text>Well, it's me. What did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_2">
    <text>I am from Knyaz. Do you guess what the conversation will be about?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_3">
    <text>He's fed me up. I told him: "Wait a bit, business is about to get better." And now the Garbage is practically empty. Broke in a word, sitting without work.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_4">
    <text>Knyaz won't be satisfied with such an answer.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_5">
    <text>Well what do you want? Here, kill me... But money won't fall into his pocket from that... Or listen, there is one option...</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_6">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_7">
    <text>I can offer one thing: this... this is a map fragment. If you assemble it completely, you will find out the location of Semetsky's stash itself.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_8">
    <text>You are pushing bullshit on me. Why do I need this piece of paper?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_9">
    <text>No, I know what I'm saying. One old digger gave it to me, don't remember the name. We waited out a blowout with him. I waited it out, but he... but he didn't. He reached the Sarcophagus together with Semetsky. Their group formed just of eight people plus Semetsky. And further he went alone. Said, if he returns alive, he will show the way to the rest. And finally took out a map where his stash is marked and divided into eight different parts. And distributed to everyone present. Either as a keepsake, or for some other reason, I don't recall now...</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_10">
    <text>And what do you propose?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_11">
    <text>Well, I give You the map piece, and you pay off the debt for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_12">
    <text>You are probably lying... Eh, sink or swim, give me the map piece.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_first_speak_13">
    <text>No, brother, you won't fool me!</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_0">
    <text>Hello, Knyaz.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_1">
    <text>And health to you, how will you please me?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_2">
    <text>That Jeka tried to scam me. Had to shoot him. Especially since he wasn't going to return the debt anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_3">
    <text>Eh. Immediately visible, fraer, couldn't scam people for money. Well okay. Here, take this.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_0">
    <text>Hello, Knyaz.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_1">
    <text>Hello, well how is our business?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_2">
    <text>Everything is right. He paid up.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_3">
    <text>Well, then cough up the dough.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_4">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_5">
    <text>Oh damn, I lost my wallet at the Garbage. Wait, I'll be there and back in a flash.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_6">
    <text>Well done, fraer! Worked normally. And here is a small present from me for the work.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_need_0">
    <text>Work some more? By the way, my name is Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_need_1">
    <text>There is a little business, Strelok. On one hand easy, on the other... In short, a bag of weed was dropped for us here. You understand, not hay. It was before the blowout, and the Zone before a blowout behaves damn inhospitably. The helicopter itself almost crashed. The wind was blowing - oh boy, and the pilots got pretty sick, so they had to drop the bag wherever they could. The only thing they could say is that there was a tower nearby, a water tower. I sent my fraers to search, but they didn't find jack... So consider the tower your only landmark.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_need_2">
    <text>Some landmark. That's, consider, several kilometers. Crawl on my belly?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_need_3">
    <text>Yeah, a problem... Listen here. You can also go to the nerds at Yantar. Those eggheads can surely help you. Ask them to put a marker on the bag of weed.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_need_4">
    <text>Alright, let's see. If I don't find it myself, I'll go bow to the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_0">
    <text>Greetings, Respectable one.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_1">
    <text>Hello to you too, stalker. Hiding from monsters or came for business?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_2">
    <text>Well, essentially, for business.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_3">
    <text>Well, spill it.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_4">
    <text>I need to hang a marker on one little thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_5">
    <text>What thing? Speak clearer.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_6">
    <text>A bag of weed. Marijuana, most likely, is in there...</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_7">
    <text>Wow, valuable goods! I don't even ask where from... We'll hang a marker, no problem, but you understand yourself...</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_8">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_9">
    <text>2 "Fireball" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_10">
    <text>Expensive, of course. But okay, here.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_help_metka_11">
    <text>D-damn, what prices. I better look for it myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_est_0">
    <text>Hello to the gang.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_est_1">
    <text>And don't you cough either, fraer.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_est_2">
    <text>Here, hold this! The bag is heavy, damn it. Got wet, or what? Can't figure it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trava_est_3">
    <text>We'll dry it, don't fear! You work efficiently, mine should learn from you. But okay. Here, I saved something here. Take it, we'll be even.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_0">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_1">
    <text>I see you are a tough guy. Want to earn money?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_2">
    <text>Do you want to offer me a job?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_3">
    <text>Well, there is one place here, you can raise good money. True, the risk is substantial too.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_4">
    <text>What place, what job? Don't be shady.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_5">
    <text>Alright, there is one man, Varyag. Can be found in the Agroprom basements. So, he offers to play a game. Pays well. But there is one but...</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_6">
    <text>What "but"?</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_7">
    <text>Problem is that no one has won yet. Not once. And losing equals death.</text>
</string>
<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_8">
    <text>Fun. Alright, I'll think about it. Maybe I'll risk it.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Varyag?</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Decided to test yourself?</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, sort of yes.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Know the conditions? No? I'm telling: you need to pass four circles in a row. Each time there will be more monsters, and they will be more insidious. If you pass all four circles in a row, you will receive a reward: Transmutation recipe "Grandmother Burer's Beads" and a weapon - FN FAL rifle. Remember! You cannot leave the Agroprom basements while participating in the run. And also you will have to hand over your weapons. Only a knife. You cannot take anything else with you. You will need to run to that end of the dungeon, almost to the end. In that place a medkit and a bandage will be waiting for you. Hope you figure it out. When you run there, I'll give a signal to return.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_0">
    <text>Everything is clear to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_1">
    <text>Well, ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_2">
    <text>Yes, sort of.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_3">
    <text>Hand over your things. Reminding, as you run to the end, a medkit and a bandage will be waiting for you there. If you return, if you return, of course, I'll give a medkit and a bandage too. And so every circle. So your things won't be needed for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_4">
    <text>Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_0">
    <text>Yeah, seemed okay. True, these zombies, bitches, are tenacious...</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_1">
    <text>Catch your breath. Here, take a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_2">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_3">
    <text>Well, the first circle is passed.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_4">
    <text>Yeah, I see.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_5">
    <text>Alright, let's go for the second.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_6">
    <text>You can wish me luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_0">
    <text>Woah, that was harder now.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_1">
    <text>Issuing a medkit now.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_2">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_3">
    <text>Well, ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_4">
    <text>Yeah, sort of caught my breath... Well, I'm going for the third...</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_0">
    <text>Bloodsuckers! Beasts! Almost tore me to pieces.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_1">
    <text>Yeah, better not mess with them... Especially without a weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_2">
    <text>Well okay. Last circle left.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_3">
    <text>Yes, you are right. Here, take a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_4">
    <text>That's it, I'm going.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>I did it!</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, didn't expect it! Good job!</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>Alright, give the things back. Need to eat something.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>Here are your things. And here is your prize. And also giving you one transmutation recipe. Will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks, and especially for the recipe. I'll go teach those burers a lesson in politeness.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_fail_0">
    <text>Damn, Varyag, I couldn't do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_fail_1">
    <text>Here are your things and get out of here, cheater.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_need_0">
    <text>What did you want, Brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_need_1">
    <text>Listen, brother. We snatched two unique guns from mercenaries here. We don't need them, it's hard to find ammo for them anyway. But Duty will probably be interested in them. Take these guns to them, and in return take a crate of ammo from them, but only for the Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_need_2">
    <text>Well, it's not really on my way...</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_need_3">
    <text>Come on, brother, help me out. I won't remain in debt either. I'll throw in some junk.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_need_4">
    <text>Okay, convinced. Give them here.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_0">
    <text>Greetings, Colonel.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok? What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_2">
    <text>Well, I brought you something.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_3">
    <text>O-oh, where did you get this?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_4">
    <text>Bes passed this. He and the guys captured them from mercenaries, asks for ammo for the Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_patron_need_5">
    <text>Interesting rifles, and they don't seem to ask for much. Alright, I won't keep you. Here, take the ammo. Greetings to Bes. A good man, pity he is not with us.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Bes. Greetings to you from Petrenko. Calls you to join them.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_est_1">
    <text>No, Strelok, I won't go to them. They have their own business, I have mine. And I don't like their drill.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_est_2">
    <text>Alright brother. Here is the ammo, take it. As promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_est_3">
    <text>Thank you. And I saved something for you too.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_0">
    <text>Hello, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_1">
    <text>Greetings, young man. Do you have business with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_2">
    <text>Yes. Here, stopped by to buy something. And maybe there is some work for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_3">
    <text>M-m-m... Actually there is. But can you handle it?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_4">
    <text>Let's try, Professor. I am capable.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_5">
    <text>Well then, here is your task: we discovered several specimens of monsters that possess abilities unexpected for their species, namely very fast regeneration. We are very interested in why and when this mutation occurred. And it is necessary to simply observe them. To do this, you need to hang, so to speak, a marker.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_6">
    <text>Where to look for them and how to hang a marker on them? They are unlikely to be happy to communicate with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_need_7">
    <text>A pseudogiant was last seen at Rostock. There is a downed helicopter lying there for a long time. A "bald" chimera can be met in the Dark Valley. You know, there is an abandoned factory, bandits sometimes set up their lair there. So, behind it there is a small swamp, right by the fence, where the drain pipes are. Well, hope you understood. And a bloodsucker lives at the Cordon. You know, there is a destroyed bridge and two abandoned pig farms nearby. That's somewhere there. Now about the method of hanging a marker: I will give you a carbine, converted by one of our craftsmen. So, it shoots only special ammo, which upon contact with the victim's body hangs a marker on it, without causing harm. Thus, you will be able to hang a marker on all three. Yes, don't forget to return the carbine later, you don't need it anyway, you can't kill with it, and we still need it. If everything goes successfully, in return I will send useful information to your PDA - the transition from Yantar to Radar and back. And, of course, you cannot kill the test subjects, I need them alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_est_0">
    <text>Professor, I returned.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_est_1">
    <text>You handled the task well, Strelok. Didn't expect it, to be honest.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_est_2">
    <text>I told you, Doc, that I am capable. Although had to run around.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_first_work_est_3">
    <text>Well then, give me the carbine and your PDA. I will record the data about the Yantar-Radar transition on it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_0">
    <text>Doc, well? Work some more?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_1">
    <text>Well then, there is one very delicate matter. One of our scientists, Associate Professor Dorodin, betrayed us. He stole one very rare artifact and passed it through a corrupt major to a customer on the Big Land, receiving very big money for it, which was transferred to his bank account. Then he agreed with three military men to help him get out of the Zone. Another scientist, his assistant, fled with him. And this second one possesses very valuable data, for which they are ready to pay a considerable sum on the Big Land too. His memory is phenomenal, keeps all information in his head. But without Dorodin he is nobody and his name is nothing. No one will even talk to him there.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_2">
    <text>So. And what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_3">
    <text>For such betrayal punishment must be severe! Eliminate Dorodin and that's it. Do as you see fit with the second one. He will no longer be dangerous for us later. Although he should be punished too.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_4">
    <text>I'm afraid I'm not on the same path with the military. Unlikely they will be happy to see me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_need_5">
    <text>Let's do this: I give you the task to eliminate Associate Professor Dorodin, and all the details are with Dan. He seems to have planned everything already. After all, he is our head of security.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_second_work_need_0">
    <text>Hi, Dan. The Professor said that you are aware and will explain everything to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_second_work_need_1">
    <text>Hi, Strelok! I see Sakharov briefly told you about the betrayal of Dorodin and his assistant. We tracked their movement. These two are still in the Zone. Now they are in the Dark Valley under the protection of three corrupt soldiers and are waiting for a helicopter, which is supposed to ferry them out of the Zone. You need to find them and eliminate them. Dorodin must be destroyed. He is your main target. The second traitor should also be shot for order's sake, but that's how it goes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_second_work_need_2">
    <text>Everything is clear. Let's get to business, what and how?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_second_work_need_3">
    <text>Do you know the X-18 laboratory in the Dark Valley? Just a bit to the right there is such a hilly field, many anomalies and mutants. There is also a small fence along the edge... Alright, I'll hang a marker in your PDA. So, the three soldiers guarding the traitors are clearly special forces. You, of course, don't need to meet them. I'll mark a spot on the map for you. Climb onto the roof of the X-18 complex, it's an excellent firing point. And remember, your main task is the elimination of Dorodin. He must be taken down quietly. And most importantly, do not catch the soldiers' eyes before that, otherwise you will fail the whole thing. Yes, and one more thing: both scientists are dressed in identical green scientific suits. So you won't have time to figure out "who is who". Therefore, take down both in turn, the bullet will sort it out itself. As you get to the roof, act quietly and quickly. And as you take down Dorodin, then you can lay down the soldiers quite calmly. I will be in touch. Read messages from me...</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_0">
    <text>Dan. Do you have a sniper rifle?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_1">
    <text>I can supply a powerful sniper rifle and thirty sniper rounds for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_2">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_3">
    <text>Not much. Four "Fireball" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_4">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_trade_5">
    <text>Don't have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_est_0">
    <text>Professor, good afternoon.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_est_1">
    <text>Come in, Strelok. You handled the task well, I am pleased with our cooperation.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_est_2">
    <text>Nice to hear. Hope this will reflect somehow on my well-being?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_est_3">
    <text>You know, I thought here that you will still have time to earn weapons and ammo. Instead, I will give you valuable information and a couple of artifact transmutation recipes. Give me your PDA, I will send information about the transition from Agroprom to Yantar and back to it. Yes, and one more thing: Your help is required again. One of our employees disappeared here. Kruglov has all the information. Talk to him, please.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_second_work_est_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll go talk to Kruglov.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_0">
    <text>Professor, do you have anything for sale? %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_1">
    <text>There are ammo, medkits, weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_2">
    <text>What ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_3">
    <text>What weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_4">
    <text>What medkits?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_21">
    <text>From ammo here is what I have:\n 
	- "7.62x51 mm NATO" - 2 packs for three "Droplet" artifacts,\n 
	- "7.62x51 mm NATO BP" - 2 packs for two "Fireball" artifacts,\n 
	- "7.62x54 mm B-30" for PKM - 2 packs for "Film" artifact.\n</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_31">
    <text>There are NATO sniper rifles:\n
        - FN FAL - for 1 "Soul" artifact,\n
        - HK G28 - for 1 "Crystal" artifact,\n
        - SV-98M - for 10 poltergeist eyes.\n</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_41">
    <text>Scientific medkits - three pieces for ten cat tails, Antirads - two pieces for ten Burer Hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_211">
    <text>Give me 7.62x51 mm NATO I just have three "Droplets" with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_212">
    <text>Give me 7.62x51 mm NATO BP. Love to shoot with armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_213">
    <text>Give me 7.62x54 mm B-30 for PKM.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_214">
    <text>No, Professor, nothing needed today.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_311">
    <text>Give me Howa Type 20. I have ammo, but nothing to shoot from.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_312">
    <text>Give me the HK G28 Rifle. I'll test what kind of beast it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_314">
    <text>SV-98M - my dream, taking it without looking.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_411">
    <text>Need scientific medkits, taking.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_trade_412">
    <text>Give me antirads, I guess, my back is itching, isn't it from radiation?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_0">
    <text>I met "Captain". It is not my brother, a mistake occurred...</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_1">
    <text>Sorry, I sympathize with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_2">
    <text>General, Captain Sobolev told me that you can show the path to the Cordon from the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_3">
    <text>Well, that will be known in some time. I sent a scout to the factory where bandits are entrenched. So he must obtain information about where bandits keep information about transitions from the Dark Valley. Meanwhile, you help us a little too.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_4">
    <text>Alright, General, I'll wait. How can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_5">
    <text>I see you handle weapons well. So, I think there is work for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_6">
    <text>What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_7">
    <text>Lately, painfully a lot of different filth has bred near the X-18 laboratory. It would be necessary to clear the entire territory adjacent to X-18. Scientists asked us a long time ago, but somehow we never got around to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_need_8">
    <text>Understood, General, executing already.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_est_0">
    <text>General, permission to report?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_est_1">
    <text>Hello to you, Strelok. Still joking? Alright, what about the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_est_2">
    <text>Task completed, territory cleared. Path to the laboratory is free.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_snork_est_3">
    <text>Well done! And here is the deserved reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_0">
    <text>Well, what about the transition to the Cordon, General?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_1">
    <text>Listen, Strelok. According to our data, somewhere on the territory of the abandoned factory in the Dark Valley there is a bandit stash. If we find it and, so to speak, expropriate it, then by this we will inflict quite serious damage to local bandit gangs. In this stash, besides weapons, there seems to be a flash drive or disk with information about the transition to the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_2">
    <text>General. The factory is big. Searching for a stash there without exact coordinates is like looking for a needle in a haystack.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_3">
    <text>I understand. But if everything were simple, we would have found it long ago ourselves. The only thing I will say, there is one person, a bandit, called "Jila". Find him, he can help find the stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_4">
    <text>Strange. A bandit will help me rob his own?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_5">
    <text>He has some beef with bandits. Crossed the path of one of the leaders, apparently. So, I think if you talk to him normally, he will crack. It was he, by the way, who leaked useful information to my scout.</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_6">
    <text>And where to look for this Jila?</text>
</string>
<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_7">
    <text>Look somewhere near the factory, can't say more precisely. He is hiding from everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_0">
    <text>Greetings! Are you, by chance, Jila?</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_1">
    <text>Well, it's me. And what is it to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_2">
    <text>Well, if you are Jila, then I am at the right address.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_3">
    <text>Don't stall. What do you need, fraer?</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_4">
    <text>You possess some information that I need. Namely: You must know where the bandit stash is.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_5">
    <text>Ah, so that's it. But why the hell do I need you?</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_6">
    <text>For those who don't understand, the layout is like this: Any day now your own will whack you. Strangers don't need you at all. And here I am, your savior. You help me, and I will put in a word for you before Voronin. You'll be able to stay at the Duty base.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_7">
    <text>Alright, fraer. But let's change the layout a bit: You first agree with Voronin, and only then I tell you about the stash. You have all the trump cards, and I have only one. You understand yourself, if I tell you about the stash, then I won't be needed anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_nychka_need_8">
    <text>Deals. Wait, I'll be back soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_0">
    <text>General!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_1">
    <text>What is it, Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_2">
    <text>I found that bandit. He agrees to tell about the stash. Only this... He wants you to take him under your protection and let him onto your base.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_3">
    <text>What next! Why do I need all sorts of bandit scum here? Things will start disappearing from the guys. I know these criminals, only the grave will fix them.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_4">
    <text>Voronin. He is a former paratrooper, not a thief. He just got unlucky. Well, went to prison, and there learned about the Zone. So he rushed here after serving time. And who else is he supposed to go to here? You don't take former convicts. So the guy had to join criminals. But otherwise he is a normal man, I vouch for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_5">
    <text>Well, if you vouch, then fine. Let him come. Just warn him: If I catch him stealing - straight to the wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_0">
    <text>Hello, Jila.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_1">
    <text>Greetings.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_2">
    <text>Well, that's it, I agreed with Voronin, you can move to their base. Only he also asked to warn that you'll go to the wall if you steal anything. That's it, I fulfilled my part of the deal. Now it's your turn.</text>
</string>
<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_3">
    <text>Listen to me. The stash is in the pantry, in the main building of the former factory. I'll send you a marker, with it you will surely find it quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_0">
    <text>Here, General, hold this. Everything I found.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_1">
    <text>Not bad, so much ammo! Could arm a small gang!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_2">
    <text>There was also that very flash drive you talked about.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_3">
    <text>Well done! That's it. Those bandits will be "happy" when they discover that their stash is empty. Ah yes, here, take this for the work. Deserved. So, let's see what's on the flash drive. One minute...</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_4">
    <text>Well? What's there?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_5">
    <text>There is data about the transition. I am ready to send you the marker of the path from the Dark Valley to the Cordon and back to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_est_6">
    <text>Well that's excellent. Now I can move out to the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_zahar_0">
    <text>Want to say something?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_zahar_1">
    <text>I want to ask you about something. By the way, what is your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_zahar_2">
    <text>Call me Strelok. What do you want to ask?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_zahar_3">
    <text>I have a portable radio station here. Take it to Zahar. I want to have constant communication with him. Instructions are inside if needed. I think he'll figure it out. And tell him I hold no grudge against him and will definitely find him when possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_zahar_4">
    <text>A bit far, but okay. If there is time - I'll drop it off.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_racia_give_0">
    <text>Zahar, hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_racia_give_1">
    <text>Strelok, hello! Decided to visit us again? Found your brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_racia_give_2">
    <text>No, haven't found my brother yet. But I found your friend, Captain Sobolev. He serves in Duty now. Asked to convey that he holds no offense against you. Here, he passes you a portable radio for constant communication with you. Instructions inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_racia_give_3">
    <text>Huge thanks to you, Strelok! You brought good news. Here, take this. A little buckshot for you as gratitude from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_racia_give_4">
    <text>No need for thanks, Zahar. Today I helped you, tomorrow you help me. That's how we live in this cursed Zone, damn it...</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_0">
    <text>Can I be useful to you in anything else?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_1">
    <text>M-m. There is one little matter in which you can help me.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_2">
    <text>Speak, what needs to be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_3">
    <text>You see, after I walked you to the transition to the Warehouses last time, I was returning back and collected rare artifacts. And when passing near the bridge, I ran into a pack of pseudofleshes. They drove me under this bridge, barely fought off the beasts. But here is the bad luck, I dropped the container with collected artifacts somewhere. There was no time to search, fleshes wounded me slightly. Had to go to the camp faster. Thank God, managed to get there before dark. My leg still hurts.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_4">
    <text>I understand that you suggest I find your container with artifacts?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_5">
    <text>Yes, it would be very handy if you helped me. I won't remain in debt. And I will mark the place where to search approximately on the map.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_6">
    <text>Alright, Zahar. Mark the place for searches, and I'll try to help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_0">
    <text>Zahar. I found your container.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_1">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok!</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_2">
    <text>Ran into beasts. They almost drove me from this world! But nothing, managed.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_3">
    <text>Yes, Strelok. Many monsters bred in the Forest nowadays. Can't keep up shooting them. Well, give me my container. And I prepared something for you for your work.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_4">
    <text>Here, keep your container. And don't lose it anymore!</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_0">
    <text>Hi, Dan.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_1">
    <text>Haven't seen you for a while. And our zombies, you see, still keep coming and coming every day. How many of ours have already fallen. Listen, here is what I think...</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_2">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_3">
    <text>There are so many monsters and zombies on the factory territory at Yantar... Ugh... And all this filth howls, moans, yells and growls every night. I haven't been able to sleep for a whole week. Here is the thing: need to go there and clear the territory. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_4">
    <text>The job is not simple. Do you pay well?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_need_5">
    <text>I won't pay very much, honestly saying. But I have a handheld grenade launcher and charges for it. Here, take it. Have a blast there to the fullest.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Dan. Well, I was there. Had a blast to the fullest!</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_est_1">
    <text>Yeah, everyone heard. Finally I will be able to sleep.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_est_2">
    <text>Will you take the grenade launcher back?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_est_3">
    <text>No, take it as a reward. And I'll throw in some more ammo for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="petruha_about_tolik_0">
    <text>What did you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="petruha_about_tolik_1">
    <text>Buddy, help me out. Tolik is sending an SOS signal, but I can't leave. Wolf placed me here. We've had problems with bandits lately. Well, you'll get to the camp, and Wolf will explain everything there. You, uh, don't go into the village, bandits are there. Wolf and the experienced ones went on a raid, and bandits came. Who was there to defend the camp? Rookies either scattered or, well, you understand... Anyway, I'm talking too much. Help Tolik.</text>
</string>
<string id="petruha_about_tolik_2">
    <text>Where should I look for him?</text>
</string>
<string id="petruha_about_tolik_3">
    <text>Wolf placed me here, and Tolik near the transition to the Garbage. So, look for him there. Hurry, brother, there are beasts here - God forbid they take him down!</text>
</string>
<string id="petruha_about_tolik_4">
    <text>Alright. I'll go see what happened there.</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_need_help_0">
    <text>Are you Tolik?</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_need_help_1">
    <text>I am. Oh, brother, I feel awful.</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_need_help_2">
    <text>Well, nothing, you'll recover. Main thing is, you stayed alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_need_help_3">
    <text>Brother, help me out. Help me get to the camp, Wolf will thank you there. I'm afraid I won't make it alone, seeing double. A bloodsucker gored me pretty bad. Good thing a couple of boars appeared, it switched to them.</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_need_help_4">
    <text>Alright, brother, let's go. Or you really won't make it.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_0">
    <text>Are you the boss?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_1">
    <text>Yes, I am. They call me Wolf. Thank you for not leaving Tolik in trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_2">
    <text>Don't mention it. Helped and helped. We are own people - we'll settle up.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_3">
    <text>No, brother, not everyone will rush to help, and some will even help send you to the other world. For a good gun or a valuable artifact. I have something here, take it. Not much, though, don't hold it against me.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_0">
    <text>Petruha told me about bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_1">
    <text>Eh, yeah... such things happened here: I went to Agroprom, well, Barman sent me. Took the guys who are more experienced with me. Fanat and a few rookies remained in the village. Well, bandits took advantage of this and came. Shot half of them, half ran away, and they took Fanat while he was sleepy. Told him to drink less. He gets wasted and sleeps for a day, you can't wake him up even with a cannon.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_2">
    <text>Didn't try to retake it?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_3">
    <text>How?! Look yourself. There are two or three times fewer of us. And go with whom, just youngsters.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_4">
    <text>Well, what if I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_5">
    <text>Well, you are evidently a seasoned stalker! With you, of course, chances to kick bandits out of the village are higher, but we still need more experienced people. Listen, I called for a small group of experienced stalkers for backup, but they got delayed on the road somewhere. They say they are afraid of monsters. Thinking about turning back altogether. Right now they set up camp not far from here. If only we could help these guys get here faster, then we'd kick bandits out of the village in two counts.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_6">
    <text>I can go to them. But what about themselves? Especially since you say it's not far?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_7">
    <text>What, you haven't heard?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_8">
    <text>No. About what?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_9">
    <text>So many mutants bred there, oh boy! It is very dangerous there now. No, brother, I won't go there. Too risky business.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_10">
    <text>Well okay, I'll go. Speak, where?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_11">
    <text>Well, if you are not afraid, then listen... Or better let me drop a marker on your PDA. Find the stalker guys there, persuade them to join us. If they agree, lead them to me. When they arrive, then we can try to retake the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_about_tainik_12">
    <text>Understood everything. Moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="podmoga_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, stalkers. Are you going to Wolf?</text>
</string>
<string id="podmoga_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, us. Only we are afraid to go further... There were five of us, mutants tore two apart. We had to hide here.</text>
</string>
<string id="podmoga_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood. I came to escort you to Wolf. Don't be afraid, we'll run there quickly with me. If anything, I'll cover. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="podmoga_dialog_3">
    <text>Deal. Yes, honestly speaking, I'm tired of being afraid all the time myself. After all, we are not some cowards. Let's go, lead us.</text>
</string>
<string id="podmoga_dialog_4">
    <text>O-oh, that's the spirit! Moving out, don't lag behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_0">
    <text>Well, Wolf? I brought the guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_1">
    <text>I see, well done. Now we can move out. Eh, if only Fanat wouldn't get killed. Well okay, you see yourself. My people are mostly inexperienced, so the main work falls on your shoulders. Just don't climb forward too much, stay close to me while we walk to the village, and then act according to the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_2">
    <text>Understood, not the first time. Well, moving out?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_3">
    <text>Let's go. Walk next to me. We'll cover the rookies, if anything. Don't run far from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_0">
    <text>Well, Wolf, rejoice - the village is ours.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_1">
    <text>Yes, brother, thank You.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_2">
    <text>Listen, why didn't bandits touch the Barman?</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_3">
    <text>Barman? You're kidding! That old fox will get out of any trouble. And who will touch him, with his connections? Bandits want to eat and drink too. Weapons again. A lot goes through him in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_4">
    <text>Alright, Wolf, see ya. I just need to visit the Barman.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_5">
    <text>Wait. I'll drop a couple of transmutation recipes for you, they'll come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_0">
    <text>Hello, Knyaz! Is there work?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_1">
    <text>Oh, look who's here! There is a little business, Strelok. My kids gathered for a meeting with Chehov's gang.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_2">
    <text>And who are these Chehovskie?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_3">
    <text>Just some trash. Work mostly by lawlessness. For a "Stone Blood" they'll blow brains out just like that, damn... In general, for me, they are complete lawless ones. But they have power, so we have to reckon with them... Freaks.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_4">
    <text>So, what is the problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_5">
    <text>One problem - I don't trust them a damn bit. Agreed that the meeting will pass without weapons. We'll see... In any case Krest will be there, my old pal. I fear something might happen. Would need to cover Krest just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_6">
    <text>Where should the talk take place?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_7">
    <text>At the Garbage, not far from the transition to the Dark Valley. You, don't catch their eye. Chehov's people are nervous. No wonder, made so many enemies. If you get spotted, they'll start blasting immediately. There is a ruined building, not far from the checkpoint at the Garbage. You climb to the top. The view from there is most excellent. Hide there and sit. Don't move. If everything is tip-top, we'll part peacefully. You holster the weapon and come to me. But if shooting starts, you don't leave these nits alive, damn, and mostly protect Krest. In short, until my signal don't think about shooting and don't catch their eye. Sit in place and wait. I know you: one thing - immediately grab the gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Knyaz.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_1">
    <text>Ah, Strelok arrived! Yes, you processed them skillfully!</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_2">
    <text>Yeah, I almost fell asleep. Thought it was over, they'd part peacefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_3">
    <text>Okay, okay. Special respect for Krest. Here, take this. A small gift from the gang for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, science.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_1">
    <text>And hello to you, Stalker. Want to earn money?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_2">
    <text>And what is needed?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_3">
    <text>We discovered one artifact here, unknown to us until now. Called "Controller's Heart". Need you to get one specimen.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_4">
    <text>And where am I supposed to look for this artifact? First time hearing about such thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_5">
    <text>There is one place, it is definitely there. At Agroprom, where the swamp is. It's somewhere there. But beware! This artifact has a strange property - it emits telepathic waves, which press hard on the brains. Also, it can be detected only by one detector.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_6">
    <text>What detector? Where to get it?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_7">
    <text>"Veles Detector", modified by me. Only with it you will be able to find the "Controller's Heart" artifact. Without it, you won't succeed in finding this artifact. Also will give info about transition from Yantar to Agroprom, you'll come out right near the swamp.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_8">
    <text>Alright, give the detector. I'll try to find this artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, science. What a task you gave me.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Was it hard?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_2">
    <text>There was a controller there. Had to tinker.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_3">
    <text>This artifact attracts controllers to itself. Why - is unknown yet, but there is something in it that pulls them to it. Well okay. Here is what I propose: Either you give back the detector now, and I pay you the reward for getting me the "Controller's Heart" artifact, or I leave it to you. And with it you will look for "Controller's Heart" artifacts and turn them in to me. And I will pay you for every brought "Controller's Heart" artifact. Without this detector you won't find them, that's for sure. Yes, I will pay with rare arts and not just one piece! Think about it...</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_4">
    <text>Nah, brother. Better pay me for the work now, and keep the detector for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, I'll keep the detector for myself. Will come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_0">
    <text>Hello Kruglov, I changed my mind.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_1">
    <text>About what?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_2">
    <text>Well, I want to take your detector from you. They say you pay well for every "Controller's Heart" art, and without it I can't find them.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_3">
    <text>I can give it, but not for nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_4">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_5">
    <text>Grandmother Burer's Beads.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_6">
    <text>So expensive! But okay, here.</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_need_detector_7">
    <text>Don't have it, will bring later.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_0">
    <text>Wanted to ask: I have a simple anomaly detector here. Do you happen to have a better detector?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_1">
    <text>I do. Can exchange for arts.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_2">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_3">
    <text>One "Controller's Heart" artifact exchange for "Veles Detector".</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_4">
    <text>Eh, the last one. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_5">
    <text>I'll go search.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_0">
    <text>Hello to science.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_1">
    <text>And hello to You, Strelok! What did you bring?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_2">
    <text>Well, brought "Controller's Heart" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_change_3">
    <text>Well done! Rare artifact. Here is your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen. There is a talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_1">
    <text>About what?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, you trade information?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_3">
    <text>There is such a thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_4">
    <text>I have several map fragments, on which, if you assemble all parts together, the location of Semetsky's stash is displayed.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_5">
    <text>And?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I ran through the whole zone, but can't find a few parts. Maybe you can help determine coordinates by what is available?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_7">
    <text>There is one person. But you understand...</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_8">
    <text>What is required?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_9">
    <text>"Crystal Soul of Bengal" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_10">
    <text>Wow, so expensive! Alright, I'll search.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_11">
    <text>You search. And I'll strain the little man, let him ponder.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Informer. Not empty-handed I came to you!</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_1">
    <text>What, brought it?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_2">
    <text>Here, take it. "Crystal Soul of Bengal" artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_3">
    <text>Well done. Give it here.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_0">
    <text>Well, what about my business?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_1">
    <text>Had to tinker, of course. Data that you provided is scarce. But still...</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_2">
    <text>What "still"? Don't obscure.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_3">
    <text>Oh, how you turned crimson! Don't fear, everything is normal. Give your PDA, I'll drop stash coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Yes, Informer.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>There is information about Radar - Dark Valley transition. There and back.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Two "Chimera Tears" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Just knew it! Cooked this morning, exactly two. Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>Alright, went to cook.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Barman.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok. I've been waiting for you for a long time.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Wow! You know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Remember! I know a lot, if not everything. Well okay, let's get straight to business. I know, you are looking for a brother. Came to me. That is good. Right now, truthfully, can't help you with anything yet, but will help a bit later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_4">
    <text>You really are the "Information Center". People don't talk for nothing...</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Strelok, I don't need compliments. You need to find Mahomet, right? Exactly right, I know. Mahomet is an experienced loner digger and he has some beefs of his own with Sidorovich. That is a trader, holds a "point" on the perimeter territory, Deep Station. So you need to go to Sidorovich. He will suggest where to find Mahomet. And I in turn also have business with Sidorovich, but I can't contact him now, because after the last blowout the Zone expanded and captured a large part of the territory and something weird is happening with connection there. And I extremely need to send a message to Sidorovich, savvy? So we have a mutual interest emerging.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_6">
    <text>And what do you propose?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll ponder a bit, consult with someone, on how to get you to the territory. And you, while I'm deciding this question, help good people.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_8">
    <text>What "good people" and help them with what?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_9">
    <text>You know them: Fang, Ghost, Feldsher... Continue?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Yeah, all familiar people... What is needed from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_11">
    <text>You see, many don't believe in the extraterrestrial origin of the Zone. Gets an impression that it didn't do without human hands here. You probably know that there are several laboratories on the Zone territory?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_12">
    <text>I know. Even visited some.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_13">
    <text>Well so, what are they for? What experiments were conducted? Unclear... The military visited some of them and found some documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_14">
    <text>Continue.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_15">
    <text>Need to find these documents. Or something that can shed light on this whole situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_16">
    <text>Where will I find documents? More than sure, the military already took all documents out of the zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_17">
    <text>Here you are right, of course. But you understand yourself, to get to the laboratory, one must know the Zone. Know it well. Someone surely guided the soldiers there. Understand what I mean? They had a guide. It's either a stalker, or a military from former stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_18">
    <text>How will we find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_19">
    <text>And here I will help you. I know who was the guide. Stalker by the nickname "Varyag". I can even approximately say where to look for him. At Agroprom. Can't say more precisely, but somewhere there. Find him and try to make him talk. He is a serious man, so be more careful with him. Go, and I'll ponder meanwhile how to cook up a "pass" to Peacekeepers for you and generally how to get you there through the soldiers' checkpoint. Find Varyag, find out what and how and immediately to me. By that time we'll come up with something worthwhile.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_start_dialog_20">
    <text>I love business people. Alright, everything is clear, I'm going to Varyag.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_zanat_0">
    <text>Are you Varyag?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_zanat_1">
    <text>Well, I am. And what is it to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_zanat_2">
    <text>I have a couple of questions for you. Barman sent me.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_zanat_3">
    <text>I have no desire to talk to you. Especially answering your questions. And I saw your Barman in a coffin. That's it, beat it, you are bothering.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_0">
    <text>Varyag, hello!</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_1">
    <text>Oh, hello, Strelok! What brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_2">
    <text>Listen, Varyag, business for you. Barman directed me to you. Remember, you led the military to the laboratory? They were looking for some documents there.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_3">
    <text>And why do you or Barman need this?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_4">
    <text>Believe me Varyag, necessary. Very necessary to know.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_5">
    <text>Anyone else I would have shot, but you are the first who managed to win against me... Alright, listen: It was about a year ago. I was digging with might and main then, walked and researched the Zone far and wide. Especially various dungeons and laboratories interested me. Kept thinking, here I'll find such a place where there will be many-many artifacts, I'll hit, so to speak, the jackpot and leave the Zone forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_6">
    <text>Next.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_7">
    <text>Well and so once from another raid returning to the cordon, well and as always straight to the Barman. Walking, mumbling something under my nose, a few decent arts in the backpack, mood is good. And here out of nowhere spetsnaz. Twisted me and took to the checkpoint. And there... major Yarofeev. Rare bitch! He starts rubbing it in, say, either I lead a group of military to one laboratory, or they shoot me right here, since officially there are no people on the Zone territory, and everything that moves is subject to automatic destruction. \n\nWell what to do? Agreed, damn it! In general I led the soldiers to the laboratory. Moreover out of ten people only half survived. Told them to listen to me in everything. But no, where there, I am just a piece of meat for them that knows the way. Burer in the X-18 laboratory embellished me too, see. In short, they carried out a whole box with documents and back we went with them to the Cordon. There I bolted from them, because I was more than sure, Yarofeev would have shot me. What the hell does he need a witness for?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_8">
    <text>Listen, and those documents? Don't you know what was in them? Well, at least approximately?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_9">
    <text>Wow you give! Had nothing else to do but read a pile of various documents. I wanted to survive, and then for me it was the main thing. I think you need to somehow find this bitch Yarofeev. He definitely knows something.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_10">
    <text>Where to find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_11">
    <text>Where-where... At the Checkpoint, where else? Although he is sly, but a drunkard indeed. Because of this he will stay at the Checkpoint forever like that. As he gets wasted, starts yelling, and then can snooze for a day or two - hell you'll wake him. In short, find out from Barman how to find Yarofeev.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_about_lab_12">
    <text>Well, thank you, Varyag. I'll go to Barman at the Cordon. Think he will suggest how I can see Yarofeev.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_0">
    <text>Greetings, Barman. I was at Varyag's - serious man.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_1">
    <text>Well and what? Managed to learn anything on our question?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_2">
    <text>Yes, managed to find out something. There is one major at the checkpoint. Yarofeev is his surname. He is exactly who is needed. He should have key information on our case. Do you know if Yarofeev is at the checkpoint now?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_3">
    <text>I know this nit. He is there. In short, such a picture is emerging: have to fight a little with the soldiers, time has come. If it won't work out to talk to him unnoticed. You try to slip through, well and there according to situation. In short, Godspeed, Strelok. After you find out information from Yarofeev, straight to me. Tell what and how, and I'll give you a pass to Peacekeepers and a letter for Sidorovich then. Such is the plan.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_4">
    <text>Alright. I'll go fight again.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_0">
    <text>Well, Yarofeev. I have a talk for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_1">
    <text>Who are you, damn it?</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_2">
    <text>You better here, drink some water, and then listen carefully. Whether you live or not will depend on your answer.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_3">
    <text>What do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_4">
    <text>Remember Varyag? A year ago or something like that he led a group of military to laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_5">
    <text>Wait... well yes, happened sort of... Happened! Remembered! And what do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_6">
    <text>I need to know what was in those documents that were carried out from the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_7">
    <text>How should I know? It's a top secret operation. Who will tell me anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_8">
    <text>Well, if you don't know, then I don't need you.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_9">
    <text>Stop... stop, I really don't know what documents, but I remember that one of their main ones, a colonel, seems, who was "in the know", blabbed. We drank a lot, I remember, so his tongue loosened a bit. Spoke about that in this laboratory research on prisoners was conducted. Something there with impact on brains. Don't know, I don't understand a damn thing in this. Remember, that colonel also said that one should go to X-16, there is some installation or something like that. There should be some important documents there. Only how to get there? Two groups already disappeared. Helicopter is practically impossible to land there. All pilots say, as soon as you start approaching the laboratory territory, the helm fights out of hands, helicopter starts steering by itself as if. Some devilry.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_10">
    <text>Is that all?</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_11">
    <text>Swear, that's all. Don't know anything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_12">
    <text>How I want to whack you... Well okay, live. But if you twitch - don't blame me. I'll shoot.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Barman.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Well what about Yarofeev?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>Learned from Yarofeev that in laboratory X-18 some research on convicts was conducted. And there is also laboratory X-16, where some installation is. So, he says that there should be some important documents or something else there. But only getting there isn't simple. Some devilry is happening there.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_3">
    <text>I heard about this laboratory. Truly a dangerous place. Alright, will need to ponder what to do next, consult with someone. And you go to Deep Station territory meanwhile, find Sidorovich there in the village in the north-east and pass him an encrypted letter from me. And at the same time ask him about Mahomet. Here, hold the letter and pass to Peacekeepers. Show to the sentry, they should let you through. Peacekeepers are not soldiers, they think first, then shoot. But still be careful with them. Say that you work as a guide for the military at the Cordon. Don't worry about the pass, real one. Well, almost real. No one will dig under.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_4">
    <text>Clear. Give the letter and pass, and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_0">
    <text>Hello, Barman.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_1">
    <text>Well, how is the success?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_2">
    <text>Took your letter to Sidorovich. He, in turn, passes you an answer. Here, hold. Learned from him about Mahomet too. Well, where he can be found. For this I need to get to Yantar to scientists first. So, the hike was very useful. True, had to shoot and run there too, but I'm already used to this. Alright, what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_3">
    <text>Wait. Checking what Sidor writes there... So-so, interesting proposal. Alright, will need to think...</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_4">
    <text>Something important there?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_5">
    <text>Yes, quite important affairs are emerging. But can't reveal the secret to you yet. Need to think everything over thoroughly and agree with someone before making a final decision. Alright, that's for later. And now to urgent matters. Regarding laboratory X-16 Yarofeev spoke about: you will need to go to this laboratory at Yantar and find something: documents, computer, laptop, in short, any thing that will help us understand what was happening there. Especially since for you, as I understand, it is on the way with your search for brother. \n\nYou, if you find anything, carry to Fang, he will wait for you at Army Warehouses, at the Farm, near Freedom base. Getting into X-16 will be uneasy. They say that in the laboratory itself there is a certain installation that burns out brains of everything living. Need to ask around scientists at Yantar, perhaps, they will be able to help penetrate the laboratory. Talk to Sakharov. The road to Yantar lies through "Rostock". How to get there, ask Count, especially since he asked you to drop by on a very important matter. Think you know where to look for him. Especially since it's on the way. While you sort this question out, I'll ponder here about our business with Sidorovich. Your help will be needed later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_about_lab_6">
    <text>Understood everything. Moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Greetings, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_1">
    <text>O-oh, Strelok! Come in, I am always glad to see you. How are your affairs? Found brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_2">
    <text>No. Not found yet, unfortunately. I have a slightly different matter for you. I need to pass into laboratory X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_3">
    <text>They say that a certain psi-installation works there, which destroys the brain of any living human. Don't even know how to help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_4">
    <text>Doctor, look. I have a helmet, perhaps something can be done with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_5">
    <text>Let me have a look. So, done quite not badly. Your helmet should screen radiation coming from the installation. But, apparently, still protection from your helmet is insufficient. You know, I thought here: if your helmet is retuned a little, then, perhaps, you will be able to pass into the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_6">
    <text>Professor, how is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_7">
    <text>But, alas, I cannot do this myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_8">
    <text>And who can?</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_9">
    <text>There is one person. We worked together once, but then... then something terrible started happening to him: He started screaming at nights, then suddenly fell silent and could sit looking at one point for whole days. Then even worse: He started throwing himself at people. We... I had to part with him. Apparently, he was covered by a radiation wave from the laboratory. Hand didn't rise to kill him. Dan and the guys took him to Radar to Sviblov, but they say he escaped. So you need to find him. He once long ago dealt exactly with the influence of psi-installation radiation on human brain and kept a diary. In this diary there is a lot of valuable stuff. And if one could acquire this diary, then I could retune your helmet.</text>
</string>
<string id="saharov_about_lab_10">
    <text>Understood. I'll go talk to Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Sviblov, hi.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_1">
    <text>O-oh, Strelok! What brought you to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_2">
    <text>Sakharov sent me to you. I am looking for the crazy professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_3">
    <text>This lunatic escaped at night, gnawed through ropes with teeth and escaped. Look, even wounded Kolka. As he goes on a rampage, hell you'll stop him. For me, he should have been shot long ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_4">
    <text>And where should I look for him now?</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_5">
    <text>Well, most likely in the laboratory. But does it make sense to look for him? He is violent. Need sleeping pills, otherwise he will simply throw himself at you. Got hold of a machine gun somewhere, the freak, and shoots at everything that moves.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_6">
    <text>Where will I get sleeping pills?</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_7">
    <text>Well, go to Kruglov, he will give you sleeping pills. Ask for a pistol at the same time. He has such a special pistol, shoots tranquilizers.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Greetings, science. I have a request for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_1">
    <text>What request?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_2">
    <text>They say you have a pistol that shoots tranquilizers. I need it. Help out. Give it to me for a couple of days.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_3">
    <text>I can give, but not for free, You understand yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_4">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_5">
    <text>Here I gathered some valuable materials on monsters for Duty. And there is no one to carry.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_6">
    <text>Painfully far to walk.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_7">
    <text>Carry it, and besides the pistol I will give you one transmutation recipe. Very rare. Yes, and another request: go through "Rostock". Some gang of thugs appeared there. Need to deal with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_about_lab_8">
    <text>Alright, nowhere to go. I'll go, deal with the thugs.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_lab_0">
    <text>Greetings, General.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_lab_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, come in! What did you come with?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_lab_2">
    <text>Well here. Kruglov passed a case to you here.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_lab_3">
    <text>Finally! Or I already started to worry. Now we will at least approximately know what the situation with monsters is. Hope this will help us. Well okay. Stop by Petrenko, he was looking for you for some reason.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_0">
    <text>Hello, colonel. You have business with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_1">
    <text>Yes, there is one little business. According to rumors, freedomers modified RG-6 for NATO Round M-209.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_2">
    <text>And what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_3">
    <text>Everything is very simple: Acquire one specimen for us.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_4">
    <text>Alright, colonel, I'll try.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_0">
    <text>Halt.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_1">
    <text>Serviceman, have business.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_2">
    <text>I am ordered not to let anyone through.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_3">
    <text>And if really needed?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_4">
    <text>I don't take bribes.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_5">
    <text>I mean, maybe vodka?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_6">
    <text>What the hell do I need your vodka for, we have heaps of our own.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_7">
    <text>Maybe some weapon or medkits?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_8">
    <text>I have everything... Here, maybe... puff something good, but where to get?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_9">
    <text>Seems I can help you. Well, agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_10">
    <text>Alright, bring weed, we'll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_0">
    <text>Greetings, Knyaz. Have business for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_1">
    <text>And don't you cough either! What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_2">
    <text>Need weed, you understand yourself, not parsley.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_3">
    <text>E-e-eh, bro, sorry, but don't have, sold what was, and new will be brought in a week.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_4">
    <text>Come on, Knyaz, really won't find even a little for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_5">
    <text>Well, there is a little, but you understand yourself...</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_6">
    <text>What do you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_7">
    <text>Strelok, my pal has a birthday soon here, want to gift a decent gun. Abakan with integrated collimator. He wanted such for a long time. Woah, remembered! Called "Assault Abakan", for real!</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_8">
    <text>Labs, I'll search a gun for you, just don't give the weed to anyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_0">
    <text>Hello Knyaz, here, hold, dug up "Assault Abakan" for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_1">
    <text>Respected! Pleased, for real, damn! The boy will be happy. Wanted such for a long time. Well, thank you!</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_2">
    <text>Well, didn't sell the weed?</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_3">
    <text>You offend, boss! Everything is right, here is your weed. Put it in packaging, so it won't get wet. And also. Here is a present from me. Take, Knyaz doesn't keep junk!</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_0">
    <text>Greetings.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_1">
    <text>Hello, got the weed, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_2">
    <text>Good job. In short, I am stepping away now and pretending I see nothing. Come on, you have three minutes for everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_0">
    <text>Hello, colonel.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_1">
    <text>Come in, what did you bring?</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_2">
    <text>Well here, as promised, brought modified RG-6.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_3">
    <text>Worked well, respect, and here is your reward - record one transmutation recipe and also: here, personally from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_0">
    <text>Well, fulfilled your request.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_1">
    <text>Thank you, helped out.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_2">
    <text>Alright, Kruglov, I am in a hurry. Give what promised, and I'll go. Many things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_3">
    <text>Here, hold the special colt and extra clip with tranquilizer. Is this for the crazy professor?</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_4">
    <text>For him the darling.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_5">
    <text>Well, then here is advice for you: as you see him, shoot him immediately, otherwise they say, he is rabid. If you hesitate, he will start firing at you. With this pistol you won't harm him, but if you hit, you will be able to talk to him. He will calm down for a while. Think you'll have enough time to talk. And also: need to hit the madman only once, and if more, then he can get even more enraged, and then definitely calm him down with nothing. Such is the peculiarity. And don't forget to bring the pistol back.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor... Professor, wake up!</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_1">
    <text>I am listening... I am listening, I hear them. Do you hear them?</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_2">
    <text>Whom?</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_3">
    <text>Voices, they... they are calling me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I hear nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_5">
    <text>Mumble-mumble.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_6">
    <text>Professor. I need your diary.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_7">
    <text>Listen... they sing... so beautifully...</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes, yes, very beautifully. But listen to me at least a little.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_9">
    <text>Diary?</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, yes! Voices asked you to give me your diary.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_11">
    <text>Voices... painful... and... beautiful.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_12">
    <text>They ask you to give the diary. And then it will always be beautiful and won't be painful.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_13">
    <text>Won't be painful, don't want... head.. very-very painful...</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_14">
    <text>Believe me, everything will be fine. Give me the diary. After all you have it?</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_15">
    <text>Alright... alright (gives diary). Won't be painful... they call... I will be happy... mumble-mumble.</text>
</string>
<string id="mad_professor_dialog_16">
    <text>God forbid such thing with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor! Finally got to you!</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Did you acquire the diary?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes. Here it is, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_3">
    <text>So-o. Very good. Let's look... uh-huh... understood. Give your helmet... so... he-ere. That's it. Now I think, it will protect you from psi-radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_4">
    <text>I hope so too. God forbid becoming same as your professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_5">
    <text>Well then, Strelok. Hope you will succeed. May God keep you. Well, or whoever you believe in.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well here we met.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you, mercenaries, bastards, pressed hard.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on. Today I help you, tomorrow you help me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Did you bring documents from laboratory X-16?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_4">
    <text>There were no documents. Here is a laptop.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's look. Uh-huh... so... Know what turns out? They conducted experiments on people in laboratory X-18, and then used obtained results in X-16, tuned their psi-installation.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_0">
    <text>Well and what should we do?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_1">
    <text>We still don't know who stands behind all this. But we learned that there is a group of people that produced terrible experiments on humans. That there is a certain installation in X-16. By the way, I think, it is not the only one. Surely there is more. Here is the thing: Need to visit laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_2">
    <text>Why? Soldiers were already there. Unlikely they left anything for us.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_3">
    <text>In laptop there are relatively fresh records. There are even month old ones. Understand what I mean? Means someone was there quite recently.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_4">
    <text>Alright, I'll go. Maybe, find something interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Fang.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well what, was in the laboratory?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Was. And strange as it is, they were waiting for me there.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Who?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Monolithians.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I somehow thought so, that they are involved here somehow. Strelok, situation is heating up! Such a feeling that Monolith planned something. Diggers transmitted that they saw a group of Monolithians at Radar. Your meeting with them in the laboratory... Something very serious is brewing here, plus these mercenaries... In short, Strelok, Ghost is waiting for you. We need, before it's too late, to figure all this out.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Back to Pripyat? No, I won't go.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_7">
    <text>But why?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I barely left from there. No, screw it, this Pripyat and CNPP taken together! As you wish, but I pass...</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_9">
    <text>Damn... Didn't expect from you, Strelok. Well okay. Will you fulfill one more request? Not hard.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_10">
    <text>What is needed?</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Here is unsafe. Carry to Barman this flash drive that you brought, and laptop from X-16. Let them lie at his place for the time being. This is all I ask, go. Yes and Barman has new information for you. And I meanwhile will occupy myself with your question. Then come by, we'll decide how to be.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_12">
    <text>Alright, Fang. I'll carry laptop and flash drive to Barman.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Barman. Parcel for you here from Fang.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_1">
    <text>What parcel?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_2">
    <text>Flash drive and laptop from laboratories.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_3">
    <text>Eh, d-damn... well... Well okay, give here. And what, no other place was found?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_4">
    <text>Fang asked me. Unsafe to store at Warehouses. There was already an attempt on him anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_0">
    <text>What wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_1">
    <text>There is work not dusty, walk a foreigner a bit around Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_2">
    <text>Screw these tourists. Will step in something again. What are they thinking about generally, is here what, culture and recreation park?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_3">
    <text>Come on, work is not dusty, pay well. You don't walk far with him. Lead to the destroyed bridge, well maybe a bit further, and back. He first asked to Garbage, but I told him immediately that no one will go with him to Garbage, too dangerous, primarily for him. Yes he will be glad even to this.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_4">
    <text>Where is your tourist?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_5">
    <text>He waits for you in the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_6">
    <text>Well okay, I'll work as a guide a bit, hope he is not a complete cretin.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, is it you looking for guide?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I... I want watch monsters, how is it "bloodsucker", "chimera".</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Bloodsucker, chimera... hmm... feel have to tinker. Well, let's go or what.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Why stopped?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Hard. Now, let breathe. And where bloodsucker? Want see living bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well you persistent, okay let's go over bridge, there, think, will see not only bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, saw everyone wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Not quite, maybe to Garbage?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>To Garbage go yourself. I won't lead you there. Too dangerous, primarily for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>Pity, very pity, well okay, then to camp return.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_4">
    <text>Long time ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_0">
    <text>Well, Sidor, job done.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_1">
    <text>I counted on you, that won't fail.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_2">
    <text>Okay, give payment and I'll go.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_3">
    <text>Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_0">
    <text>What else happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_1">
    <text>Doctor and his friends have problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_2">
    <text>What problems?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_3">
    <text>Monolith announced hunt on them, yes and mercenaries also don't give rest. In short, they need help.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_4">
    <text>Here we go again! I thought, engage, finally, in my own affairs.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_5">
    <text>Turns out not good. They helped you after all. Besides problem needs solving, can't run from it. Monolith planned something serious. Fear, lest the end comes to us all. In short, need to go to Pripyat, rescue Feldsher and Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_6">
    <text>Well okay, it's on my way. I also planned to move closer to CNPP. Found out something about my brother. Need to find someone... Damn! Only how will I get to Pripyat? Through Radar? So full of mercenaries there.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_7">
    <text>Talk to Doctor, he will help you. Yes, and also Fang asked you to stop by. Something important he has for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidr_about_doctor_8">
    <text>Alright, I went. Will stop by Fang on the way. See you!</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_give_perehod_0">
    <text>Hello, Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_give_perehod_1">
    <text>Good that came, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_give_perehod_2">
    <text>Your friends in danger. To help them, I must get to Pripyat. Especially since I myself need there too. I am going to CNPP. Seems, I found a lead that can clarify what happened to my brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_give_perehod_3">
    <text>Yes, serious matters twisting now. And path will show, give your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_give_perehod_4">
    <text>Understood everything, hope see you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Feldsher. Long time no see!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes... Can't cheat fate.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you want to say by this?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_3">
    <text>However you try to run from what is destined to you, you won't run away. You must fulfill your mission.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_4">
    <text>What mission? What about?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_5">
    <text>Strelok, you need to go to Control Bunker once again. Apparently, in such short term something very not good happened for all of us, and you need to find some opportunity to prevent threat. Concrete information about what exactly those insane scientists plan in Bunker, no. Therefore have to act according to situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright. But what are my chances?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_7">
    <text>Won't lie, chances little, but you are the only one who can cope with this task. Most likely, you will have to encounter in Bunker some new kind of psi-influence, judging by specifics of experiments scientists plan there. Therefore necessary at least somehow secure yourself from possible danger. There is one very strong preparation. Called "Adulin". This is powerful biochemical mean, protecting human psyche for long time from various psi-influences and psi-attacks. Protection of this preparation is much higher than psi-helmet can give.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_8">
    <text>So and where to take this preparation?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_9">
    <text>Here not far, in very center of Pripyat, somewhere on Lenin square is a stash, and in it backpack with injectors of "Adulin", which lie in special refrigerator container. This is Monolithians' stash. Solomon told me about it. Bring me this backpack, and I will make you injection that will protect your mind from possible psi-influence or any other interference in your psyche, in Bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_final_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright. Going search backpack with "Adulin" in stash on square.</text>
</string>
<string id="rukzak_dialog_0">
    <text>Here, Feldsher. Found backpack with "Adulin" on square.</text>
</string>
<string id="rukzak_dialog_1">
    <text>So, good. Give it here.</text>
</string>
<string id="rukzak_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_0">
    <text>So... And what next?</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_1">
    <text>I will make you injection of "Adulin" now.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_2">
    <text>Hope it's not painful.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_3">
    <text>No, Strelok, it's not painful. But after injection some time you will feel a bit sick. But it will pass quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_4">
    <text>Eh... How want to take and send you all to such mother.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_5">
    <text>I understand you, but such is fate... Your fate. And also: while you were absent, we with Doctor prepared gift for you - disposable "Teleportator". It can be very useful to you when no other exit will be. Only remember: after activation teleportation will happen from that point where person holding "Teleportator" in hand is located, to Swamps to Doctor. Teleportation possible only once and for one person. And be careful: here, in Pripyat, mercenaries already arranged one roundup on me. But nothing, left them. Had to move from stadium here... Surely they hang around somewhere nearby now too. Watch out! Well here, seems said everything wanted. Now prepare arm for injection.</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_dialog_6">
    <text>Here is arm, inject faster. And for teleportator thanks. Surely will come in handy. Well and farewell, just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Do I have a choice?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_final_dialog_1">
    <text>No. We need you. Beside, you know too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_final_dialog_2">
    <text>And what do you intend to do with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_0">
    <text>Have anything for sale? %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_1">
    <text>Have weapons, ammo and simple medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_2">
    <text>What weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_3">
    <text>What ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_4">
    <text>How much medkits?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_21">
    <text>Propose following:\n
	- SMG PP-19 "Bizon" for 40 blind dog tails,\n
	- MP-153 for 30 pseudodog tails,\n
	- TOZ-66 for 25 bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_31">
    <text>There are simple ammo for Kalash - 3 packs for 6 chimera claws and there is buckshot - 3 packs for 6 boar hooves.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_41">
    <text>Medkits 2 pieces for 6 flesh eyes.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_211">
    <text>Give Bizon, I like it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_214">
    <text>Yes, Barman, being greedy is good, but in moderation.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_212">
    <text>Where is MP-153? My favorite weapon, taking.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_213">
    <text>TOZ - is a thing, taking.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_311">
    <text>Ammo for Kalash? Give, I just have many claws with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_312">
    <text>Buckshot? Need, give.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_313">
    <text>At such prices! Shoot yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_change_411">
    <text>Well, give medkits perhaps, going deep into zone, you never know.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_0">
    <text>What wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_1">
    <text>I doing small business here.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_2">
    <text>What business?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_3">
    <text>Change monster parts, but not all.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_4">
    <text>Which exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_5">
    <text>Tushkano head - 10 pieces for 3 packs NATO ammo,\n
Zombie hand - 10 pieces for 3 packs NATO armor-piercing ammo,\n
Pseudogiant paw - 5 pieces for 3 packs sniper ammo to SVD,\n
Controller hand - 5 pieces for 5 army medkits, plus five antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_predlag_6">
    <text>Alright, if have - will bring.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_0">
    <text>Hello, Mazay. Here, brought something. %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_1">
    <text>What have? Note, accept by fixed rate:\n
Tushkano head - 10 pieces for 3 packs NATO ammo,\n
Zombie hand - 10 pieces for 3 packs NATO armor-piercing ammo,\n
Pseudogiant paw - 5 pieces for 3 packs sniper ammo to SVD,\n
Controller hand - 5 pieces for 5 army medkits plus 5 antirads.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_2">
    <text>I have 10 tushkano heads.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_3">
    <text>I have 10 zombie hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_4">
    <text>I have 5 pseudogiant paws.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_5">
    <text>I have 5 controller hands.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_change_6">
    <text>Sorry, I mistaken.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_0">
    <text>What for sale have? %c[orange][Barter]</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_1">
    <text>Weapons, ammo and army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_2">
    <text>What weapons?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_3">
    <text>What ammo?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_4">
    <text>How much army medkits?</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_21">
    <text>Have this:\n
        - SIG 552 for 1 "Cobblestone" artifact,\n
        - SIG 550 for 1 "Fire Tears" artifact,\n
        - Kalashnikov Machinegun for 1 "Symbion" artifact,\n
        - M4A1 for 1 "Ruby Spring" artifact,\n
        - Steyr AUG A1 for 1 "Gold Chunk" artifact,\n
        - Desert Tech MDR for 1 "Soul Drops" artifact.\n</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_211">
    <text>Give SIG 552</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_212">
    <text>Give SIG 550</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_213">
    <text>Give Machinegun</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_214">
    <text>Give M4A1</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_215">
    <text>Give Steyr AUG A1</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_216">
    <text>Give MDR</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_217">
    <text>Nah, at such prices, screw it, I better walk with Kalash.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_31">
    <text>Have this:\n
	- 3 packs "5.56x45mm AP" for 2 "Droplet" artifacts,\n
	- 3 packs "5.56x45mm SS109" for 2 "Stone Blood" artifacts,\n
	- 3 "F-1 Grenade" for 2 "Sparkler" artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_311">
    <text>Give armor-piercing.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_312">
    <text>Give simple ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_313">
    <text>Give grenades.</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_41">
    <text>Army medkits, 2 pieces - for 3 "Slime" artifacts</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_change_411">
    <text>Give army medkits.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_detector_0">
    <text>Hi, Lefty.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_detector_1">
    <text>Don't cough either. Long time no see.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_detector_2">
    <text>Business to you available. Have detector one unusual. Found it at one monolithian. Look. Maybe, possible to repair it?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_detector_3">
    <text>Well, let look. O-o-o. This is very good detector! If tune it, then it will display practically all anomalies. So... so, in principle possible to do, but need to re-tune it. And for this need artifacts of those anomalies, which we want, that it showed. In short, need 6 artifacts: \n1)"Mica"; \n2)"Crystal"; \n3)"Goldfish"; \n4)"Soul"; \n5)"Ruby Spring"; \n6)"Flash".</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_detector_4">
    <text>Damn! Where will I get so many good artifacts? Well okay, going search.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_0">
    <text>Hi Lefty.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_1">
    <text>Hello, brother. Found arts?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_2">
    <text>Ran half zone. Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_3">
    <text>Alright, wait a bit. Now little more... so... Here is all. Hold, like new. Now should recognize anomalies... almost all. Well, at least, most dangerous, that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi. What wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, head splitting. Don't you have anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, have a little.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait, will bring now.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, let's, splash?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Let's. Well so what business do you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Went well. Let's another one?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_3">
    <text>In short, have transmutation recipe. Very valuable.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_4">
    <text>What recipe?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, this... Let's another one?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Alright, let's... Well so what recipe?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_7">
    <text>"Stone Porcupine" transmutation recipe. Rare, I tell you, artifact! If I had one such... Eh...</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_8">
    <text>What want for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_9">
    <text>You know, I have health problems lately. Liver to hell. Knowing people advised to hang on belt two specimens of one rare artifact. Called "Gold Chunk". But two such artifacts I don't have.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, brother. If find, will bring. You only don't forget about recipe. And stop booze, won't end good!</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_0">
    <text>Hi, I came for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_1">
    <text>What wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_2">
    <text>What you, old man, forgot or what? About recipe I am.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_3">
    <text>Damn, memory became leaky! Well what, acquired arts?</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_4">
    <text>Yeah. Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_art_est_5">
    <text>Well, helped out, thank you! Will heal now. Well, and will drop transmutation recipe to you. Give your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, bro.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_1">
    <text>What wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_2">
    <text>Job is one, not dusty.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_3">
    <text>What job?</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_4">
    <text>In short, one fraer is, called Noodle. So this bitch killed my pal. M-mother! If knew, where he... With these hands would little bastard...</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_5">
    <text>What required from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_6">
    <text>In short, need find this nit and kill. And I for this will drop you one transmutation recipe, "Giant's Little Brother". Just in case say: one guy came here recently. Said, that saw this bespectacled bastard at Garbage not far from transition to Dark Valley. Try search him there. Only hurry, otherwise he might bolt somewhere.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_dialog_7">
    <text>Labs, try find your Noodle.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_0">
    <text>What have you done?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_1">
    <text>About what you?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_2">
    <text>And you, like, don't guess? Ordered you!</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_3">
    <text>Who? For what?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_4">
    <text>And this better you know...</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_5">
    <text>Ah, that one... You understand, we here with one man, I was little familiar with him, went for artifacts. Well, found little. On return way found stalker corpse. Well, you understand yourself, looted, this and that, found transmutation recipe one, artifacts several. Good, I tell you, artifacts. \n\nWas getting dark. We arranged lodging. He, my partner, stayed on guard, and I lay near fire. Woke up from that someone chokes me. That bitch! Spared bullets, or maybe didn't want noise, understand yourself, monsters-shmonsters. And I have knife in bootleg, big such, hunting. Well, I somehow reached it and, in short, stabbed man to death. And here his pals, apparently, try avenge me for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_6">
    <text>Lying, probably?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_7">
    <text>Believe, so it was! Listen, he, this Hmyr, what promised you for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_8">
    <text>"Giant's Little Brother" transmutation recipe.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_9">
    <text>That b-bitch! How he knew about it? Well okay... Let's so. I give you "Giant's Little Brother" transmutation recipe and on top, so to speak, thing one. Rare gun: revolver "Taurus Raging Bull". Thing very rare and valuable. Very powerful gun. True ammo to it hard find will be. So here, give you one more pack spare. Sorry, no more. And so, if gun likes, then ammo to it at Antiquarian can acquire. He trades various rare weapons. It's from him I bought revolver... For expensive! In Bar search Antiquarian, he visits there often. Ask around Borov, he suggests, where find him.</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_10">
    <text>Screw you!</text>
</string>
<string id="atp_barman_dialog_11">
    <text>Alright, persuaded. Give recipe and revolver. And Antiquarian I will find anyway. Love rare "toys".</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_est_0">
    <text>Well what? How there business our?</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_est_1">
    <text>Yes all. Kicked bucket your Noodle.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_est_2">
    <text>Lad said - lad did. Respect.</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_est_3">
    <text>How there about recipe?</text>
</string>
<string id="band_kill_est_4">
    <text>Give your PDA, upload recipe. With you joke dangerous, pal!</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Borov, is work?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Strelok, such matter. To me here man should have come with important information.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_2">
    <text>Well, and?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_3">
    <text>And what and! Not him, already second day, as should have appeared.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_4">
    <text>Well at least something known?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_5">
    <text>Yes really nothing. Only clue, that last message from him from Dark Valley came. Probably, Dutyers tied him or lawless-marauders, who often hang around there. Here what, go to Voronin, he seems there with his cop gang controls Valley. Maybe, manage clarify something. Only, certainly, don't need say, by whose request you came. Understand yourself, we have with Duty some ideological divergences.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_kogot_6">
    <text>Alright. Try carefully find out everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Greetings, general.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok. What brought you to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_kogot_2">
    <text>One person sent me. Says, that his courier disappeared. At you, in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_kogot_3">
    <text>About courier know nothing. And not whole Valley we control. At factory generally hell what happens. Although... Here recently appeared gang of bastards, exactly on territory of abandoned factory. So, I sent guys mine there check. And neither hearing nor spirit from them. Go, look, maybe find out something.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Hello. Not you Borov searches?</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Yeah, me. Thank you, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_2">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_3">
    <text>Yes devil pulled me shorten path little. Thought, from Radar through Dark Valley, and there to Bar not far. Aha, shortened... Here two days as here sit.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_4">
    <text>And why didn't they kill you?</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_5">
    <text>And I told them, that Borov for me ransom give. Knew, that won't give, but time pull wanted.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_6">
    <text>Understood. Alright, let's to business. Information, that you carried Borov, where it?</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_7">
    <text>Yes they cleaned me under zero! So that I don't have it.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_8">
    <text>That shit! Where will I search it?</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_9">
    <text>Don't worry. I overheard little bandits talk. They wanted whack me anyway. They have stash somewhere in laboratory X-18. Not in laboratory itself, but in that its part, that on top.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_kogot_10">
    <text>Well okay, thanks on this too. Go search PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_podarok_0">
    <text>Hello. See alive reached Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_podarok_1">
    <text>Yeah, on way looked in my stash and took present for you. Thanks, that pulled me out from that mess!</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_podarok_2">
    <text>Presents I love. Show what there you have.</text>
</string>
<string id="kogot_about_podarok_3">
    <text>This artifact "Chimera Tears". Not bad protects from various brain-breakers. Hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_0">
    <text>Well what, Borov. Seems all, swam away PDA. Exploded so, that whole stash to devil mother.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_1">
    <text>Now have again go to Pripyat to Ghost, it he me information obtained and passed through courier, and I already paid him advance. In short, have ask Ghost, so gave copy information, if, of course, he has copy...</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_2">
    <text>Is one more but!</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_3">
    <text>What but?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_4">
    <text>Road to Pripyat no... How get there?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_5">
    <text>Oh you devil... Here what, Strelok, is exit one.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_6">
    <text>Which?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_7">
    <text>Say, recently Freedomers either to Pripyat itself, or to Radar went... But, rumored, that they definitely found passage to Pripyat. And what if talk to Lukash?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_about_pda_8">
    <text>Alright, try with him talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_0">
    <text>Greetings to you!</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok. Something long you not stopped by.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_2">
    <text>Yes all no time was. Listen, I on business.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_3">
    <text>What business you have?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_4">
    <text>Say, you found road to Pripyat?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_5">
    <text>Who told you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_6">
    <text>Come on you. Not all same? I desperately to Pripyat need.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_7">
    <text>Well, is sort of path one. Information although not 100%, but, likely, accurate. Ours, when on Radar were, accidentally discovered.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_8">
    <text>Well so what? Help?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_9">
    <text>Listen, let's so: Service for service.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_10">
    <text>What want?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_11">
    <text>On Radar, in forest recently helicopter crashed. Well so, on it scientists something transported. This something in container metal. I sent guys there, but they found nothing. Find me this container, and I help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_12">
    <text>Understood. You need iron container, which must locate not far from crashed helicopter?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_box_13">
    <text>Yes. Forgot warn, container radioactive, so don't forget with self grab antirads more. And if exist arts, removing radiation, then you on belt them hang.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_0">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_1">
    <text>Well what, found container?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_2">
    <text>Yeah, here it. Take faster, painfully radiates from it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_3">
    <text>Here well done. And mine... only vodka guzzle, yes fables at fire tell. Idiots!</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_4">
    <text>Alright, Lukash. What there with request mine?</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_est_box_5">
    <text>Ah yes. Helped out you me great. Give PDA, mark road to Pripyat.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_0">
    <text>Hello. Here and met.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok, come in. On business, suppose?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_2">
    <text>On business, how without it. You to Borov through courier information some passed?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_3">
    <text>Well, was, and what? You, probably, surprises, that I with bandits contacted? Borov although bastard rare, but pays well. And us then desperately money needed were. Here and got involved we with Fang in this scam. Obtained needed information and passed it through courier.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_4">
    <text>Understood. But here such matter: trouble happened. Courier that marauders... No, he alive, but PDA lost.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_5">
    <text>Here devil. That information in single copy was... although... although wait, remembered. Fang seems made copy. Only preserved whether it at him?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_6">
    <text>You assume, that at Fang must be copy?</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_7">
    <text>Yes, likely, he man meticulous, loves reinsure. So that now you only Fang help.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_8">
    <text>Well so, remains one - go to Fang. Alright, bye. Maybe, still see.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Fang.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, hope, at least you me gladden.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_3">
    <text>Try. And what wanted?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_4">
    <text>Listen, long explain, but PDA, which through courier Ghost passed Borov, lost. Ghost said, that, possibly, at you exist copy data.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_5">
    <text>Can you gladden! Yes, at me exist copy.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_6">
    <text>Glory god! Well so where it?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_7">
    <text>PDA here not far, in village bloodsuckers. There house exist from corner, in it cellar. I this cellar usually pallet close. From people, of course, won't save, well so people there and not walk. And radiates decently. But instead beasts accidentally won't fall. True, exist one problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_8">
    <text>What problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_9">
    <text>Since recent times in this house either anomaly appeared, or what. But get into my stash I can't. Me as if throws out from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_10">
    <text>Alright, various miracles - this on my part. Will sort out.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello. Sit by fire, chat.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_2">
    <text>I ask you wanted: You not in course, what anomaly over there in that house? Try pass, and me pushes out from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_3">
    <text>Radiates in which? You this, come night, all explain.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_4">
    <text>And why night?</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_5">
    <text>Come, all explain... Yes, sweet something with self grab. Love I sweets.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_6">
    <text>Chocolate fit?</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_day_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, carry it.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_0">
    <text>Well what, brought I you chocolate.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_1">
    <text>Here thanks!</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, come on, tell.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_3">
    <text>Here what I you tell: with recent times settled in village family poltergeists. Night they on walk, so speak, go out, and day in this house sleep off. How already they so do, I don't know, but and day while rest, and night as if force field around self put. And pass in this house decisively impossible. Well, now understood, why night?</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, sort of understood. Meaning day, while they in house, to them not reach?</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_night_dialog_5">
    <text>Correct think. Until them all not kill, into house you not get.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Yes indeed. Well and job you me gave. Half zone ran, while PDA searched, and here such surprise!</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_1">
    <text>You found it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, found. Here, hold.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_3">
    <text>This very valuable information, well done! Here, take, you deserved.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_dopr0">
    <text>Well what, Dyak, silent our little bastard?</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_dopr1">
    <text>Silent, dog. Have to shoot.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_dopr2">
    <text>Wait, brother. His worthless life still needed Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_dopr3">
    <text>Alright, I'll wait. But then, allow me to shoot this infidel.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_dopr4">
    <text>On everything will Monolith. And mysterious paths, which opens he us.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_ded0">
    <text>I finished, brother. His life no more needed Monolith. I think, you know, what need further do.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_ded1">
    <text>Don't doubt, I all do.</text>
</string>
<string id="spy_ded2">
    <text>I and not doubt, Dyak. Do, what must do. And me time, Charon waits.</text>
</string>