<string id="totalizator_0">
    <text>Hello, Bookmaker. I'd like to place a bet, want to raise some dough.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_1">
    <text>Well, good business, just note: here it's either make or break - since you can bet 50 grand, but win only 500 rubles. And then, either pay - hustle however you want, and if you can't - into debt slavery... Or one day they'll find someone's corpse in the swamp... That's how it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_2">
    <text>Yeah, a bit harsh... However, gambling is such a thing. So what?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_3">
    <text>Are you asking me? Want to risk - risk, your right. So, the choice is yours, Stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_4">
    <text>Alright, what are the conditions?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_5">
    <text>The bet is taken and is non-refundable. You will be informed about the win or loss... You can also play on credit, but hefty interest will accrue on the debt amount. Every 12 hours. So the choice is yours: to play or not to play. By the way, in case of winning - you can leave the money with me: I'll give a good percentage.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_6">
    <text>Alright, I agree. What are the bets?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_7">
    <text>Bets change constantly, like the wind from Pripyat. Even I sometimes don't know which one will be today. Right now here is such a bet.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_8">
    <text>Bet is one thousand. We bet on whether another rookie stalker will get out of the anomaly trap at the Swamps or not, where he fell yesterday while drunk.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_9">
    <text>Bet is 5 thousand. We bet on whether another loser will manage to return the debt to Timon Bonesetter before the designated deadline or not.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_10">
    <text>Bet is 10 thousand. We bet on who of these two rookie idiots will first find and bring the "Stone Flower" for Gera of Tula.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_11">
    <text>Bet is 15 thousand. We bet on who of these two regular upstarts will first get to the stash of the deceased Badger at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_12">
    <text>Bet is 20 thousand. We bet on who of two rookies will win in the nearest knife sparring. Go to the Cordon, maybe you'll make it to this fight. Although, the spectacle is so-so - two regular juvenile morons decided to play heroes.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_13">
    <text>Bet is 25 thousand. We bet on luck or failure: two regular idiots decided to bolt from the Zone and went to the Checkpoint, to bow to the military. As for me, that's two new corpses, but you decide yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_14">
    <text>Bet is 30 thousand. We bet on another "braggart". He promised to bring Wolf the head of a chimera. I think he'll crap himself at the mere sight of it. Although... Who knows, they say he handles a knife not badly.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_15">
    <text>Bet is 35 thousand. We bet on interest: egghead scientists sent their regular courier to the Dead City with a parcel for the Wanderers. Many think he won't make it, but the choice is yours. Who knows, maybe they tamed a mutant and dressed it in a spacesuit. And now he runs errands for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_16">
    <text>Bet is 40 thousand. Good bet, large one... We bet on one psycho, who promised Knyaz, against his debt, to scrounge five bottles of whiskey from the Peacekeepers.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_17">
    <text>Bet is 50 thousand. We bet big: one experienced stalker, however, how many of them there were already, promised the Informer to catch and drag in a live bloodsucker. He is either crazy, or a hero like never seen before.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_18">
    <text>I refuse.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_19">
    <text>Well that's it - the bet is made, now wait for the message. Good luck, Stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_20">
    <text>Alright, I'll be going...</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_21">
    <text>Did you fall from an oak tree or what, guy? You owe more than a hundred grand and you are forbidden to make bets. Come on, move your tomatoes out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_22">
    <text>You are mean...</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_0">
    <text>Hello, I came for the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_1">
    <text>Let's see now what is due to you there.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_2">
    <text>Well come on, don't stretch the rubber. Get the dough out.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_3">
    <text>Wait... Now... Let's open the safe first.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_4">
    <text>Take the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_5">
    <text>Leave for storage.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_dolg_0">
    <text>Good day to you. Here, came to pay off the debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_dolg_1">
    <text>Alright - there is no debt on you anymore. You are free.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_0">
    <text>Take the deposit.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_1">
    <text>Choose how much you want to withdraw.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_2">
    <text>Withdraw 10% of the sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_3">
    <text>Withdraw half of the sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_4">
    <text>Withdraw the whole sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_5">
    <text>Well, hold it.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_6">
    <text>Thanks for keeping it well. I'll go relax a little.</text>
</string>