<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Ohhh, what is wrong with me? My head hurts so much... And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm the one who wants to ask you that: who are you, handsome, and where did you come from wearing only a sweater?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I... I don't remember... There was a flash... Then a complete blackout.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_3">
    <text>If you want to live, use your brain and remember quickly. If I think you're lying, I'll shoot you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Wait! Don't shoot! All I remember is that yesterday evening my older brother, his friends, and I went on a bus excursion to see the "Dead City". They told so many interesting things about the Ghost City that we decided to get here ourselves. We wanted some thrills, wanted to play paintball in the ruins with the guys, and we took all the necessary gear with us. There were ten other people with us... In the center of the city, we were supposed to meet a guide-instructor with whom we had agreed in advance by phone. But when we drove through the gates, suddenly something flashed, blinded us and... I don't remember anything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_5">
    <text>What damn excursion, what paintball! Stop feeding me bullshit. This has been a closed territory for a long time, the very center of the Zone: deadly anomalies and crowds of mutants, may they all burn in hell... And the last excursion here was about 3 years ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_6">
    <text>How can that be? I'm telling the truth! We just yesterday... On the bus with my brother and the guys... We paid the driver 2000 hryvnias to take us here along the abandoned road... And where are all the others? What is happening, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Uhhh, buddy, it seems your head is really not okay. The last time tourists were brought here was in 2008. In the autumn, I think. I was moonlighting as a guide here back then. Until that second explosion at the CNPP happened. And then another powerful emission, and everything started... damn it... Three years have passed, but I remember it like it was yesterday. This nightmare...</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_8">
    <text>So what year is it now, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Today is October 5, 2011... Alright, let's stop chatting! I don't know why, but I believed your delirium. Perhaps the Zone really played a "cruel joke" on you, poor fellow. If so, then you got hit right by that same emission, and for some reason, the Zone "spared" you... just like it spared me back then... If only I knew why... Anyway: forget everything you told me, and don't tell anyone else about it. This is the Zone, and there are enough "miracles" here without you... Now let's do this: come with me, you need to get your head straight, and it's too dangerous to stay here for long.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Where are we going? And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I am Forester. A hermit... We'll go to the Red Forest, to my humble abode. It's not far. We need to discuss everything slowly, what is happening here. I have a feeling of some strange deja vu... Okay, questions later. Well, are you ready to go? Just don't lag behind, but don't get ahead of me either. Walk next to me, or better yet, follow in my footsteps so you don't step into anything. The main thing now is to get out of this godforsaken place into the Forest, and from there it's a stone's throw to my humble shelter. Here, I'll give you a flashlight, binoculars, and my old knife. It's better than nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Thank you. Well, it seems I have no other choice... Let's go, I won't lag behind.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Forester, what is dangerous in this city?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Firstly, deadly anomalies. I hope you noticed them while we were walking. Besides that, mutants. They are called pseudodogs. One of the many sinister spawns of the Zone. This place is full of them, especially at night. We were lucky not to meet any of them today. Also, after emissions, zombies appear. Where they come from is unclear, but there are plenty of them here.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>I see. Well, are we there yet?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, behind me are the old gates, that's the transition to the Forest. All right, you go first now, I'll follow you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, I'm going.</text>
</string>


<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_0">
    <text>So this is where you live?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, this is where I while away my days and nights. I go into the Forest, sometimes visit the Dead City. I gather various roots, artifacts, and then trade them with scientists for medicine and food. That's how I live quietly, away from everyone. Well, let's talk about you now. It's extremely strange that I found you in the Dead City. How did you end up there?.. Some kind of mysticism, by God. I visit that place once a week.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I'm telling you, I don't understand how it happened. I told you everything I remember!</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, okay, don't worry so much. Listen to me now. I think you said the last thing you remember is arriving at the Dead City with your older brother and his friends on a bus, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, exactly. And I have no idea what happened to him and the other guys. And I don't understand what happened to me either. And for some reason, the last thing I remember was three years ago...</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't know what happened to the others, but it seems I can tell you something about your brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_6">
    <text>Why did you stay silent the whole way then? I asked you if you knew anything or not!</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_7">
    <text>Don't make noise, too much time has passed since that day. And your story smacks too much of some devilry. Anyway, listen further. Three years ago, as I told you, the second explosion at the CNPP happened, and then there was a powerful emission. Most of those who were within the radius, including in the Dead City, died. I managed to survive by hiding in the basement of a high-rise building. When I came out two days later, I didn't recognize the place where I worked as a guide for tourists and curious people like you. Everything suddenly changed and became... I can't even explain it properly. Well, basically, as if not 2 days passed, but twenty or thirty years...</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_8">
    <text>So what happened next?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_9">
    <text>And then I realized I needed to get out of there urgently. Without special equipment, I wouldn't have survived. The radiation level was quite high. I went out into the city and rushed to the nearest building, where I found you too. I look: aside, on the floor lies a guy and seems to be moving. I go up to him, check his pulse and sure enough - alive! I somehow brought him to his senses, hauled him on myself and rushed to the Forest. That guy looked very much like you. I assume it was your brother. Already here he told me how he ended up where I found him. His story repeats yours, that's why I believed you. He introduced himself as "Captain".</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, that's correct. It was my brother. We invented calling each other that since childhood: he was "Captain", and I was "Strelok". Our childhood nicknames later grew into names that our friends started calling us. Well, so what happened to my brother? Where is he now?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_11">
    <text>He lived with me for about a month, helped settle the dwelling, grieved greatly over the loss of friends and brother... He kept trying to go searching. He was brave, but understood that it was impossible to go to the Dead City then - certain death. Once we gathered and reached almost the exit from the Forest, but heard howling and screams of some monsters and decided not to risk it for now. After the second explosion, the Zone appeared in the form in which it remains to this day: mutated animals and deadly anomalies, artifacts with unprecedented properties and constant emissions, changing and reshaping the Zone after each time stronger and stronger. God forbid you meet the creatures inhabiting closer to the center of the Zone. \n\nAnd your brother left later anyway... Five people came to our dig, called themselves Stalkers, looking for valuable artifacts for sale in the formed Zone. "Captain" left with them, hoping to find you and the other friends. As I see, he didn't succeed... He didn't appear anymore. Only once, six months later, I heard from scientists who came to study the Zone and mutants and set up camp near Lake Yantar, that a group of daredevils went to the Sarcophagus in search of valuable artifacts and to unravel the mystery of the Zone's origin. Among them, apparently, was a stalker nicknamed "Captain". That's all I know about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_12">
    <text>Thank you for what you told me. It means there is still hope to find my brother's trail or him himself. I must find him. Or, at least, find out what happened to him during this time. Maybe he is still looking for me too. If you need help with anything, speak, I'll do everything.</text>
</string>


<string id="vasiliev_dialog_0">
    <text>You look gloomy, father.</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, a problem appeared while you were away.</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_2">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_3">
    <text>A courier from the ecologists was supposed to come to me yesterday, bring medicine and food, and in return take various roots and several artifacts that I collected for the scientists over the last week. But yesterday another sudden emission happened, and I decided that he just didn't leave the camp. I thought he would wait out the emission there and come in a day or two. But turns out, he was already walking to me when the emission started. While you were going for the Mandrake root, he contacted me by radio. True, the reception was bad. From what I heard, I only understood that he hid from the emission in the southern part of the forest. And while he was looking for that shelter, he ran into mutants and barely escaped. Now he is afraid to leave there, and he lost the map of the Forest while running from the beasts. He asks me to come to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, that means we need to go and rescue the man.</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_5">
    <text>We need to go, but my heart seized up even more. Lately, my health is really bad. And the courier was bringing me medicine from the scientists... Listen, son, help an old man out, find this ecologist, help him get here with the medicine and food, and I'll lie down here for a while, maybe the pain will let go. Yes, this courier's name is Docent Vasiliev. I'll put a mark on the map for you. Look for him near the big boulders, beware of anomalies and mutants. And here, take a medkit, bandages, and a couple of packs of buckshot, just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="vasiliev_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood, I'll go find Docent Vasiliev.</text>
</string>

<string id="yantar_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you okay, intact? Didn't expect such bravery from a scientist! You have a dangerous job here.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_dialog_1">
    <text>I seem to be intact. We need to go to our Bunker, rest there. At the same time, you'll meet Professor Sakharov. He is our chief. He will issue you more medicine for Forester, which I couldn't deliver. And you'll meet Dan and his "eagles". That's our security. For helping me, a reward awaits you. I'll put in a good word with Sakharov. And when we get to the Bunker, find Dan immediately, introduce yourself. He is the head of security for the scientific base after all.</text>
</string>
<string id="yantar_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, let's go visit you, for a short while. I'll pick up the medicine for Forester at the same time.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings! You must be Dan - the head of the scientists' base security?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Thank you, Stalker, for helping Vasiliev get out of the Forest and reach here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't mention it. And I'm not a fighter at all. I ended up here by accident. I need to pick up medicine for Forester from Sakharov. Vasiliev said I should come to you first. And I have a question: I must find my brother, or at least find out what happened to him. We lost each other several years ago under very strange circumstances. But that's a long story... Have you by chance met a man who called himself "Captain"? He looks very much like me? Since childhood, many even confused us, although my brother is 2 years older than me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We all ended up here by accident to one degree or another... I haven't met a man looking like you nicknamed "Captain", and we ourselves haven't been here long, about a year. You'd better ask Sakharov - he is the chief among local scientists, a professor, and has been in the Zone practically from the very beginning, met and knows many people. And one more thing: we really need brave fighters, join us in "Clear Sky", serve for the good of science.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I can't. I need to go back to the Forest, to Forester. I promised to return to him, need to bring medicines. And I'm in his debt. He saved me and led me out of the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, as you wish, decide for yourself. But if you change your mind, come to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I'll think about it. Tell me, how do I get back to the Forest from here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Only Sakharov can tell you that. When he needs to send one of his employees to the Forest accompanied by a couple of my guys, he always very carefully calculates the safest route using his devices. So go to him. Get the reward for helping Vasiliev and ask about your brother at the same time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, I'll go to Sakharov.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes, I'm waiting for you, dear sir. You are due a reward for the help provided to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_start_dialog_2">
    <text>No, I'm not here for the reward, but for the medicine for Forester. And I also need to find out something from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, young man, one shouldn't refuse a reward. Here, take this from us in gratitude. And I will try to answer your questions. Especially since the medicine will be ready only in a few minutes, so we can talk a little.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you, Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_0">
    <text>I have two questions for you, Professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak, I'm listening attentively.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_2">
    <text>I am looking for my brother, who should be somewhere in the Zone. We missed each other several years ago, if you can call it that. In the Dead City. And under very strange circumstances.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_3">
    <text>So, and what was your brother's name? Any distinguishing marks?</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_4">
    <text>He always called himself "Captain", that's how he introduced himself to Forester too. Forester found him, like me, three years ago in the "Dead City", sheltered him for some time. Then my brother went to look for me, and Forester hasn't met him since. And his marks are very simple. My brother and I are like two drops of water, like twins. Although he is two years older than me and a bit taller. The only thing is he has a large mole above his upper lip, right in the middle.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_5">
    <text>You know, young man, I recall that exactly about two years, maybe two and a half years ago, a stalker nicknamed "Captain" came to me. He and several other people came to our Bunker together to stock up on scientific medkits and powerful anti-radiation drugs before a big trip to the center of the Zone. These were some of the first brave stalkers who were not afraid and went to the Sarcophagus in the very heart of the Zone to learn the main secret. Unfortunately, I haven't heard anything more about the fate of the participants of this daring expedition. Rumor had it that they did reach the Sarcophagus and made their way inside. But I have no other information about this.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you, Professor. At least something became known. I will definitely find out about the fate of this expedition and what happened to my brother. And the second question: how can I get back to the Forest? I need to return to Forester.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_7">
    <text>As you probably already know, in the Zone you cannot walk the same road twice. The Zone constantly changes, and one has to look for and calculate new routes, find new paths to move. More or less stable transitions exist only in some places, for example, in the territory of the Bar, Agroprom, Garbage, and Cordon. But I can help you. You can get to the Forest from Yantar, I marked the path in your PDA. Give my regards to Forester. And here is the medicine for him, which Vasiliev failed to deliver. And with food, young man, things are tight for us right now. You and the grandfather will have to be patient. Tell Forester that we'll pick up the artifacts and roots next time, in a week, when the courier brings provisions.</text>
</string>
<string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood. I'll go find this Secret Path leading to the Forest.</text>
</string>

<string id="lekarstvo_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm back. Sorry it took so long. Vasiliev simply lost your package when running away from monsters. Had to go with him to Yantar and pick up new medicine from Sakharov.</text>
</string>
<string id="lekarstvo_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, lately everything is going terribly wrong. Bad luck everywhere. Anyway, give me the medicine and grub, because I feel really bad with my heart. I thought I wouldn't wait for you anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="lekarstvo_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, take the medicine quickly. But with food, the eggheads are tight right now, asked to wait a week.</text>
</string>

<string id="eda_dialog_0">
    <text>Father, where are we going to get provisions now? I see your supplies are running low.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_1">
    <text>We'll have to come up with something... I have a small box hidden in a secluded place. For a rainy day, so to speak. Well, apparently, this day has come. You'll have to go and get the box. True, you'll have to go to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_2">
    <text>Give me the coordinates, I'll go.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_3">
    <text>Eh, I don't want to let you go alone, but, apparently, I have to. Listen to me carefully: I made the stash in the School building. This building has columns, just not far from the place where I found you. I was actually going to this stash. But I had to get distracted by you, Strelok. While bringing you to senses, time ran out. Had to leave quickly. Look for the stash on the first floor. Understood everything? As soon as you take the provisions, come back immediately and don't linger there!.. Oh, my sick heart senses something wrong. But there is nothing to do, must go. Here, take more buckshot just in case and a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't worry, Father, I'll be careful. Alright, I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="eda_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Father, I got delayed again, sorry. An unforeseen situation happened there.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Strelok, I was very worried about you. Thought dogs tore you apart. What else happened there, tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_est_2">
    <text>In the Dead City, in the School building, tenants appeared. Call themselves "Wanderers". Their leader is Leila. A tough woman, but beautiful. At first, they almost killed me, then it was okay. Turned out to be normal guys. They found your stash... I helped them a little. They gave me the box with the remains of provisions. In addition, gave me an assault rifle and a protective suit. And Leila also said that one of their people should return from a raid soon, who can help me in search of my brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_est_3">
    <text>It's good that you found friends. You can't be bored here with an old man forever. Who knows, maybe they really will help you find your brother... Well, show me what provisions we have there.</text>
</string>
<string id="eda_dialog_est_4">
    <text>There's still half a box, enough for a week or two if we tighten our belts a bit. Here, take the box.</text>
</string>

<string id="skit_start_dialog_0">
    <text>And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I'd ask you to be polite, don't look for trouble, stalker. What are you doing here? Answer short and clear.</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, okay, don't worry. I came here at the request of a man just to pick up provisions from a stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_3">
    <text>What fool thought of making a stash in this godforsaken place?</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_4">
    <text>It's not a fool - it's Forester. Do you know him?</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I heard about Forester. Seems like a good man... Okay, let's go to our base now. Leila will deal with you there. She is our leader, you can't fool her! Just watch out, walk next to me. Try to run - you'll get a bullet. If you move further than ten meters away, it will be considered an escape attempt. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="skit_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, understood, I understood. Let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="leila_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, speak. Who are you and what did you come to the Dead City with. Just don't be shady.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I came here on Forester's errand to pick up provisions from his stash. He couldn't come himself, his heart is bad. I actually live with Forester now, help him. Just that food is tight now. So he sent me to bring the box with food from his stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I know Forester well... And where is his stash hidden?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I see I need to be completely frank with you. You are serious guys. Forester's stash, according to his description, is in this building on the first floor.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Now I believe you. Because we already found this box with provisions. Your Forester hid it poorly. Probably thought no one walks here. He was wrong. Now our Skete is here, and we are "Wanderers". Heard anything about us? Forester didn't tell you anything?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_6">
    <text>No, haven't heard anything about you before. And Forester didn't tell me anything. I'm actually quite new to the Zone. Forester found me under strange circumstances. I'm looking for my brother now. Have you heard anything about a stalker nicknamed "Captain"? He looks very much like me.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No, Strelok, I don't know such a person and haven't heard anything about him. We've been in the Zone for only a year and a half ourselves, and during this time, except for enemies and envious people, we haven't met anyone. And we don't particularly strive to make acquaintances here. We have other goals. Although, whoever comes to us with good, receives good from us.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I see. And what are you doing in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_9">
    <text>We are here unofficially carrying out a mission for a large scientific company. You don't need to know more. We have a peaceful mission, but sometimes we have to shoot. Too many surprises in the Zone. Must be constantly on guard and fully armed. By the way, if you want to buy some provisions, equipment, or weapons, talk to "Mozart" - he is our "supply manager". By the way, he was the one who found your Forester's stash. Understood everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, everything is clear to me.</text>
</string>


<string id="leila_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Tell me, what about Forester's box now?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_1">
    <text>It's very simple: we don't need what's not ours. But we found the stash ourselves. Now this is our territory and everything on it also belongs to the "Wanderers" brotherhood. And I will give you Forester's box, but only on the condition that you help us with one matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, I'll work for the provisions. What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_3">
    <text>It's simple, Strelok. Now go to Demon, he is our head of security. Find him in the former store building, near the Lenin monument. We are currently conducting an operation to clean the city territory from all scum. You will help us with this. Basically, Demon will tell you everything and give you an automatic weapon with ammo. And at the same time, we'll check what kind of "shooter" you are. I'll warn Demon about you.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, going to Demon.</text>
</string>


<string id="leila_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I fulfilled your condition. Give me Forester's box.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You really are a brave fellow, Strelok. We, Wanderers, keep our word. Take your box. True, we already took something from there, so let Forester not be offended. Should have hidden it better. And come by if you have a chance. We honor and respect brave people. And one more thing: about your business regarding your brother... We have one Wanderer in the team, called "Grig". He has been in the Zone for a long time, joined us from the very beginning of our mission. He was a guide, and then joined our ranks for good. He is on a mission right now, but should return soon. And you can find out about your brother from him. Perhaps he knows something. As soon as he returns, I will inform Forester on the radio.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Good, I will wait impatiently to meet him. And how do I get back to the Forest now?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Go to the sentry who brought you to me. He is waiting for you near the entrance to this room and will tell you everything. Without him, you won't find the path to the Forest.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Aha, understood. I'll go talk to him.</text>
</string>



<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, chief!</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>What chief am I to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, okay, don't boil over. Leila told me that you will show me where the path is that will lead me to the Forest.</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll show you, daredevil. Follow me, when we reach the post, then I'll upload the marker of the transition to the Forest to your PDA. Don't lag behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood, let's go.</text>
</string>



<string id="demon_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings. Are you Demon?</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes that's me, Strelok. Leila warned me about you. Ready for exploits?</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Always ready! What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We don't control the whole city yet. The houses are full of zombies. They constantly appear after emissions... Where do they come from? Now, after the last emission, my guys already cleared most of it, but one five-story building remains. The last one, the one next to the corner five-story building with a broken roof. That's where, in one of the entrances, there is full of scum. Zombies are slow, but it's better not to let them close. You'll go alone, my guys are extremely exhausted by the last raid. Show what you are capable of. Here, take an assault rifle and four packs of ammo for it. And be careful there, don't ask for trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything. Going to fight the scum.</text>
</string>

<string id="demon_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I cleared that house of zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done, Strelok! Keep the assault rifle as a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="demon_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thank you. I'll go to Leila and pick up what she promised to return to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, Forester. The Wanderers have a trader, called Mozart...</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>Looking to buy something you spotted?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I spotted something. He has many useful things and good weapons. And most importantly, he sells ammo cheaply. But where can I get money, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I can offer you a way to earn. The scientists from Yantar pay very well for various roots and artifacts. Especially valued by them, as you already realized, is the Mandrake root, which you obtained for me recently. They prepare a protective potion from it. They want to penetrate some laboratory, where brains supposedly "boil" from some powerful, unknown scientific impact. So they constantly offer me big money for every root I find. They don't really want to search themselves, and can't, honestly speaking. And Mandrake grows only here, in the Forest, in places where not everyone would guess to look. And why do I need money? I trade what I find for provisions and buckshot for my double-barreled gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>So, interesting. And how much can one earn from this?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>They pay fifteen thousand for each root. Considerable money... I can tell you where to find more roots.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>Go ahead, tell me!</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>Alright then. I know where to find three Mandrakes. Only the scientists won't take them from you. They overinsure themselves greatly. They will sell or exchange roots only with me personally. I have money. Two months ago I collected a large amount of roots and artifacts for the scientists. They not only gave provisions but insisted I take money. So now it lies idle. And I see you need it more. Just giving it away is wrong, but earning it is the right thing. So, do we have a deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>Of course, we have a deal. Tell me where to search for the plants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>Right here behind the fence, there is an old abandoned mine. Mandrake should be growing there. Find three roots and bring them to me, and I'll give you the money - 45 thousand. I'll also give you some buckshot and a medkit. Just be careful there!</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood. I'm going.</text>
</string>


<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Forester, I brought three roots!</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>What a good fellow! To be honest, I'm afraid to climb into that mine alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>And rightly so. There are some flying creatures there. Horror! And as soon as I took the last, third root, a monster appeared. A hypnotist or something. Barely got out of there.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Flying creatures are poltergeists. They are cowardly but dangerous if you run into them nose to nose. And the hypnotist is a Controller. That one is scarier than a pack of boars. A treacherous beast. Okay, give me the roots and take your honestly earned money. And go rest.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here are the roots, take them. I'll go for a walk. My hands are still shaking.</text>
</string>



<string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, father? Any news while I was climbing mines?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_1">
    <text>Leila informed me that the very person you are waiting for has appeared. So you have to go to the City again, son... Apparently, we won't see each other soon now...</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, father, don't grieve. We got provisions, we have roots! And I won't be long. Just find out about my brother and return. Soon, I hope.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, Strelok, don't worry about me. Go to Leila, she is waiting for you. You know the secret path from the Forest to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_4">
    <text>See you, father, I will definitely return!</text>
</string>

<string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, soldier!</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't distract me. Go to the Skete, you know the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_2">
    <text>See you.</text>
</string>



<string id="leila_grig_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Sister!</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't be a smartass! What sister am I to you? I thought you had a brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_2">
    <text>That's what I came for. You informed Forester that your guide appeared, who might be able to help me. Is that so?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, he arrived recently from a raid to the Swamps. We have a checkpoint there, and Grig is in charge there. But before you go to him, I will ask you to help with one simple matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_4">
    <text>What matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_5">
    <text>You see, a gang of marauders constantly hangs around in the Dead City. Just homeless kids. Thugs, of course, but still children. They rummage through abandoned houses, take out everything they find for sale. But recently a leader appeared among them, someone named Razuvaev. A former criminal. With his arrival, things got serious. The gang now not only quietly robs abandoned houses and shops in the district but also kills. Just recently, they robbed and killed one of our brothers returning from a raid. We staged a raid on them, but to no avail.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_6">
    <text>So how can I help you? You have your own small army.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_7">
    <text>That's true, but it's a delicate matter... My soldiers swore to catch and destroy everyone. Demon even set a reward for Razuvaev's head - 100,000 rubles. For the others, the order is: Destroy on the spot without trial or investigation. I cannot and do not want to interfere and violate the laws of the "Wanderers". But despite all this, I don't want unnecessary, useless deaths. I'm not ready to take on the sin of fighting children, even if they are criminals. Do you understand me?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes, I understand. So what do you want from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_9">
    <text>According to my information, the marauder leader Razuvaev left the Dead City for a while with a group of hardened killers and criminals. A small group of teenagers led by a kid nicknamed Maloy remained here. I want you to quietly find this gang and convey my demands to them. Don't be afraid, they are thugs, but not killers. They are unlikely to shoot first at a lone Stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay. And what conditions should I convey to them, and where to find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_11">
    <text>The conditions are simple: I pass them twenty thousand rubles through you. For them, this is good money, and in return, they tell everything they know about their leader: who he is, where he comes from, where he usually sets up camps, and so on. And then let them leave the Dead City and never appear here again. Otherwise, Demon's fighters will shoot them. I will mark their suspected camp location on the map for you. Just please: not a word to anyone, otherwise the boys are done for. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, I understood everything. Mark the map, give the money, and I'll try to negotiate with your "kids".</text>
</string>




<string id="maloy_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you Maloy?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I am. And who are you, uncle?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_2">
    <text>Doesn't matter. Leila sent me to you. Know her?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_3">
    <text>The chieftess? Yeah, I know. Does she want to invite young boys for a visit?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_4">
    <text>Idiot! She offers you a deal to save your useless lives.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_5">
    <text>And you are, like, a messenger of goodwill? Is that it? And what does our "savior" offer?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_6">
    <text>You are laughing in vain, young man. The "Wanderers" are preparing a raid on you for your "wet work". So you don't really have a choice. And Leila's offer to you is this: she gives you twenty thousand rubles. You tell about Razuvaev, who he is and where to find him, and then get the hell out of here forever. Otherwise, you are dead. Choose.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, I'm not stupid, I get it. I need to talk it over with the gang.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, I'll wait.</text>
</string>

<string id="maloy_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, have you decided?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Listen, uncle, we agree. Only we don't know much about Razuvaev. I only know that he escaped from prison and gathered a gang here in the Zone and scavenges little by little. We ended up with him by accident, had nowhere to go, so we started doing petty work for him. And we have nothing to do with his "wet work", keep in mind! I don't know where to look for him either. They say his main camp is somewhere in an abandoned village, not far from the "Glubokaya" station, in the south of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Okay, I'll take your word for it. So, you take the money and get out of here, did I understand correctly?</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yes, right, right. Don't rush the horses. Give the money. Then step away from this place about 50 meters behind the bushes so you don't see which way we leave. Conspiracy, chief, understand? We won't come back here, I swear.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Okay, here, take the promised money. I'll step away 50 meters. Then I'll come back, check. There better be no trace of you here. If you tricked me, I'll personally shoot you to hell.</text>
</string>

<string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_0">
    <text>Well, I dealt with the marauders.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_1">
    <text>So, you managed to persuade them and they left?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_2">
    <text>Yes, they left. Promised not to return here anymore. Impudent guys. Young, green still, but daring. Accepted your conditions, took the money. They don't really know anything about their leader Razuvaev. Say he went deep into the Zone with a group of experienced ones. Seemed to plan to return to the Dead City soon, but no news from him yet. Seemed like Razuvaev's main camp is somewhere in an abandoned village, near Station "Glubokoe", in the south of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_3">
    <text>Good. I hope these young idiots have enough brains not to come here again. Thank you, Strelok. Now it's time to go to Grig. Talk to him, because he is getting ready to go back soon. He is located not far from here, in the former Party Committee building. And as for the marauder leader, we'll catch him yet. The time will come. If you suddenly meet this little reptile Razuvaev on your way, give him a fiery firearm "hello" from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_4">
    <text>Okay, agreed. All right, going to Grig quickly now. Thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, are you Grig?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Leila told me that you might be able to help me with a matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, she warned me. I'll help with what I can, Strelok. Speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_4">
    <text>The matter is like this, can't tell in two words... Basically, I'm looking for a brother. We "missed" each other here several years ago, in the Dead City, under very strange circumstances. Forester, and then Sakharov from Yantar said that they had met a man looking like me nicknamed "Captain" before. All they know is that he and several other desperate guys planned a raid to the Sarcophagus at the CNPP. Maybe you know something or, perhaps, heard about "Captain" and that team of stalkers?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, Leila briefly told me about your case. No, I haven't met such a person personally. But I know a little more about that team of "suicides" who two and a half years ago attempted to get into the heart of the Zone, into the Sarcophagus. You know that the city of Pripyat is very close to the CNPP. That's exactly where they went through Pripyat. My partner was a guide for them, just like I was then, rest his soul, undertook to lead them to the hotel in Pripyat. No one went further in those days. He returned, and they went on. \n\nMy partner soon died from a high dose of radiation received in Pripyat... That's all I know. I don't know if you'll find your brother or the trail of that group of stalkers, but in any case, search should start in Pripyat, I tell you for sure. Only I strongly advise you not to meddle there. A rotten place: high radiation, everything swarming with anomalies. And on top of everything, half a year ago some group appeared there. Mysterious. Either half-humans or half-zombies. Basically, lately no one who dared to go to Pripyat has returned...</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, wow... But I swore to myself to find my brother or find out what happened to him, so I have no other way. I must go to Pripyat. Can you escort me to the place? I'll pay or work it off somehow.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No, Strelok, I won't be able to act as a guide for you. Plenty of other important things to do. But to show the path leading from the Dead City to Pripyat - I will show. But, of course, not for free. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Of course, agreed! What is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Well, basically, a mere trifle. Need to bring ten dog tails. There are plenty of dogs in the ravines on the outskirts of the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood, I'll be quick.</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Grig, I shot the dogs. Here are your ten tails.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>That's great. The transition to Pripyat is through the sewer pipe of the Dead City. You'll find the entrance not far from here: First go strictly east until you pass the basketball court, and then turn northeast. Be careful there. And remember, this path is one-way only. You'll have to find the way back yourself. Well, good luck to you, Strelok. May your faith keep you! I'm here for a short while. Soon going to the Swamps. We have a checkpoint there. We'll meet again.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thank you, Grig! See you around.</text>
</string>


<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Sergeant!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, we've been waiting for you. Time is short, we must act. Hands are itching, wanting to kick these bastards' asses as soon as possible! Is the Bar map with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_2">
    <text>Here is the map, Sergeant.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_3">
    <text>So, excellent. Now let's figure out how to distribute the strike forces... Aha, everything is clear. We enter the Bar and split into three groups. And then according to the situation. Well, time to move out. Are you with us?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_4">
    <text>Where would I go? Of course, with you. Let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_5">
    <text>Then a special task for you: don't rush forward too much, but don't lag behind. First goes the assault group, then the snipers. I will go last. The most dangerous place is the narrow passage to the Bar territory from the northern checkpoint through the gates. Here, to avoid confusion, and not to become a good target for bandit shooters, someone needs to go slightly ahead and clear the passage of guards. I think you can handle this. Especially since you are like "one of their own" to the thugs. They won't immediately figure out what's what. \n\nWell, and then act according to the situation. But remember, we need to occupy several key positions. First, the "100 Rads" Bar itself, I'll direct the main strike forces there. Second, the bunker where the bandits have a prison. This will be my task exactly. Then we definitely must eliminate Knyaz, their leader. I'll entrust this to a couple of the most experienced guys. And, of course, both checkpoints need to be taken under control. One fighter will stand at the northern post immediately, and I'll send two to the southern one: an assaulter and a sniper. So, that's the layout. And then as luck has it. Is everything clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, everything is clear to me. Moving out?</text>
</string>


<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, Sergeant? Are you satisfied with how everything turned out?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, quite. Now they can't kick us out of here! General Voronin and the others will arrive soon, and we'll set up a powerful Duty base here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well then, good luck to you.</text>
</string>


<string id="about_voronin_dialog_0">
    <text>How else can I be useful?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_voronin_dialog_1">
    <text>Need to meet General Voronin and escort him here. Several bandits led by Borov managed to escape the Bar territory from the southern side. And the General with three guards and another person with them are moving towards the Bar right now from the Garbage side to the southern post. Need to warn Voronin and escort him and those with him to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_voronin_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood. I'll run towards the Garbage. Hope I make it in time to warn the General about the possible danger.</text>
</string>


<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, General!</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok! Well then, Plichko reported that the Bar territory is ours now. Very good news! And he sent you to help us get to the Bar, apparently?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, exactly. Just that unfinished bandits could still remain in the district. By the way, Borov managed to escape from the Bar at the last moment... Couldn't catch him. And I see Barkeep is heading to the Bar with you too.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, God be with him, with Borov, we'll catch him later. Main thing is the Bar is ours now. Here we are leading Barkeep with us. What is a Bar without a Barkeep? Especially since he organized everything. Well, let's go slowly to our new "residence".</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, moving out. Follow me, General.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well then, here you are. How do you like it here?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_1">
    <text>A chic bunker! No worse than the scientists have at Yantar. Beauty! You, Strelok, deserved a really big reward. Here, take this, personally from me. Stop by Barkeep, he has a special gift for you. Now the rest of our brothers led by Colonel Petrenko from the Dark Valley can move here too.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thank you, General. I'll go stop by Barkeep. See you again, hopefully.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Doctor!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, young man. You must be Strelok, about whom my student and assistant Paramedic informed me? Thank you for helping Ghost. We are in your debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_2">
    <text>No need for thanks, Doctor. I should rather thank you for meeting Paramedic in Pripyat. He cleared my brains and returned my memory.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_one_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor, I have a very important question for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Listening, dear sir.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_2">
    <text>I want to ask you if you know a stalker nicknamed "Captain", who two and a half years ago, accompanied by several other brave stalkers, tried to penetrate through Pripyat into the CNPP territory and further into the Sarcophagus. He is my brother. I'm trying to find him or at least find out what happened to him. A man named "Grig" told me that his partner - a guide, accompanied that very group to the center of Pripyat. Then they went themselves, and he returned, but soon after died from a strong dose of radiation he received...</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, it was a long time ago... Indeed, several stalkers attempted to reach the CNPP and the Sarcophagus. But this, as I see, you already know without me. The leader in the group was indeed a certain "Captain". Whether he is your brother or not, I don't know, but comrades called him exactly "Captain".</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, Doctor, Ghost and Paramedic didn't lie. You really know a lot. Maybe you know some more significant details? What happened to them?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_5">
    <text>How this trip ended and what became of your brother, I won't say because I don't know. This story is covered in mystery and darkness. Now, after so much time, all this seems like mysticism or just a fairytale. But there is one detail that only I know and which makes this story quite real. I never told anyone about this, and in general, no one needed it. But for you, I see, details might be useful in your search.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_6">
    <text>And what is this detail? And generally, how do you know all this?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_7">
    <text>Grig, whom you mentioned, knows a lot. He is an "old seasoned wolf", been in many scrapes. But he still gave you not quite accurate information. More precisely, he simply didn't know about one nuance... That very guide comrade of his actually led the group not to the center of Pripyat, but transferred it directly to the CNPP territory. Took a risk and paid for it with his life...</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_8">
    <text>So how do you know this?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_9">
    <text>That very guide, being already near death, came to me. I was no longer able to help him... He stayed with me for a week. God sees, I did everything possible, but, alas, it was all in vain... So, right before death, he told me himself that he took a risk and together with those stalkers crossed from Pripyat to the CNPP. And he did so because in Pripyat they found several unique artifacts that give very powerful protection against radiation and psi-impact. And everyone was confident that such protection would be sufficient and enough for everyone. \n\nBut once on the CNPP territory, it turned out that the background was too high and there simply wouldn't be enough protective properties of artifacts for everyone. The group split. Only two went to the Sarcophagus, hung with all found artifacts - "Captain" and one more, Yuri Semetsky. The others returned to Pripyat and stayed there to wait for the return of those two. Only soon everyone felt a sharp malaise and were forced to return from where they came. They never waited for Captain and Semetsky. What happened next - no one knows for certain. Just then some devilry started: literally a couple of days later a powerful emission of psi-energy began, after which much in the Zone changed. \n\nAfter some time, the same message about Yuri Semetsky's death began coming to stalkers' PDAs, which comes to this day. Some of the "old-timers" claimed they saw Semetsky alive and healthy six months later, and then a year after all these events. Believe it or not, I don't know... Soon they stopped recalling it and the story of the stalkers' trip to the center of the Zone became just a legend, and the situation with constant messages about Semetsky's death was written off as another unexplained phenomenon of the Zone. Such is this difficult matter, Strelok. Try to find out from the masters, maybe someone did survive from that group? For this, you will have to go through the whole Zone, starting from here, from the Swamps, and to the Cordon itself.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_one_dialog_10">
    <text>Thank you, Doctor, you instilled hope in me! I believe I will find my brother's trail, or maybe him himself.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor, how can I be useful to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_1">
    <text>There is a matter, just for such a brave and desperate person as you, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak, I will gladly help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_3">
    <text>Here, in the Swamps, until a certain time everything was relatively calm. Well, except maybe a stray pack of dogs or stupid rodents appear. But these are trifles. And then suddenly quite recently some Swamp creature appeared. Scared all my "patients". Barely revived two fractures after their meeting with this monster. And yesterday night this hellspawn devoured all of my Murka's kittens. Actually, I can tame any beast, but this one... This one does not succumb to any influence and no hypnosis. That's how things are.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand, I need to find out who settled there in the Swamps, and destroy the mutant?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, that's correct, Strelok. Just be careful. This is a very, very rare and dangerous creature. Wanderers, well, you know them, I gathered, since you already met Grig. They have a checkpoint still in the west of the Swamps, a small base... So they are afraid to even approach the place where presumably its lair is. They lost quite a few people when trying to destroy the creature. But I know you'll come up with something. You are smart. But I ask you again, be careful, Strelok. If you feel you can't overcome the monster, return back, we'll think of something else.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_6">
    <text>Don't worry, Doc, I've met all sorts of rubbish on my way while getting to you. So, whoever is there, can't scare me.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Yes, I've seen all sorts of things... But this! I've never met such a creature anywhere before.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Did you, young man, overcome this creature?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, but had to work ve-e-ery hard!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well, thank you, Strelok! You saved us all from great danger.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Come on, Doc, no need for thanks. Would be good not to meet this hellspawn again.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_skit_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor, I need to get out of here and move further in search of my brother. How do I leave the Swamps?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_skit_dialog_1">
    <text>You see, young man, the transition to Pripyat is currently unavailable. After this last emission, everything turned upside down. And you, actually, don't need to go to Pripyat. You just came from there. From the Swamps, you can also get to the Forest, and from there further into the Zone. But this path can be known only to the Wanderers. You need to talk to Grig about this.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_skit_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, Doc, I'll go to the Wanderers' checkpoint, talk to Grig about the transition. I actually need to get to the Forest first. I left one elderly man there in bad condition. His name is Forester. Maybe you know him? I worry about him greatly, he helped me a lot.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_skit_dialog_3">
    <text>I know Forester. Good man, sensible and brave. Not afraid to live alone in the Anomalous Forest, where it's full of deadly traps and various mutants. He is the one who will tell you how to pass from the Forest deeper into the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_skit_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. Means my path is through the Forest again. Thank you, Doc, and see you!</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Grig! Haven't seen you in a while.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok! So, found your brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_2">
    <text>No, Grig, haven't found the brother yet. Doctor told me some details that allow hoping for the best. But for this, I need to get deep into the Zone. Actually, I came to you to ask you to show the path further into the Zone through the Forest. Doctor says that you know where the path to the Forest is. Will you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, Strelok, I can show you the transition to the Forest. And from the Forest, you'll come out to the Army Warehouses. Forester will help, you know him. But only a favor for a favor.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_4">
    <text>O-oh, excellent! Just on the way deep into the Zone I'll see Forester, how he is there... What is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_5">
    <text>As last time - a mere trifle. Need to check the work of one search device. Which one and why you don't need to know. All that is required of you is to escort our specialist, called Kent, to the abandoned village so he can test the device there. And then back him up on the way back. You never know, there is enough rubbish around here. We, of course, could handle it ourselves, but now no one from security can leave the checkpoint. We lost several people recently. Swamp creature tore them to shreds... And until Leila sends reinforcements from the Dead City, not one day will pass. So if you help us out, then I will help you. Show the path to the Forest.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood, I'll be quick. By the way, I eliminated this creature at Doctor's request, so nothing to fear particularly anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_7">
    <text>You alone could destroy it??? Well, you, Strelok, are either an unheard-of brave man or crazy... Well okay, means even better, we won't find a better convoy than you. Means I wasn't mistaken. All right, time to move out. Kent is waiting for you at the end of the bridge by the wrecked truck. Follow him and watch out so nothing happens to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, I'm going. Wait.</text>
</string>

<string id="zamery_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, are you Kent?</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_2">
    <text>Grig asked to escort you to the measurement site. You have to test some device there, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, yes, correct. I was just waiting for Grig to send someone. Only I thought there would be three people. Dangerous places there.</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't chicken out, we'll handle it together. Just pay attention there, and I'll back you up if anything. Well, moving out.</text>
</string>

<string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_0">
    <text>See, and you were afraid. Together with you overcame the creatures without much trouble! So, what? Are we there?</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_1">
    <text>Yes, that's it. We are there. Now I'll quickly check the settings, wait a bit. And then we'll go back immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_2">
    <text>Okay, be faster, waiting.</text>
</string>

<string id="zamery_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, measurement operation completed?</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, everything is excellent. I still need to tinker with the device settings here a little, and everything will be ready. And huge thanks to you for help. All right, go to Grig. Report to him that his task is completed, the device functions normally. In a couple-three hours I will finish settings and return to the Checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="zamery_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well okay, bye. Take care.</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Task completed, Grig. Your man returned alive and unharmed.</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, that's great! Here, look, I'll mark the transition from Swamps to Forest in your PDA. True, this is a one-way transition... If you need to return to Swamps again, find Pathfinder in the Bar, he'll help find the "Secret Path" to us here. Understood everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, everything is clear. I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_0">
    <text>Glad to see you, father. How is health?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok? Thought I wouldn't see you, son, anymore... It's hard for me alone here, without a helper. I went to the forest recently for roots for scientists, and forest cats attacked me. A whole pack! Fought them off with grief in half. Only they bruised my sides, ugly creatures. And with medicines, as luck would have it, trouble. The courier from eggheads still hasn't arrived.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_2">
    <text>Bruised sides, you say? Let me help you with medicine. Here, take this, heal up.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you, son. And take something from me in gratitude. Here, a rare recipe for artifact transmutation, you'll find it useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_4">
    <text>Won't refuse, thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_0">
    <text>How have you been here all this time?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm fine now, but where have you been? Found anything about the brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, father, so much happened to me during this time, can't tell everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, tell the old man briefly about your affairs.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, if briefly, I ended up in Pripyat. Got memory loss there - managed to get into an anomaly. Then salvation. One "sorcerer" saved me, called Mervin. For some time I was a brainless soldier-puppet in the "Monolith" clan at the CNPP. Then people of the Swamp Doctor "pulled me out" and helped get out of Pripyat to the Swamps. Then met the Swamp Doctor. Learned something about my brother. Now came to the Forest again. And next I need to get deep into the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, son, that's how life "spun" you. Well okay, alive and good. What do you plan to do next?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I'm saying, next I need to get deep into the Zone. They told me that you can show the path leading to the Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, I don't know this path myself, never went there. But there are some guys - hunters. They appear here in the Forest sometimes for a short while to hunt mutants. They collect certain parts of these mutants and then sell to scientists. So hunters are here right now. Just visited me yesterday. Chatted with them about this and that, drank tea. Basically, they have a temporary camp not far here, to the southeast. The leader among them is a seasoned hunter nicknamed "Hunchback". Find him and talk. He definitely knows how to get to the Army Warehouses. And I'll mark the coordinates how to find hunters on the map.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_8">
    <text>Aha, understood. Give the coordinates and I'll go find these hunters.</text>
</string>

<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, are you Hunchback?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I am. And who are you? and what brought you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Forester told me that you can show me the transition from the Forest to the Army Warehouses. And generally I wander the Zone looking for a brother, called "Captain". Have you heard anything about such a stalker and his team, which a couple of years ago made a bold attempt to sneak into the very heart of the Zone, into the Sarcophagus?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, so that's it... Okay, then it's another matter. About "Captain" I heard nothing. And we don't particularly communicate with anyone. We are hermits by ourselves. But the path from the Forest to the Army Warehouses can be shown. But, you understand yourself, favor for favor. I'm equipping a couple of fighters to shoot boars here, to collect hooves for sale. Here is a proposal for you: help them shoot mutants, and we will open the Secret Path to the Warehouses for you. Agree?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, what else can I do? Agree. Say when and with whom moving out.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Now that's business! So: the leader for the "operation" is Grek. There he is, bored on the side. Zakhar will go with him. Old stump, but knows his business. True, he whines constantly. You chat with him later, he needs something in the "inhabited" Zone, and you are seemingly going there. Maybe you'll help with something. And if suddenly you collect necessary mutant parts, then contact Mazay or Zakhar, they will exchange various "tails-hooves" for ammo and medkits. Well okay, that's just in case. And now to business: go to Grek now, he will give all instructions on the upcoming operation. Help him, he will show the transition to Warehouses to you later after we do the job. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, everything is clear. Going to Grek.</text>
</string>




<string id="grek_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Grek.</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, stalker. So, ready for the big hunt?</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm always ready for anything. Speak, what's the plan.</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Everything is outrageously simple: Now moving out three of us to the place. You, me and Zakhar. Don't get ahead of me, need to sneak up quietly there. It's not far, near the fallen tree. We tracked a pack of boars there recently. So we'll hunt them. Just be careful, these are treacherous creatures. As we do the job, Zakhar will take you to the transition to Warehouses. And I'll give you three packs of armor-piercing ammo for Kalash and a couple of packs of "darts" for shotgun. And throw in a couple of scientific medkits, won't be superfluous. So, ready to move out?</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm always ready, like a pioneer. Give the ammo and let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="grek_ohota_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Grek, shot the mutants after all!</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_ohota_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, worked nicely. Well then, now, as promised, Zakhar will take you to the place where the path leading to Army Warehouses starts. Follow him, don't get ahead, but don't lag behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="grek_ohota_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks and good luck.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Zakhar, are we there?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, we are on the spot. The path leading to Army Warehouses starts here, between boulders.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood everything, thank you. Maybe there is some request for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, basically, there is one request. I heard out of the corner of my ear here, when you were talking with Hunchback, that you are looking for a missing brother. Eh... in your question I can't help with anything, sorry... But I have a very similar situation to yours. Maybe you'll understand my position... There is one man, his surname is Sobolev. Retired military. We used to be neighbors with him before, before the disaster. Lived nearby for twenty-something years. Went fishing, hunting together, families were friends. During the disaster our families died... \n\nSince then I have no one closer than him left. Sobolev and I then decided to stay here, in the Zone, where our families are buried. Started moonlighting as guides. At first for tourists, then for stalkers. Knew these places well. And then our paths parted. We quarreled with him once, quarreled badly, and I decided to leave and joined Hunters. And he remained a guide. And where is he now?.. Eh, haven't heard about him for a long time. Know that in the Zone, but where fate carries him?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>So there is a stalker network, can search through it. Do you have a PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>No, Strelok, don't have. And I don't know how to use it. Basically, I have a request for you: if you meet Sobolev, give him this personal letter. Want to make up with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, Zakhar. If I find Sobolev, I will definitely give him your letter. And now it's time for me. Show where the path to Warehouses starts and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_0">
    <text>General. I ended up here, in the Dark Valley, not just like that.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_1">
    <text>And what brought you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I'm looking for my brother. I have information that he is in your ranks. Works as a guide for you. His nickname is "Captain". Is he here with you?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_3">
    <text>So that's it. Yes, in our ranks there is Captain, an experienced guide. Walked the Zone far and wide. Only he never said he had a brother. Strange...</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_4">
    <text>There is! He has a brother! It's me. Just we lost each other long, very long ago. So where, General, can I find "Captain"? My older brother, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_5">
    <text>Don't make noise like that. He is here, here, I say. Go to the yard, there is a small structure, you'll find him there. Then return to me. I have some work for you, daredevil.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_about_sobolev_6">
    <text>Good! Would you look at that... I found him after all! All right, running, I'll be quick.</text>
</string>

<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Uh-uh... "Captain"?!</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Captain Sobolev, at your service. How can I help, young man?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Damn it! How can this be, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_3">
    <text>And what, actually, is the matter? What is happening here?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I stomped half the Zone looking for my brother. Suffered so much during this time. And in the end get such a result of all my sufferings and insane risk... Lord, why are you so unfair to me!</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Stop hysterics, soldier! What do I have to do with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_6">
    <text>With the fact that my brother's name is Captain. And I came here, to the Dark Valley, to finally find him. I received information that a stalker nicknamed Captain is in Duty location in the Dark Valley. But fate is ironic! I met "Captain", only not the right one...</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Ye-e-ah, fate sometimes plays cruel jokes on us. Regret that I became the indirect cause of your disappointments, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, captain. You have absolutely nothing to do with it here. Excuse me for a moment of weakness.</text>
</string>

<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_0">
    <text>And what do I do now with searching for the brother? Have no idea.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't hang your nose, Strelok! I will try to help you. Especially since I remembered something...</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_2">
    <text>What? You know something about my brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, I know something. As you probably know from Zakhar, we were guides once and led various tourists and stalkers around the Zone. And about that very expedition to the Sarcophagus, in which your brother "Captain" participated, I know not by hearsay.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, Zakhar told me about this.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_5">
    <text>So, I didn't participate in that raid myself, but I know a lot about this sortie from a buddy. He was exactly the guide for those stalkers. Died, true, later. He told that only two went into the Sarcophagus itself: "Captain" and Yuri Semetsky. None of them returned, but no one found their corpses either. But everyone was sure they died. Some time later I led one experienced digger through the "Red Forest" to Pripyat. And so he told that he saw alive and unharmed Yuri Semetsky and even allegedly talked to him. Where he saw Semetsky, he didn't tell. \n\nI didn't believe him then. After all, legends were already composed about Semetsky by that time - "Eternal Stalker". You probably know yourself about these constant messages on PDA, about endless deaths of this Semetsky. Besides this, he said he was a participant of that very expedition and that only one of all remained alive. Well, except Semetsky, if believe his words. Would be good for you to find that man and find out from him where he saw Semetsky and what he talked about with him. If all this is true, and Semetsky is alive, and that digger really was part of that very group, then, maybe, your brother is also alive, and you can find him...</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_6">
    <text>And what was that digger's name and where can he be found?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, where to find him, neither I nor anyone of ours knows. And his nickname is "Mahomet". Where to find Mahomet, someone of traders might know. "Barkeep" from Cordon or "Sidorovich", who settled in the village on the territory of Glubokoe station.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_8">
    <text>You instilled new hope in me, captain. Thank you! And is it possible to go to Cordon by a short road from Dark Valley, otherwise have to stomp through Garbage for a long time?</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_9">
    <text>Possible. About the transition from Dark Valley to Cordon you need to talk to Voronin.</text>
</string>
<string id="sobolev_one_dialog_10">
    <text>I'll go ask Voronin about the transition to Cordon. And he had some business for me anyway.</text>
</string>

<string id="tankist_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi! Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_1">
    <text>We are vagabonds, like everyone. I'm called Tankist. Marauders battered us with guys recently, barely escaped alive. Now sitting here, licking wounds. And who are you yourself and what are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I am Strelok. Looking for a trace of missing brother. By the way, being in the Dead City I found a corpse, rather even already a skeleton of some stalker and a diary next to him. So, in this diary, besides everything else, there was a mention of a certain device. Called Bioradar. And also it said there that a stalker nicknamed Tankist might know where a specimen of this device can be obtained.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_3">
    <text>So that's it. Was that deceased called Krol by any chance?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, exactly, Krol. At least, the diary was signed with this name.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I knew this Krol. Was a meticulous man, attentive. See, kept a diary too, turns out. Pity he died. As for Bioradar: yes, indeed, several prototypes were stolen from eggheads and went somewhere "away" later. By the way, I have nothing to do with this case, if you thought something. I just knew a kid who participated in this robbery. He sold me one device later: A good thing, I tell you!</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_6">
    <text>So is this device with you now?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No, I lost it. Dropped it when running from marauders.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Why don't you go find it? What if someone finds it? Will be a shame to lose such a thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Too dangerous place there. I'm afraid. My life is dearer to me. Can offer you a deal: you find and bring me my unique gun anomalous "Groza", which I also lost. And I'll give you a tip where I dropped Bioradar. You, man, I see, are not timid. Maybe you'll find the device. It will surely be useful to you in your brother searches. And I, honestly say, plan to bail from the Zone. Does such offer suit you?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_10">
    <text>What a scatterbrain you are... Dropped Bioradar, lost your anomalous "Groza"... And where is your tank? Lost too?.. Come on! Don't get angry, I'm joking.. Your offer suits me. Where to search for your gun?</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_11">
    <text>The matter was like this: we with guys were running from marauders through "Wild Territory". Well, "Rostok" factory. You probably know. Scary place. Normal people try not to appear there, bypass it. So that's where I dropped it. The place where it happened is not hard to find: if walking from "Bar" side, go towards transition to Yantar. Reach unfinished building. Then go further and see a green wagon, which sort of fences off a small area. So in the yard, behind this wagon I waited out for a short while. Must search there. That's all. Yes, and give me that diary you found in Dead City. You don't need it anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Understood, wait. Will try to find your "Groza".</text>
</string>

<string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Tankist! Found your "Groza". Good thing, I tell you.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>O-oh, thank you! I thought that's it. Goodbye, my gun, forever. Give me my beauty here quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well, you are a brisk fellow. Forgot what you promised in return? Come on, to make everything fair, lay out the tip on "Bioradar" and then take your gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So, listen here: we ran from marauders through "Wild Territory". Well, "Rostok" factory. You probably know. Scary place. Normal people try not to appear there, bypass it. So that's where I dropped it. The place where it happened is not hard to find: if walking from "Bar" side, go towards transition to Yantar. Reach unfinished building. Then go further and see a green wagon, which sort of fences off a small area. So in the yard, behind this wagon I waited out for a short while. Must search there. That's all. Yes, and give me that diary you found in Dead City. You don't need it anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Understood. Okay, trust your word. Take your "Groza" and Krol's diary, and it's time for me.</text>
</string>

<string id="parol_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>
<string id="parol_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you? This is a closed territory. To pass, need an electronic special pass of the military. Have a special pass?</text>
</string>
<string id="parol_dialog_2">
    <text>I work as a guide for the military at Cordon. Here is my pass.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, "ghostly" trader.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Why so pompous? Speak up, who are you and why did you come. Haven't seen you before.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>I am Strelok. And I haven't been here before. I'm walking too long, and my path is oh so not simple. So now I am here. Brought you a message from Barkeep, because the connection is glitching after the last emission, and he can't contact you at all. And the matter, he says, is secret. Here, take the encrypted letter from Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_one_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, Sidorovich. I have a personal matter for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait a minute. Now I'll read what this "Cunning Fox" writes to me. So-so... Interesting layout. Uh-huh... Look how he laid everything out "on the shelves"! .. Okay, what's that matter of yours?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for my brother. Called "Captain". We "got lost" with him more than two years ago under very strange circumstances. Well okay, that's long to tell. I already walked almost the entire Zone, talked to many "old-timers" on this topic, but so far all in vain. But hope still exists.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_3">
    <text>So how can I help? I don't go into the Zone. I learn the latest news and gossip from stalkers and diggers who drop by here from time to time, or via stalker radio channel, which doesn't work here at all now.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Barkeep told me that you know a digger nicknamed Mahomet. He seems to drop by you often. I need to find him and find out something that can help find the brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, I know Mahomet. He was just here the day before yesterday. Turned in loot and went back to the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_6">
    <text>Listen, I don't understand. This is supposedly Peacekeepers territory. So how do stalkers scurry back and forth? Turns out to be some thoroughfare, not a "closed territory".</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, you are a smart fellow, walked the whole Zone, you say. So you should know that there is always a "Secret Path" through which one can pass unnoticed. Understand? Do you think they go through the checkpoint? No, of course, other paths lead into and out of the Zone. And Peacekeepers are good guys, true a bit dim-witted. Think everything is under control for them, but actually everything is a bit different. The territory here is large, and they don't control nearly all key points and not all routes are known to them. And they don't particularly want to climb and sort it out. \n\nAs long as everything is calm and peaceful, they remain confident in safety and complete order. They often drop by me for booze. We, so to speak, are "friends". This is not the Zone, after all, and who comes to my store doesn't concern them. Maybe guys from nearby villages stopped by, what's the big deal. Check documents and that's it. True, after the last emission everything changed here. Looks like the Zone started absorbing this previously free territory too. Look, anomalies started appearing here and there. And guys said they seemed to see mutants in the Forest. Such affairs. Peacekeepers will surely activate now.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_8">
    <text>Now understood. So still, where can I find Mahomet?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_9">
    <text>How would I know where his legs will carry him this time. He is a digger! Where he smells scent, there he goes. You, if you want, can wait for him here, in the village. In ten days he should come, or maybe earlier.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_10">
    <text>I don't have that much time. And can't contact him somehow? Ah yes, I forgot, trouble with connection here. What to do? I desperately need to talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, will try to help you. One person should come to me soon. They have a meeting with Mahomet scheduled somewhere in the Zone. Will try to find out from him where they planned to meet with Mahomet. Only favor for favor, while we are waiting anyway. You do something for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_12">
    <text>O-oh, now that's a business conversation! What needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_13">
    <text>Well, firstly, need to carry the answer to Barkeep. But that's later. First I must think about his proposal. And now you'll need to go to Peacekeepers base and carry five bottles of whiskey to General Smith. He asked to get some. And now, due to all these changes, need to be friends with Peacekeepers, otherwise they'll close my shop here in two counts. In short, carry five bottles to the General, say you are a messenger from me. I'll warn the General about you by radio. Fortunately, connection works at least within this territory. Talk to him, maybe help them with something else. Say you are local, live not far here, know these places well. If asked why with a weapon, say you work as a guide for military, understood? Well, Barkeep probably prepared you without me what to say. When you finish everything there, return to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_one_dialog_14">
    <text>Yes, understood everything. Give the bottles and I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="smith_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, General!</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah, courier from Sidorovich. Well, come on, what do you have there?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Here. Sidorovich passed something to you. Take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="smith_one_dialog_0">
    <text>How can I be useful, General?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I see you are not a simple guy. Look how armed. Not a saboteur by chance?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, I'm local. Moonlighting as a guide for military at Cordon. Now helping Sidorovich. My name is Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, Strelok. We trust Sidorovich. Local, you say? Means you should know these places well. We had an emergency here. A soldier disappeared, Corporal Foster. Was sent with a secret report to the Checkpoint. Delivered the report, but didn't return. Something is wrong here. Before everything was calm, but now, after this last emission, everything turned upside down. Looks like the Zone captured this section too. Anomalous activity is observed everywhere and mutated animals were seen repeatedly. Problems with connection too...</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah. All this I already noticed myself, not stupid. So what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_5">
    <text>You see, my people - they are soldiers. Just soldiers... They aren't supposed to think and make decisions. You are different... you are on your own. You survive, not live. You think and weigh every step, every action. In the end, you always make decisions yourself. Am I right? Ri-i-ight! I see through people like you. Loners... Keep to themselves... Well anyway, now your experience is exactly what we need.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_6">
    <text>General, enough philosophy. Let's get to business.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, agreed. Now is not the time for philosophy. Corporal Foster didn't return from the task. Need to find him. Get all details from Colonel Brown. Go to him. If you help us, we'll pay well.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_one_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay. Will help with what I can.</text>
</string>

<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Colonel Brown. General sent me to you. About the case of missing corporal.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah. Yes, yes, we are just looking for a person who can help us. The essence of the problem is: the corporal took documents to the Checkpoint and was supposed to return, but didn't return. It's been two days he's missing. We tracked his PDA signal. Signal is weak, but stable. Impossible to contact. Constant interference. Combed the whole square - unsuccessfully. He vanished into thin air. Basically, my people are simple soldiers. Need an experienced digger. I understand you work as a guide for military, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, correct. My name is Strelok. Give me the coordinates of the place where signal comes from, and I'll try to find the corporal or find out what happened to him there.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Give me your PDA, Strelok. I'll mark the search radius. Definitely find him. And if alive, bring Corporal Foster here, to the base. We won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. Mark the place, and I'm moving out for the search.</text>
</string>

<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found Corporal Foster, Colonel. Alive, healthy, delivered to base. Will tell everything himself later, what happened to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done! My fighters spent a whole day, but never found the corporal. And look how fast you managed. Expressing gratitude to you from all our leadership. And here is deserved monetary reward from us.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Glad to serve! Thank you.</text>
</string>
<string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wait. Too early to thank. There are more matters.</text>
</string>

<string id="foster_plen_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Corporal.</text>
</string>
<string id="foster_plen_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you! You are my savior! And I already thought that's it, I'm done for. These creatures will devour me for lunch. What is my savior's name?</text>
</string>
<string id="foster_plen_dialog_2">
    <text>Call me Strelok. How did you manage to end up here anyway, in such "friendly" company?</text>
</string>
<string id="foster_plen_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, don't ask... Don't understand myself. Seemed to walk the usual road, as always. Then something buzzed in the head, and some feeling appeared that someone is controlling me. And mainly, I don't want to resist... Well, can't explain better. And then suddenly boom and enlightenment. And you standing in front of me. How long was I here?</text>
</string>
<string id="foster_plen_dialog_4">
    <text>About two days, I assume. And what happened to you - is a Controller. He captured your mind and brought here, but, apparently, was full, so left you "for later". Well okay, time to get out of here, they are waiting for you at the base. Let's go, I'll escort you.</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>So what, Colonel, is there more work?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>There is. Just for such an experienced digger as you.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, you clearly exaggerate my abilities, Colonel. What is the matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>As you probably already know, here used to be absolutely ordinary territory - waiting room of the Zone. So to speak, a checkpoint. And after the last emission everything turned upside down. Looks like the Zone captured this section too. Anomalous activity is observed everywhere and mutated animals were seen repeatedly. Problems with connection too arose...</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah. All this I already noticed myself, not stupid. So what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_5">
    <text>The place where we are now is a forced coincidence. Actually, our main base is in another place. Not far here, in the south, is our main base. Only we had to leave it hurriedly, because after the last emission absolutely incomprehensible things started happening there. Everyone seemed to go crazy. Soldiers and officers started shooting each other, who remained alive, later shot himself. And after even worse. We had a scientist, so he went and disabled the radar. Without radar we are like without hands. Were cut off from the whole world. No connection, provisions running out, can't call for help. From "Big Land" they don't hurry here either, afraid. This is now Zone territory, turns out. And finally some mutants attacked the base. Had to retreat hurriedly from there. We blocked the gates when leaving. Imagine what is happening there now.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, "fun" you have here, Colonel. And what do you want to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_7">
    <text>Must win back the base by all means. Then will be necessary to fix the radar and establish connection. And you have the power to help us. You seem to be a specialist in all Zone wisdoms and all sorts of devilry. And there exactly anomalous things will be encountered. I and five more fighters will go with you. No more people. Can't abandon this temporary base either. Dangerous without normal security. So, agree? I won't remain in debt. Reward will be appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, persuaded. When moving out?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_9">
    <text>Leaving now. Cannot delay. Just don't rush, walk nearby. Five fighters will already wait for us there. We'll reach the base gates with you, meet my fighters, orient by situation and make a decision what to do next. Here, take an assault rifle, five packs of armor-piercing ammo, three F-1 grenades and several medkits and bandages.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_10">
    <text>Clear. Give weapons, ammo and let's go.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_11">
    <text>Here. Take and moving out.</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_vorota_dialog_0">
    <text>So? Everyone seems to be in place.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_vorota_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, everything in order. May Virgin Mary keep us all!</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_vorota_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood everything, Colonel. I'm going.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_vorota_dialog_3">
    <text>Go on, be careful there.</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_0">
    <text>So what, Colonel? Job done. Base under your control again.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, was a glorious hunt. Now need to bring everything in order here, and most importantly - fix the radar and restore connection. Thank you, Strelok, you helped us out. But that's not all. Here, take deserved reward for now. This is a universal repair kit with bio-electronic damage level scanning. Intended for repair of any type of small arms. Restores one hundred percent of damage. Created in secret military laboratory of Peacekeepers. Operation principle built on anomalous properties of "Jellyfish" artifact. To activate repair kit, presence of "Jellyfish" artifact in inventory is necessary. After each repair procedure "Jellyfish" artifact evaporates, transferring all its anomalous properties to activate bio-electronic scanner. Very rare thing. Use it.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_2">
    <text>O-oh, dreamed of such for a long time! Thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_0">
    <text>Colonel, you said that's not all. What did you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_1">
    <text>We returned the base to ourselves. That's good. But there is also an abandoned antenna. Not far here, northwest of the base. So. We had temporary connection there. Had... Until some treacherous creature appeared there. And had to leave the antenna following the base. Before you appeared, General Smith sent a small special forces squad there for reconnaissance, but they didn't return. Not even a weak signal from their PDA. How crappy without connection... We will urgently deal with radar restoration now.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_2">
    <text>You suggest organizing a raid there too?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_3">
    <text>No, not enough forces for assault now. Just need to quietly scout everything there and find out what happened to our fighters. You'll handle it, I know. I saw how you can do it. So, will you help once more?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, will help. What exactly needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_5">
    <text>Sneak there and look what is happening there now and what happened to our people. Find any traces of the missing squad. Then return to General Smith and report the situation to him. Take a couple of military medkits just in case and a couple of F-1 grenades.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. Going for reconnaissance.</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, General!</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_1">
    <text>And to you too, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Colonel Brown asked me to scout the territory of the old antenna, where you had temporary connection earlier and where your recon squad disappeared recently.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So what? Were you there? What did you manage to find out?</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_4">
    <text>I was there. Territory around antenna is swarming with zombies. Found the corpse of only one. He had a PDA, on which were his last words before death.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Oh you damn... How many people we lost in the last week. Well okay, we'll tune the radar, call helicopters and take all scum to hell out of here!</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Okay, General. Helped with what I could. If not needed anymore for now, I'll go to Sidorovich. One important matter awaits me there.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_7">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok. Helped us out greatly. From here we are on our own. Just that I have nothing particular to reward you with. We are in poverty ourselves: ammo, provisions and medicines running out. Well, except maybe I can guarantee you free passage to our territory at any time. Ah yes, here I have an assault rifle. But tight with ammo. Sorry.</text>
</string>
<string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_8">
    <text>Thank you! Will drop by you sometime later. And now time for me. See you and good luck! Here, take the PDA I found.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_two_dialog_0">
    <text>Sidorovich, here I am.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_two_dialog_1">
    <text>Returned? Well done! Did you take the whiskey to General Smith?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_two_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, delivered the whiskey. Then had to run and shoot a bit, at the Peacekeepers' request. Had to save someone there. Saved him. Also cleared their old base from mutants. Now they will try to fix the radar and restore connection. So things are getting better for them. And now I'm sort of "friends" with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_two_dialog_3">
    <text>I see. Means we can calm down for a while. While you were away, I wrote an answer for Barkeep here. Here, I ask you to pass the encrypted message to him on your way back.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_two_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay. Give me the letter, I'll pass it.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>And what about my question?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>So, listen here: that Stalker who has a meeting set with Mahomet came to see me. Basically, their meeting is scheduled somewhere in the Dead City, on the outskirts. You'll find him there. Don't delay too much. How to get to the Dead City, I think you'll figure out.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>How will I figure out how to get to the Dead City? I have only one lead - it's the Wanderers on the Swamps. Grig is in charge there, he surely knows. Or the Swamp Doctor. But first I need to get to the Swamps. And how?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>You are reasoning correctly. You need to go to Yantar to the scientists. They possibly know safe paths to the Swamps and, maybe, even to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood everything. Thank you very much! Means my path is to Yantar now.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes. But don't forget to pass the letter to Barkeep at the Cordon, since you undertook to help.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_magomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Don't worry, I'll do it. See you!</text>
</string>

<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day! Are you called Mahomet?</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>Na-ah, I'm Fima. And who are you? And why are you looking for Mahomet?</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I have personal business with Mahomet. Sid told me that I could find Mahomet here. He was supposed to have a meeting here. Apparently with you, as I understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, so that's it... Well yes, Mahomet was here. We really met here. So you are a bit late. Mahomet left. Where to - I don't know.</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Da-amn! How can that be... I'm late. Unbelievable. And I need this Mahomet so much. Do you surely not know where he can be found now? I'll pay well for information.</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_5">
    <text>I don't need your money. I really don't know where he headed now. Mahomet never spreads word about where he goes next. He is a loner. But Sid told me about you, that a stalker nicknamed "Strelok" craves a meeting with Mahomet. So it means it's you?</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, it's me. But what should I do now? I have no idea...</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_7">
    <text>Don't worry so much. I told Mahomet about you, that Strelok wanted to meet him very much. Very much. Mahomet couldn't wait, so he left. He will find you himself. As they say: "If the mountain won't come to Mahomet - Mahomet goes to the mountain". So don't worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_8">
    <text>How will he find me? Should I sit in one place and wait?</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_9">
    <text>I'm telling you - he will find you! You just don't know Mahomet. If he said he'll find, means he'll find. Moreover, he said he heard about your exploits and wouldn't mind meeting you himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="drug_magomet_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I understood. I will hope that he really finds me. Thank you. Whatever happens. See you.</text>
</string>





<string id="leila_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Chieftess!</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Haven't seen you in a while, Strelok. What successes? Found the brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>No, haven't found the brother yet, but I definitely will. I'm here on another matter now.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>And what matter brought you to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't even know how to start... Basically, I turned out to be slightly aware of your relationships with Clear Sky members. Including about your sister Karina I learned... Anyway, closer to business: Sviblov sent me here. Karina left to you a few days ago and disappeared.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>What are you saying!? She was here. Came with a guide. They left three days ago. So she didn't return to Radar?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>No, didn't return. Sviblov sent people to search, but they disappeared too.</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>Sviblov... idiot! Never liked him... Yes, our relationship with Clear Sky is not entirely smooth, but he could have at least informed about my sister. What a bastard! I'm so angry...</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, don't boil over. Which road did she take back?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>She said she knows the road well. They went through the Forest with her guide, since there is no return path from here to Radar, so only through the Forest. She said it's no more than half a kilometer there to the exit to Radar, and along the edge of the Forest at that. Supposedly safe places. What happened there? Need to send someone to search. And my people have never been to the Forest, this territory is unfamiliar to us...</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_10">
    <text>Let's do this: since I volunteered to help find your sister, then I should go to the Forest. That territory is familiar to me, plus Forester lives there, will help if anything. And there are hunters too. They surely know something. By the way, is the path to the Forest in the same place?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_11">
    <text>Yes, the passage to the Forest is still where it was before. Here, just in case, I'll send the mark of the transition start to your PDA. Just I beg you very much, as soon as something clears up about my sister, inform me immediately by any means. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="leila_karina_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, of course. Well, I'm going to the Forest.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Father! Long time no see.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you, Strelok. How is your search?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>Still nothing so far. But there is hope. I need to find one experienced digger nicknamed Mahomet. He can shed light on this whole tangled and mystical story with my brother. By the way, do you know this digger? Where can he be found?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>No, son, I don't know such a man. And what brought you to the Forest to the old man again?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, firstly, to visit you, and secondly, a matter turned up. A girl disappeared, Leila's sister. They say she went from the Dead City to Radar through the Forest. Three days already, as she disappeared: no news, no trace. Maybe got lost. Do you know anything about this?</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>No, haven't seen any girl here. Better ask the hunters. They are still hunting here. Stayed a bit late this time. Apparently want to collect more tails and hooves, or maybe something else.</text>
</string>
<string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, thank you. I'll go to the hunters, find out what's what. Maybe they'll help find Leila's sister.</text>
</string>


<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to fearless hunters!</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>What, Strelok? Decided to hunt with us or on another matter?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>I hunted enough while wandering the Zone searching for my brother. I came to you on business.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, speak out, what business brought you to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>You see, a girl disappeared here. Went from Dead City to Radar through the forest with a guide, but never reached Radar. Three days passed already. Maybe you know something? Saw them here?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, listen, you came to the right address. Just yesterday evening Grek and Mazay went to the bridge and, when returning, said they saw three people from afar. Seems like two old women and a young girl with them. Were dragging along the road towards the tunnel. Well, Grek and Mazay decided it was someone from the locals who live in the village closest to the Forest, you never know why they walk here. My guys didn't approach and scare them, we don't need it, we try not to interfere in anything. Although, they say, they were a bit strange, the girl looked sick.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>Wow! And where did your eagles see these three?</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>Right here in the forest, let me mark the place on the map for you. There is an old bridge, a tunnel next to it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Thank you. I'll go, maybe I'll catch up with them yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>Go on, dare, Strelok.</text>
</string>

<string id="babka_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, grandmother.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, dear man. What brought you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for a girl. Called Karina. Hunters told me they allegedly saw two old women and a young girl with them recently. I understand, that's you.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, you pra-a-ankster! Want a girl? Well, then you came to the right place. We have a girl. Young, beautiful. And inexpensive. Only three thousand rubles. Give the money and amuse yourself, relax. Our girl is very good, you won't regret it.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_4">
    <text>What are you saying! I didn't come for this. I have a task to find a girl named Karina. I must talk to her. Let me in. I need to see Karina.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_5">
    <text>O-oh, dear, don't confuse us. Find, see, talk, then want to touch, and then something else... Sli-i-y one! Anyway: pay first, and only then enter and do what you want with her. Our granddaughter is affectionate and responsive. And if you think of misbehaving, my sister will blow your head off with the gun in a flash! So, will you pay?</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_6">
    <text>I don't have money now. I'll go try to get some from the hunters.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, to hell with you, old perverts. Here is three thousand rubles, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="babka_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, hold on, boy!</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Karina.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_1">
    <text>O-oh, how my head is splitting... What is wrong with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Nothing scary, will pass soon. Need to drink vodka, helps.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_3">
    <text>And who are you? Where am I?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't worry, I'm a friend. Controllers captured you, decided to use as bait. But now everything is fine. They are no more. My name is Strelok. I came for you, Sviblov sent me.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_5">
    <text>Lord, everything is like in a fog... Everything is floating... Sviblov? And where am I now?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_6">
    <text>We are in the Forest. You were walking from your sister Leila from Dead City to Radar. Walked with a guide. Remember at least this?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, remembering now... Guide... Those... those creatures killed him! There, on the hill. Only he knew the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_8">
    <text>So. Do I understand correctly that you don't know how to get out of the Forest to Radar?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_9">
    <text>Do I look like a stalker or digger? Of course I don't know!</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_10">
    <text>I see. Thought so. But we must get you out of here somehow. Any thoughts? I know there is a path to Army Warehouses here. Maybe there?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_11">
    <text>No, no, can't go there. Enemies there. Need to find the guide's body. He should have a PDA in his pocket with encrypted data about secret paths. I know the code. Find the PDA, means we can get out somewhere from the Forest. Must search. Let's go, I'll show approximately the place where those creatures killed him. I remember. We'll reach the place, and there I'll remember where to search.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_help_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay, let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_pda_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, are we there?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I remember exactly. The guide died here. While I was still conscious, I saw them dragging him here. We absolutely must find the guide's corpse and take his PDA. Otherwise we won't get out of here. I'm scared...</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, I'll try to find. Wait here, don't be afraid. If anything, scream, I'll come to rescue.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found your guide's corpse.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Did you take the PDA?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So... Let's see what paths are in the Forest.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Well, what's there?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Don't rush me! Now, wait... Aha, here: From the Forest one can go only to Swamps now. No way to Radar... Well okay then. Everyone annoyed me. Both Sviblov and my sister. Everyone is annoying, bickering among themselves like dogs... I'll go to Doctor. He is a kind man. Especially since I helped him in his clinic once. So it's decided, going to the Swamps to Doctor!</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Well, to the Swamps, then to the Swamps. Lead, beauty.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>It's okay, everything is fine, don't be afraid. What a beast! Main thing, sneaked up so unnoticed... Apparently followed us the whole way. Well anyway. What do we have here? Transition to Swamps here?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Whew! Almost peed myself from fear... Yes, transition is here. To the left of me is a hole. Need to go down there, transition will be there. Only can't predict to which place of the Swamps it will throw. Every time and with everyone it's different. So let's agree: you go first. If in a minute I'm not near, means we meet in Swamp Doctor's house. Yes, by the way, I never thanked you for my rescue. Sorry... Thank you, Strelok! You saved my ass.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't mention it. Saving your ass was a pleasure! By the way, I paid three thousand to controllers for you...</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh-oh, how cool we are! Just no need to be rude. Okay, that's it, time to go.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, we stayed too long here. Time.</text>
</string>




<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_0">
    <text>Beauty, you ended up on the spot faster than me.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, "threw" me right near the gazebo in front of Doctor's house. And what took you so long?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_2">
    <text>And I ended up in the southern part of Swamps, so had to get here practically swimming. My feet are all wet. Should dry them, although time is short and plenty of things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, things will wait. Rest. This is probably the calmest place in the whole Zone. I, perhaps, will stay here with Doctor. Will help him.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_4">
    <text>How so? And Sviblov? And Leila? They worry about you. Need to inform them that you are alive and healthy.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry. Doctor will inform via Grig, and I'll contact Sviblov myself later.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_6">
    <text>Well okay, as you wish... Listen, how do I leave the Swamps now?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_7">
    <text>O-oh, that you need to go to Doctor. Ask him.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_bolota_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay. Going to talk to Doc.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Doc, good day.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you, Strelok. Thank you for saving Karina. She already told me briefly about your adventures.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>Trifles. Been in worse scrapes.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>No, Strelok. I haven't met such a brave stalker as you for a long time. You have a brave heart, kind soul and pure thoughts. Such a set is rarely met in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, thank you, of course, for the compliment, Doc. Only I have a question for you: how to get out of Swamps. Well, somewhere closer to the Bar?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>I will help you. I have a guide dog named Barbos. He will show you one of the most secret and long paths of the Zone - transition from Swamps through Dead City to Army Warehouses. This path was discovered by my faithful friend and guide Pathfinder. But first I will ask you to do one thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>Listening to you attentively, Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>I have a transmitter and antenna installed in the southern part of Swamps, in one of the old wooden houses. It is the best, and, basically, the only place in this part of Swamps for signal reception. So, recently the antenna broke three times already. Never happened before... I went first time - fixed it. Went second time - fixed it. Well, thought, wind or birds breaking it. Moved the transmitter to a slightly different place and again the same thing. I went there the third time. Arrived at the spot, look - no transmitter. \n\nWalked around and found it in a completely different place. And such a feeling arose that someone is watching me, looking at my back. Turned around - no one. Listened and hear some barely distinguishable sounds. As if a child is sobbing quietly. Definitely not a bird. I thought then: maybe, Water Spirit? Ran chills over the skin from all this. I stopped fearing any living creature long ago, but here... Basically, I quickly moved the transmitter and antenna to another place again and left there. But shortly before you and Karina arrived, again the same song.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Some devilry.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>That's what I'm saying... So, Strelok, I beg you very much, go there, maybe at least you manage to find the reason. Find out who or what is constantly breaking my antenna. Yes, and take the transmitter from there, I'm tired of all this mysticism. Better arrange with Grig and put it at the Wanderers' checkpoint. Although the signal is not very good there, I'll be calmer. I'll send the mark where my antenna is installed to your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, Doc. Will go, look what's what and bring your device. Put mark in PDA. I'll be quick.</text>
</string>





<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I returned, Doc. And you were right when assumed it could be a Water Spirit...</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Didn't understand you, Strelok. What do you mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_2">
    <text>That in the place where your receiver was installed, a family of real Water Spirits settled. Creepy creatures, I tell you... Almost invisible. Instead of blood some acid splashes. Horror.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So that's it... How many more miracles does the Zone prepare for us? Well okay. Brought the device?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes. Here is your device, take it.</text>
</string>





<string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_0">
    <text>So what, Doc, now your guide will lead me to the transition to Dead City?</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, of course, Strelok. Now you can go. The guide will take you. Just remember, to find the way back from Army Warehouses to Swamps... And this path will be useful to you yet, I am sure of it. You will need to talk to Pathfinder. Here, pass this flash drive to him from me, he will understand everything and show you the way back. That's all. And now, as they say, run after the "White Rabbit". My dog is waiting for you in the yard near the house. He will take you to the place where the path starts. Look, protect him, so he doesn't get into anything. This is a very valuable dog. I picked him up as a puppy, cured him and raised him into a guide, an unsurpassed seeker of "Secret Paths".</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood, Doc. Will definitely visit Pathfinder and pass the flash drive to him. All right, I'm going. See you!</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_3">
    <text>Goodbye, Strelok. Go with God!</text>
</string>


<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Pathfinder!</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_1">
    <text>What did you want, Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_2">
    <text>Doctor passed something for you here.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_3">
    <text>You were at Doctor's on Swamps? How did you get there?</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_4">
    <text>Long story. Ended up there by accident. Was rescuing one person from trouble. Doctor passes some flash drive to you. Here, take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_5">
    <text>Give it. Let's see what's there... Aha, clear. So, and what else did he pass?</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_0">
    <text>He also said that you can show me the secret path from Army Warehouses to Swamps through Dead City. I just came here by it. But to the return end...</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_1">
    <text>Well, since Doctor said, means I'll help you. Especially since this path is very, very convenient and will surely be useful. But there is one "but". You can open this path only with the help of one very rare artifact, which bears the name "Superconductor". It was named "Superconductor" for its ability to shift space for a long time and thereby create spatial corridors, so-called "Secret Paths", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. Differs from its "younger brothers", conductors of lower order, in that it activates transitions along several routes at once. To activate, just pick up this artifact. One but: finding this artifact is extremely difficult. It appears in a short period of time, approximately during one hour, somewhere between one and two o'clock at night. If you don't find it during this time, the artifact disappears. So that's how it is...</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_2">
    <text>Ve-ery interesting. Will try to find this superconductor. The path is painfully important. Will surely be useful in the future. Suggest at least approximate place where it can be found.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_3">
    <text>Well, since the path it should open starts at Warehouses, means need to search at Warehouses. In other places, in the Zone, I met it only once. As you probably guessed - on Swamps. Where exactly to look at Warehouses is hard to say, but I think in hard-to-reach places. Just remember, %c[red]time for its search is limited to only one hour: between one and two o'clock at night.%c[default] If you find it, drag it to me. Will open the transition from Warehouses to Swamps through Dead City for you. Yes, and also: %c[red]You will have three days for the search, maximum four.%c[default] Then for a whole month there will be extremely unfavorable conditions for its appearance. So don't drag with time.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_4">
    <text>Everything is clear to me. Yes, not a simple task, but I solved harder ones. So I will definitely find "Superconductor" and bring it to you so you open the path to Swamps.</text>
</string>


<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Pathfinder!</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_1">
    <text>What business, Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I found the "Superconductor"! Here.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wow! You really are an experienced seeker. Let's see where the path interesting to us starts at Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Hold.</text>
</string>


<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_0">
    <text>What business do you have, Barkeep?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_1">
    <text>While you were away, Sidorovich and I fully agreed on how to pull off one big deal. Few details left and that's it. All past discords between him and me are in the past now. Now we are partners. Basically, Strelok, your help will be needed. If everything works out, you will receive a very large reward for your labors.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_2">
    <text>And what is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_3">
    <text>I can't tell you all details yet, but one of the important conditions for our business is support of Duty members. I almost agreed on everything with Voronin. Now we need to meet Sidorovich personally. The meeting is scheduled for the nearest time on the territory of Station "Glubokoe", in the abandoned village. Sid will surely come with security. I also need a person I can trust to be nearby. You are the best candidate for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_4">
    <text>That is, I must escort you to the meeting with Sidorovich. Right?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, right. But first I will ask you to carry an encrypted note to Voronin and give it to him personally in hands. We'll go to the territory of Station "Glubokoe" secretly and separately. Don't meddle through Peacekeepers Checkpoint. They shouldn't guess anything. So you will go to Station "Glubokoe" through Dark Valley. Voronin will show you the secret path there when you give him my message. And I'll go my own way. I know one short path to Peacekeepers. We'll meet there, not far from the abandoned village. I'll let you know where exactly. When you cross from Dark Valley to Peacekeepers territory, I'll drop a message to your PDA. Understood everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, everything is clear. Give the letter, and I'm off to Voronin.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>General. I came to you from Barkeep with an encryption.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you, Strelok. You are just like a reconnaissance spy, carrying encryptions.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>That's Barkeep. Keeps encrypting: Business, he says, is very secret, and no one should know anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_3">
    <text>Ye-eah, they started a grandiose business with Sidorovich. It just so happened that our interest is in this business too. So a large number of people will be involved. And for the time being no one should know anything, otherwise it will be a failure.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand everything, that's why I don't interfere with questions. Here, take the message from Barkeep. By the way, Barkeep said you will show me the path from Dark Valley to Peacekeepers.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, I'll show. Give PDA, will mark the place where the transition to peacekeepers territory starts.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_6">
    <text>Here is PDA. Mark and I'm moving out.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_strelka_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Barkeep, where are we going?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_strelka_dialog_1">
    <text>Right nearby here. Follow me. While we talk with Sid, don't eavesdrop. As we finish, I'll tell you what to do next. Is everything clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_strelka_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, everything clear. Let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_posle_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, agreed on everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_posle_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, now all i's are dotted. Everything will be decided soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_posle_dialog_2">
    <text>What are the further actions?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_posle_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen to me carefully. Sid and I need to chat about something else face to face. And you must go to Voronin again and pass him one more letter, the last one. It has final instructions, as they say, safe houses-passwords for our common business. Then I myself will go to Duty guys, but later. And Sidorovich will take my place in the bunker at Cordon. This is the first stage of our plan. After you give the message to Voronin, he will pass you an answer for Sidorovich. Sid will be at Cordon by that time. You'll carry the answer to him, and he will say what to do next. Comprehended?</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_posle_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, everything clear. Gone to Voronin.</text>
</string>


<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, General.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok, how are things?</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_2">
    <text>Everything seems fine. Barkeep met with Sidorovich. I gathered they finally discussed all details. Here, Barkeep passes one more encryption on your common business. Says, as you read, write an answer for Sidorovich. Sidorovich is moving to Cordon now, and Barkeep said he will come to you soon.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, give the message. Let's see what those sly faces invented there.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_4">
    <text>Here is the letter, General.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_5">
    <text>So-so, let's see what Barkeep writes... Aha, look how they propose... Clear, clear. Okay, let's try this way... Strelok, here is my answer for Sidorovich. Carry it to him at Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_6">
    <text>Come on, General. Will carry.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Sidorovich! New shop, congratulations!</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you. Just dealing with goods right now. Doing audit, so to speak. And wouldn't hurt to clean up here. In a couple of days can start trading... Did you bring the answer from Voronin?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, of course. Here is the letter.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so. Let's see what our brave General writes... We-ell, very good! Voronin gives go-ahead and ready to start. Well, means time of great achievements has come.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_4">
    <text>So, does it mean I did my job? Barkeep promised a worthy reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait, Strelok. The job is not done yet. The hardest part is ahead. And we really need your help.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_6">
    <text>And what else is required of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, will reveal our cards to you so you understand the whole importance of the moment. Barkeep and I used to feud heavily over zones of influence. He always said I lure his clients, lower prices on goods and so on. I, in turn, also had a mass of claims to him. Became unbearable to work in such spirit further, and Barkeep made the first step and proposed the following: I move here, to Cordon, and engage in honest trade at his old place. Part of his clients automatically switch to me. He, in turn, wanted very much to move to the Bar. But, as you know, thugs have been running things there for a long time. And here Barkeep invented a sly exit.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_8">
    <text>And what is it? Bandits sit very tight in the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_9">
    <text>That's the difficulty. But only recently a new warlike faction Duty appeared, which would very much like to make a powerful base on the Bar territory. But alone they can't overcome bandits yet. Barkeep didn't have connections among Duty members then to come out to them with a proposal to unite efforts. And I happened to be a supplier of provisions for Voronin and his fighters and had certain respect with them. Barkeep asked me to introduce him to Voronin. I did it. We three talked and decided to act together. Barkeep organizes secret movement of Duty strike squad to the northern deserted territory of the Bar, and I organize a diversionary maneuver, set mercenaries on the southern checkpoint of the Bar. Bandits, of course, will lay down mercs, but mercs will batter them good too. And just then sudden strike from the north and capture of the Bar by Duty members. After which Barkeep occupies his rightful place in the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_10">
    <text>Look what you stirred up. Ho-o-oly cow... Bold, can't say anything. And what help can be from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_11">
    <text>And you, Strelok, are virtually a key figure in this case. Missing a small detail to execute the plan. For successful attack a detailed map of the Bar is needed. But there is no one to get it or draw. And you, as far as we know, have a decent reputation with the Thugs, right? So we ask you to get the map of the Bar and pass it to the commander of the assault squad. And so that thugs in the Bar respect you even more, you will just slightly help them overcome mercenaries at the southern checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_12">
    <text>You guys are dragging me into some scam! Well, okay, and where will I get a map in the Bar? Or do you propose I measure everything and draw it?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_13">
    <text>Just listen first. The plan is sure. We thought through everything to the details. Borov has the map, that's for sure. After you help defend the southern checkpoint from mercs, propose to Borov to strengthen both checkpoints to secure from further similar dangers. Say that you have familiar guys, former builders, specialists in fortifications, who will organize everything in best form and cheaply. Bandits themselves will never do anything, but if proposed such, they will agree with joy. They are thugs, but not fools. And to do everything correctly and wisely, ask Borov for a detailed map of the territory, on which you allegedly need to put necessary measurements and calculate everything in detail. He will give you the map with joy.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_14">
    <text>Okay, persuaded. Will try to help you. Hope the reward will be worthy.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_15">
    <text>Well, that's great! Means agreed. Now go to the Bar, and I'll inform Barkeep to give go-ahead to Duty members. When you take the map, exit through northern checkpoint and to the right, to transition to Warehouses. A Duty squad will wait for you there in ambush. Give the map to the commander, and then... Well, and then an extra gun won't hurt them.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_16">
    <text>What am I getting into, huh? Well okay. Cannot die twice, cannot avoid one death. Only I have good acquaintances left in the Bar. Should warn them, because, as I understand, there will be a devilish meat grinder. What if in confusion they get it too.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_17">
    <text>Strelok, if you are about Count and Pathfinder, you can not worry. They are aware of affairs. It is with the help of Count's trick we managed to set mercenaries on the southern checkpoint. Come on, hurry, time doesn't wait. If you have any business left with them, don't delay. Unlikely you will be able to find these guys in the bar later.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_18">
    <text>Clear, moving out.</text>
</string>


<string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Something else?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes. One person stopped by here, was looking for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>What person?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>Pleasant surprise! He is probably already waiting for you at the entrance to my bunker.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay. I like surprises.</text>
</string>


<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Something else?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Strelok. My intelligence reported that you treated Peacekeepers badly: Stole some body armor from them. And it came out sideways for my old buddy... Mahomet.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_2">
    <text>Wow! And I'm looking for him... And what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_3">
    <text>After you stole armor from Peacekeepers, terrible fuss rose there. They put ambushes everywhere. And Mahomet was just walking to me by secret path from Dark Valley. Well, by the one I told you about. And you, apparently, brought a tail to the transition. Get it?</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, I get it... Only I had no other choice then!</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_5">
    <text>Choice always exists, Strelok. You just didn't want to think. Because of this a good man died. Peacekeepers killed him... He ran into their ambush and got a bullet in the forehead. They were waiting for you there, but Mahomet got caught accidentally.</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Damn... Pity Mahomet. Forgive me. And now I won't find the brother.</text>
</string>


<string id="magomet_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello... And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I am Mahomet. Didn't expect to meet me here, Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Holy cow! What a meeting! How long I searched for you, Mahomet!</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_3">
    <text>They told you I'd find you myself. So I found. Well, tell, why did you search for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_4">
    <text>On a very important matter for me, Mahomet. I'm looking for my brother. Called Captain. Several years ago he was in that very group which first attempted to get to the CNPP territory, into the Sarcophagus. Together with him were several other brave stalkers, including Yuri Semetsky. And I have information that you met Semetsky alive and unharmed. So, if Semetsky remained alive, then, possibly, my brother is alive too. Because then only they two from the whole group went inside the sarcophagus... Tell what you know on this matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_5">
    <text>So that's it, Strelok! Actually no one believes me that I met alive Semetsky. But this is pure truth. And I met him twice. First time it was about year and a half ago. Then I saw him briefly in the Forest on Radar. He looked, let's say, not very good. Either zombie or human - couldn't make out. But it was definitely him, I'm sure of it. There, in the Forest, were plenty of anomalies and mutants, and he disappeared somewhere quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_6">
    <text>And the second time when?</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Second time quite recently, about two months ago. It was near Pripyat, in abandoned hospital. I just led a small group of stalkers to Pripyat and was returning through hospital to Yantar. That's where I met him... Yes, a sight not for faint-hearted. Little human left in him, walking corpse. He didn't let me close. Muttered something about "Monolith". About that he has long been a hostage of some "dark forces" and his own stupidity. Also said that he must fulfill his mission - destroy this "devil stone". Basically, some delirium... Yes, as it seemed to me, he wasn't talking to me at all, but to himself. But in any case, if you want to figure out what actually happened many years ago with your brother, you need to find Semetsky and somehow try to talk to him. Only he will be able to help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Ye-eah, story... Where do you think one can find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_9">
    <text>I think at CNPP, in Sarcophagus. As I understood from his words, he was going exactly there. To fulfill some delirious mission of his.</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_10">
    <text>In Sarcophagus, then... Yeah, rotten place. But nothing to be done. Have to go. Just will finish one business and go. Maybe I'll get lucky, and find out something...</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_11">
    <text>Well then, good luck to you, Strelok. Glad to meet you.</text>
</string>
<string id="magomet_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Thank you for everything, Mahomet. And see you.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_new_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Barkeep! Well, everything seems normal.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_new_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, buddy, you helped us very much. Thank you!</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_new_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, thank you won't feed you...</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_new_dialog_3">
    <text>You offend me. I didn't forget that promised to reward you generously. Here, take. From all of us for your invaluable help one hundred thousand money and a machine gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_new_dialog_4">
    <text>O-oh, truly generous. Thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, sister!</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_1">
    <text>And you are incorrigible, Strelok. Still being rude.</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on! Zombies destroyed. Life is getting better!</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok, for helping us get rid of zombies once again. We are leaving the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_4">
    <text>Why so? Did something happen?</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_5">
    <text>No, just became too dangerous here. City became not so "dead" now. These zombies constantly climbing... Basically, we are leaving. Enough for us.</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_6">
    <text>Clear. But it seems to me matter is not in zombies and not in dangers. Something else here, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, you are right, Strelok, matter is in something else... We are leaving the Zone completely. That's it, enough for us... Now can tell you the truth. We were looking for a very rare artifact here - "Wind Rose". This artifact could help thousands of people get rid of a terrible disease, but we never found it... Apparently it doesn't exist. All were legends. So farewell. Don't hold a grudge, if anything. And I have absolutely nothing to reward you with for help...</text>
</string>
<string id="mg_nechist_dialog_8">
    <text>Come on. Don't worry, sister. Farewell, time for me to go further.</text>
</string>


<string id="kristall_dialog_0">
    <text>I came for my brother!</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_1">
    <text>Your brother is not here, human. There is only enlightened mind freed from everything superfluous and mundane. Mind capable of creating miracles and ruling the world.</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother! I know you are there... You are inside. Fight! They captured your mind! But you are human! Fight!</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_3">
    <text>Stupid monkey... You can change nothing! Step away and don't interfere. I propose you to watch and enjoy the great spectacle before death. Soon we start our performance. Not long left now. It will be a grandiose show, triumph of the power of freed mind!</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_4">
    <text>Brother, Wake up! Wake up, Captain! I know you hear me. It's me, Strelok!</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't waste strength in vain before death, human. Better relax and enjoy the great and grandiose spectacle. Today the World will become different.</text>
</string>
<string id="kristall_dialog_6">
    <text>I didn't walk here for so long to be a dull observer and give up so simply! I learned a lot. Here, catch! This is "Wind Rose". Greetings from Semetsky!</text>
</string>

<string id="brat_dialog_0">
    <text>Brother, it's you!</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok! Kid, you found me... How glad I am to see you! How did you manage?</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother, about this later. I also have a mass of questions for you. But now must get out of here faster.</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_3">
    <text>Kid, I'm too weak to go anywhere now. Head... My head... Like a cast-iron bell... Legs... legs like cotton... Listen to me, brother: practically no time. The fact that you managed to free me from this captivity essentially changes nothing... The process of Zone rebirth is already launched. You just delayed its beginning a little. Go alone, save yourself! And my place, looks like, is here after all... Go, brother! One of us must remain alive and get out of this cursed Zone! Not far here, at northern gates, there is a transition to CNPP-2. From there I think you'll find the way. At least, I hope for it very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_4">
    <text>No, Captain, I won't leave you! Listen to me now: I have an individual one-time teleporter, which from any place of the Zone can throw one person to Swamps to Doctor. So the layout is this: you take the device and teleport to Doctor. You need his help oh so much right now. And I will come a bit later. I will get out, don't worry. In the end, I got here, means can get back too.</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_5">
    <text>Kid, you don't understand what and whom you are dealing with! They won't let you leave so simply, believe me. I know what I'm saying. Practically no time.</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_6">
    <text>Captain, let's not waste precious minutes! Take the teleporter and blow to Doctor, and I'm on my own. Don't worry! I'll be quick.</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_7">
    <text>Kid, and you grew up... You are not that young romantic you were before. You became an adult man, a warrior. I see fire in your eyes. Okay, let it be as you propose. But only I beg you, don't get involved in anything. Just run and don't look back. Transition to CNPP-2, as I said, somewhere at northern gates. Oh, my heart feels, they won't let you pass just like that. Okay, give teleporter and let's go. God keep you, Kid! Absolutely no time left. Soon will begin...</text>
</string>
<string id="brat_dialog_8">
    <text>Here. Take the individual teleporter and see you, brother.</text>
</string>


<string id="end_dialog_0">
    <text>How can this be???</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_1">
    <text>And hello again! Unexpected, yes? And we warned: shouldn't waste strength and energy on dubious activities. Did you really think that here, in the Zone, you can make decisions and act independently?</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_2">
    <text>I always make decisions myself and act as my mind and heart tell me!</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_3">
    <text>We have another opinion on this account... Well okay. You freed the brother. That's good. Well done! It was intended so. You delayed the Great Emission for some time. There is nothing scary in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you mean "it was intended so"?</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_5">
    <text>And it means that you proved your great power once again. True, you turned out insufficiently agile to run away from us. But that is good! And your brother... Your brother is not needed to us anymore. He worked out his resource...\nNOW YOU WILL TAKE HIS PLACE!</text>
</string>
<string id="end_dialog_6">
    <text>No-o-o-o!</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day! I understand you are Sorcerer?</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Understanding correctly, stalker. What brought you to me?</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_2">
    <text>One person told me that you can revive the dead. I don't particularly believe in it, but dropped by to find out for interest sake.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You weren't deceived. It is really so. This is the ZONE, and there are so many miracles in it you never dreamed of. Practically any person who died within limits of anomalous activity of the Zone, I can return to life, or rather create his clone. True, it won't be quite a human anymore, but a zombie. But most importantly his mind and memory for some time will be in the state they were before his death.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Is it really possible? But how?</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_5">
    <text>How - is not your worry. I was "on the other side of the world" and returned from there with such knowledge. So, if you want to return a dead man to this world, I am ready to help you. Only it won't be cheap. Cost of my labors is one hundred thousand rubles. And also: Resurrect a person by your request will be possible only in case if not you killed him. Clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I understood everything. If suddenly I need to return someone to life, even for a while, I will definitely contact you.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Lapsha".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Lapsha" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Skinflint".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Skinflint" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Screw".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Screw" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Lukash".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Lukash" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_dan_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Dan".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_dan_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Dan" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_dan_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_dan_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Lefty".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Lefty" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased named Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return Sviblov to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>


<string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to return to life deceased nicknamed "Snitch".</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_1">
    <text>Well then, knew such one. Give one hundred thousand and I return "Snitch" to this world. He will appear right here, nearby, so don't get scared. For some time he will be a bit "out of it", but not for long. Already in a couple of minutes you'll be able to talk to him normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_2">
    <text>Eh, don't have enough money. Going to collect.</text>
</string>
<string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take money.</text>
</string>

<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Screw!</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_1">
    <text>And you too don't fall ill, Strelok. What business to me?</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, want to charge the homemade flamethrower from Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, let's try, but you understand yourself, not for free.</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_4">
    <text>And what do you ask for work?</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, first, you need a fireball to charge the flamethrower. Second, my fee is a modest reward - two bottles of vodka and 10,000 cash. Deal? If yes, bring me everything on the list and you'll get your mixture.</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I won't haggle. Here you go.</text>
</string>
<string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll come back later.</text>
</string>

<string id="vano_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Sobered up, Vano?</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Eh, dea-ar! From where know me? What is your name?</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_2">
    <text>The whole Zone talks only about you, that Vano is the most notorious drunkard and brawler. Worthless person. And my name is Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey, Strelok! Why you say so bad about Vano, huh? What bad did I do to you? Vano is kind and cheerful. Vano offends no one.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Just look at your drunk face! You'll croak soon if you don't quit boozing. Baker is a good man, worries about you, and you let him down. Look, he can't even entrust any serious business to you. You lost his trust.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Come on, friend. Vano controls situation. Vano is good man. Vano soon will go to "Freedom" guys. There Vano will be like at home. But here Vano is bored...</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_6">
    <text>They won't let you within a kilometer there! Bullet in the forehead and done. Freedom guys are serious and won't let any rubbish in.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Vano is not rubbish! Vano is scout. Vano tracked marauders who hung around here for whole week. And Vano learned something important.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_8">
    <text>And what so important was Vano able to learn?</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_9">
    <text>And you don't laugh. Vano pursued marauders from Peacekeepers base itself. Marauders stole a box with mines from Peacekeepers and carried it to abandoned village. But only didn't reach there... Swamp creature ate them a little on the swamp... If Vano had assault rifle, then Vano would deal with them himself. But so Vano only hid and watched how they ran from there, abandoning the looted.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_10">
    <text>So need to go pick up that box and return to Peacekeepers. They are generous guys, will give good reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_11">
    <text>No-no. Peacekeepers evil. They once treated Vano badly. Vano doesn't love them. Vano proposes this: you walk with such gun, and Vano has no weapon. And Vano afraid and little sick now... Therefore go to swamp, pick up box from there and bring it to Vano. Vano will take this box and carry to Freedom guys. For this they will respect Vano and take to them. So, will you bring? And Vano won't stay in debt. Vano will give you part of mines from that box. Vano honest man.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay, hell with you. Give the mark where approximately to search for the box there. Maybe I'll go.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_13">
    <text>That is good! Everything simple. Swamp is very close here. Vano will put mark on map for you. Need to search for box in the swamp itself. It's shallow, near broken helicopter. Just look out, Strelok, be careful there. And on way back be attentive too. Marauders hang around here constantly. Although they are cowardly creatures, but there are many of them. That makes them dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_14">
    <text>Put mark. Will try to find box with mines in swamp.</text>
</string>

<string id="vano_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Enough boozing, Vano! You'll croak soon from vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes... You are right, stalker. Must quit drinking...</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I found the box with mines in the swamp. Ran into marauders on the way back. But nothing, dealt with them. Warded off trouble from you and Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wah, dear! Well done! Give it to me quickly! If you want, we can mine the whole base of these Peacekeeper bastards. Will be fun to watch how scum fly into air!</text>
</string>
<string id="vano_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>No, thanks for "wise" advice, but you deal with Peacekeepers yourself, only I don't advise you. Okay, hold the box with mines.</text>
</string>

<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_0">
    <text>So? Recovered, darling?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah you, basement rats! Cowardly creatures! Only know how to sneak from behind!</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_2">
    <text>And you don't fume here much, stalker! Fact that you are still alive only because we have important question for you. As you probably already noticed, your loot is with us. Want to return your things back peacefully? Well, of course, except that box you pulled from swamp and which belongs to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_3">
    <text>If you, lice, met me face to face, would see then who is who...</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_4">
    <text>Look at you! Half step from death, and demanding rights. Fearless hero, or what? Huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_meet_dialog_5">
    <text>Goats!</text>
</string>

<string id="maroder_start_dialog_0">
    <text>You answered for goats... Will you continue being hero further?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah you, reptile! Okay... Ending the chat. What do you need from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Now that's another matter. So, listen here: I understand, you sort of can pass freely to Peacekeepers base, right? Yes, know for sure. So, go and bring us two Peacekeepers body armors SKAT-11M from there. Bring - get your things back from Gena. And Gena will guard them for now, don't worry. Body armors should lie in warehouse, warehouse opposite toilet, won't get lost. Here is key to warehouse, don't ask where I got it. Don't think Peacekeepers will let you go just like that if they see you stole armors from them. So here is my advice: after taking body armors, find how to exit base another way. There is a loophole, otherwise Peacekeepers will shoot you. And you, I think, don't really want to quarrel with them. But that's your problems. And don't think of playing games with us, you'll regret!</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, rat. Will bring what you ask. Guard my things and weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Go already, darling, work. And more. Don't think of meddling to Baker anymore. Kill on spot. He is our "client". We watch him for long time. Soon a parcel should come to him. Then we will utilize him. So, if you think of warning him, death to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes I understood everything. Wait. I'll be soon.</text>
</string>

<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>So, hero? Brought two SKAT-11M body armors?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Brought.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>That is good. Give them here.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>And where are my weapon and things?</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>I said - Gena guards them. Give armors here!</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Okay. Here are body armors, take them. Now give my things and weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_6">
    <text>What a loser you are, boy!</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_7">
    <text>Didn't understand...</text>
</string>

<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, General! I have business for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_1">
    <text>Speak, Strelok. What business?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_2">
    <text>I got captured by marauders in abandoned village. Stripped me to the thread. Took everything: weapon and things.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_3">
    <text>Unlucky you, stalker. Good that they let you go alive at least.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_4">
    <text>General, to return my things and weapon, marauders ordered me to get two body suits SKAT-11M. Steal them from your base and bring to them. But I don't want to do this, that's why came to you for help.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_5">
    <text>You are an honest man, Strelok! How exactly can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_6">
    <text>Give me assault rifle, ammo, five grenades and a couple of fighters, and we will take out the whole marauder village.</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, Strelok, can't allocate people to you now. We have one important operation planned in the south of territory, so every barrel counts. But assault rifle, ammo for it, couple of grenades, medkit with bandages and that very body armor I will give you. I think you'll handle marauders yourself. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="smith_maroder_dialog_8">
    <text>Agreed, General. Give. It will be even more pleasant for me to deal with them alone and return my things and weapon. Thank you very much! Going to deal with these rats.</text>
</string>
