<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_0">
    <text>Can you tell me something for free?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_1">
    <text>Alright, Stalker, let me tell you about a man who made it to the sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_2">
    <text>Well, go ahead.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_3">
    <text>Recently I was walking through the warehouse territory and I saw a man. He was covered in dirt, leaves, and an old jacket served as his clothing, probably an old anti-radiation suit. I approached him and saw that he seemed to have no wounds, only a crazed look. His eyes seemed to look at someone behind me, wandering, in short. I asked him what he was doing there and what had happened. He begged with trembling lips to give him something to drink and eat. "At least respect an experienced one for the last time," he said. \n\nWell, I'm not a beast. I gave him a sip from the flask and some bread with sausage. I made a fire in a hollow, put two cans of stew on the fire, since this old man, there's no other way to say it, said the conversation would be very long. Well, I didn't need to hurry, so I listened. This man was called Efim, and he was 43 years old. He entered the Zone among the very first, explored it far and wide, hauled a bunch of artifacts. What's interesting is different. Once he decided to break through beyond the Radar to Pripyat.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_4">
    <text>Seriously? How?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_5">
    <text>Wait, let me speak. The way he went can no longer be passed, as the tunnel that ran the communication routes between the Radar and Pripyat was blocked in one of the Emissions. Here I suspected he was lying, but then he began to tell such things that it was simply difficult to make up. The tunnel ended near one of the supply stations in Pripyat. He wandered into a hangar - a huge room with lots of rotten, gnawed and sour food, rusty cartridges. \n\nGetting out of the hangar, the old man almost got into an anomaly. It looked, as he said exactly: "In the center silver threads sparkle like a spider web, on it tiny bubbles, like some kind of dew... And behind the web... Darkness. The whole world seemed to be drawn into this darkness... Under the anomaly everything seemed to be drawn, twisted... torn... around hung some brownish-gray dust, flesh and blood suspended in timelessness." The old man felt terrible. He threw a bolt at the anomaly. The bolt first flew normally, but then...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_6">
    <text>What then?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_7">
    <text>The bolt suddenly bent, twisted, the thread straightened and curled in the other direction, and then... the bolt crumbled into pieces, which were ground into dust, finer and finer as it moved toward the center. Slower and slower... and hung on the threshold of nothingness... Swallowing hard, the stalker bypassed the strange anomaly and quietly moved on, throwing bolts ahead. In one of the houses he stumbled upon a poltergeist lair, from which he had to get rid of using an underslung launcher. \n\nIn the freed dwelling he spent the night. And in the morning he saw another surprise from the Zone. Efim came out to the square in the city of Pripyat. On the pedestal rose Lenin himself. Only the color was rusty for some reason and the statue was all covered in some kind of hairs. Well then, research interest forced him to throw a bolt. The bolt had a very bad time. Touching the hairs on the monument, it rusted itself and oxidized in an instant. Only rusty dust fell on the asphalt. And in Pripyat the dawn was burning out...</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_8">
    <text>You speak beautifully! And then?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_9">
    <text>In the strange murky sky the sun was rising, not knowing that such a vile place as the Zone exists in the world. Passing the entrance to ChNPP, Efim, or as you already understood, Shooter, Guide, saw it. The Sarcophagus. It loomed gray against the sky. And then... The sky also turned gray... more... even stronger... some black dots flashed before his eyes, the whole world decomposed into two colors - black and gray... The Geiger counter showed frantic activity. Lightning flashed from who knows where... And then the Emission struck. It seemed that it wasn't the sarcophagus or something else that burst. It seemed that his head exploded. By itself, from the inside, turning into a ball of squirming gnawing pain. New anomalies exploded nearby. Different anomalies: acid, gravitational, electrical. Poplar fluff flew, but he didn't notice it. His legs carried him away from this terrible place by themselves, and someone screamed in his head, somewhere a strange noise was heard.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_10">
    <text>And what happened to him?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_11">
    <text>It seemed to the Guide that his brains were simply squeezed out, that he was hit with a current of myriads of volts... As if a bunch of people were screaming right in his cerebellum, shouting something meaningful, but fading behind a veil of pain... The man luckily got into the "Portal" anomaly, it simply transferred him somewhere to the Radar from there. I mentally calculated the facts. Yesterday there was a not particularly strong Emission. So the man might not be lying. The Guide at this place choked on his own blood. It had some strange lilac color. Zone, Zone... what are you doing... what are you? Or maybe who?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_12">
    <text>Did he die?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_13">
    <text>Yes, he just fell apart like jelly. A terrible sight, better not go look.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story_14">
    <text>Alright, thanks. You should write memoirs about the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story2_0">
    <text>Listen, how to make money in the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story2_1">
    <text>Showing off and having dough - these are two big differences... What, think the dough is given here for nothing? Not a damn thing! For nothing only some freak will eat you, or soldiers will kill you... You need to think. There you need to think, and here even better. Complete idiots don't last long here. It doesn't work without brains... In short, here's what happened. The three of us - me, Bruise and Chain, may they rest in peace - were going through the utility yard. Cutting the road short, basically. We look - some bandit is scratching along. Well, we hid. And he passes by us, doesn't notice. Small guy, but dragging a bag - damn heavy. And the rifle hangs cleverly: anything happens - he'll fill us with lead. \n\nWell, Bruise tells me: "Let's feel out the dumbass, what's he got there?" And I tell him: "Quiet, woodpecker! Better watch where he's dragging his loot." Well, what... Here the moron vanished somewhere, we didn't even understand. Well, we wait. He came out in about twenty minutes. While he was shaking off, Chain quietly came up behind him and blew off half his head with a shotgun. They started gutting the body with Bruise: he had a cool armor, and there should be a backpack... I went off to piss - my guys always give me my share, I'm always in on the deal. Then it goes boom!.. In short, that sucker was not simple: he rigged something clever so it would blow if someone tried to take the armor off him.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story2_2">
    <text>Clever bastard you ran into.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_osvedomitel_story2_3">
    <text>Yeah. I got out of there quick. Not many will show up for a shot and explosion... I came back in a month. Not even a bone left from Chain, Bruise and the moron. Complete zero. In short, I figured out where he dove into the ruins, and went there myself... Well, went through three rooms - nothing! Then I see a pile of beds stacked in the corner. What the hell are so many cots there for? In short, I started to clear it. Cleared it. I look - mother of God, a hatch! I lift the lid, shine a flashlight. Holy shit! I'm in heaven!.. Well, what was there - my business... Didn't come out empty-handed. But if I'd kept my ears open, I'd have been a corpse long ago. Or still running around barefoot, broke... Like some people...</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story_0">
    <text>It's boring here at the Cordon... Tell a story or something...</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story_1">
    <text>I remembered one story... I came to Sidorovich once, and he says some foreigner is coming... Need to meet him, take him to some places, show him an anomaly and all that. And I was walking around almost naked: no ammo for the rifle, the sawed-off broke long ago, only the pistol left, and even that with blank cartridges... Damn, but I want to eat. In general, I agreed to drag the foreigner around the Zone. Well, near the village, of course. He arrived. In dark glasses, with a camera. Saying something in his American and smiling, the bastard. Like on safari, came. "Well, let's go," I say. We went not far, our guys just cleared the territory up to the mill, right from the village. We go. The foreigner smiles, adjusts his hat, and keeps clicking his camera.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story_2">
    <text>Heh-heh. Some tourist...</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story_3">
    <text>We reached a small hangar, well, remember, where Fedya Constructor died. "Be quiet," I tell the foreigner, "now we're going to zombies." He instantly got into it, eyes like saucers and the damn tourist pulls a Desert Eagle from his backpack. "Shit," I think, "what did I get myself into..." "No," I say, "you hide the gun." Somehow I convinced him with gestures and told him to follow me. And it's dark... Can't see a thing. We go, water dripping somewhere, glass rattling (wind walking). This tourist is shaking all over. \n\nAnd then from the darkness in camouflage a zombie comes at us. I just wanted to yell at the foreigner to run. I look, and he's already vanished. Then me and the "zombie" couldn't hold it, we burst out laughing! Petrovich really scared the client... Overdid it even. I wanted to shoot a couple of blanks at Petrovich for show... Didn't have time! The tourist must have heard about zombies, and when he heard the howl and saw this one coming at us with outstretched arms... Made good money, in short.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story_4">
    <text>Holy shit, you guys are something... Ha-ha! Haven't laughed like that in a while!</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story2_0">
    <text>Tell me something about the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story2_1">
    <text>Listen, I'll tell you. The Zone is a harsh mistress. She gives, but mostly she takes. You need to respect her, understand her moods. Otherwise you won't last long here.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_volk_story2_2">
    <text>Wise words, brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_0">
    <text>Hello, what's interesting here?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_1">
    <text>This recently happened to me. I'm walking, see, through the Garbage, not bothering anyone. I look - a characteristic dent in the ground, like a "Mosquito Bald." I throw a bolt and freak out! The bolt, damn, flies right through, and not a scratch! "Well," I think, "a glitch, drank too much alcohol while wandering the Zone."</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_2">
    <text>Definitely drank too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_3">
    <text>No, come on... Visually everything, you understand, you're experienced, everything's like "Mosquito Bald"! And the soil's lighter, flattened at the edge, pebbles pressed in. And a breeze pulls toward it.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_4">
    <text>Looks like "Bald," can't mistake it for anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_5">
    <text>So, then. I crouched down, took a pebble from the ground and threw it in an arc there.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_6">
    <text>Tore it to dust?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_7">
    <text>Uh-huh. I wish I'd seen that then. No. The pebble calmly fell on the ground, as if there was no anomaly there. Fell and that's it. I immediately started sweating. Intuition tells me this is special! On my haunches I quietly crawl to the "Bald" and throw pebbles. Reflex, damn it.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_8">
    <text>Well, don't torture a stalker's soul.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_9">
    <text>I crawled up, you won't believe, right close. Sweated like a mouse in a suit. The pebbles I threw are lying right in the "Bald." My stalker gut says - need to get out! But I don't. Special! Need to figure it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_10">
    <text>You wouldn't be sitting with us if you got right close to the "Bald."</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_11">
    <text>But I am sitting. And, see, I put the gun on my knees. Scared shitless! I reach my hand into the "Mosquito Bald" to one of the pebbles! Took it. Pebble like a pebble.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_12">
    <text>Yeah right, Fanatic, I believe you. Come on, what did you find?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_13">
    <text>So, I was thrown back 5 meters from this anomaly. Shouldn't have touched the pebble. The "Bald" started working, damn thing. While still flying, I saw how the stones were torn to dust. Hit, passed out.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_14">
    <text>You, damn, definitely got drunk on alcohol.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_15">
    <text>Yeah, right! Look what a pebble!</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story_16">
    <text>Yes, indeed, here's the stone... Can't believe it... Hmm... But curiosity will kill you someday, that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story2_0">
    <text>What do you think about the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story2_1">
    <text>What I think... Not even what I think, just, I'm figuring... What if everything, just everything here - is some kind of experiment on people? It could be some little green men... Why not? No worse than other versions... I'm curious: if this is something like a testing ground, what exactly are they testing here? Checking which artifacts we drool over most? Or maybe it's some kind of bombs, huh? They scattered them all over the world, to all kinds of laboratories, rich people forked out money... No, well this would be cool!.. This would be with my pleasure!.. \n\nThey bought some crap under the table... forked out a pile of money... Like "we're cooler than everyone," be jealous, suckers... and it... it... goes boom!.. Oh, awesome!.. Oh, I can't!.. Oh... phew... But in general, of course, hell knows what really... Unless the one who went beyond the Radar can tell about this... Well, they might know, only they can't say. They mumble and drool. Maybe that's exactly why they drool... Eh... So all sorts of thoughts creep in... Not cheerful at all...</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story2_2">
    <text>Yeah, not cheerful at all... Come on, brother, let's have a drink or something?</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_lager_fanat_story2_3">
    <text>Let's, or all sorts of thoughts creep into my head...</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_story_0">
    <text>What will you entertain me with?</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_story_1">
    <text>With a funny story. I was walking one evening from the Dark Valley. And outside it's getting dark, almost can't see anything. I only see a fire in the village in the distance. Well, I think, now I'll arrive to my people! I pass by bushes, I look - someone's silhouette in the bushes. Again some bandit is watching our guys, and then will report to command how we live, what we do. And they'll stuff his pockets with money and give him an artifact gun. I think: "I'll scare him! Let him know not to stick his nose on someone else's territory!". \n\nI sneak up behind him, make a skillful hold and so quietly in his ear I say: "What are you doing here, you beast?" "Gr-r-r-rah-h-h..." - came from the bandit. And right! I pressed him with my professional grip where I needed to. He can't even twitch now, can't even say a word properly. And I feel he stinks like a ghoul. Looks like the guy honestly shit himself. Well, I loosened the grip and say: "Come here one more time, you bastard, I'll pull your brains out with these very hands and make you eat them, got it?" And suddenly this wonder answers in a hoarse voice: "What's your problem, man? Let me go! Can't even a simple bloodsucker take a piss under a bush now?!"</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_story_2">
    <text>Heh-heh, nice story, made me laugh...</text>
</string>
