<string id="dm_action_info_0">
    <text>What could be new here? It's practically kindergarten, a nursery school. Although, to be honest, if you don't hang around here for a bit, you'll be done for in five minutes out in the Zone, just like that. A smart guy always rubs elbows here first, and only then climbs into the devil's jaws. Besides, you can get hold of gear or weapons here, no question. Everyone stocks up.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_1">
    <text>I just need to wait for the lunch break of those pretty boys in uniform... I'm stuck here uselessly, I need to get to the Mainland, but they won't let me through, damn them! I'm not the only one trying to soap up for an exit, but we still can't slip through yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_10">
    <text>The lads in uniform needed something not far from here. Nobody used to go there at all - everything was cleaned out to a shine even before me, they even cut the cables. And now they found something, apparently... I couldn't even get close to the building - they spotted me immediately and fired. Good thing I got away without a hole in my hide.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_100">
    <text>Nothing. Trying to survive, that's all.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_11">
    <text>We are gathering a team of those who aren't afraid to go underground in the Zone. There is an old factory, and all sorts of communications under it; they say there's a lot of stuff there. Always something to profit from. It's interesting, too...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_12">
    <text>Not new - old! They say Strelok's main base used to be located here... I'm wondering - maybe some traces from that time can be found if one searches properly?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_13">
    <text>Can you believe it - an hour ago I almost got into deep trouble! I was here half a year ago - peace and quiet, and now skinheads in their sweatpants are under every bush! Crazy...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_14">
    <text>You're lucky, stalker, that the bandits didn't take you while you were warm: they have a base nearby. Eh, I would hit it if it were up to me... But for now, we just watch. This is their auxiliary point. The main one is located closer to the center of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_15">
    <text>They say there was a serious, classified laboratory here. Eh... On one hand, I'd love to find the entrance - there must be loot there, probably! On the other hand - it's kinda creepy...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_16">
    <text>Are you aware that in the current Dark Valley, before the disaster, there was a research complex, and an underground one at that? Its purpose is unknown to me, but hardly anything good, I reckon. People tell all sorts of things about it, but mostly bad stuff. Scary even.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_17">
    <text>So what? What do you want to hear? I'll tell you this: "Dolg" (Duty), of course, are cops, but they know how to establish order, that's for sure. But generally, I don't like them. They act like owners everywhere - don't take this, don't take that out of the Zone... Moreover, they've already invented what can be said on the Mainland and what is a no-no! Rumor has it they want to destroy the Zone little by little. Well, soldiers, even former ones, I'm not surprised... dreamers. What's worse is that they say their support comes from the very top.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_18">
    <text>This territory is now controlled by Duty, and the law here is Duty's rules. We control the borders of the Zone and cool down hot heads: the crazy ones arrive here by whole trainloads, amateurs, romantics... and then they perish in batches on the very first day.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_19">
    <text>Have you been to our transit base? True, it's not only ours - you can meet a lot of people there. The main thing is, it's a good place, without any trash, and all news about the Zone flows there. You can almost always hear something useful or just chat with folks about life. It's just a pity, Lysiy (Baldy) left with a group the day before yesterday - so I didn't see him this time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_2">
    <text>Go to the camp, you'll find out all the rumors there. Everyone who is here for the first time - rookies like you - usually comes to us: to gain some experience or rest a little. We have soldiers right by our side, don't be too afraid of them, but don't loom around much either - they might shoot, it's as easy as two fingers for them... Not far from here, near the trader - well, the local reseller - there is a place where you can quietly organize a halt for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_20">
    <text>This place is safe now, stalker, and we try to keep it in this state. There are always a lot of people here: some have settled completely and don't go beyond the outskirts, and some are preparing for the next raid. It's a pity Iroquois didn't return - he loved to guide first-timers like you on the true path.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_21">
    <text>Heard that Duty announced recruitment into their slender ranks? I thought about it for a minute, and then decided: why the hell do I need it, again "every other day on the belt" (army duty)? Discipline, this and that... I served my two years already, that was enough...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_22">
    <text>If you haven't heard yet, I'm informing you: additional recruitment to us has been announced. If you have more or less experience, come, you won't regret it. You'll need to ask for Petrenko at the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_23">
    <text>Did you also come to watch the fights, place a bet?.. Whoa! There is an Arena somewhere here, and you are a complete zero! So: the Duty guys catch mutants, right? After research, if the creatures are still alive, they release them into the Arena. And these dolls are oh so different: sometimes you can die laughing, and sometimes you can wet your pants.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_24">
    <text>We just provided the Arena with fresh meat. Entertainment for the people, and it's not a sin for us to earn a percentage on bets. Again, we'll prove to the stalkers once more that Duty doesn't just wag its tongue, but actually does business.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_25">
    <text>Listen, have you been to the Rostok factory? It used to be quiet there, but now it's hard to go alone - a natural wild field, painfully many mutants have bred. Let's go together, eh?.. Although... I don't know you, you don't know me. You never know. Alright, man, sorry. We split.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_26">
    <text>We just came from the Rostok factory. I don't advise you to poke your nose in there, especially if you are alone. Do you want to live? Then better not go.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_27">
    <text>Yeah well, I thought about going to Yantar and got bummed out. The eggheads have a natural outpost of science in the Zone there. They are digging around, god knows in what, and zombies wander around the complex. An idyll, by god.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_28">
    <text>We recently cleared the area of Lake Yantar... Yes, we shredded quite a bit of the bitch's tribe! There are research laboratories there, only there are always a lot of zombies around. We have to regularly run to help the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_29">
    <text>The Freedom base is located at the old warehouses. They are carefree, soulful guys; sitting with them over a bottle of something good is a pleasure. And Duty doesn't flicker around like around the bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_3">
    <text>There is an old factory nearby, we keep kicking the bandits out of it, but they keep coming back every time! Not even a month has passed since the last time, and they are right here again. You be careful there...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_30">
    <text>Freedom has settled behind the old warehouses... Those stoned slackers, damn them...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_31">
    <text>Leave while it's not night yet! During the day it's still so-so here, but once the sun goes down...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_32">
    <text>Stalker, leave! We are going to remove the cordon now. We only hold it during the day for now, and leave for the night - it's too shitty here at night.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_33">
    <text>You see, at night one needs to take cover here... and preferably behind good doors. During the dark time of day, we effectively find ourselves in a state of siege.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_34">
    <text>Well, buddy, I see you're not in the loop? At night you need to go bye-bye somewhere far from here. At night, even a grenade launcher doesn't always help here!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_35">
    <text>You know what? Let Duty and Freedom and the marauders decide whose piece this is, I don't care! To hell with it all...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_36">
    <text>We are working here now, stalker. There's enough trash bred already, and on top of that, these bastards, mercenaries and idiots from Freedom, prevent us from living...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_37">
    <text>I am forced to warn you that it is quite unsafe here even during the day. Firefights happen from time to time - as far as I understand, there is some confrontation going on between local bandit groups.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_38">
    <text>Listen, tell me this: this is totally our territory, right? It's easier for us to hold back the trash that comes from the center of the Zone, right? Let the eggheads dig around, who touches them, but Duty and the marauders should get out of here!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_39">
    <text>Don't you know? They've trampled a new path here to sneak straight to the perimeter with loot, bypassing Duty patrols. From Yantar to here, then through the backyards to Agroprom - and that's it, you're there!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_4">
    <text>Nothing. I don't know a damn thing. I'm just picking up scraps, gathering for my daily bread. I'm scared to go into the Zone itself, screw that. And at home there is no work, the wife nags... Gotta live somehow? Here at the Garbage, if you walk around for a day, you can collect various artifacts by the little bits. In principle, it's enough for food and drink.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_40">
    <text>Why are you here? Going to Yantar or want to sneak artifacts past the bar quietly?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_41">
    <text>I won't hide that here your colleagues, stalkers, from time to time offer us very interesting anomalous formations - artifacts, as you call them. These places, due to their... let's say, uncertainty of control over them - are something like a busy smuggling trail.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_42">
    <text>Are you serious, man? We laid a path so we wouldn't meet with the bureaucrats from Duty if you want to run to the Mainland! No, well, they certainly wander around here quite a bit, but so far they don't know a damn thing, so at least you can bypass them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_43">
    <text>I'm just coming from Yantar. Thought I'd push some stuff to science, as always, but they locked themselves in their bunkers there, they don't really come out now even during the day, except to the next chopper. So, if you're stomping there, turn your shafts around - you're out of luck...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_44">
    <text>In the area of the Yantar factory, some research is being conducted, but lately, zombies have been pressing hard. So we are guarding the approaches.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_45">
    <text>I don't even know what to tell you. I was about to return to our complex - that's Yantar, I think you know. And here you go: they say that if it was just dangerous before, now it has become completely impossible to pass. Maybe they are exaggerating?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_46">
    <text>I was at Yantar, science has completely withered there: they are scared, hiding... They only survive on what is dropped to them by choppers. On the other hand, zombies really have bred a lot there. Live among them for a week - you'll get even more spooked. A so-so place. Unattractive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_47">
    <text>To hell with hanging out with zombies! They've bred in this damn complex - they keep coming and coming. And there are more and more of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_48">
    <text>We are trying to stop the advance of zombies from the laboratory complex. Honestly, I won't mind at all if you join in - we are short on people...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_49">
    <text>You know, we collect various information ourselves... I myself am researching the main distribution routes of quasi-liv... that is, zombies, in your terminology. Would you share your observations?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_5">
    <text>It's all kinda like this... Those who fed at the Garbage gather small stuff, those who drilled deeper into the Zone. There, of course, the pieces are noticeably fatter, but not everyone will poke their nose there. Rookies without experience have nothing to do there, and if there is also no decent gear - turn off the lights, totally. No chance.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_50">
    <text>Have you shot at the zombies climbing out of the laboratory building yet? Look at you: they aren't afraid of a damn thing, don't feel pain. Completely brainless! Beasts, in a word!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_51">
    <text>I'm going to hire on for work at the laboratory! Okay, man, relax - a joke of humor... Because here, if you wandered in - that's it, consider yourself lost. At best, you'll become a zombie.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_52">
    <text>I'm warning you: don't go to the laboratory. No, well, if you really want to - go, I won't hold you by force. Only they don't come back from there alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_53">
    <text>You see... I would like to warn you. You shouldn't go to the laboratory. Nobody, strictly speaking, should: it is associated with cardinal changes in the psyche and metabolism. I'm afraid, completely irreversible changes...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_54">
    <text>Whoa! Now I will enlighten you... educate you... save you, in short, a lost sheep. So: don't point your skis toward the laboratory complex. It's shitty there, very shitty. People disappear, and then, it happens, they come to you at night. Only these aren't vampire fairy tales, but the truest reality about zombies. Such matters.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_55">
    <text>Have you seen our eggheads, this flower of the united, damn, nations? They've become totally paranoid lately. For them to move two steps from the base - they drive a whole regiment of soldiers, APCs, and choppers for protection.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_56">
    <text>And what business is it of yours? Don't pester with stupid questions, then they won't pester you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_57">
    <text>You understand, we usually don't leave the bunker without appropriate security: environmental conditions do not allow it. I am sort of an exception - I don't really like large expeditions, all this fuss, soldiers... However, I'm afraid I can't tell you anything useful yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_58">
    <text>I get a kick out of our funny science! I'm just amazed by it, man!.. Usually, it doesn't show its nose out of the bunker. But if it does show, like recently, then such things start - oh mommy! Full of soldiers, choppers, armored vehicles! It would be cool if they dragged a battleship here or an armored train, at the very least...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_59">
    <text>I've been spinning around here for the third day, observing. The laboratory is here - right? Nobody went into it from the very beginning, the "Duty" guys only cleaned zombies on the surface, and now they stopped completely, right? But science started climbing in there. Means they found a way to defend themselves, who the hell knows from what... So I'm thinking of finding out - there must be loot in that place, enough to shovel it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_6">
    <text>In recent days, beasts have been rushing in whole packs from the Dark Valley. It's unclear what drives them from there, but they are bursting through like from a fire. And in the eastern sector, mutants have bred like bedbugs, we only have time to shoot them. Those are the news.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_60">
    <text>And what are you looking for here? Also lathered up for the laboratory? Heard a fairy tale about miraculous devices and placers of artifacts? M-mother... when will you idiots die out from the world?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_61">
    <text>I work here, young man. Just work, fulfilling my duty to science and humanity. And if you want to know about the abandoned laboratory, the secrets of which every met stalker suspects me of knowing, I will answer: I don't know and I don't want to know! This topic does not interest me and never interested me, is that clear?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_62">
    <text>Maybe the brainiacs really came up with some device, don't you know? It's interesting, after all, what is hidden in this damn laboratory. Even if there is no normal loot - it's still interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_63">
    <text>I'm thinking - should I join Freedom? There is their base, at the former army warehouses... Why not? The people seem sensible, and well, if they are a bit sloppy, that's even good: no need to crush me with discipline, I know what to do myself, not the first month here...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_64">
    <text>You don't sympathize with Freedom, by chance, eh? Okay-okay, don't get offended. I think soon we will pick them out of those warehouses. Neither organization nor discipline... A herd. A pack at best. And they decided to twitch against us, NATO fosterlings...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_65">
    <text>I meet with one Duty guy here when there is a truce. We chat. The guy is generally smart, but, damn, narrow-minded, like a tank. You understand, our philosophy is completely different: the Zone can only be tamed, assimilated, not destroyed. For this, open access to all information is needed: someone will come up with something sensible sooner or later. And they: "close", "forbid", "do not disclose"... Idiots, by god, idiots. On the other hand, it is understandable: when the whole state machine is behind you, you are not supposed to think too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_66">
    <text>There is a small hamlet here, everything used to be calm, but now some trash has bred. Better to make a detour, so I am going around... Look, I warned you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_67">
    <text>I want to warn you immediately, stalker: bloodsuckers have long nested in the village, and maybe something worse, so be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_68">
    <text>What new... There have been no artifacts here for a long time, and over there in those houses bloodsuckers used to live, we shot them as best we could. Now I went - and I can't reach the place. Intuition or what - but I can't go there, and that's it. No way. Death is there...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_69">
    <text>I'm getting the hell out of here! Drummed four weeks on the Barrier - and that's it, enough for me! From the side of the "Brain Scorcher" some nastiness pushes round the clock, and every day more assertively...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_7">
    <text>Many have become "scavengers" lately. Before, nobody even looked in the heaps - the radiation was such that it would hard-boil your balls in half an hour. But now, since loot has become tight, they wrap themselves in protection, take meds, and climb in to search. A lot of stuff can be found there, though mostly small fry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_70">
    <text>If you're coming to us, to the Barrier, I respect you. If not - get out of my sight! We need real men, not screw-ups. We have enough of our own...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_71">
    <text>You heading to the Barrier, dude? That's good - at least one more normal person will appear. We organized this thing and held it quite well... but then the beasts just started pouring in!.. It's tough now, so every gun is welcome.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_72">
    <text>Don't you know? The path to the center of the Zone has opened! Either by itself, or someone made an effort, human thanks to them. Now you know, rake in the choice loot!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_73">
    <text>You should wait a bit, stalker. Don't run after everyone else. Tell me: do you know what's there? Correct, you don't. You don't know if there is anything to profit from. You don't know what traps are there either. So why are you rushing like a herd of moose?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_74">
    <text>The path to the center is free, got it?! Now straight ahead - to the center! Now everyone will climb there in a crowd. The main thing is to be among the first, to squeeze the best juice for yourself!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_75">
    <text>Move forward, you'll see everything yourself! Don't you want to see for yourself what is happening further out there? Well, you are generally... blissful. There must be so much there! Have you heard about the Wish Granter, for example, or not?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_76">
    <text>Like children, by god! "Wish Granter", "Klondike of artifacts"... It's ridiculous to even listen!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_77">
    <text>I want to find out what's over the horizon myself, dude! What if it's possible to find an explanation for all this crap called the Zone in one fell swoop?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_78">
    <text>Seen the high-rises? That's Pripyat already. Right behind it is the station. Eh, to get there... only it's unknown what wanders among those buildings now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_79">
    <text>Let me explain. There is Pripyat. Behind Pripyat is the CNPP. What is happening there now, and who lives there - is unknown. Our place is here. We'll find something to dig up, that's as always.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_8">
    <text>Not in the loop! I'm just going to the bar to talk to people. What, haven't been there even once? You're something! Listen here: move straight north from where you stand. You won't make two steps before the bar is right there. It's generally useful to go there, and for rookies like you, the doctor ordered it: experienced guys hang out there sometimes, they'll tell you what's what. The only thing is, bandits might meet you on the road... So be attentive, keep your ears sharp.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_80">
    <text>Pripyat! Damn, pinch me! Finally! The station is just a stone's throw away. Who knows, though, who you might meet here now, what beast is sharpening its teeth for you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_81">
    <text>Friend, listen... Is there a voice ringing in your head too, or is it just me who went crazy? Keeps harping and harping...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_82">
    <text>Damn, another one... Alright. I explain for the umpteenth time what kind of telepathic influence people are subjected to here. Voices inaudible from the outside constantly call them to the center of the Zone and promise to grant any wish to the one who manages to touch... what's it called... ah, yes - some Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_83">
    <text>Do you hear the voice? Cool, just like a player in your head! A pity though, the track is the same: come to me, it says, and you will have great happiness. Two hours already jabbering the same thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_84">
    <text>Don't you guess? You are breaking through to the station too! Well, so are we, what other news?! If only we could clear these obsessed idiots from the road...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_85">
    <text>The station territory is very close! We can't handle the resistance of the Monolithians yet!..</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_86">
    <text>There it is, the CNPP, a stone's throw away. Just a little left, but these bitches are stubborn, they won't let us through! Nothing, we'll comb them down now!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_9">
    <text>Listen, friend, do you know anything about Agroprom yourself? I wanted to go, but people laughed at me: they say there isn't a damn thing there anymore, picked clean, back when only anomalies remained. Do you know if they are telling the truth, or just for laughs? I'm new here, I believe if locals speak... Maybe they conspired, and decided to prank me? Just give them a reason to laugh, those pests!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_94">
    <text>Stop! Haste makes waste. Monolithians are all around; they know the city inside out, planted ambushes everywhere. Need to be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_95">
    <text>Warning: for now, most of the city is controlled by the "Monolith" faction. A mass of ambushes - they studied everything here like their five fingers. Don't lower your attention and check your weapon one extra time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_96">
    <text>Eh, what I would do with pleasure is cover this little town with a carpet bombing. Bastards... settled everywhere except maybe sandboxes and flower pots. How many people have died because of these assholes!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_97">
    <text>Listen, who the hell knows about this Granter... Maybe it's not eternal, so there won't be enough for everyone? And what to do - stand on four points? Well, you, guy, if we get there, you'll be behind me, I promise that...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_98">
    <text>Duty must break through to the center, if not first, then among the first! Just imagine, stalker, that some psycho - and almost all of you here are like that, one way or another, schizos, paranoids, and retards - gets to the thing that actually knows how to grant any wish. Huh? And what then?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_99">
    <text>News of the century: everyone who can walk and hold a weapon is here now! It's just... everything you wish for can come true here! Just grasp the topic, buddy, eh? Anything you wish! And then someone goes and says: "I want the Zone to disappear now and ever, and unto ages of ages." Huh? Appreciate the scale of the tragedy? We'll all be left out in the cold then. Every single one!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_119">
    <text>Where would new stuff come from? Chasing bandits and helping scientists. That's all the business.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_120">
    <text>Brother, don't bother me, my head is buzzing after yesterday. Better pour me one. Then we'll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_121">
    <text>Wait, bro. We'll sit with the guys by the fire, have a smoke, then you can pester with questions. But not now, I can't do it with a clear head. Doesn't pull me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_122">
    <text>Oh, stalker, hello! Come in, don't be afraid, everyone's friendly. Did you talk to the senior? No? Well go on, he's been waiting for you, getting angry, and when he's angry he starts kicking us like there's no tomorrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_123">
    <text>I tell you, mercenaries have worn me out. They occupied Rostok, they catch our brother stalker and... Well, you know yourself, they don't let you go alive. I need to get to the scientists, but there's no way to pass.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_124">
    <text>Gather some tougher guys and hit this scum. You don't know Vanka, my friend, do you? Well, yesterday mercenaries caught him foolishly. He went alone, and well, he is no more.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_125">
    <text>It's tight for us here, brother. Look at my team. Suckers and drunks. How to fight with such rabble against mercenaries? Duty guys only help with words. Occasionally a squad passes, another one towards Yantar, that's all the help.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_126">
    <text>There are unmeasured amounts of beasts here, and where do they come from? I think they are pushing from the side of Yantar, nowhere else. I went to take a piss at night the other day, walked away from the fire maybe thirty meters and then a bloodsucker behind me roared, it would have eaten me, but good thing I wasn't standing alone. Vadik was on lookout, put a bullet between that reptile's eyes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_127">
    <text>Don't walk alone here, we move in a group with the guys, and even then every rustle gives us chills, we go to the toilet in twos or threes. And if you go further alone, it's certain death.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_0">
    <text>New? Why the hell do we need new, when old shit - scoop, you won't scoop it all out? Bandits have completely lost it, the bastards! When it comes to hustling for artifacts between anomalies, that's us, but when it comes to taking away someone else's loot... Ugh, reptiles! Don't wander into the Garbage - it's their prime spot.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_1">
    <text>I'm stuck here, stuck, you understand? I want to go home, but these guys won't let me, that's all the news... True, the people who go into the deep Zone - the seasoned ones, they tell all sorts of things. And sometimes they bring loot - you'd be envious. They say there are places there, like gold placers: take as much as you want. Not everyone reaches there though, and even fewer return with a profit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_10">
    <text>Otter bought it a week ago at the "Scorcher". If it was a rookie, a headless yellow-beak - it would be understandable, but he's been stalking for years. He was even in Leshy's (Goblin's) team, they say. And there you go...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_100">
    <text>I'm somehow not in the loop of recent events.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_101">
    <text>These nits, local creatures, are pushing from all sides! It already seems to me that the more we take down, the more of them appear. But nothing, victory will be ours! If only we had weapons and more tough guys. We would establish order here and avenge the fallen guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_102">
    <text>This place is cursed. Not Agroprom, but the Zone in general. We fight, we fight... But with whom and against whom? Ordinary monsters cannot reproduce at such speed. We crumble them, shoot them, and there just become more of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_103">
    <text>Heard that many anomalies and artifacts stopped being visible. Probably because of the emissions - they pump the Zone with energy too strongly. So be careful: you can't just run around so simply anymore, a detector is now a matter of life and death. And sensible artifacts can only be found with advanced detectors, so keep that in mind. Good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_104">
    <text>I'm looking for loot. This is one of the safest places: no robbery extortion like at the Garbage, no crowds of mutants like at Agroprom, no corrupt military. And anomalies and rare monsters - that's a tolerable phenomenon. Compared to other places, naturally.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_105">
    <text>I'm hunting mutants. Traders and scientists pay good money for organs of some of them. Don't believe me? Go yourself, ask both.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_11">
    <text>Tell me this, stalker: why do you loners sometimes lose your minds? Is it lack of normal discipline or what? One guy last week decided to go into the forest at the Radar. And they say he was experienced... You can lose your brains easier that way: barrel in the mouth - and pull the trigger!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_12">
    <text>Those goats... mercenaries. They've been drinking our blood for a long time, and now they switched to the eggheads too. And why the hell do they need them? For ransom? Or to share their Nobel prizes?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_13">
    <text>Mercenaries have become very active in recent weeks. We also call them marauders. There is such trash here too, if you haven't heard. Like bandits, only specialists in military affairs. Moreover, they always preferred to attack stalkers, but lately for some reason became more interested in scientists. But you should look around anyway, it won't hurt them to shoot your head off too.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_14">
    <text>Heard out of the corner of my ear recently: eggheads, they say, dug up something awesome. And immediately everyone stood on their ears: soldiers, mercenaries, and Duty aren't lagging far behind...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_15">
    <text>If you are also asking about what you all have been bothering me with for the last two days, answer: go to hell! If I knew, and wasn't forbidden, I would tell. But as it is, I don't know, I don't know a damn thing at all! What those scientists obtained, where our leadership went? What do I have to do with it?! He is on vacation, and he is not obliged to report to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_16">
    <text>Ha! Everyone is on their ears here! Confederate returned from a raid with his group, they brought artifacts - oh dear mother! Confederate, of course, is silent, doesn't crack - well, that's as always - but his guys are joking: like, they went to Yukon mines, washed a little bit... What bastards!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_17">
    <text>For several days now, all sorts of evil spirits have been pouring in bulk from the territory of the Radar. People at the Barrier seem to be coping for now. If the flow doesn't weaken - we'll have to go for reinforcement, what to do...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_18">
    <text>Heard them say the Zone is growing? I think it's true: I myself saw such ugly beasts almost at the very perimeter, which used to be met only closer to the center. Shitty business, eh?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_19">
    <text>Possibly, they aren't lying about bloodsuckers near the border of the Zone. But what does the increase in the Zone's size have to do with it? Well, a pack wandered in... well, we missed it, yes. We sometimes work for several days straight! And we work normally. Outside the perimeter, they aren't screaming yet: "Save us, mutants are surrounding us!"</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_2">
    <text>Everything is somehow sad. Otter disappeared for no reason the other day, can't believe it... Ah, you probably haven't even heard of Otter once, have you? Well, he was practically a professor - here from the first year, knew the whole Zone like his five fingers... and yet, look at that! Even experienced stalkers exist, but the Zone still takes them. There are also those who go to the Mainland of their own will.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_20">
    <text>Do you think Barman knows details about what the scientists dug up? Listen, maybe he's in cahoots with science? Something lately he's been looking for more experienced stalkers and giving them strange tasks. Explains nothing, just says, go, he says, there or there... and those places are rotten, and never smelled of good loot. And what is he looking for there?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_21">
    <text>Something strange is happening. Zombies that used to be afraid to come out into the light have now scattered all over the district. What kind of bullshit is this?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_22">
    <text>Zombies for some reason became more aggressive and mobile. We used to clean them from time to time in the complex itself, but now we only hold the approaches to it. But I didn't tell you anything like that, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_23">
    <text>Be careful, or these walking corpses will flood the whole district. Very stupid and aggressive. We are constantly on defense - both night and day. So it is quite dangerous here, young man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_24">
    <text>Ah, probably eggheads in their laboratory messed up something wrong. Before, you could rarely meet a zombie anywhere, but now they are pouring from the complex. Main thing is, they wander as if they lost something and are looking for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_25">
    <text>A rumor went around that science did persuade one of ours to go down into the laboratory. Gave him something... some protective contraption... Nothing else, and no details.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_26">
    <text>People say all sorts of things. They say someone reckless was found: conspired with scientists and climbed into the laboratory for something useful to them. What a stupid asshole!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_27">
    <text>Ah, here is the main joke of the week! The eggheads signed one of yours for a hefty fee, he climbed into the laboratory with some device of theirs. A new victim of science, dammit!..</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_28">
    <text>I think something is brewing again. Eggheads dug up something that put everyone on their ears. And incidentally, life won't exist for you and me either.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_29">
    <text>Who the hell knows. Only they started chasing us twice as much as before - cordon, cleaning... There are also an order of magnitude more soldiers in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_3">
    <text>Everything is sad, that's what I'll say. The outskirts have always been full of people, half of them never go into the deep Zone, and there aren't enough artifacts for everyone. Even from the laboratories and factories, everything possible has already been broken out and taken away. Soon there will be nothing to do here at all, except maybe opening a restaurant... With a view and exotic cuisine.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_30">
    <text>I don't even know what to tell you... Something is always happening here, but that is in the order of things. On the Mainland, of course, they don't think so, but you and I are currently, after all, in an anomalous zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_31">
    <text>The eggheads are sniffing out something. Who knows what secret they've already dug up there, but they are twisting the soldiers' tails - big time! Those guys are already rummaging through Agroprom and the Dark Valley with might and main, searching and searching...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_32">
    <text>Every day more trash pushes from the territory of the Radar, and Duty and Freedom have decided to bicker again. Well, they'll wipe each other out, but what's the use? How long can we hold the Barrier alone?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_33">
    <text>Mutants are trying harder and harder to leak past the Barrier. Lately, it's been really tough. If some people would quit their slacking, we could take them easily!..</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_34">
    <text>Duty keeps shouting about their super-feats in the Zone. If only anyone here believed them... We started this business, we carry it further, and how many loners like you stayed voluntarily. And these guys... ah, to hell with them, goats!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_35">
    <text>I heard that Duty has become very arrogant. Like "we are volunteers who want to achieve safety and order in the Zone"... yeah, volunteers! Some sponsor supplied these volunteers with such gear, such guns, that you'd be envious. And these guys sold out too.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_36">
    <text>What rumors are going around? I'm telling you without any rumors: soon there will be more order. We will clean the Zone of beasts and of some goats too...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_37">
    <text>And did you hear what the "Duty" guys boast they'll do to us? "Grind into powder" - that's putting it mildly. This business worries me... Especially since they say they re-equipped to the first class.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_38">
    <text>And what's the news? We sit here, beasts push at us, we shoot them, and then they push again... only even stronger. True, military choppers flew here a few times... and the impression was that they even flew beyond the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_39">
    <text>What could be new here... same old, same old. Mutants, Freedom... although military helicopters have gotten into the habit of flying here too. If only they fired at the beasts once - nope, damn all...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_4">
    <text>New... People say all sorts of things! Believing everything - no believer is enough. Here, they say, some seasoned stalker came, let-me-out-tear-me-loose, from the inner regions, brought something totally unseen, made a pile of money... I can invent a hundred such stories for you myself!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_40">
    <text>I saw military choppers: imagine, they passed over us and towards the Radar - z-zip! Well, I think, they're gonna fall down now. Damn no - went further, circled there, and went back the same way. Normal move, huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_41">
    <text>Eh, now that there is a passage to the center... Just imagine how much wealth must be lying underfoot there!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_42">
    <text>Now, since the opportunity appeared to relatively calmly pass to the center of the Zone, stalkers flew there like flies to honey. Yea-ah... greed is still not the best human quality.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_43">
    <text>Here is the life coming to us! While all those from the bar, from the perimeter catch up - all the cream is ours! We'll collect the tastiest bits, and let others stock up on small fry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_44">
    <text>They say it actually exists, the Wish Granter. Someone already managed to reach it and make a wish to the fullest...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_45">
    <text>Listen, buddy, I know that anything happens in the Zone. Saw it myself. But these stories about instant wish fulfillment about your own hotel in the Caribbean - it's complete bullshit and nothing more.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_46">
    <text>What, don't you know?! Two of ours - well, those who rushed to the center the very first - actually broke through to the Granter and made a wish! They dreamed of islands in a warm sea all their lives, so now they are tanning somewhere in the tropics, no doubt.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_47">
    <text>Miklukha has been found - the main Freedom guy. Everyone thought he went to the Mainland, but he actually somehow managed to sneak past the "Brain Scorcher" with a small group. Now that's a man!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_48">
    <text>One of the Freedom squads was discovered in the previously inaccessible zone. How did they manage to pass unharmed, and then survive here for several weeks? Generally boggles the mind. It seems we underestimated these guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_49">
    <text>Imagine, our Miklukha was found! Alive, and the guys who were with him also survived. Sneaked past the "Brain Scorcher", and then cuckooed here for a month, couldn't get out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_5">
    <text>Something murky is brewing with us. Rumors are going, the Duty commander, the big shot, didn't just leave the Zone for some business, but to negotiate with Freedom. Well, they could have made peace openly, instead of creating some muck! This business smells bad, that's how it is. On the other hand, experienced men say they started fighting way back for a completely stupid reason too. Lest those cabinet freaks from the Mainland drag us all into some new meat grinder...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_50">
    <text>Heard?! The military rushed to the ready-made, they'll be here any moment! Found out that a path to the center of the Zone appeared, want to scoop up all the loot at once!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_51">
    <text>Information just came through: a large-scale landing at the station by army forces is planned. My advice to you: if you want to manage to grab at least some loot - hurry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_52">
    <text>This is total lawlessness happening! Just, you understand, the corridor opened, they started cleaning the station from all sorts of shit - and there you go, soldiers gathered for the ready-made! Well, damn it, no shame, no conscience...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_53">
    <text>I just don't understand one thing: how could those Freedom guys hold out here for a month? Do they have invisibility caps or something? It's a total alert here generally!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_54">
    <text>Did you understand what's happening here? No, well, I respect Miklukha even more now! Just imagine: to endure four-plus weeks in such guano, and not lose anyone from the guys!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_55">
    <text>Someone here lost their mind. And they were always tough guys, but now they are drooling... like complete morons. Scary...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_56">
    <text>As we approach the station, the unknown telepathic influence intensifies. Some started to go crazy, others have disorders and visions. Maybe now is the time to back off a little...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_57">
    <text>Listen, people are really blowing their tops here. Someone sees a pebble and suddenly starts screaming that it is, damn, his artifact, that he noticed it first, and the rest can go south. To another, Jah appears on a cloud hugging partners who disappeared god knows how many years ago... No, clearly some unhealthy crap is happening here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_6">
    <text>Soldiers are hustling something. Searching, digging... Before, choppers only flew to Yantar - guarding scientists, carrying supplies and equipment. And now it's like an invasion. Started arranging sorties, driving APCs. They've already been seen at Agroprom, in the Dark Valley, again. Unclear.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
    <text>Someone again, they say, tried to break through the dead forest on the Radar. Well, it's curtains, clearly, the person is done for... Haven't you heard of this place? Are you crazy, man?! That is generally the main bugbear for the whole neighborhood! Only one trouble. The horrors they gossip about it are mostly true.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
    <text>Besides bandits, soldiers also started prowling here for some reason. Before, you'd see a helicopter once in a hundred years, and now they've crawled over almost the entire Zone. Did they lose something or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_9">
    <text>I want to warn you, stalker. The military here have gone crazy lately. Before, they quietly and peacefully guarded scientists, and now it's like someone twisted their tail: running, rushing about... They aren't tuned particularly peacefully - they've shelled your brother more than once, and we have two wounded in a week.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_help_thanks_1">
    <text>Thank you very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_0">
    <text>Why are you walking empty, without protection? Tired of living or what? Here, behind every bush is an anomaly - one zap, and you're a king! Here, without protection, people don't even twitch to take a leak - you'll catch a dose in an instant.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_1">
    <text>I see you don't really orient yourself here yet, so I'm warning you immediately in a neighborly way: don't mess with the soldiers. See one - beat it to hell's grandmother, cause they have zero brains. First they'll stitch you with a burst, and only then look at documents to see what your name was.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_10">
    <text>Bandits run things here. Keep this in mind so you don't get into trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_100">
    <text>Good day.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_101">
    <text>Good afternoon.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_102">
    <text>I wish you health (Military greeting).</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_103">
    <text>Hi, dude!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_104">
    <text>Hi.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_105">
    <text>Oh, hi!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_106">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_107">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_108">
    <text>Hello, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_109">
    <text>Greetings, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_11">
    <text>You are in territory where order is maintained by members of the Duty group. Any demand of the patrol must be obeyed implicitly; all necessary explanations will be given if necessary. Although the rules of behavior here are simple: behave like a human being with everyone, and everything will be fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_110">
    <text>Hey you, stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_111">
    <text>Howdy.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_112">
    <text>Whoa! Look who's here!..</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_113">
    <text>And who do we have here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_114">
    <text>Hello, man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_120">
    <text>I'm new here myself. But the local atmosphere has already worn me out. It's harder to get out of here than to get in.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_121">
    <text>Hi, kind person! Hiding too? Everyone hides here - some from their past life, some want to run away from themselves...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_122">
    <text>Do you know about Clear Sky? A clan like that. They conspire better than any secret agents. I only found out about them from snippets of radio traffic, plus other stalkers tell various tall tales...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_123">
    <text>A group appeared here recently. Called "Clear Sky". Unclear what kind of clan, what goals. But I've seen people in my life, learned to understand. Those I met are "nerds" - I give my tooth! What "in what sense"? Scientists they are or some other intellectuals. Although, I must say, they also know how to hold a weapon. And a person with brains and a weapon - that is, you understand, a serious person. Better not joke with such.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_12">
    <text>If you have questions, go straight to the bar - here it is, right here! There they will tell you everything, and answer, and ask themselves, but I'm tight on time right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_13">
    <text>First time here? Then I advise you to go to the bar: your colleagues there will tell you all the latest news.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_14">
    <text>Try not to approach zombies too much. And don't go to the laboratory, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_15">
    <text>I don't advise approaching the laboratory building: many zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_16">
    <text>You know, I would advise you to stay away from the laboratory complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_17">
    <text>Beware of zombies, they are stupid, don't fear a damn thing. Better not go to the laboratory - they have a breeding ground there, or something...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_18">
    <text>Bear in mind - Radar is already nearby here. Don't even think about rushing in the northern direction.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_19">
    <text>Look, if you don't want to lose your brains - don't go north from here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_2">
    <text>Be careful behind the bridge, got it? Stray dogs have bred unmeasured there. If you clap your ears - they'll eat you in two seconds.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_20">
    <text>Take care of yourself as a person! It's two steps to the Radar here: if you go north - oops, and one more idiot is ready at once.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_21">
    <text>It's just like walking through a minefield, only worse. Devil knows what happens here at times, can't relax for a second.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_22">
    <text>I advise you to increase attention, and once increased - don't relax. Relaxed - lost, curtains for you immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_23">
    <text>Need to keep ears on top of the head all the time here! Sleep with half an eye! Any moment some bullshit can happen.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_24">
    <text>Be careful with the scumbags! Like cockroaches here - swarming!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_25">
    <text>Destroy Monolithians as soon as you see them! Very dangerous - real fanatics!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_26">
    <text>There are some idiots here, call themselves Monolithians... or someone else nicknamed them that - well, doesn't matter. In short, they don't fear pain, if ammo runs out - they throw themselves like that, literally try to gnaw your throat. Anyway, see one - shoot immediately, don't hesitate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_3">
    <text>Listen here. See a tunnel - don't go into it. I'm telling you right away, cause not everyone has enough brains not to climb into the deepest ass. They won't even carry you out of there later - you'll remain in pieces on the walls. This is already the Zone, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_4">
    <text>Why are you empty? Did you meet those guys under the bridge too? Such bitches! They almost stripped me naked just now. Gave them almost all the loot! And they sit there, fattening... Bandits, soldiers at the checkpoint - zero difference.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_5">
    <text>Why do you walk alone? It's full of skinheads here, they can catch you at any moment! Lately they've become completely insolent, I heard they even attacked checkpoints.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_6">
    <text>Warning you, if you're not in the loop: bandits have been stirring here lately. Second shootout with them in a week already. Be careful, look around, cause they already sent six loners to the other world.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_7">
    <text>Did you, by chance, hear out of the corner of your ear what the soldiers suddenly needed in the research institute building? Why did they bustle so much there today?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_8">
    <text>Be more attentive here. Lawless ones settled in the main building. Jackals, one word - no conscience, no pity in them, I'd strangle them all...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_9">
    <text>Not worth walking alone in the Dark Valley. Bandits have a strong nest in one of the buildings here, still can't smoke them out. Watch out you don't run into them, kid.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_1">
    <text>Bro, help!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_10">
    <text>Help, somebody!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_11">
    <text>Guards, I'm wounded! To me!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_12">
    <text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_13">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_14">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_15">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_16">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_17">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_18">
    <text>Stalker... give a medkit... dying... Help - and I will help you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_2">
    <text>Guys, a medkit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_3">
    <text>Medkit here!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_4">
    <text>Anti-shock, lads! Faster!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_5">
    <text>Medkit, men!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_6">
    <text>Somebody!.. Give a medkit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_7">
    <text>Friend, medkit... medkit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_8">
    <text>Help, dude!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_9">
    <text>Share some pharmacy, buddy, eh?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_128">
    <text>Eh, mother... My luck has run out. I was lucky in everything for so long, and here life started asking for everything at once. You think I came to this rotten hole of my own will? I had everything tip-top in the Zone! A warm spot, and earnings like there's no tomorrow. Only everything ended, and my buddies wanted to put me on a knife - that's why I had to make tracks to where they won't find me. Why on a knife? And that, I'll tell you, is no longer your concern.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_129">
    <text>It's simple. I crossed the path of the wrong guy... Solid, you know, very much so. He put a price on my head. And there are oh so many willing to grab it! So I came here, away from human eyes. Wait it out until everything settles down, and then I'll visit this guy myself. Need to talk about old business...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_130">
    <text>I got into Clear Sky by accident. Guys pulled me out of the swamp back in the day. Brought me to the base, listened to Dan, think - here is a sensible man! Knows such things about the Zone that not every brain is capable of comprehending. And "Sky's" goals are correct. So I joined it, now I help to the best of my modest abilities.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_131">
    <text>Gaining experience, saving finances. Once I get rich, I'll buy myself a gun and armor cooler, and rush to the center of the Zone, where the Wish Granter is located. They say someone already managed to pass there. So I will go too. Once I find it, I won't miscalculate with the wish, rest assured!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_132">
    <text>Listened to stories and all sorts of tall tales, so the difficult carried me across the Cordon. From that side, everything was painted completely differently. And once I got here, all the flair flew off. You can die here at any minute, and dragging loot isn't that simple. But what kills me most of all is that there are no quiet and calm places anywhere. Even need to sleep with half an eye...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_133">
    <text>The Zone mesmerized me. Got here by accident, sort of like an illegal excursion... and, you know, it hooked me! People here are real - both enemies and friends. And this danger, the feeling of imminent death - it, willy-nilly, forces you to feel alive and enjoy every minute of this life.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_134">
    <text>I'm waiting for a buddy of mine here. Should return with loot. We missed each other there. I was just lucky that I left earlier. No, he couldn't disappear: do you know what kind of pretzel (tough guy) he is? Na-ah, nothing can happen to such a guy. Must return now, I know. Well, you never know: maybe he went around or went on a spree in the Bar with some acquaintance...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_135">
    <text>Some schmuck sold me a map of a stash. I'm starting to suspect it's fake. I climbed all over here with it - and damn all! There is no stash with loot here. Well, if I find him - I'll kill the bastard!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_136">
    <text>Resting after the last raid. Went almost to the Barrier itself - we organized a defense there against all sorts of evil spirits pushing from the center. Good guys gathered. Sanya Shaggy, Lyokha Pal, Maldi - all soulful guys. And I also found some good loot. Here, sold it to the trader and decided to rest a bit here. It's easier here, after all, than in the big Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_101">
    <text>Oh those Monolithians, damn them... Their roof has totally moved already, there was a time they were still peaceful... I remember I met one in the Zone once, well he started his blabber about the Monolith again, like: "Brothers, the Monolith called me at night. I spoke with him. He was beautiful in his greatness. I almost went blind, but his light filled me with great power! I know, I feel that his power resides with all of us! He told me that only firm faith can defeat evil. He said that his power will fill only the faithful. He also revealed to me that our victory is already close." And I answer him: "Go to hell with your Monolith!". He boiled over, yelled: "The time will come, and we will cleanse the Zone of the infidels!", and all that. Apparently, the bastard didn't lie - now they have become completely brutal, pushing from the CNPP in crowds, shooting at everyone indiscriminately, totally went nuts!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_102">
    <text>Got matches? Don't smoke? Eh, damn, no luck for me today...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_103">
    <text>You, young stalker, if you see a message on the PDA about Semetsky's death - don't get distracted, this is one of the legends of the Zone. This message will come to you more than once. They say that Semetsky is one of those who managed to reach the Monolith. What did he ask for? Correct, immortality. So now he crawls around the Zone, dying repeatedly. Some even saw him, although they might be lying. E-eh, Zone, you are full of secrets and mysteries... Did I annoy you much with my legends? Well go on, go in peace. Good loot to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_104">
    <text>I'll tell a joke. Three stalkers argued who is cooler, decided like this - whoever kicks more people out of the stalker bar is the coolest. The first grabs a heavy machine gun, flies into the bar and yells at the top of his lungs: "Everyone get out of here fast!" Half the audience washed away, a dozen stalkers remained. They beat him up so bad, he barely got away. Next day the second one did some magic, pretended to be a mutant and zip into the bar. The audience washed away through windows and doors, a Duty squad remained, beat him up - like there's no tomorrow. Well, a day later the third simply walks into the bar and from the threshold starts coughing: "Kha-k-kha-guhu-guhu-kha, kh-kh-kh-ptui! Yo, cursed syphilis!"</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_105">
    <text>Anyway, there is another tale. True, they say it was a long time ago, long before I got here myself. So... A foreigner decided to become a stalker somehow, like to collect money. Seems he was a scientist... Hell knows what he needed here, but he understood almost damn all in Russian, and spoke generally little... Not clear how he reached the Zone and the Barman. Outside the Zone someone advised him to see the Barman. So, he understood damn all in Russian, although he thought the opposite... Started pestering the Barman in broken language... Fought with him for a couple of hours. Either he needed to get somewhere, or wanted to find someone... In short, Barman didn't understand anything clearly, and decided to send this weirdo to the Freedom territory, says to him: go, he says, there and there, that territory is controlled by Freedom fighters, so they will tell you everything. Back then, for some reason, people thought Freedom guys were good with English. So out of all Barman's words, this foreign miracle liked "control" - it sounds the same in English for them. Coming to Freedom, he started interrogating everyone: "Control, control-ler, controller". Waves his hand towards Duty and keeps saying his "control". They say Freedom guys got scared not weakly, raised the whole camp. And it was night, guarded on towers until morning. That guy was kicked out of the Freedom base later, they didn't see him in Duty either. Unlikely he found what he was looking for in the Zone...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_106">
    <text>Many have become "scavengers" lately. Before, nobody even looked in the heaps - the radiation was such that it would hard-boil your balls in half an hour. But now, since loot has become tight, they wrap themselves in protection, take meds, and climb in to search. A lot of stuff can be found there, though mostly small fry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_107">
    <text>Rookies have become completely insolent lately. They climb into anomalies and die, die, die... In the last two days, imagine, five young stalkers vanished. And if only they became a bit more careful! Nope. Look, Mukha recently took three oafs into his squad - where are they now? And he, by the way, rose nicely with loot. Maybe he whacked them himself? Nah, unlikely... he is honest... relatively. Anyway, as I see, you are also a rookie, so keep ears on top of the head. Good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_108">
    <text>Know about secret laboratories deep in the Zone?.. They say they still work... Well yes, well yes... It's unclear how anyone could survive there at all... without supplies, energy... So the question arises - maybe it's not humans working there? I talked to a guy here... He didn't see laboratories himself... No, didn't see himself, but caught some strange negotiations on the scanner at Yantar. They talked about some laboratory. And another guy swore to this first one that he stumbled upon a figure in a jumpsuit like a stalker's, but more fancy... And this semi-transparent figure told him to get the hell out of here. "Don't interfere, he says, leave, we are working here". Well, the guy crapped himself... understandably! Who of us saw such a thing before?.. On the other hand, this seems to have happened not far from the radar... Well yes. So it's unlikely true... But on the other hand... mutations, they happen differently, probably? Maybe these are not humans anymore, but some energy entities? Huh?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_109">
    <text>They say a couple of Spetsnaz guys were invited to the Arena... Gotta see the brave man who decides to fight them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_110">
    <text>A pack of rats runs. A stalker meets them. "Any cool ones?", - he asks. "No". "Then one artifact from each rat, and run along". Next day same thing! Rats decided to call a blind dog. Running. Stalker comes out, stops the pack: "Any cool ones?" Rats scatter, and a blind dog comes out. "Well, like, I'm cool". Stalker steps back, a controller comes out: "So, ten artifacts from the cool ones, one from the rest! And run along!"</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_111">
    <text>Hey, man, do you know anything properly about "Intercept"? They say they are specialists, career military! But how they work, eh?! How they work! Not like the assholes at the cordons! Not only do they climb into the deepest ass, but also sit in the Zone for months! I'm not lying! They have bases, several at once, tons of stashes, and supplies are dropped to them at the perimeter by chopper constantly. Their commander is some Gromov... think the surname is fake, not real. They call him either "Major" or "Thunder". Don't believe me?! Well Pakhomych caught an intercept once! Caught it and barely carried his legs away, otherwise they would've wasted him just for living... Secrecy, damn it! Everyone knows Pakhomych? Well, exactly! This isn't bullshit, but a serious team. Hell knows what appeared so interesting to them here, but they work - oh dear mother! If only I could do a third... no, ten percent like that! Would have built a house in Sochi ten floors high already... They say they have a thing... detects monsters at two hundred meters. Any beast! Clearly, then you can walk through the Zone spitting... And they also say, there are some doers... Not military, but sort of from ours... Anyway, some broke through to the center of the Zone. Not only broke through - they say they know how to tame beasts! They generally don't go beyond the perimeter, to the Mainland - and nobody goes to them either... well, except those, probably, who are written in fate to reach the Sarcophagus... They have artifacts - enough to wipe with! Duty knows about them well... they know, bastards, fight and keep silent! Ask any of these cops, everyone answers: "Fairy tales". Bitches, aren't they?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_112">
    <text>A misfortune happened to me, lost my backpack with loot. Just like that! Thought I'd return with big earnings, and here is misfortune: at night a blind dog dived out from under the bushes, snarled at me. Well, I almost crapped my pants from fear, even confused it with a pseudodog at first, cause you can hear the approach of blind ones, and these trashes are silent. And I dropped the backpack, and ran! Thought at first that this reptile would run after me, but she grabbed the backpack and disappeared in an unknown direction, bitch! I'll go on a new raid. By the way, don't want to come with me? No? Well okay, bye.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_113">
    <text>I heard during Emissions controllers glitch childishly, and are capable of nothing. In short, you can take them with bare hands...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_114">
    <text>A joke. A bit dumb, but funny. Stalkers sit in a pub in the evening, downing beer, telling stalker tales... One says: "I met a monster THI-I-IS big in the Zone the other day, emptied all ammo into it, barely took it down with a grenade launcher". Everyone: "O-o!" Second tells: "And I saw a monster THI-I-IS big in the Zone yesterday, emptied all ammo, grenades didn't take it, only took it down with a flamethrower". Everyone: "O-O-O!" Third says: "And a monster THI-I-IS big noticed me in the Zone today..." Everyone at once: "Wha-a-at???" Stalker calmly: "What-what? Barely washed my pants at home!"</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_115">
    <text>Heard about the Guide? The very first of stalkers. Started walking into the Zone first. Still alive. They say he can guide to any point. Another matter is that finding him is problematic - doesn't paste posters with his address... And doesn't agree to guide everyone either. Takes a lot of dough, but if you found him and agreed, be sure - he'll deliver you ironically where needed. That's who I'd like to chat with. He must have seen what is there, beyond the radar...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_116">
    <text>You know what I'll say? In this part of the Zone you can barely sleep... I'm lucky, I can't fall asleep anyway... but people have such nightmares that, happens, they don't wake up in the morning... from heart rupture, for example... Some kick the bucket, some lose their roof concretely... Recently, true, a rumor went that there is a remedy. If you really need to sleep, preferably find an old bucket... or a large pot at least... a boiler... Main thing, needs to be whole... Put your head in there - and sleep like in God's bosom... Well laugh, laugh. I'll look at you in a couple of days, when you start falling off your feet from fatigue. Wise guy... And tell me yourself, why the hell did soldiers start prowling here lately in tricky helmets? Well yes! Before, for two years, not a peep, and lately they frequent! Their helmets are some new ones - guys found a body of one, told about it. A mesh inside made of thin copper wire, attached to the liner. So think - what kind of harness, why the hell is it like that? And generally this "buzz-buzz" isn't for nothing, I tell you precisely. There isn't much to pick from anomalies here - not those grounds, in other sections it's both safer and fatter pieces can be found... I think, they are marking approaches. Preparing a bridgehead. Want to break through to the Sarcophagus, mark my word. Soon it will bang so hard - it won't seem little to anyone. Mark my word... Main thing is to be far away from here at that moment...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_117">
    <text>Heard the news, eh? Yesterday there was a terrible massacre in the neighboring camp. Mercenaries worked, their handwriting - cut everyone. Seems the sentry fell asleep at the post, and these Herods slashed his throat with a blade - and that's it, remember his name, and then his sleeping buddies. None of ours even heard shots, oh how...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_118">
    <text>Did I tell you about the Black Stalker? You see, there is such a legend here, they say some strange stalker appeared in the Zone. Who is he, where from and what he trades in, nobody knows. Wears a black cloak with a hood thrown over so his face isn't visible, no weapon with him. Generally only a few people saw him from afar. So they tell that unimaginable horror came over everyone when they looked at him. Even monsters shy away from him, they say. Who is he, eh? Some say - it's some new mutant appeared, others - that it's a ghost, third - that these are all tales of drunk stalkers, and he doesn't exist at all. Hell knows... Until I see with my own eyes - I won't believe.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_58">
    <text>Well, listen to humor about a controller. Old controller teaches a young one: "See over the-e-ere, a soldier standing at the post? Belt tightened, new uniform, boots shine - called a 'Spirit' (Rookie). You can take him under control right from here, but no use: shoots bad, afraid of everything, no meat, skin and bones. And nearby see a fighter smoking? Uniform worn, boots trodden - called a 'Scoop' (Regular). Prey so-so, hard to take under control, shoots good, always on alert, lots of meat but stringy. Good to take him at night when he naps. And see over the-e-ere, under the bush a soldier sleeps, no belt, barefoot? That's a 'Grandpa' (Veteran). Lots of meat, fatty, but hell you'll get close to him, doesn't sleep at night and will crush you even with bare hands. Gotta take him when he goes to the village for moonshine or tramps into the Zone for loot. And see a soldier walking, belt tightened, boots shine, but may the Zone forbid you confuse him with a 'Spirit'. I took one like foolishly, so I scrubbed my lair with a toothbrush for two weeks, barely escaped - called a 'Comrade Warrant Officer'".</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_59">
    <text>Listen to a new joke - told in the bar. A stalker comes to Sidorovich somehow. And he says to him: "Listen, stalker. They passed me a spacesuit from a Kiev secret research institute, seems like with 100% radiation protection. But nobody tested it yet. Go into the Zone in it, see what's what. And I'll give you a discount on it later, if you survive..." Stalker agreed. Went into the Zone and no show for a day, and two, and three... On the fourth he comes angry as a snork, and slams the spacesuit on Sidorovich's table! He was taken aback: "What, stalker? Doesn't protect?" And the stalker barked at him: "Protects!" "Not 100%?" - asked the trader, lost in guesses. "100%!" - roared the stalker. "So what are you unhappy with?" - Sidorovich couldn't understand. Stalker leaned to the trader and yelled in his ear: "The whole Zone treats radiation with vodka from morning till evening - ONLY I LIKE A FOOL HAVE BEEN SOBER FOR THE FOURTH DAY!"</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_60">
    <text>Yeah, saw the other day how soldiers cleared the territory near the forest on the Radar - about thirty people, wasted everything that moves: fleshes, boars, even "trampled" dogs... So I... got out of there, you never know... Don't want to receive lead in the ass.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_61">
    <text>Tell a joke? A car rushes on the highway towards the Cordon at a speed of about 120 km/h. A traffic cop whistles like a nightingale, car brakes, a whole squad of "Duty" guys climbs out, gave the soldier a beating, shoved the whistle up his ass and rushed on. The patrol takes out the radio: "Seven, two-seven three!" "Seven two!" - answer on the radio. And the patrol warns: "Senya! Some ugly rushing in your direction, doesn't react to the whistle! So you stop him with the baton, the baton! Do you copy, seven-two?..."</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_62">
    <text>Man, ever heard of the Phantom, no? Gonna tell you, you won't believe. They say there was one stalker in the Zone, don't know the name, everyone called him Phantom. He was an experienced stalker, and good as a person, in general, understood people. Rumor had it he studied to be a psychologist in college, well, that doesn't matter at all, moving to the main point: he was a sneak, would slip through everywhere. Neither checkpoints nor anomalies were obstacles to him, he went deep into the Zone, and once disappeared, most likely got caught in an Emission or somewhere else, well, in general, he became something like a poltergeist, for ten years he's been walking the Zone, looking for other stalkers, when he finds one - looks into your soul, and if you are a good person, he helps you with something, points to a shelter, helps fight off mutants, but if, brother, you have sins unmeasured behind your soul, then hide - will tear to pieces. Here is a bedtime story for you...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_63">
    <text>Stalker, where did you get such a gun? Bought at the Barman's, probably? Yes, his guns are classy, only cost oh so expensive. He, bastard, probably buys them from the army for pennies, and sells to us for triple! No brother, no stupid ones here. I better look for a gun at the garbage, even if it radiates so you start glowing yourself, at least it's free.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_64">
    <text>Hey, stalker, they told me a funny one the other day. Listen here. Showdown between Duty guys and stalkers from Freedom. So, Freedom commander stands up, shouts: "Forward, for Freedom!" Well, everyone breaks into attack, you understand. Duty stalkers from that side of the front: "Well that's it, damn, ass, need to run". And an old experienced Duty guy says: "Wait with the running", - takes out a machine gun: rat-tat-tat-tat. Freedom guys lay down. Five minutes pass, Freedom guy stands up again: "For the Zone! Hurra-a-a-a-a-a!" Well, everyone into attack again. Duty: "Well now for sure ass, need to run". Old Duty guy: "Wait you!" - takes a rifle and again rat-tat-tat-tat. Well, Freedom guys lay down again. More time passes. Freedom commander stands up again: "For ours, for Freedom in the Zone, forward!" And again everyone rushed into attack. Duty youth panic again. Old Duty guy does his thing again. Freedom had to lie down once more. After 5 minutes Freedom commander stands up. Face in shit, all in shit, and roars: "Damn, I didn't understand!" Old Duty guy, throwing a cigarette butt aside: "Now it's time to run".</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_65">
    <text>Heard about mercenaries? No? Well then listen carefully and write down: they, brother, are hitmen, and serious and desperate guys, they will get anyone you want alive or dead. Remember someone wasted Sych recently? Precise shot to the heart and head, corpse burned, no traces on site - their work, believe me. These bastards have no conscience, killing a person for them is like crushing a cockroach, only respect coin. Rumors go they have a base somewhere in Pripyat, only nobody returned alive from there yet, they don't like strangers. And know how they train? Take, catch a bandit or some stalker, bring to their place, give him an AKS with two clips and let him go to all four sides. If after 12 hours the man isn't a corpse yet, then he can live on. Those are their amusements, brother. For all time only Misha Squint managed to stay alive, and even then because he served 10 years in Spetsnaz. In general, stalker, see dudes in blue suits - legs in hands and wind it far away, although if they laid an eye on you, you won't get away anyway - will get you from underground.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_66">
    <text>They say there is one group of comrades... Sometimes called shamans, sometimes druids. They, they say, don't carry electronic equipment at all - closer to nature, they say, and all that... Well, they say that the Zone reacts to electronics... to all sorts of electromagnetic radiations stronger... yes, and sets monsters on you. As it turns out according to them, the Zone is a living organism. Cannot, they say, climb into it with devices - a correct person will manage without any extra attachments. True, they carry rifles, goats... Why not try with teeth and claws... On the other hand, seems not so many of them die in the Zone. They don't glue flippers (die) more often than us... So, maybe they figured correctly... They, true, seem to enter the Zone more from the Belarusian side... Would be good to look at them... and check at the same time how many artifacts they have in their pockets...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_67">
    <text>Hey, Barman told me that yesterday bloodsuckers attacked the village at Army Warehouses - nobody left alive, didn't even manage to give a clear signal. Freedom guys went to check next day, say there was such a slaughter - guys cut like pigs, only shreds lying around... horror, in general.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_68">
    <text>Treat me to a cigarette? Don't smoke? Clear... Doing right, by the way. Good for the body, and breath saved for running from dogs, heh-heh... Generally, you know, some skilled mercenaries, fucking snipers, wasted stalkers in the dark by an interesting principle. When stalkers gathered in a bunch and relaxed with nicotine, the mercenary spotted the flash of a lit match and the cigarette light when the first one lit up. Then the second stalker lit up - the match light moved, second cigar lit up, and the sniper took a lead on fire transfer. Third lit up and immediately received a bullet in the head... Therefore stalkers now have a law "Three don't light from one match". So jokes aside, but human life can depend on these trifles, so there...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_69">
    <text>Met some crazy man here recently. His suit was army issue, spetsnaz rifle, but behavior - a total zombie: one leg drags halfway, movements indistinct, body obeys poorly... I almost shot him at first. Was confused that he held his rifle firmly in hands. How many zombies I've seen in my time, but haven't seen one like that yet. And he tried to say something to me, only I understood almost nothing... Understood only "controller" and "help". Just wanted to help the kid, heard a chopper, got scared and ran. Dived into a grove, soldiers appeared, about seven people, and then a helicopter. Three took this kid at gunpoint, and the rest rushed to him and knocked him to the ground. Imagine, their own and face in the mud! Shouted something else about some helmet. Then under the arms and into the helicopter... Something strange here... This kid, his words about controller... Soldiers... Did he really manage to get away from a controller...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_70">
    <text>I managed to sit by the fire with one mercenary recently. Turned out to be not a bad guy, killed stalkers, as you understand, only by order of superiors, just like that - no-no. Generally, mercenaries treat our stalker brother not badly, especially seasoned ones and veterans. Respect, although they consider only themselves unsurpassed masters. And this mercenary told me the story of his life. For his service he has an Order of Courage and a medal "For Bravery". He studied at a sniper training center. Everything was serious there: checking weapons every time and stuff. But he said such a thing, that real sniper skills can be acquired only in war, in hot spots. Happened that a person was taught long, thoroughly, but as soon as he takes the exam (usually conducted in Chechnya) - nope, person can't do it - and that's it. In school you can prepare, shoot at targets, hit them confidently, but at the most crucial moment something might switch inside a person, and he simply won't be able to do it. Just like that. So you, stalker, be more confident in the Zone. If something threatens your life - be more confident. Psychology.</text>
</string>