<string id="item test1">
    <text>This is a test string for the backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="item test2">
    <text>This is another test string for the backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="item_case_esc_desc">
    <text>Case with documents. Made of fireproof material.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_decoder_desc">
    <text>Something like a powerful electronic lockpick. Seems it was created with the aim to hack some specific electronic lock.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_decoder_name">
    <text>Decoder</text>
</string>
<string id="item_detector_yantar_desc">
    <text>Device for measuring psi-emission.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_detector_yantar_name">
    <text>Sensor PP-4A</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x16_desc">
    <text>Polyethylene file with documents. Without a degree in biology it's hard to understand anything in them.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x16_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-16</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18_desc">
    <text>Thick stack of scientific papers. Solid terms, formulas and diagrams.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p1_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-18, p. 1</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p2_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-18, p. 2</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p3_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-18, p. 3</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p4_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-18, p. 4</text>
</string>
<string id="item_doc_x18p5_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-18, p. 5</text>
</string>
<string id="item_docs_hiden_pri_desc">
    <text>Worn manuscript in a leather cover. Written by Strelok himself. Judging by the titles, some mysteries of the Zone are revealed in it.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_docs_hiden_pri_name">
    <text>Documents from Pripyat</text>
</string>
<string id="item_dynamite_esc_desc">
    <text>Heavy wooden crate with "Explosive" inscriptions in several languages.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_dynamite_esc_name">
    <text>Crate of dynamite</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_crazy_mil_desc">
    <text>Flash drive - a convenient device for transferring information.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_crazy_mil_name">
    <text>Madman's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_eco_rost_desc">
    <text>Flash drive - a convenient device for transferring information.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_eco_rost_name">
    <text>Professor Kruglov's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_esc_desc">
    <text>Flash drive - a convenient device for transferring information.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_esc_name">
    <text>Prisoner's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_desc">
    <text>Flash drive - a convenient device for transferring information.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_flash_gslinger_agro_name">
    <text>Strelok's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="item_key_x18_desc">
    <text>Electronic key from the underground laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_key_x18_name">
    <text>Borov's key</text>
</string>
<string id="item_krot_flash">
    <text>Mole's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="item_PDA_lucky_desc">
    <text>Pocket personal computer. An indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_PDA_lucky_name">
    <text>Lucky's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="item_PDA_tiran_desc">
    <text>Pocket personal computer. An indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_PDA_tiran_name">
    <text>Tyrant's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="item_quest_case_02_desc">
    <text>Case with documents. Made of fireproof material.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_quest_case_02_name">
    <text>Military documents from RSI "Agroprom"</text>
</string>
<string id="item_case_esc_name">
    <text>Documents from the checkpoint</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_bad_psy_helmet_desc">
    <text>Untuned prototype, developed by scientists for protection against psi-emission.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_bad_psy_helmet_name">
    <text>Untuned psi-helmet</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_good_psy_helmet_desc">
    <text>Tuned prototype, developed by scientists for protection against psi-emission.</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_good_psy_helmet_name">
    <text>Tuned psi-helmet</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case1_desc">
    <text>Ordinary metal fireproof case #1. Apparently, it contains valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case1_name">
    <text>Ordinary metal case</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case2_desc">
    <text>Ordinary metal fireproof case #2. Apparently, it contains valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case2_name">
    <text>Ordinary metal case</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case3_desc">
    <text>Ordinary metal fireproof case #3. Apparently, it contains valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case3_name">
    <text>Ordinary metal case</text>
</string>
<string id="stranger">
    <text>Stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_box_desc">
    <text>Convenient container for carrying medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_box_name">
    <text>Container with medicines</text>
</string>
<string id="box_food_desc">
    <text>Wooden crate with canned food inside. Apparently, lain for more than a day, but, strangely enough, the meat in the cans is edible. At least something we know how to make with quality.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_food_name">
    <text>Wooden crate with canned food inside</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_sms">
    <text>Personal messages.</text>
</string>
<string id="sms">
    <text>Message.</text>
</string>
<string id="sms_haron_text">
    <text>This is Charon, I am waiting for you, there is an urgent matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_desc">
    <text>Scheme of communications of Pripyat and CNPP. Blueprints and graphs, hard for an unprepared person to figure out.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_name">
    <text>Scheme of communications of Pripyat and CNPP</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_box_desc">
    <text>Small metal container. Solomon's parcel.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_box_name">
    <text>Small metal container</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_pismo_desc">
    <text>Letter wrapped in durable cardboard packaging. For Sobolev from Zahar.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_pismo_name">
    <text>Letter from Zahar</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_doc_desc">
    <text>Folder with a list of agents who somehow collaborated with the military.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_doc_name">
    <text>Folder with list of agents</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-winchester_knyaz">
    <text>Knyaz's Winchester</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_computer_desc">
    <text>System unit from laboratory X-10 on the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_computer_name">
    <text>System unit</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_doc_desc">
    <text>Documents from laboratory X-10 on the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_doc_name">
    <text>Documents from laboratory</text>
</string>
<string id="part_sect_desc">
    <text>Fragment of a map indicating the stash of Semetsky himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="part1_name">
    <text>Fragment #1</text>
</string>
<string id="part2_name">
    <text>Fragment #2</text>
</string>
<string id="part3_name">
    <text>Fragment #3</text>
</string>
<string id="part4_name">
    <text>Fragment #4</text>
</string>
<string id="part5_name">
    <text>Fragment #5</text>
</string>
<string id="part6_name">
    <text>Fragment #6</text>
</string>
<string id="part7_name">
    <text>Fragment #7</text>
</string>
<string id="part8_name">
    <text>Fragment #8</text>
</string>
<string id="semeckii_treasure_box_descr">
    <text>Stash of Semetsky himself. According to rumors, very valuable things are stored in it.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_semeckii_treasure_box_name">
    <text>Semetsky's Stash</text>
</string>
<string id="tainik_semeckii">
    <text>Search for Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="first">
    <text>First fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_part_text">
    <text>You found the first fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="second">
    <text>Second fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_part_text">
    <text>You found the second fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri">
    <text>Third fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_part_text">
    <text>You found the third fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="four">
    <text>Fourth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_part_text">
    <text>You found the fourth fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="five">
    <text>Fifth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_part_text">
    <text>You found the fifth fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="six">
    <text>Sixth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="six_part_text">
    <text>You found the sixth fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="seven">
    <text>Seventh fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="seven_part_text">
    <text>You found the seventh fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="vosem">
    <text>Eighth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="vosem_part_text">
    <text>You found the eighth fragment of the map that indicates the location of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="new_plan_desc">
    <text>Sack with weed for Knyaz. Marijuana, or something more serious?</text>
</string>
<string id="new_plan_name">
    <text>Sack with weed</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_ucen_need_metka">
    <text>Place markers on monsters: The Pseudogiant was last seen at Rostok, there is also a downed helicopter lying there for a long time.
A bald chimera can be met in the Dark Valley. You know, there is also an abandoned factory, bandits sometimes set up their lair there. So behind it there is a small swamp, right by the fence where the drain pipes are. Well, hope you understood. And a bloodsucker lives at the Cordon. You know, there is also a destroyed bridge and two abandoned pig farms nearby. Somewhere there. Now about the method of placing the marker: I will give you an "SKS" carbine, modified by one of our craftsmen. It shoots only special ammo, which upon contact with the victim's body places a marker on it, without causing harm. Thus, you will be able to place a marker on all three. Yes, don't forget to return it later, you don't need it anyway, you can't kill from it, and we still need it. If everything goes successfully, in return I will send you useful information to your PDA: the transition Yantar - Radar. And of course, you cannot kill the test subjects - I need them alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="detector_kruglov">
    <text>Kruglov's Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="detector_kruglov_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's Detector, with its help one can detect a very rare artifact - "Controller's Heart".</text>
</string>
<string id="book_zombi_name">
    <text>Diary of the mad professor</text>
</string>
<string id="book_zombi_desc">
    <text>Diary of the mad professor. Apparently, the professor at one time was very interested in the laboratory on Yantar, especially he was interested in how the psi-installation works.</text>
</string>
<string id="notebook_x16_name">
    <text>Laptop from X-16</text>
</string>
<string id="notebook_x16_desc">
    <text>Laptop from X-16. Records were kept in it, research schedules were compiled. Probably, once X-16 was a fairly large laboratory, but then something happened and the workers fled. Well, and the majority still roam the factory territory. Only they haven't been humans for a long time, but wandering zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_colt_ucen">
    <text>Kruglov's Colt</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_colt_ucen_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's Colt. A Colt modified by craftsmen with a silencer, shooting special ammo that does not kill its victim, but only temporarily paralyzes it.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_case_name">
    <text>Kruglov's Case</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_case_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's Case, intended for Voronin.</text>
</string>
<string id="check_name">
    <text>Bag of weed</text>
</string>
<string id="check_desc">
    <text>A small package with herbs, not parsley or dill. Reminds more of marijuana.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx18_flash_name">
    <text>Monolithian's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="labx18_flash_desc">
    <text>Monolithian's flash drive from laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_mayor_yarofeev">
    <text>According to Varyag's words, Major Yarofeev can be found at the Cordon, at the checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_sidr_lab">
    <text>Go to the laboratory on Yantar and find something: documents, computer, laptop or any thing that will help us understand what was happening there. As you find something, carry to Fang, he will wait for you at the warehouses, at the farm, near the Freedom base. They say that in the laboratory itself there is a certain installation that burns out brains of everything living, need to ask around scientists, possibly, they will be able to help.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_sahar_shlem">
    <text>There is one person, we worked together once, but then... then something terrible started happening to him: he started screaming at nights or suddenly fell silent and could sit looking at one point for whole days. Then even worse, he started throwing himself at people. We.... I had to part with him, apparently, he was covered by a radiation wave from the laboratory, hand didn't rise to kill him. Dan and the guys took him to Radar to Sviblov, but they say he escaped. So, it is necessary that you find him. He once long ago dealt exactly with the influence of psi-installation radiation on human brain and kept a diary, in it there is a lot of valuable stuff, and if one could acquire this diary, then I could retune your helmet.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_black_name">
    <text>Black box</text>
</string>
<string id="box_black_desc">
    <text>Black box from the crashed helicopter on the Radar. Careful - it is radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_priz_name">
    <text>Ghost's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_priz_desc">
    <text>Ghost's PDA. In it there are various data on artifacts and places of their appearance. Also mentions the destruction of the "Last Day" group and the murder of its leader. There is a little information about Monolith. Data is encrypted.</text>
</string>
<string id="af-caterpillar">
    <text>Controller's Heart</text>
</string>
<string id="af_caterpillar-desc">
    <text>A rare artifact. It can be found, but it is very difficult, and for this one must have special equipment. This artifact attracts monsters, especially controllers, which is why it was nicknamed the Controller's Heart. This artifact protects well against bullet wounds, but if a controller attacks you, beware. This artifact will not only not help, but on the contrary - will strengthen the controller's effect on your brain.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-rostok">
    <text>Guide (Rostok)</text>
</string>
<string id="af-rostok-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Electra" anomaly and a strong anti-gravitational field. It was named "Guide" for its ability to shift space for a while and thereby create spatial corridors, the so-called "Secret Trails", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. Only very experienced stalker-guides can "open" new routes using this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-sklady">
    <text>Guide (Warehouses)</text>
</string>
<string id="af-sklady-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Electra" anomaly and a strong anti-gravitational field. It was named "Guide" for its ability to shift space for a while and thereby create spatial corridors, the so-called "Secret Trails", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. Only very experienced stalker-guides can "open" new routes using this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-kordon">
    <text>Guide (Cordon)</text>
</string>
<string id="af-kordon-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Electra" anomaly and a strong anti-gravitational field. It was named "Guide" for its ability to shift space for a while and thereby create spatial corridors, the so-called "Secret Trails", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. Only very experienced stalker-guides can "open" new routes using this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-agro">
    <text>Guide (Agroprom)</text>
</string>
<string id="af-agro-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Electra" anomaly and a strong anti-gravitational field. It was named "Guide" for its ability to shift space for a while and thereby create spatial corridors, the so-called "Secret Trails", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. Only very experienced stalker-guides can "open" new routes using this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-sverhprovodnik">
    <text>Superconductor</text>
</string>
<string id="af-sverhprovodnik-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Electra" anomaly and a strong anti-gravitational field. It was named "Superconductor" for its ability to shift space for a long time and thereby create spatial corridors, the so-called "Secret Trails", with the help of which one can move along previously inaccessible routes. It differs from its "younger brothers", guides of a lower order, in that it instantly activates transitions along several routes at once. To activate it, you just need to pick up this artifact. But there is one thing: finding this artifact is extremely difficult. It appears in a short period of time, approximately within one hour, somewhere between one and two o'clock in the morning. If it is not found during this time, the artifact disappears. And the time for its search is limited to three days. Only very experienced stalker-guides can "open" new routes using this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-remover">
    <text>Liquidator</text>
</string>
<string id="af-remover-desc">
    <text>A very rare artifact which, when put out of the inventory on the ground, destroys all known anomalies within a radius of 15 meters. For its action, it was named "Liquidator". Besides this, it possesses no other properties. Reusable.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-spring-red">
    <text>Ruby Spring</text>
</string>
<string id="af-dummy-spring-red-desc">
    <text>A unique artifact, resembles a regular "Spring" in appearance, but red in color. Emits light. Has the effect of protection against shock impacts and increases bullet resistance, but makes the body more susceptible to radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-battery-red">
    <text>Ruby Battery</text>
</string>
<string id="af-dummy-battery-red-desc">
    <text>A unique artifact, resembles a regular "Battery" in appearance, but red in color. Emits light. Has the effect of restoring strength and protects against shock impacts, as well as increases bullet resistance and protection against electric shock, but makes the body more susceptible to radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-snake-eye">
    <text>Snake Eye</text>
</string>
<string id="af-snake-eye-desc">
    <text>A unique artifact allowing its owner to see what is hidden from others.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-1">
    <text>Chimeron</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-1-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet of the first order. If hung on the belt, the owner will receive 10% protection against electric shock and 10% protection against rupture. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-2">
    <text>Dragon</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-2-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet of the second order. If hung on the belt, the owner will receive 10% protection against burns, including chemical ones. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-3">
    <text>Avalon</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-3-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet of the third order. If hung on the belt, the owner will receive 10% protection against explosions and 10% bullet resistance. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-4">
    <text>Sarkon</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-4-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet of the fourth order. If hung on the belt, the owner will receive 10% protection against radiation. True, along with this, resistance to electric shock somewhat decreases.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-5">
    <text>Garganon</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-5-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet of the fifth order. If hung on the belt, the owner will receive 15% protection against telepathic influence. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-6">
    <text>Catalon</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-6-desc">
    <text>Mysterious Amulet-catalyst. Slightly radioactive. If placed together with collected amulets of all five previous orders, a process of magical catalyzation will occur and instead of six amulets, one Amulet-Absolute will appear, possessing doubled protective properties of all five ordinal amulets, and with all this, completely non-radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet-total">
    <text>Talisman</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet-total-desc">
    <text>Amulet-Talisman, obtained as a result of magical catalyzation of Amulets of five ordinal levels using the Amulet-catalyst. Possesses doubled protective properties of all five of its "progenitors", but unlike them, is completely non-radioactive and generally devoid of negative qualities. And besides, adds 40% protection against impacts and noticeably increases stamina.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-roza">
    <text>Wind Rose</text>
</string>
<string id="af-roza-desc">
    <text>One of the rarest artifacts in the Zone. Derivative of the "Burner" anomaly and strong radiation exposure. Originates only a couple of times a year in zones with a strong radiation background. Humans have not succeeded in finding it, so nothing is known for certain about this artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_pda_name">
    <text>Wolf's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_pda_desc">
    <text>Wolf's personal PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_krest_razborka">
    <text>At the Garbage, not far from the transition to the Dark Valley, a meeting between Krest and Chekhov's men is supposed to take place: "You, this, don't catch their eye. Chekhov's people are nervous. No wonder, made so many enemies, seeing you, they will start firing immediately. There is a destroyed building, not far from the checkpoint at the Garbage, so you climb to the top, the view from there is excellent. Hide there and sit, not a move from the spot. If everything is tip-top, we'll part peacefully, you holster the weapon and come to me. But if shooting starts, don't leave these nits alive, and, most importantly, protect Krest. In short, until my signal don't think about shooting and don't catch their eye, sit in place and wait. I know you, one thing - immediately grab the gun".</text>
</string>

<string id="svitok_1_name">
    <text>Manuscript #1</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_1_desc">
    <text>Handwritten scroll containing the first part of the code of laws of the "Monolith" brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_2_name">
    <text>Manuscript #2</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_2_desc">
    <text>Handwritten scroll containing the second part of the code of laws of the "Monolith" brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_3_name">
    <text>Manuscript #3</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_3_desc">
    <text>Handwritten scroll containing the third part of the code of laws of the "Monolith" brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_4_name">
    <text>Manuscript #4</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_4_desc">
    <text>Handwritten scroll containing the fourth part of the code of laws of the "Monolith" brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_5_name">
    <text>Manuscript #5</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_5_desc">
    <text>Handwritten scroll containing the fifth part of the code of laws of the "Monolith" brotherhood:\n"...The warrior who betrays the Brotherhood will turn into an outcast, and there will be no peace for him and no salvation, and demon-phantoms will pursue him eternally, as long as he lives."</text>
</string>
<string id="box_pekar_desc">
    <text>Wooden crate with stove spare parts inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_pekar_name">
    <text>Baker's wooden crate</text>
</string>
<string id="diplomat_skryaga_desc">
    <text>Leather briefcase with very important information inside. Parcel from the "Big Land" for Skinflint.</text>
</string>
<string id="diplomat_skryaga_name">
    <text>Leather briefcase</text>
</string>
<string id="muka_desc">
    <text>Sack with rye flour weighing 25 kg.</text>
</string>
<string id="muka_name">
    <text>Sack with flour</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_new_desc">
    <text>Device determining, with insignificant error, the date and time of the next blowout. Developed in a secret laboratory on Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_new_name">
    <text>Blowout detector</text>
</string>
<string id="bread_pekar_desk">
    <text>Fresh rye bread that does not go stale for a month. A loaf costs quite a lot, but whoever tastes it once will understand and appreciate it rightfully. Only one person in the Zone can bake this miracle bread. His nickname is "Baker". He sacredly keeps the secret of the recipe for making this truly wonderful bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="bread_pekar_name">
    <text>Rye bread</text>
</string>
<string id="helmet_new_desk">
    <text>Special helmet protecting against the destructive effect of blowouts. Developed in a secret laboratory on Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="helmet_new_name">
    <text>Protective helmet</text>
</string>
<string id="doc1_name">
    <text>Document #1</text>
</string>
<string id="doc1_desc">
    <text>Encrypted information.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc2_name">
    <text>Document #2</text>
</string>
<string id="doc2_desc">
    <text>Encrypted information.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc3_name">
    <text>Document #3</text>
</string>
<string id="doc3_desc">
    <text>Encrypted information.</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_tsezar_name">
    <text>Caesar's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_tsezar_desc">
    <text>Flash drive storing mercenary cipher codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_cod_name">
    <text>PDA with base code</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_cod_desc">
    <text>PDA into which Caesar loaded the common base code for decryption and asked to pass it to Count, together with the third part of the found encrypted documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_graf_name">
    <text>Count's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_graf_desc">
    <text>PDA into which Count loaded decrypted data about the mercenary special operation. This PDA must be passed to Fang.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_solomon_name">
    <text>Solomon's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_solomon_desc">
    <text>Solomon's PDA, where his personal data is stored.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_chelnok_name">
    <text>Shuttle's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_chelnok_desc">
    <text>Shuttle's PDA, where he stored all information about his clients and tasks. The device is heavily damaged. Apparently, due to the impact of an anomaly or claws and teeth of monsters.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_name">
    <text>Mandrake Root</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_desc">
    <text>Mandrake root, to which many attribute almost magical properties. Resembles a human figure in appearance.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_box_name">
    <text>Zahar's Container</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_box_desc">
    <text>Zahar's container, in which the rare artifacts found by him are located.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_remont_name">
    <text>Container with medicines</text>
</string>
<string id="box_remont_desc">
    <text>Metal container with medicines inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_green_name">
    <text>Fireproof Case</text>
</string>
<string id="box_green_desc">
    <text>Fireproof case with important information inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_lazarev_name">
    <text>Lazarev's Device</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_lazarev_desc">
    <text>Device determining the level and dynamics of anomalous activity growth.</text>
</string>
<string id="rukzak_adulin_name">
    <text>Backpack with Adulin</text>
</string>
<string id="rukzak_adulin_desc">
    <text>Backpack with potent medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_ban_name">
    <text>Bandits' flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_ban_desc">
    <text>Simple flash drive for storing information. Among other information, there should be data about the transition from Dark Valley to Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="mini_part_name">
    <text>Manual part</text>
</string>
<string id="mini_part_desc">
    <text>One of seven parts of the assembly manual for Item 62.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin">
    <text>Adulin</text>
</string>
<string id="adulin_desc">
    <text>Adulin - a powerful biochemical agent protecting the human psyche for a long time from various psi-influences and psi-attacks.</text>
</string>

<string id="antizombin">
    <text>Antizombin</text>
</string>
<string id="antizombin_desc">
    <text>A complex of biological elements that slows down the mutation of human body cells caused by the consequences of powerful psi-impact for a long time.</text>
</string>

<string id="cognac">
    <text>Jack Daniels Whiskey</text>
</string>
<string id="cognac_desc">
    <text>Jack Daniels Whiskey. A great rarity in the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="repair_kit">
    <text>Repair kit</text>
</string>
<string id="repair_kit_desc">
    <text>Universal repair kit with bio-electronic scanning of damage level. Designed for repairing any type of small arms. Restores 100% of damage. Created in a secret military laboratory of Peacekeepers. The principle of operation is based on the anomalous properties of the Jellyfish artifact. To activate the repair kit, it is necessary to have a Jellyfish artifact in the inventory. After each weapon repair procedure, the Jellyfish artifact evaporates, transferring all its anomalous properties to activate the bio-electronic scanner.</text>
</string>

<string id="harm">
    <text>Harmonica</text>
</string>
<string id="harm_desc">
    <text>Old harmonica.</text>
</string>

<string id="guitar">
    <text>Guitar</text>
</string>
<string id="guitar_desc">
    <text>Old six-string guitar.</text>
</string>

<string id="lekarstvo">
    <text>Medicine</text>
</string>
<string id="lekarstvo_desc">
    <text>Medicine for Forester.</text>
</string>

<string id="provisia">
    <text>Crate with provisions</text>
</string>
<string id="provisia_desc">
    <text>Crate with provisions from Forester's stash. Forester kept these supplies for an extreme case.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc_krol">
    <text>Krol's Diary</text>
</string>
<string id="doc_krol_desc">
    <text>Diary of a dead man, judging by the entries inside, it was the diary of a stalker-guide nicknamed "Krol", who finished his path in the catacombs of the Dead City. Among other entries, there is a mention of a unique secret device called "Bioradar", several prototypes of which were stolen from scientists. If "Bioradar" is hung on the belt next to mutant parts, it will display on its screen the location of those mutants whose parts hang on the belt at the moment. How to get this device should be known to one experienced stalker nicknamed Tanker. Apparently, he was involved in the robbery of the scientific camp. If only I could find this Tanker.</text>
</string>

<string id="propusk">
    <text>Pass</text>
</string>
<string id="propusk_desc">
    <text>Electronic pass with a password for access to the Peacekeepers territory.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo">
    <text>Letter to Sidor</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_pismo_desc">
    <text>Encrypted letter for Sidorovich from Barman.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_pismo">
    <text>Letter to Barman</text>
</string>
<string id="sidor_pismo_desc">
    <text>Encrypted letter for Barman from Sidor.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_pismo">
    <text>Letter to Voronin</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo_desc">
    <text>Encrypted letter for Voronin from Barman.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_pismo2">
    <text>Letter to Sidor</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_pismo2_desc">
    <text>Encrypted letter for Sidor from Voronin.</text>
</string>

<string id="pda_mir">
    <text>Scout's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_mir_desc">
    <text>PDA of a Peacekeeper Scout, whose corpse was found at the old factory.</text>
</string>

<string id="pda_nebo">
    <text>Guide's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_nebo_desc">
    <text>PDA of a Guide from "Clear Sky" faction. This PDA contains encrypted data about Secret Trails.</text>
</string>

<string id="karta_bar">
    <text>Map of the Bar</text>
</string>
<string id="karta_bar_desc">
    <text>Detailed map of the Bar and adjacent territories.</text>
</string>

<string id="doktor_flashka">
    <text>Doctor's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="doktor_flashka_desc">
    <text>Doctor's flash drive, which must be given to Pathfinder. In exchange for this, he will show a secret trail from Army Warehouses, through the Dead City, to the Swamps.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc_tele">
    <text>Disposable Teleport</text>
</string>
<string id="doc_tele_desc">
    <text>Disposable teleport. Might be needed at the most crucial moment. Teleports one person, one time, to the Swamps from any point in the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="money">
    <text>Money</text>
</string>
<string id="money_gg_desc">
    <text>Money taken from Strelok during the robbery.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_5_desc">
    <text>Five thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_10_desc">
    <text>Ten thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_15_desc">
    <text>Fifteen thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_20_desc">
    <text>Twenty thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_25_desc">
    <text>Twenty-five thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_30_desc">
    <text>Thirty thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="money_50_desc">
    <text>Fifty thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_zapiska">
    <text>Scribbled scrap of paper</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_zapiska_s">
    <text>Note</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_zapiska_desc">
    <text>Scrap of paper with some notes, possibly useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="detector_elite_bad">
    <text>Broken universal detector</text>
</string>
<string id="detector_elite_bad_desc">
    <text>Perhaps the best detector in the Zone, although it still needs repair.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_detector_name">
    <text>Detector tuning scheme</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_detector_desc">
    <text>Detector tuning scheme. With the help of this scheme, a high-quality anomaly detector can be tuned to identify virtually any anomaly in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="device_pda1">
    <text>PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_device_pda1">
    <text>Individual stalker PDA. Storage of personal information and data necessary for survival.</text>
</string>
<string id="detec_flash_name">
    <text>Monk's flash drive</text>
</string>
<string id="detec_flash_desc">
    <text>Ordinary flash drive, which are often found in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_sak">
    <text>Universal anomaly detector</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect_sak">
    <text>Detector, the latest development in the field of mechanization of paranormal phenomena research, allows detecting and identifying virtually any anomaly in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_military_name">
    <text>Scheme of military underground communications</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_military_desc">
    <text>Scheme of military underground communications. Drawings and plans of underground catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_case_name">
    <text>Freeman's metal case</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_case_desc">
    <text>Freeman's metal case. Ordinary case, money and documents are usually transported in such.</text>
</string>
<string id="resiver_name">
    <text>Army radio station</text>
</string>
<string id="resiver_desc">
    <text>Ordinary army VHF radio station. In the conditions of the active Zone, its outdated tube design turned out to be the most resistant to various types of radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_notebook_new_desc">
    <text>Laptop with data. It contains information about the underground communications of the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="item_notebook_new_name">
    <text>Laptop with data</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_journal_desc">
    <text>Journal with records from the Sarcophagus. Detailed records of the "behavior" of the Monolith for several years. Many, many numbers and letters. There are photographs.</text>
</string>
<string id="monolit_journal_name">
    <text>Journal with records from the Sarcophagus</text>
</string>
<string id="sweets_desc">
    <text>Snickers chocolate bar, a great rarity in the Zone</text>
</string>
<string id="sweets">
    <text>Chocolate bar</text>
</string>
<string id="plan_labx16_document_desc">
    <text>Communication plan of laboratory X-16. Among other things, a secret passage to the Sarcophagus is marked.</text>
</string>
<string id="plan_labx16_document_name">
    <text>Communication plan</text>
</string>
<string id="money_case_desc">
    <text>Case with money for the Scientist</text>
</string>
<string id="money_case_name">
    <text>Case with money</text>
</string>
<string id="experiment_case_desc">
    <text>Case with experiments. Inside are three liter jars with some liquid.</text>
</string>
<string id="experiment_case_name">
    <text>Case with experiments</text>
</string>
<string id="eight_pda_desc">
    <text>PDA of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Eighth" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="eight_pda_name">
    <text>PDA of "Eighth"</text>
</string>
<string id="seven_pda_desc">
    <text>PDA of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Seventh" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="seven_pda_name">
    <text>PDA of "Seventh"</text>
</string>
<string id="six_pda_desc">
    <text>PDA of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Sixth" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="six_pda_name">
    <text>PDA of "Sixth"</text>
</string>
<string id="four_flash_desc">
    <text>Flash drive of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Fourth" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_flash_name">
    <text>Flash drive of "Fourth"</text>
</string>
<string id="five_flash_desc">
    <text>Flash drive of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Fifth" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_flash_name">
    <text>Flash drive of "Fifth"</text>
</string>
<string id="gold_art_name">
    <text>Gold Chunk</text>
</string>
<string id="gold_art_desc">
    <text>A special variety of "Meat Chunk". Can be found only near the CNPP. Occasionally found in other parts of the Zone, but this happens extremely rarely. Possesses some properties different from the ordinary "Meat Chunk".</text>
</string>
<string id="third_pda_desc">
    <text>PDA of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Third" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="third_pda_name">
    <text>PDA of "Third"</text>
</string>
<string id="photo_alboum_name">
    <text>Photo album</text>
</string>
<string id="photo_alboum_desc">
    <text>Album with photographs and personal notes of Grinya.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_patron_name">
    <text>Crate with ammo</text>
</string>
<string id="box_patron_desc">
    <text>Heavy wooden crate. Zincs with cartridges inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_vano_name">
    <text>Crate with mines</text>
</string>
<string id="box_vano_desc">
    <text>Crate with mines, which Vano asked to find and bring.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo1_desc">
    <text>Book one from laboratory X-16. All in formulas and graphs. Apparently, research on animals and humans was conducted in this laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo1_name">
    <text>Book one from laboratory X-16</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo2_desc">
    <text>Book two from laboratory X-16. All in formulas and graphs. Apparently, research on animals and humans was conducted in this laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo2_name">
    <text>Book two from laboratory X-16</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo3_desc">
    <text>Book three from laboratory X-16. All in formulas and graphs. Apparently, research on animals and humans was conducted in this laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_nebo3_name">
    <text>Book three from laboratory X-16</text>
</string>
<string id="first_flash_desc">
    <text>Flash drive of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "First" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_flash_name">
    <text>Flash drive of "First"</text>
</string>
<string id="second_flash_desc">
    <text>Flash drive of a nameless mercenary. Only the nickname "Second" and a strange code.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_flash_name">
    <text>Flash drive of "Second"</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_decoder_desc">
    <text>Something like a powerful electronic lockpick. Seems it was created with the aim to hack some specific electronic lock.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_decoder_name">
    <text>Lefty's Decoder</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_document_name">
    <text>Documents for Dan</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_document_desc">
    <text>Documents for Dan. Sealed folder. From Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="inventory_new_box_name">
    <text>Metal box with Sidor's things</text>
</string>
<string id="inventory_new_box_desc">
    <text>Metal box with Sidor's things. Heavy, with a lock.</text>
</string>
<string id="cd_disk_name">
    <text>CD disk</text>
</string>
<string id="cd_disk_desc">
    <text>CD disk with results of analyzes and observations of animal mutation. Recorded about five years ago in the very first scientific expedition to the Zone, organized shortly after the second explosion at the CNPP.</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_haron_name">
    <text>Charon's Decoder</text>
</string>
<string id="pribor_haron_desc">
    <text>Decoder which Charon asked to bring.</text>
</string>
<string id="mir_key">
    <text>Warehouse Key</text>
</string>
<string id="mir_key_desc">
    <text>Key to the Peacekeepers' warehouse on the territory of "Deep Station".</text>
</string>
