<string id="Artifacts">
    <text>Artifacts</text>
</string>

<string id="af-ameba-mica">
    <text>Mica</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-mica">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Fruit Punch anomaly. While wearing the artifact on the belt, the probability of losing a large amount of blood due to severe wounds decreases, but vulnerability to any types of burns increases. High price. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-ameba-slime">
    <text>Slime</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slime">
    <text>The artifact can be found near the Fruit Punch anomaly. Represents a translucent jelly-like formation. While wearing the artifact on the belt, the probability of losing a large amount of blood due to severe wounds decreases, but vulnerability to any types of burns increases. Low price. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-ameba-slug">
    <text>Slug</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-ameba-slug">
    <text>This artifact is most often found near the Fruit Punch anomaly. Wearing this translucent jelly-like formation on the belt reduces the probability of losing a large amount of blood due to severe wounds, but makes a person vulnerable to any types of burns. Average price. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-blood">
    <text>Stone Blood</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-blood">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Whirligig anomaly. Represents an ugly reddish formation of compressed and fancy curved polymerized remains of plants, soil, flesh and bones of dead stalkers and mutants. While wearing the artifact on the belt, wound healing is mystically slightly accelerated, and bleedings stop. At the same time, resistance to physical damage worsens. Stalkers have a belief that the power of people who died in the anomaly is enclosed in this artifact, probably that's why the artifact noticeably increases stamina. The selling price is low due to fairly wide distribution. Medics and various religious cults show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-cristall">
    <text>Crystal</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall">
    <text>The artifact can extremely rarely be found near the Burner anomaly. Its name very accurately describes the shape of the artifact - it is a large iridescent crystal of reddish color. Alas, the artifact does not affect stamina in the best way and increases the degree of fire damage. And besides, it is better not to approach bonfires with this crystal, although it contributes to resistance to physical damage. High price. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-cristall-flower">
    <text>Stone Flower</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-cristall-flower">
    <text>Born in the Springboard anomaly. Such an artifact can be found in few areas of the Zone. Inclusions of metal compounds give a beautiful play of light. Looking at this artifact near a fire at night calms down remarkably. Possesses some protective properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-drops">
    <text>Droplet</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-drops">
    <text>Artifact appearing next to the Burner anomaly. Teardrop-shaped small formation with a cracked glossy surface. Stalkers say that wearing this artifact reduces sensitivity to explosion, but due to strong heat emission, stamina worsens and vulnerability to any types of burns appears. Low price. Collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-battery">
    <text>Battery</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-battery">
    <text>The origin of the artifact is unknown. Ribbed shiny formation. A very useful artifact for its wearer. Improves all characteristics of resistance and susceptibility to electricity and physical damage. It creates the impression that the artifact enhances most processes occurring around it. It also increases vulnerability to any types of burns. Selling price is huge. Scientific organizations show special interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-dummy">
    <text>Dummy</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-dummy">
    <text>The origin of the artifact is unknown. Two hard disks held together by slime. The artifact greatly reduces damage from explosions, absorbing shock waves. High selling price. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-glassbeads">
    <text>Mama's Beads</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-glassbeads">
    <text>Wonderful artifact, take care of it. It is good because it has serious positive qualities (a unique phenomenon, as usually absolutes and rare hypermodificats possess such positive properties). Slightly reduces resistance to impacts. Scientists wrack their grey heads over how such properties can be obtained in laboratory conditions. The artifact slows down the onset of fatigue and hunger, stops bleeding, and gives resistance to electric discharges. Perhaps everyone and their dog shows interest in it.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-pellicle">
    <text>Pellicle</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-pellicle">
    <text>This artifact is so rare that many researchers do not even suspect that such a substance can exist in natural conditions. Rejects caustic chemical components and provides powerful protection against rupture. However, it promotes bleeding.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-dummy-spring">
    <text>Spring</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-dummy-spring">
    <text>The origin of the artifact is unknown. Represents two hard disks held together by viscous slime. It can move independently, making small jumps thanks to a variable gravitational field. When worn on the belt, it reduces the probability of serious injuries resulting from impacts by 25%. But reduces stamina. Selling price is very high. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-electra-flash">
    <text>Flash</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-flash">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Electra anomaly. Light, translucent, amorphous formation with rays of light beating from within, rarely emitting small sparks around itself. Wearing the artifact on the belt increases stamina, slightly reduces sensitivity to impact and reduces the effect of radiation, but at the same time makes a person vulnerable to electricity. High price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-electra-moonlight">
    <text>Moonlight</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-moonlight">
    <text>The artifact can rarely be found near the Electra anomaly. Light, translucent, amorphous formation with a glowing core, emitting small sparks around itself. Wearing the artifact on the belt significantly increases stamina. Removes radiation and increases resistance to impact. But when falling into the Electra anomaly, the chances of survival for a person wearing this artifact remain minimal. Very high price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-electra-sparkler">
    <text>Sparkler</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-electra-sparkler">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Electra anomaly. Translucent, amorphous, very light formation, rarely emitting small sparks around itself. Wearing the artifact on the belt gives slight resistance to impact, slightly increases stamina and reduces the effect of radiation, but at the same time makes a person vulnerable to electricity. Average price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-fireball">
    <text>Fireball</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fireball">
    <text>The artifact is most often found near the Burner anomaly. Translucent reddish ball-shaped formation. They say it reduces sensitivity to explosion, but due to strong heat emission, stamina worsens and vulnerability to any types of burns appears. Better not to approach fire with the artifact. Average price. Collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-fuzz-kolobok">
    <text>Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-fuzz-kolobok">
    <text>Artifact of unknown origin. Scientists still cannot solve the recipe for obtaining this miracle of the Zone. When worn on the belt, the body's resistance to any physical damage increases. Very high price. Medics show special interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-gold-fish">
    <text>Goldfish</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gold-fish">
    <text>Artifact extremely rarely appearing in the Vortex anomaly. Beautiful formation with a mirror surface. At night illuminates the space around itself within a radius of 1-2 meters. Represents metal compressed and fancifully curved by strong gravity with a mixture of everything that generally falls into the anomaly at the moment of discharge. When wearing the artifact on the belt, immunity to the effects of gravitational anomalies such as "Springboard" and to some types of physical impact increases. However, it promotes bleeding and impact damage. Selling price is very high. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-gravi">
    <text>Gravi</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-gravi">
    <text>Beautiful artifact formed in the Vortex anomaly. Represents remains of plants, soil and generally everything that falls into the immediate vicinity of the anomaly, compressed and fancifully curved by strong gravity. When wearing the artifact on the belt, immunity to the effects of gravitational anomalies such as Springboard increases, but due to the powerful gravitational field, the artifact attracts bullets, which should not please its owner, and also reduces stamina. Selling price and probability of appearance are average. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-medusa">
    <text>Jellyfish</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-medusa">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Springboard anomaly. Represents remains of plants and foliage compressed and fancifully curved by strong gravity. When wearing the artifact on the belt, a slight effect of a protective field appears, reducing damage from explosions. Selling price is low due to fairly wide distribution. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-mincer-meat">
    <text>Meat Chunk</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-mincer-meat">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Whirligig anomaly. Represents an ugly yellowish formation of compressed and fancifully curved polymerized remains of flesh and bones of dead creatures. When wearing the artifact on the belt, the process of wound healing is mystically slightly accelerated, and bleedings stop. Stalkers have a belief that the power of people who died in the anomaly is enclosed in this artifact. At the same time, resistance to physical damage worsens. Selling price and probability of appearance are average. Medics and various religious cults show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-night-star">
    <text>Night Star</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star">
    <text>Artifact extremely rarely formed in the Springboard anomaly. Beautiful formation with a mirror surface and colored phosphorescent inclusions. At night illuminates everything around itself with greenish light within a radius of 1-2 meters, for which it received such a name among stalkers. Represents remains of plants, soil and generally everything that falls into the immediate vicinity of the anomaly, compressed and fancifully curved by strong gravity. When wearing the artifact on the belt, the effect of a protective field increases, reducing damage from small arms and electric discharges, and also increases stamina. Selling price is very high. Scientific organizations and the military show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-rusty-kristall">
    <text>Crystallized Thorn</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-kristall">
    <text>The artifact can be found near the Rusty Hair anomaly. It slightly counteracts impact, increases stamina and removes radiation, but at the same time opens bleeding, so when wearing this artifact one must be careful and not forget about its negative effect. Average price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-rusty-sea-urchin">
    <text>Sea Urchin</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-sea-urchin">
    <text>The artifact is most often found not far from the Rusty Hair anomaly. It contributes to resistance to burns and physical impact. However, with constant use of this artifact, a person risks losing a large amount of blood. High price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-rusty-thorn">
    <text>Thorn</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-rusty-thorn">
    <text>The artifact can very often be found near the Rusty Hair anomaly. In people with weakened immunity, the artifact causes severe bleeding. Low price. Scientific organizations, collectors and jewelers show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-soul">
    <text>Soul</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-soul">
    <text>Very rare artifact formed in the Whirligig anomaly. Represents a yellowish-red shiny formation of compressed and fancifully curved polymerized remains of living fresh flesh. Stalkers have a belief that the souls of people who died in the anomaly are enclosed in this artifact. When wearing the artifact on the belt, health is fully restored mystically within a few minutes, and any bleeding stops. At the same time, resistance to physical damage significantly worsens. Selling price is very high. Generally, the artifact appears in anomalies that absorb a large number of organic objects. Medics and various religious cults show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af-vyvert">
    <text>Twist</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-vyvert">
    <text>Artifact formed in the Vortex anomaly. Represents remains of plants, soil and other small objects that fall into the immediate vicinity of the anomaly, compressed and fancifully curved by strong gravity. When wearing the artifact on the belt, immunity to the effects of gravitational anomalies such as "Springboard" increases. Besides this, it slightly removes radiation, but also promotes bleeding and electric shock. Selling price is low due to fairly wide distribution. Scientific organizations show interest in the artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_buliz">
    <text>Cobblestone</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_buliz">
    <text>An artifact that has lost all its properties as a result of energy collapse is called a Cobblestone. These artifacts remain valuable for science, as they emit light and anti-gravitational energy. Scientists pay quite well for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="af_spirit_1">
    <text>Soul Drops</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_1">
    <text>This modificat improves health, but slightly increases human fatigue.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_spirit_2">
    <text>Fiery Soul</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_2">
    <text>This mesomodificat retains the property of Soul Drops to improve health and at the same time reduces bleeding. And also contributes to resistance to explosion. Negatively affects human stamina.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_spirit_3">
    <text>Crystal Soul</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_3">
    <text>This hypermodificat retains the tendency to improve health, explosion resistance and reduce bleeding. At the same time, the negative impact on stamina is reduced by almost half compared to its predecessor.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_spirit_4">
    <text>Crystal Soul of Bengal</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_4">
    <text>This absolute improves health and slightly increases stamina. In addition, it reduces sensitivity to explosion and protects against electric shock. It is highly valued on the market both in the Zone itself and outside it.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_cry_1">
    <text>Tears of Electra</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_1">
    <text>The modificat relieves fatigue quite well.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_cry_2">
    <text>Tears of Fire</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_2">
    <text>Tears of Fire remove radiation from the body of a person wearing this mesomodificat on the belt.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_cry_3">
    <text>Chimera Tears</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_3">
    <text>This hypermodificat, besides slightly protecting against bullet wounds, is also useful because it blocks almost half of the psi-emission. Negative characteristics of Chimera Tears: deterioration of human well-being and poor wound healing.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_babka_1">
    <text>Grandmother's Beads</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_1">
    <text>The resulting modificat increases the stamina indicator and generates a temporal field that quite significantly slows down the speed of bullets hitting it, thereby protecting a person from critical wounds. But also reduces resistance to electric shock.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_babka_2">
    <text>Great Grandmother's Beads</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_2">
    <text>Great Grandmother's Beads have a somewhat worse bullet resistance indicator relative to Grandmother's Beads due to the weakening of the temporal field. But on the other hand, this mesomodificat has the ability to instantly stop bleeding and improve the health of a person wearing it on the belt.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_babka_3">
    <text>Grandmother Burer's Beads</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_3">
    <text>A unique hypermodificat, more similar in properties to an absolute. Its temporal field is very strong and has a large radius, so a person wearing Grandmother Burer's Beads on the belt has a great chance to stay alive even when hit by an SVD. At the same time, the hypermodificat instantly stops bleeding, improves general health condition, but also contributes significantly to fatigue.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_pudd_1">
    <text>Fiery Dummy</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_1">
    <text>This modificat, besides neutralizing high temperature, adds stamina to a person wearing it on the belt. But at the same time makes the body more susceptible to the effects of the Electra anomaly.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_pudd_2">
    <text>Bright Dummy</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_2">
    <text>The subject of further evolution of the Fiery Dummy. The Bright Dummy improves stamina, but also increases the body's susceptibility to electric shock. The only thing that remains unchanged in this mesomodificat is a good neutralization of high temperatures.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_pudd_3">
    <text>Moon Dummy</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_3">
    <text>The hypermodificat neutralizes high temperatures quite well, noticeably increases the stamina of a person wearing it on the belt, but increases sensitivity to electric shock.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_pudd_4">
    <text>Pudding</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_4">
    <text>The absolute neutralizes high temperatures, chemical burns and electric shock well. In addition, it slightly increases stamina.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dik_1">
    <text>Porcupine</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_1">
    <text>The modificat is very simple. The Porcupine has a very small radiation blocking indicator. But the modificat noticeably reduces stamina.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dik_2">
    <text>Electric Porcupine</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_2">
    <text>The mesomodificat possesses a radiation blocking indicator. Significantly reduces human fatigue and sensitivity to impacts, but, unfortunately, increases sensitivity to electric shock.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dik_3">
    <text>Snotty Porcupine</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_3">
    <text>This hypermodificat has a weak radiation blocking indicator. Besides this, it very effectively stops bleeding and adds stamina. The unpleasant side of the Snotty Porcupine is that it increases human sensitivity to electric shock, and it is inconvenient to wear due to the constantly oozing incomprehensible slime. The substance is harmless, but terribly unpleasant. Despite its unpresentable appearance, the hypermodificat is highly valued in the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_dik_4">
    <text>Stone Porcupine</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_4">
    <text>This absolute slightly reduces the radiation dose. Besides this, human sensitivity to electric shock is noticeably reduced, bleeding is effectively reduced, stamina and explosion resistance are added. Highly valued not only by scientists, but also among stalkers.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kol_1">
    <text>Steel Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_1">
    <text>This modificat is interesting primarily because it generates a special field around the person wearing it, which knocks bullets fired at the person off trajectory. Far from all, but still. The quality is wonderful and absolutely unstudied by scientists. Besides this, the Steel Kolobok reduces skin sensitivity to rupture.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kol_2">
    <text>Titanium Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_2">
    <text>Titanium Kolobok reduces skin sensitivity to rupture and various kinds of burns. With the generated field, it knocks off trajectory a certain percentage of bullets hitting it.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kol_3">
    <text>Diamond Kolobok</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_3">
    <text>The hypermodificat gives the skin of a person wearing it resistance to rupture, reduces the impact of fire and chemically aggressive environment. With its field "diverts" part of the bullets.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_kol_4">
    <text>Giant's Little Brother</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_4">
    <text>This amusing absolute not only reduces the sensitivity of the skin of a person wearing it to rupture, fire and chemically aggressive substances, but also "diverts" from the person a quite significant percentage of bullets falling into the generated field. An unpleasant bonus of the Giant's Little Brother is a sharp increase in a person's need for food.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_armor_1">
    <text>Hide</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_1">
    <text>The modificat reduces susceptibility to the effects of any chemically aggressive environment, slightly improves resistance to gunshot wounds. Slightly radioactive.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_armor_2">
    <text>Scale</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_2">
    <text>The Scale mesomodificat reduces the impact of chemically aggressive environments on a person, improves health indicator and affects the skin in a special way, making it less sensitive to gunshot wounds. At the same time, Scale increases bleeding in the person wearing it.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_armor_3">
    <text>Carapace</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_3">
    <text>Carapace, in a person wearing it, reduces bleeding, increases health indicator, improves resistance to gunshot wounds, neutralizes most chemically aggressive environments upon their contact with human skin.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_armor_4">
    <text>Controller's Scalp</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_4">
    <text>This absolute reduces damage from aggressive chemical environments, adds health and screens psi-emission very well! Another quite useful quality of the absolute is that in a person wearing it on the belt, the skin structure changes. It, without losing elasticity, coarsens. As a result, resistance to gunshot wounds increases. A negative property is an increase in the need for food.</text>
</string>

<string id="af_simbion">
    <text>Symbiont</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_artifact_simbion">
    <text>The unique Symbiont modificat is obtained by joint transmutation of four artifacts at once in the Fruit Punch anomaly. Jellyfish, Droplet, Stone Blood and Thorn, converted into a single whole, give a person wearing it on the belt quite significant screening from psi-emission and protection from radiation. But at the same time Symbiont increases bleeding, reduces stamina and resistance to rupture.</text>
</string>