<string id="Army">
    <text>Army</text>
</string>
<string id="Bandits">
    <text>Bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="Duty">
    <text>"Duty" Faction</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_military_army">
    <text>Soldiers of regular army units. They guard the approaches to the closed territory of the Zone, patrolling the perimeter, shooting mutants and catching looters. \nArmy Spetsnaz - elite units. As a rule, they land in the Zone to conduct rescue and special operations.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_military_milstalkers">
    <text>Soldiers who have undergone special training after serving in the Zone, or stalkers who have signed a contract with the army. Usually equipped with a large amount of auxiliary equipment and well armed. Mainly used to study the causes and consequences of the catastrophe, as well as mapping the Zone. They can walk both alone and in groups of up to five people. They do not let ordinary stalkers get close - they open fire immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-groups">
    <text>Deleted</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-labs">
    <text>A mobile laboratory looks like a small metal bunker with small tinted windows. Capable of withstanding almost all damages of any nature known to man. Can be switched to fully autonomous mode for several months, for which it is equipped with reliable life support systems. Delivered to the Zone by a cargo helicopter. Laboratory personnel never let outsiders go further than the external airlock chamber, so not a single stalker has penetrated inside the laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_bandits">
    <text>Representatives of the criminal world who came to the Zone for different reasons: to make money selling artifacts, to hide from the law, to buy or sell weapons. There are many such elements in the Zone, ranging from punks to serious criminals. For the most part, they are united in gangs. Although there is still no single bandit organization in the Zone, they strongly annoy ordinary stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_duty">
    <text>A clearly paramilitary group, distinguished by strict discipline: its members actually live according to the charter. Only representatives of "Duty" do not trade unique creations of the Zone with the outside world: according to rumors, all artifacts found by these people are handed over to scientists. Every Duty member considers his main goal to be the protection of the world from the influence of the Zone. Most of the group's operations are related to the extermination of monsters, so "Duty" raids often save ordinary stalkers from many pressing problems. Has long been fiercely at war with the "Freedom" faction.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_freedom">
    <text>Anarchists and daredevils who declared themselves fighters for freedom on the territory of the Zone, and therefore constantly conflicting with army units, military stalkers and the "Duty" faction. Freedom fighters believe that information about what is happening in the Zone cannot be hidden from humanity, thus challenging the monopoly of government organizations on the ownership of local secrets and miracles.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_killers">
    <text>The most mysterious and secretive group in the Zone, in the existence of which many do not even believe. Some constantly use the services of mercenaries: professionals in their field, they will quickly deal with any stalker and can even completely liquidate a small group. For their services, apparently, they take considerable sums in money or artifacts. The location of the base of this group still remains a mystery; obviously, it is located somewhere deep in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_loners">
    <text>Stalkers exploring the Zone alone. Such are the majority, since membership in a group takes away precious time, thereby reducing earnings; in addition, some are simply by nature inclined to loneliness and independence.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_monolith">
    <text>A group rather resembling a religious sect. Its members believe that in the center of the Zone rests an evolutionary crystal - the Monolith - of extraterrestrial origin. Most stalkers despise Monolith adepts, considering them crazy. Since its formation, the group has hindered the advance of stalkers to the center of the Zone, motivating this by the bad intentions of the latter regarding the Monolith. According to rumors, Monolithians have a large base somewhere closer to the center of the Zone, but no one except the members of the group themselves knows its exact location.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_zomstalkers">
    <text>Those who have been subjected to prolonged exposure to emitters on Yantar or some other sectors. Careless stalkers quickly go crazy, turning into wandering semi-corpses. Many of them roam the Zone, some even reach the perimeter. Either way, it is no longer possible to help them: the process of personality destruction is irreversible. Although zombified stalkers can still use their weapons, they are quite stupid. When meeting them, you can hear them mumbling fragments of phrases to themselves, which, however, are completely devoid of meaning. Over time, zombified stalkers finally lose all former skills and turn into zombies. As a rule, they are very aggressive and represent a serious threat in large concentrations.</text>
</string>
<string id="Freedom">
    <text>"Freedom" Faction</text>
</string>
<string id="Killers">
    <text>Mercenaries</text>
</string>
<string id="Loners">
    <text>Loner Stalkers</text>
</string>
<string id="Military">
    <text>Paramilitary Units</text>
</string>
<string id="Milstalkers">
    <text>Military Stalkers</text>
</string>
<string id="Mobile-groups">
    <text>Research Groups</text>
</string>
<string id="Mobile-labs">
    <text>Mobile Science Camp</text>
</string>
<string id="Monolith">
    <text>"Monolith" Faction</text>
</string>
<string id="Scientists">
    <text>Scientists</text>
</string>
<string id="Social">
    <text>Societies</text>
</string>
<string id="Stalker-clans">
    <text>Stalker Clans</text>
</string>
<string id="Zomstalkers">
    <text>Zombified Stalkers</text>
</string>