<string id="Anomalies">
    <text>Anomalies</text>
</string>

<string id="Fuzz">
    <text>Burnt Fuzz</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_fuzz">
    <text>Anomalously mutated vegetation. Upon rapid approach of a living being, it ejects a cloud of particles which, in case of contact with exposed or poorly protected skin, severely injures the latter. Does not react to slowly moving objects. Produces three types of artifacts (possibly these are seeds): Thorn, Crystal Thorn, Sea Urchin.</text>
</string>

<string id="Ameba">
    <text>Fruit Punch</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_ameba">
    <text>A formation of nature not fully clear to the end. Upon contact with the body, it inflicts injuries similar to the effect of strong acid exposure. Produces three types of artifacts: Slime, Slug, Mica.</text>
</string>

<string id="Bald">
    <text>Springboard</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_bald">
    <text>One of the first recorded anomalies. Inflicts shock damage with a variable gravitational field. Stays in one place for an average of a week, changing the force of impact during its life. The result of an encounter with a "Springboard" can be different - from small bruises and contusions to instant death. In daytime it is quite easily detected by air distortions above the anomaly, swirling leaves, as well as characteristic reddish-brown spots on the ground. Detected by any type of detectors, as well as by throwing various objects into it. Produces three types of artifacts: Jellyfish, Stone Flower and Night Star.</text>
</string>

<string id="Gravi">
    <text>Vortex</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_gravi">
    <text>Anomaly of presumably gravitational nature. At the moment of activation, it drags everything within a radius of 10-15 meters into itself with terrible force. When falling into the center of a "Vortex", there is no chance of survival: the body of both an animal and a human will be compressed into a tight lump, and then torn apart at the moment of the so-called discharge. Throughout the entire period of existence - on average about a week - the anomaly does not change the place of its manifestation; it can be visually detected during the day by the characteristic movement of air above it, swirling leaves, fragments of dismembered corpses and a characteristic dark spot on the ground in the center. Extremely dangerous at night, as it is detected only by detectors or by throwing metal objects. Produces three types of artifacts: Twist, Gravi and Goldfish.</text>
</string>

<string id="Meat">
    <text>Whirligig</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_meat">
    <text>The name is due to the effect of lifting any living creature into the air with subsequent spinning to enormous speed. The nature of the "Whirligig" has not yet been fully explored. Detected by a light dust whirlwind and scattered body fragments around. It is very important not to miss the moment of the start of being dragged into the anomalous whirlwind and not to get into the zone of the strongest effect in the center - only then is there a chance to get off with minimal injuries. Produces three types of artifacts: Stone Blood, Meat Chunk and Soul.</text>
</string>

<string id="Zharka">
    <text>Burner</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_zharka">
    <text>In an inactive state, it looks like a barely visible cloud of hot air, however, when any object or living being enters the zone of action, it forms a compact zone heated to a temperature of about 1500K. At night it can be detected only by powerful detectors or by throwing metal objects. Produces three types of artifacts: Droplet, Fireball and Crystal.</text>
</string>

<string id="Electra">
    <text>Electra</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_electra">
    <text>Anomalous formation with a diameter of about 10 meters, accumulating static electricity. A disturbed anomaly explodes with a dozen mini-lightning bolts, and electric shock for any living creature is almost always fatal. A characteristic feature of "Electra" is a bluish fog visible above it during the day. At night it is easily detected by any type of detectors or by throwing metal objects. Produces three types of artifacts: Sparkler, Flash and Moonlight.</text>
</string>

<string id="Ice">
    <text>Freezer</text>
</string>

<string id="Radioactive">
    <text>Radioactive Hotspot</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_anomalies_radioactive">
    <text>Zone of increased level - more than 50 mR/h - of radiation. Prolonged stay in such places must be avoided.</text>
</string>

<string id="ThermalField">
    <text>Thermal Field</text>
</string>

<string id="AcidicField">
    <text>Chemical Field</text>
</string>

<string id="PsyField">
    <text>Psi Zone</text>
</string>


<string id="Locations">
    <text>Locations</text>
</string>

<string id="Escape">
    <text>Cordon</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_escape">
    <text>A kind of waiting room of the Zone, the first place where rookies get to, settling in little by little. In the cellar behind the village near the army checkpoint lives a trader - it is useful to have a chat with him. Poking into the checkpoint and catching the eye of soldiers is not reasonable: they have orders to shoot without warning; on the other hand, some are ready to instantly become kinder for money, especially if there are no superiors nearby. Killing soldiers is highly not recommended, unless in case of a direct threat to life.</text>
</string>

<string id="Garbage">
    <text>Garbage</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_garbage">
    <text>A huge technical cemetery: mountains of radioactive junk were brought here even after the first accident. There are remnants of old buildings, mutants are encountered. Here, as well as at the perimeter itself, there are many rookies, and bandits hang around nearby, always looking for a fatter piece and without much trouble. You can find some artifacts, but it's better not to linger for long - there are more interesting places. If you go north, you will come out to the Wild Territory; to the west - passage to the Dark Valley; to the east - the road to "Agroprom" Research Institute.</text>
</string>

<string id="Agroprom">
    <text>Agroprom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_agroprom">
    <text>A strange area. If you go deeper into it, you will come out onto a plain heavily contaminated with radiation. The shallow lake located there is filled to the brim with debris of equipment. You can also visit the old institute and factory, however, recently the military have begun to appear there too often.</text>
</string>

<string id="Darkdolina">
    <text>Dark Valley</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_darkdolina">
    <text>It is always gloomy and foggy here, it often rains. In the Dark Valley, you can get hold of good artifacts, or quickly say goodbye to life. There are many seasoned stalkers here. They came here for valuable artifacts, but there are also bandits. You can search for the entrance to the underground laboratory located somewhere here, only no one returned from there, and what is hiding there is not properly known to anyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="Bar">
    <text>Bar</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_bar">
    <text>The "Duty" faction cleared a place for their base on the outskirts of the Wild Territory and allows stalkers to rest here. A kind of oasis in the desert: no anomalies, no mutants. There is a dungeon in which the "100 Rads" bar is located. Stalkers from all over the Zone gather in it. A local trader runs the bar, so here you can not only chat, but also sell-buy almost anything. To the north of the bar is a military base, to the south - the Garbage.</text>
</string>

<string id="Rostok">
    <text>Wild Territory</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_rostok">
    <text>There used to be a fairly large factory on the Wild Territory, of which only ruins remain now. Many stalkers found their end in them: all kinds of evil spirits bred there, as if they converge there from all over the Zone. According to rumors, truth be told, there is something very important at this factory, so there are always plenty of those wishing to try their luck.</text>
</string>

<string id="Yantar">
    <text>Yantar</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_yantar">
    <text>The legendary lake in the sector of the same name dried up long ago, one shallow swamp remained. Going there is especially dangerous because anyone who pokes too far immediately gets brain damage. And zombies roam throughout the sector and if they see someone, they go to him with not at all peaceful intentions. If you bypass the lake and groups of zombies, you will come across a scientific camp. Scientists are there - they were delivered by helicopters - studying something. You can chat with them, they buy artifacts, can even give some task.</text>
</string>

<string id="Military-loc">
    <text>Army Warehouses</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_military-loc">
    <text>An abandoned army base next to a village inhabited by strange creatures and a small swamp. Stalkers rarely poke into the village, more often bypass it by the tenth road. And anarchists from the "Freedom" faction settled on the territory of the military base. If you go further into the Zone from the base, you will get straight to the "Brain Scorcher". It tightly blocks the path to Pripyat and the CNPP.</text>
</string>

<string id="Radar">
    <text>"Scorcher"</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_radar">
    <text>A terrible place. Here you can perish for nothing, even if you were a lucky one all your life before. Anyone who gets close to the "Brain Scorcher" goes crazy, turns into a zombie and then wanders around the Zone, restless. Only shells remain of people, and no one returned from there in their right mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="Pripiat">
    <text>Pripyat</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_pripiat">
    <text>This was the city of power engineers. It was built together with the CNPP. It was a sizeable town... Only now no one lives there anymore, except, of course, all kinds of evil spirits, like mutants and zombies. Apparently, it is impossible to pass there at all. The "Brain Scorcher" closes the path.</text>
</string>

<string id="Stancia">
    <text>CNPP</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_locations_stancia">
    <text>The former nuclear power plant, about which everyone has heard at least once. This is the very heart of the Zone. If you believe the legends, somewhere there is a certain thing capable of fulfilling any wish - they call it the Monolith.</text>
</string>


<string id="Zone-story">
    <text>Zone History</text>
</string>

<string id="Zone">
    <text>Zone</text>
</string>

<string id="Story-2006">
    <text>Year 2008, April 12, 14:33</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2006">
    <text>The Exclusion Zone was illuminated by the brightest, almost unbearable light, and it was visible how clouds began to evaporate in the sky. After a moment of complete silence came a rumble and an earthquake. People fell to the ground, covering their eyes and ears; whoever could, ran, saving their life. From the side it looked as if all the nuclear fuel buried under the sarcophagus flew into the air at once. A day later, government troops completely cordoned off the new Zone. With the help of satellites, it was found out that the epicenter of the explosion was not at the blocks of the NPP itself, but a kilometer away from them. It is believed that all the station personnel died immediately, however, many other people remained inside the cordon ring. Organizing rescue operations was not possible, as detachments of people and equipment sent deep into the affected territory died almost immediately. Some time after the accident, the diameter of the Zone abruptly increased by several kilometers. Most of the government troops guarding the perimeter and scientific laboratories located there died instantly. Panic began; residents of surrounding villages and towns were evacuated in a hurry or fled themselves. Danger hung over the world, the size of which can still only be guessed.</text>
</string>

<string id="Story-2008">
    <text>Year 2010</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2008">
    <text>Two years have passed since the terrible catastrophe occurred in the Exclusion Zone around the Chernobyl NPP. A large number of dead and missing people, fallen livestock, blackened buildings, mutilated forest... Scientists still cannot give explanations for what happened. And the Zone, inside of which absolutely fantastic anomalies were discovered, meanwhile grows. Rare expeditions encounter mutated animal species possessing amazing features.</text>
</string>

<string id="Story-2010">
    <text>Year 2011</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-2010">
    <text>Following the tracks of desperate loner stalkers, scientific expeditions again undertake a large-scale study of the Zone. However, inside the perimeter guarded by the army there are already many "unaccounted persons", up to poachers and bandits. For the most part, stalkers travel through the Zone in search of various anomalous formations, so-called artifacts, for which they often get good money.</text>
</string>

<string id="Story-raid">
    <text>Breakthrough into the Zone. Year 2011</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_zone_zone-story_story-raid">
    <text>Army units, including special forces, led by detachments of military stalkers, undertook a major expedition deep into the Zone with the aim of breaking through to the CNPP and destroying the supposed cause of the emergence of deadly anomalous fields or finally obtaining reliable information about the processes occurring there. This enterprise, in which more than a thousand people and a lot of equipment took part, failed completely. Separate groups of survivors settled on the territory of the Zone without much hope for rescue.</text>
</string>