<string id="bandit_outfit_name">
    <text>Bandit Jacket</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_outfit_description">
    <text>Traditional bandit clothing - a leather jacket with sewn-in armor elements. Provides protection that is extremely insufficient in the harsh conditions of the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_outfit_name_m">
    <text>Chainmail Jacket</text>
</string>

<string id="bandit_outfit_description_m">
    <text>An ordinary weak bandit armored vest, but a chainmail sheet is sewn into the lining. Almost anyone can make one, but not everyone has enough patience.</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_bandit_outfit_name">
    <text>Bandit Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_bandit_outfit_description">
    <text>Exoskeleton produced by craftsmen from the bandit faction under the leadership of Fraer. Only real tough guys in the Zone walk in such exoskeletons. Distinguished by reliability and high carrying capacity.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_name">
    <text>PSZ-9d "Duty Armor"</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_description">
    <text>Produced by one of the Kiev defense research institutes by order of the "Duty" faction. The simplicity and reliability of the base model PSZ-9 combined with new materials provides good protection against various harmful effects, including gunshot damage. The armored vest requires improvement due to the missing breathing protection system.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_gaz_m1_name">
    <text>PSZ-9d-2 "Duty Armor"</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_gaz_m1_description">
    <text>Produced by one of the Kiev defense research institutes by order of the "Duty" faction. Based on the PSZ-9 base model. Provides good protection against various harmful effects, including gunshot damage. In this modification, the breathing system has been improved.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Hunter PSZ-9d</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>Duty armored suit with improved protection against bites and cuts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>PSZ-9Md "Universal Protection"</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Excellent protective suit for the Zone. Stalkers appreciate it for the combination of excellent anti-anomalous qualities and bulletproof protection. Includes: PSZ-9d jumpsuit, closed-cycle breathing system, built-in system for suppressing anomalous fields. Provides high-quality protection against bullet and shrapnel hits.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_black_exoskeleton_name">
    <text>Duty Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_black_exoskeleton_description">
    <text>Domestic development of one of the research institutes, specifically for the Duty faction. Combat functions prevail, large carrying capacity. The large weight of the suit, however, does not exclude the possibility of running in it.</text>
</string>

<string id="ecolog_outfit_name">
    <text>SSP-99 "Ecologist" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="ecolog_outfit_description">
    <text>SSP-99 chemical protection suit created for work in Zone conditions. Used by scientific expeditions and ecologist stalkers collaborating with them. Built-in air filtration and conditioning system. Not designed for combat operations.</text>
</string>

<string id="protection_outfit_name">
    <text>SSP-99M "Vega" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="protection_outfit_description">
    <text>High-quality modified SSP-99 suit. Torso protection against bullet and shrapnel damage has been added. Designed to equip the guards of scientific expeditions. Effective protection against radiation and biological anomalies. Resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other effects harmful to the body.</text>
</string>


<string id="super_outfit_name">
    <text>"Pegasus-85M" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="super_outfit_description">
    <text>Modified "Pegasus-85M" suit, created on the basis of SSP-99M, using fibers of the "Crystal" artifact. Designed to equip scientific expeditions to zones with greatly increased radiation background. Super-effective protection against radiation. Resistant to chemically aggressive environments and other effects harmful to the body.</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_soldier_m1_name">
    <text>Military Armored Vest</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_soldier_m1_description">
    <text>Standard soldier equipment set - light army armored vest. Protects quite effectively against pistol bullets and shrapnel. Ineffective against anomalous and other influences.</text>
</string>

<string id="specops_outfit_name">
    <text>Berill-5M Armored Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="specops_outfit_description">
    <text>Army special forces equipment modified for work in Zone conditions - Berill-5M. Includes: army armored vest of the PSZ-9a series with beryllium coating, Sphere-08 helmet. Designed for assault operations in areas with high radiation background. Poorly effective in conditions of high anomalous activity.</text>
</string>

<string id="specnaz_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Healing Berill</text>
</string>

<string id="specnaz_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>The fabric of the suit is impregnated with streptocide ointment, which accelerates wound healing.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Healing Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>This suit fell into an anomaly together with the "Soul" artifact and now it stimulates enhanced cell growth.</text>
</string>

<string id="mirotvor_outfit_name">
    <text>Peacekeeper SKAT-11M</text>
</string>

<string id="mirotvor_outfit_description">
    <text>Peacekeeper armored suit SKAT-11M created for conducting assault operations in zones of anomaly activity. Includes: heavy Peacekeeper armored suit of the PSZ-12p series, built-in compensation suit, Sphere-12M helmet. Provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, while not reducing the soldier's mobility. A balanced protection system against anomalous influence is present. Slightly exceeds SKAT-9M in its protective characteristics.</text>
</string>

<string id="militaryspec_outfit_name">
    <text>Military SKAT-10</text>
</string>

<string id="militaryspec_outfit_description">
    <text>Army special armored suit SKAT-10 created on the basis of SKAT-9M, which has proven itself well in Zone conditions. Ideal for conducting assault operations in zones of anomaly activity. Includes: heavy army armored suit of the PSZ-12SA series, built-in compensation suit, improved Sphere-12FE helmet. Provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, while not reducing the soldier's mobility. An excellent protection system against anomalous influence is also present.</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_outfit_name">
    <text>Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_outfit_description">
    <text>Experimental model of a military exoskeleton. It never went into mass production due to extreme cost and some design errors. Despite this, it is produced in small batches at underground enterprises outside Ukraine. This exoskeleton belongs to the third generation. Design flaws that radically reduced mobility have been eliminated in it, and armor has been strengthened. Provides excellent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, but does not guarantee resistance to anomalies.</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Modified Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="exo_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>Experimental model of a military exoskeleton (modified).</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_outfit_name">
    <text>Mercenary Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_outfit_description">
    <text>Suit of a stalker from the "Mercenary" faction. Based on samples of special forces equipment of Western armies. Due to special fabric treatment, the stability of the armor during physical displacement of plates is enhanced. Slightly superior to army armored vests of the PSZ-7 series in protective characteristics.</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Reinforced Mercenary Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>A chainmail mesh is sewn into the lining of the jacket, increasing protection against firearms and explosions, as well as against monster bites.</text>
</string>

<string id="merc_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Mercenary Scientific Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="merc_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Suit of mercenaries who operate in anomalous zones. Closed-cycle protection system, built-in system for suppressing the action of anomalous fields. Provides decent protection against bullet and shrapnel hits, but clearly insufficient for large-scale combat operations.</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_blue_exoskeleton_name">
    <text>Mercenary Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="killer_blue_exoskeleton_description">
    <text>Experimental model of a military exoskeleton of Western production. This exoskeleton belongs to the third generation. Used by mercenaries. Emphasis is placed on combat use, anomalous resistance is low. Running mode activated.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_outfit_name">
    <text>Monolith Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_outfit_description">
    <text>Suit of a stalker of the "Monolith" faction, manufacturer unknown. Slightly inferior to the army armored vest of the PSZ-9a series in protective characteristics. Structurally resembles suits widely distributed among neutral stalkers, in which the armored vest is combined with a radiation protection suit. Protects well against weak small arms. The level of protection against anomalous activity leaves much to be desired due to the lack of an air filtration system.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Monolith Scientific Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Like most Monolith creations - the technology is unknown. It has been established that extraterrestrial materials are included in the composition. They are lighter than their terrestrial counterparts and protect very well against radiation. Otherwise, the characteristics are similar.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_exoskeleton_name">
    <text>Monolith Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_exoskeleton_description">
    <text>Creation technology unknown. Inclusions of unknown metal were found in the material composition, origin nature unknown. Surprisingly low weight and high even indicators on all points. Maximum protection against radiation. Running function included.</text>
</string>
<string id="novice_gaz_outfit_m1_name">
    <text>Jacket with gas mask</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_gaz_outfit_m1_description">
    <text>Ordinary thick jacket, like many others. Slightly enhances bulletproof and shrapnel protection. Ineffective against anomalous and other influences. Has weak radiation protection.</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_soldier_name">
    <text>Leather Jacket</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_soldier_description">
    <text>Ordinary thick leather jacket, like many others. Slightly enhances bulletproof and shrapnel protection. Ineffective against anomalous and other influences.</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_rain_name">
    <text>Worn Leather Trench Coat</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_rain_description">
    <text>The most ordinary trench coat. Slightly enhances bulletproof and shrapnel protection. Slightly protects against burns, including chemical ones. Ineffective against anomalous and other influences.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_outfit_name_m">
    <text>Anomalous Leather Jacket</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_outfit_description_m">
    <text>This jacket was taken from the corpse of one of the stalkers who died in the "Fruit Punch" anomaly. Having lain in the anomaly for a long time, the jacket acquired the property of accelerating metabolism.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_name">
    <text>Stalker Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_description">
    <text>Produced by "folk craftsmen", the stalker suit represents an effective combination of a light army armored vest and a jumpsuit made of rubberized fabric. Reinforced with built-in Kevlar plates. Protects well against weak small arms. In general, extremely insufficient for deep raids and serious operations in the Zone nodes.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_guard_outfit_name">
    <text>Lightweight Stalker Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_guard_outfit_description">
    <text>Lightweight version of the stalker suit. Represents a light Kevlar armored vest, reinforced with armor plates made of high-strength high-alloy steel, thanks to which, with less weight, it protects well against small arms. Almost does not protect against radiation and anomalous influences. Inexpensive, but sold nowhere. How it got into the Zone is unknown. Used by guards in the Bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Ghost's Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>Legends say that the ghost stalker never carries medkits with him. Everything heals on him like on a dog. They say he has an unusual suit and that he got it from an anomaly.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_name_m2">
    <text>Tourist Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_description_m2">
    <text>The former owner of this thing was a real tourist, and, apparently, more than once went on difficult hikes on the verge of human capabilities. He knew how to distribute the weight he carried correctly and which things to prefer. Pockets on the jacket and a properly selected backpack allow carrying more weight.</text>
</string>

<string id="scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>"SEVA" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Produced by one of the Kiev defense research institutes, this suit is an excellent alternative to other stalker suits made in artisanal conditions. Represents an excellent combination of an armored suit, a closed-cycle breathing system, and a built-in system for suppressing the action of anomalous fields. Due to the successful selection of materials, it is a good choice. The only drawback is its price.</text>
</string>

<string id="broken_exoskeleton_name">
    <text>Damaged Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="broken_exoskeleton_description">
    <text>Heavily used, but still capable of serving someone, exoskeleton. The main advantage is its price. All characteristics have dropped significantly.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_name">
    <text>"Wind of Freedom" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_light_outfit_description">
    <text>Lightweight stalker suit produced by artisans of the "Freedom" faction. Light army armored vest plus overhead reinforcing Kevlar plates. Capable of protecting against weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special compound that increases resistance to anomalous activity.</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_svoboda_gaz_m1_name">
    <text>"Wind of Freedom" Suit with gas mask</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_svoboda_gaz_m1_description">
    <text>Lightweight stalker suit produced by artisans of the "Freedom" faction. Light army armored vest plus overhead reinforcing Kevlar plates. Capable of protecting against weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special compound that increases resistance to anomalous activity. This modification has reinforced protection against radiation and chemical burns.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_name">
    <text>"Guardian of Freedom" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_heavy_outfit_description">
    <text>Reinforced stalker suit produced by artisans of the "Freedom" faction. Medium army armored vest plus overhead reinforcing zirconium elements provide good protection against assault rifle bullets and shrapnel at various distances. The suit material consists of two layers: specially treated leather and fabric with asbestos thread. Gives some protection against various anomalous influences and radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_outfit_name_m1">
    <text>Modified "Wind of Freedom" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_outfit_description_m1">
    <text>Analog of the "Wind of Freedom" suit, but with increased protection against the effects of electricity.</text>
</string>

<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Freedom Scientific Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="freedom_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Production of the Freedom faction, for scientific research in the Zone. Closed-cycle protection system, built-in system for suppressing the action of anomalous fields. High protection against radiation. Bullet protection is still insufficient for active combat operations.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_exoskeleton_name">
    <text>Freedom Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_exoskeleton_description">
    <text>Product of craftsmen from Freedom. Experimenting with different modifications, after numerous attempts they managed to create a truly successful design. Comparable in characteristics to the Duty suit. Work on its improvement continues.</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_gravisak_name">
    <text>Unique Gravity Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="outfit_gravisak_description">
    <text>Armored vest modified with the help of the anti-gravity artifact "Cobblestone". Allows carrying a lot of additional cargo, while in an inactive state it is very heavy. Unfortunately, as a result of the modification, it acquired the ability to increase damaging effects.</text>
</string>

<string id="pekar_gravisak_name">
    <text>Baker's Gravity Suit</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_gravisak_description">
    <text>Unique armored vest modified with the help of the anti-gravity artifact "Cobblestone". Allows carrying a lot of additional cargo, while in an inactive state it is quite heavy. A master nicknamed Lefty managed to modernize the standard gravity suit, reducing the damaging effects of the original to zero, and with all this, increase the carrying capacity by another 10 kg. Weight in inactive state is reduced by half.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_name">
    <text>Semetsky's Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_description">
    <text>Very rare suit. Former owner - a sharp stalker who stole it from laboratory X-18. This is the first prototype of a new generation, based on the old one. Possesses protection from all types of damage. \nAccording to legend, if, wearing it, you find 5 "Cobblestone" artifacts, then the suit will instantly assimilate them, acquiring anti-gravity properties (greatly increased carrying capacity). \nIf you find 5 "Crystal Souls of Bengal", then the suit will acquire unique healing properties. True, such a metamorphosis can be carried out with this suit only once: either increasing carrying capacity or obtaining unique healing properties. %c[red] \nTo assimilate, you need to have 5 artifacts with you depending on the modification you want. If you have the artifacts, drag them onto the worn suit.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_addw_name">
    <text>Semetsky's Anti-gravity Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_addw_description">
    <text>Besides magnificent protective properties, possesses anti-gravity properties (increased carrying capacity). Possible carrying weight increased to 350 kg.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_addh_name">
    <text>Semetsky's Healing Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_outfit_addh_description">
    <text>Besides magnificent protective properties, possesses healing properties (stops bleeding very quickly, restores health and strength).</text>
</string>

<string id="mp_exo_outfit_description">
    <text>The exoskeleton perfectly protects against bullet and shrapnel damage. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
</string>


<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>This suit is intended for research activities in the Zone. Equipped with a closed-cycle breathing system, as well as a built-in system for suppressing the action of anomalous fields, thanks to which it perfectly protects against anomalies. Due to weak protection, it is very vulnerable. Possesses a built-in container for carrying artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="mp_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Scientific Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_light_outfit_name">
    <text>Clear Sky Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_light_outfit_description">
    <text>Lightweight stalker suit produced by artisans of the "Sky" faction. Light army armored vest. Capable of protecting against weak weapons. The fabric of the suit is treated with a special compound that increases resistance to anomalous activity.</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_heavy_outfit_name">
    <text>"Guardian of the Sky" Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_heavy_outfit_description">
    <text>Reinforced stalker suit produced by artisans of the "Sky" faction. Medium army armored vest. The suit material consists of two layers: specially treated leather and fabric with asbestos thread. Gives good protection against various anomalous influences and radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_exo_name">
    <text>Clear Sky Exoskeleton</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_exo_description">
    <text>The exoskeleton perfectly protects against various anomalous influences and radiation. Vulnerable to armor-piercing rounds.</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_scientific_outfit_name">
    <text>Clear Sky Scientific Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="nebo_scientific_outfit_description">
    <text>Production of the "Clear Sky" faction, for scientific research in the Zone. Closed-cycle protection system, built-in system for suppressing the action of anomalous fields. High protection against radiation. Bullet protection is still insufficient for active combat operations.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_v1_description">
    <text>Produced by "folk craftsmen", the stalker suit "Veteran-1" represents an effective combination of a light army armored vest and a jumpsuit made of rubberized fabric. Reinforced with built-in Kevlar plates. Protects well against weak small arms. In general, extremely insufficient for deep raids and serious operations in the Zone nodes.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_v2_description">
    <text>Produced by "folk craftsmen", the stalker suit "Veteran-2" represents an effective combination of a light army armored vest and a jumpsuit made of rubberized fabric. Reinforced with built-in Kevlar plates. Protects well against weak small arms. In general, extremely insufficient for deep raids and serious operations in the Zone nodes.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_outfit_v3_description">
    <text>Produced by "folk craftsmen", the stalker suit "Veteran-3" represents an effective combination of a light army armored vest and a jumpsuit made of rubberized fabric. Reinforced with built-in Kevlar plates. Protects well against weak small arms. In general, extremely insufficient for deep raids and serious operations in the Zone nodes.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_black_outfit_name">
    <text>Black Monolith Suit</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_black_outfit_description">
    <text>Elite suit of a stalker of the "Monolith" faction, manufacturer unknown. Although slightly inferior to the army armored vest of the PSZ-9a series in protective characteristics, it has one noticeable plus: wounds heal faster in it and bleeding stops. Structurally resembles suits widely distributed among neutral stalkers, in which the armored vest is combined with a radiation protection suit. Protects well against weak small arms. The level of protection against anomalous activity leaves much to be desired due to the lack of an air filtration system.</text>
</string>