<string id="General">
    <text>General Information</text>
</string>

<string id="Mutants">
    <text>Animals and Mutants</text>
</string>

<string id="Chimera">
    <text>Chimera</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_mutant_chimera_general">
    <text>The result of genetic experiments under the UZHAZ program (Universal Animal-Protector). Possesses excellent tissue regeneration, in addition to this has a duplicated system of internal organs and an additional brain. All this makes the process of killing a chimera very problematic. Very smart, strong and fast creature.</text>
</string>

<string id="Fracture">
    <text>Izlom</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_mutant_fracture_general">
    <text>Either the result of experiments, or the result of the Zone's impact on the remaining people. Or maybe the result of the sick imagination and shaken psyche of some stalkers...\nIt is believed that these mutants, very similar to thin and hunched people, possess a hypertrophied limb, and their brain and nervous system have not undergone such disastrous changes as in zombies. They are cunning and try to lure stalkers with conversation or a request. They say that by sharing food, one can learn interesting information about the Zone... \nAlthough many would prefer to feed the mutant with lead.</text>
</string>

<string id="Cat">
    <text>Cat</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_mutant_cat_general">
    <text>A representative of the feline family. Like all representatives of this species, it is graceful and cunning. Moves almost silently, can jump far and high. It is very difficult to hit it, as it is very agile. It is better not to meet with it alone.</text>
</string>

<string id="Zombie">
    <text>Zombie</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_mutant_zombie_general">
    <text>A dead person revived by the energy of the Zone. The revived corpses are devoid of higher brain functions and act solely on residual reflexes. Their actions are uncoordinated and slow, but they are capable of causing significant damage due to their numbers and physical strength. In addition, zombies are very tenacious and difficult to kill.</text>
</string>

<string id="Burer">
    <text>Burer</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_mutant_burer_general">
    <text>The result of a secret government program to create telekinetics. Fat dwarfs with a hypertrophied face dressed in the remnants of prison uniforms. They possess telekinetic abilities, can throw objects and create protective fields. They live mainly in underground laboratories and dungeons. They hate light and loud sounds.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_flesh_eye">
    <text>Flesh Eye</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_flesh_eye_description">
    <text>The eye of a Flesh. Sometimes scientists buy them, as the deformed crystalline lens of this mutant has interesting optical properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_boar_leg">
    <text>Boar Hoof</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_boar_leg_description">
    <text>Radioactive hoof of a mutant boar. Can be useful to scientists for studying the mutation of bone tissues.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_dog_tail">
    <text>Dog Tail</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_dog_tail_description">
    <text>Torn off tail of a blind dog. Of interest to scientists studying the effect of radiation on the hair and skin of animals.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail">
    <text>Pseudodog Tail</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_psevdodog_tail_description">
    <text>Tail of a pseudodog. Can be valuable for collectors or scientists studying mutant genetics.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw">
    <text>Bloodsucker Tentacles</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_krovosos_jaw_description">
    <text>Oral tentacles of a bloodsucker. They contain glands that secrete an enzyme that prevents blood clotting. Very valuable for medicine.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_burer_hand">
    <text>Burer Hand</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_burer_hand_description">
    <text>Hand of a dwarf-burer. Of interest to scientists studying telekinesis and anomalies of muscle tissue development.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_zombie_hand">
    <text>Zombie Hand</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_zombie_hand_description">
    <text>Severed hand of a zombie. A disgusting trophy, but scientists buy them to study the processes of necrosis and tissue regeneration under the influence of the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_snork_leg">
    <text>Snork Foot</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_snork_leg_description">
    <text>Foot of a snork with preserved remnants of a boot. Tendons possess increased strength and elasticity, which is of interest to biologists.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_face_tushkano">
    <text>Tushkano Head</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_face_tushkano_description">
    <text>Head of a rodent (tushkano). Scientists buy them to study mutations of the skull and brain of small mammals.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler">
    <text>Controller Hand</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_hand_kontroler_description">
    <text>Hand of a controller. Valuable biological material. Used to study the impact of psi-fields on biological tissues.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas">
    <text>Poltergeist Eye</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_poltergeist_glas_description">
    <text>Eye of a poltergeist. A very rare and expensive trophy. It has unique properties associated with the perception of invisible spectrums of radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand">
    <text>Pseudogiant Eye</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_psevdogigant_hand_description">
    <text>Eye of a pseudogiant. Very large and durable. Scientists are ready to pay a good price for such a rarity.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_tail_cat">
    <text>Cat Tail</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_tail_cat_description">
    <text>The resistance of the skin of mutated cats to chemical and electrical effects has long attracted the attention of scientists. Due to the lack of fatty deposits, cat tails are most suitable for laboratory research.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot">
    <text>Chimera Claw</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_chimera_kogot_description">
    <text>A chimera's claw is stronger than any metal, so they are very interesting for scientists.</text>
</string>

<string id="mutant_spider_leg">
    <text>Spider Limb</text>
</string>
<string id="mutant_spider_leg_description">
    <text>Lower phalanx of the Earth Spider limb, one of the most mysterious mutants of the Zone. Earth Spiders are extremely rare, so scientists, and not only them, are ready to shell out huge money for any part of this monster, as it was previously impossible to study these mutated arthropods.</text>
</string>

<string id="dead_monster_use">
    <text>[%c[yellow]$$ACTION_USE$$%c[default]] Cut trophy\n[%c[yellow]SHIFT+$$ACTION_USE$$%c[default]] Take body</text>
</string>

<string id="dead_monster_take">
    <text>[%c[yellow]$$ACTION_USE$$%c[default]] Take body</text>
</string>