<string id="enc_bioradar">
    <text>This amazing device allows detecting many living forms, both warm-blooded and cold-blooded, at a distance of up to 50 meters. The principle of its operation is described in detail in the monograph of Professor Bolshakov "Practical application of the unique properties of the artifact ZX-232 'Crystal Ball' in field conditions", as well as in the dissertation of Assistant Semenov "Biological organisms as natural transceivers of radio waves". Briefly, the operation of the device can be described as follows: Most living organisms emit electromagnetic waves during movement, which can be direction-found to measure their frequency, intensity, and determine the position of the source in space. During muscle work, electrical impulses flow along the nerve fiber to the muscle bundle, and living tissues, as well as tissues in which current conductivity is preserved, become micro-transmitters. For a quite long time, it was believed that due to the extreme weakness of the signals, they could only be detected in laboratory conditions using bulky amplifying equipment. So-called "auroscopes" worked and work on this principle - instruments recording the "aura" around a living body, which is, in fact, electromagnetic radiation of a certain range. \n\nIn the course of researching various artifacts of the Zone, scientists stumbled upon an extremely interesting effect of one artifact - the "Crystal Ball". Assistant Semenov's small pocket radio completely unexpectedly began to receive a signal from a private radio station located in one of the provincial districts of Argentina. Having studied the unusual phenomenon, the scientific camp team came to the only probable explanation: the "Crystal Ball" artifact amplifies and filters an ordered radio signal from interference. Obviously, a microscopic part of the signal from the Argentine radio point was present at the camp's location, but it was so small that no powerful receivers could fix it. However, one only had to bring the "Crystal Ball" to the stationary communication console of the camp, as hundreds of voices began to be heard from the noise of the ether, upon further tuning successfully filtered and turning out to be signals of almost all radio transmitters available in the range of the communication console, the most distant of which was at a distance of 14 thousand kilometers! \n\nThe "Crystal Intercept" project was immediately classified as "Top Secret", however, before that moment, some devices made using such an amazing property still became public property. The "bioradar" device takes bearings on the radiation of living tissues of organisms, filtering them by frequency and distance. As a result, on a regular liquid crystal display, you can see marks indicating living organisms. \nThe disadvantages of the device include its high cost.</text>
</string>
<string id="bioradar">
    <text>Bioradar</text>
</string>

<string id="Antirad">
    <text>Anti-radiation drugs</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-heavy">
    <text>Heavy stalker equipment</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-light">
    <text>Light stalker equipment</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-medium">
    <text>Medium stalker equipment</text>
</string>
<string id="bandage">
    <text>Bandage</text>
</string>
<string id="binoc_name">
    <text>Binoculars</text>
</string>
<string id="Bread">
    <text>Bread</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_desc">
    <text>Detailed map of the Dead City, containing the layout of mercenary positions</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_name">
    <text>Map of the Dead City</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_doctors_key_desc">
    <text>Doctor's key to the stash in Pripyat</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_doctors_key_short_desc">
    <text>Doctor's Key</text>
</string>
<string id="Conserva">
    <text>Tourist's Delight</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect1">
    <text>Anomaly Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect2">
    <text>Dosimeter</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect3">
    <text>Anomaly Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect4">
    <text>Elite Anomaly Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="Devic">
    <text>Devices and units</text>
</string>
<string id="device-PDA">
    <text>PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="device-torch">
    <text>Flashlight</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight - 18 kg. Features: protects the body from "Fruit Punch", "Burnt Fuzz", most anomalies and mechanical damage. The chest and back are protected by built-in biometal plates. Equipped with a hermetic metal-plastic helmet and two oxygen tanks. Warning: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - gets damaged and torn.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight - 8 kg. Features: protects the body from the effects of weak anomalies and mechanical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Warning: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - gets damaged and torn.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight - 12 kg. Features: protects the body from "Fruit Punch", "Burnt Fuzz", many anomalies and mechanical damage. Equipped with a hermetic helmet and an oxygen tank. Warning: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - gets damaged and torn.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
    <text>Protective spacesuit of red color with a hermetic helmet. Weight - 11 kg. Features: protects the body from fire, acids, gases, the effects of various anomalies, "Burnt Fuzz" and mechanical damage. Equipped with two oxygen tanks. Warning: with prolonged use, it becomes unusable - gets damaged and torn.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul">
    <text>Army portable binoculars.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
    <text>Dosimeter - a device measuring the dose or power of ionizing radiation. To work, it must be activated by placing the device on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect2">
    <text>A device determining the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances and reporting them with a sound signal. To work, it must be activated by placing the device on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect3">
    <text>Elite anomaly detector invented by scientists in the Zone. Determines the presence of most of the most dangerous anomalous fields, but also shows the location of anomalous formations on the display.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect4">
    <text>Prototype of the elite anomaly detector. Unlike the previous version, it shows on the display not only anomalous formations but also the location of anomalous fields.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
    <text>Pocket Personal Computer (PDA) - an indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
    <text>Flashlight with a fairly powerful bulb. A very useful thing in low light conditions.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
    <text>Flashlight with a fairly powerful bulb. Thanks to an improved transformer, the battery charging time is reduced.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
    <text>Excellent energy drink "Non stop". Contains caffeine, taurine and a powerful vitamin complex that relieves fatigue and adds strength. Unable to take even a step? Then this is exactly what you need.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_energydrinka">
    <text>Unknown object. The label says it's beer.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
    <text>It is unknown who manages to bake loaves on the territory of the Zone, but this bread is not contaminated and quite edible. In any case, none of the stalkers have complained yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
    <text>Canned food from an army food warehouse looted by stalkers. The expiration date seems not to have passed yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
    <text>Often for lack of better, this sausage - a mixture of chicken and soy substitute - is a stalker's breakfast, lunch, and dinner.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
    <text>Vodka produced by "GSC" company. Easy to drink, noticeably reduces the effects of radiation, however, it should not be abused.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
    <text>Reduces the effect of radiation on the body.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
    <text>Dressing material. Helps to stop bleeding.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
    <text>Universal medical kit. Allows coping with injuries of various types and degrees of complexity: wounds, burns, poisoning.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit2">
    <text>Specialized medical kit for combating physical damage and bleeding. It includes: components for accelerating blood clotting, painkillers, antibiotics and immune stimulants.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit3">
    <text>Medical kit designed specifically for work in Zone conditions. The composition of the kit is selected both for combating wounds and for removing radionuclides from the body. Prevents the development of radiation sickness, and also reduces the dose of accumulated radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name">
    <text>Energy drink "Non Stop"</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name_dbeer">
    <text>Beer of unknown origin</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name_dbeer_short">
    <text>Beer of unknown origin</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_name">
    <text>Cylinder with colloidal gas</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_name_short">
    <text>Cylinder with colloidal gas</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_opisalovo">
    <text>Colloidal gas was supplied to research laboratories for experiments during research, exactly which ones is now unknown. It is only known that the contents of the cylinders are extremely chemically active, explosive and poisonous.</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_name">
    <text>Jerrycan with gasoline</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_name_short">
    <text>Jerrycan</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_opisalovo">
    <text>Jerrycan with gasoline</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
    <text>Energy drink "Non Stop"</text>
</string>
<string id="Equipment">
    <text>Equipment and food</text>
</string>
<string id="Food">
    <text>Foodstuffs</text>
</string>
<string id="Kolbasa">
    <text>"Practical" Sausage</text>
</string>
<string id="MediÑ">
    <text>Medical supplies</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit">
    <text>Medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit_army">
    <text>Army medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit_scientific">
    <text>Scientific medkit</text>
</string>
<string id="Sci2">
    <text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
</string>
<string id="Vodka">
    <text>"Cossacks" Vodka</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector1">
    <text>Echo Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector2">
    <text>Bear Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector3">
    <text>Veles Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector4">
    <text>Svarog Detector</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector1_descr">
    <text>The simplest detector, reports the presence of anomalous formations with a sound signal and a built-in diode.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector2_descr">
    <text>A more advanced detector, determining the presence of anomalous fields and anomalous formations, reports the presence with a sound signal, and also shows the approximate location of anomalous formations on the display.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector3_descr">
    <text>Elite anomaly detector invented by scientists in the Zone. Determines not only the presence of anomalous fields and "formations", but also shows their location on the map, reports them with a sound signal, and also shows "formations" on the display.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector4_descr">
    <text>The newest prototype, the difference from the previous model is that it shows anomalous fields on the display.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_matras">
    <text>Sleeping bag</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_matras_s">
    <text>Sleeping bag</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_matras">
    <text>Camping sleeping bag. Perhaps the most comfortable way to spend the night in the Zone. It won't save from radiation, but it will protect from rain.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_ruksak">
    <text>Small backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ruksak_s">
    <text>Small backpack</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_ruksak">
    <text>Small camping backpack. Made of rubberized fabric, so it does not get wet. In such a backpack you can store valuables somewhere in a secluded place - it will make an excellent stash.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_metka">
    <text>Delete</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_metka_s">
    <text>Delete</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_metka">
    <text>Delete</text>
</string>

<string id="psy_block">
    <text>Phytozepam Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="psy_block_desc">
    <text>Powerful tranquilizer. Blocks avalanche-like nerve impulses, causing a short-term loss of all emotions. Used in the Zone exclusively for protecting consciousness in zones of anomalous psi-fields and controller influence.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_block">
    <text>Indralin Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_block_desc">
    <text>Radioprotective drug that was part of the first aid kit issued to nuclear power plant personnel. Used in the Zone instead of excessively toxic cystamine hydrochloride, repeated use of which often causes serious complications.</text>
</string>

<string id="weigth_boost">
    <text>Hercules Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="weigth_boost_desc">
    <text>The main component of this product is an anabolic androgen - an artificial steroid, the chemical composition of which resembles testosterone. Often used by stalkers during long marches to reduce muscle fatigue.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_restore">
    <text>Cystamine Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_restore_desc">
    <text>Radioprotector substance. Weakens the negative effect of ionizing radiation on the body. Often used by stalkers to effectively and quickly reduce irradiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="health_boost">
    <text>Epinephrine Injection</text>
</string>
<string id="health_boost_desc">
    <text>Epinephrine, aka adrenaline. Contains substances that cause a rush of adrenaline in the blood, increased heart rate and artificial increase in energy in the body. That is, it also serves as a kind of stimulant. Often used by stalkers in critical situations.</text>
</string>