<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7000">
    <text>Thanks a lot Strelok! It seems we did it... damned crazy bastards! Though those Monolith nutjob's aren't the worst that could happen around here though, lately mutants have been trying to break in from the Radar area. So it's hell here! They move pretty fast and not everyone can shoot such a quick moving target! We had a flamethrower, a great weapon against those freaks, but it's broken now. Maybe our technician Screw can fix it. But how can the rest of us get out of this damned place?! With you as witness there's not even a second for some rest! Well it's time for a small reward for you. Is money alright?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7001">
    <text>Sure, money sounds great, as long as it is not USD.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7002">
    <text>Do you have anything else?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7003">
    <text>Well, you see we need money ourselves. Listen I'll give you 1,000 rubles and that broken flamethrower. It's useless here anyway and as I said before none of us are gonna fix it. I see you're a clever guy. Take it to Screw. I'm sure he'll have some idea how to fix it. Believe me it's worth much more than money when it's working! Cooked Snorks are pretty tasty.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7004">
    <text>No thanks! I don't need that piece of junk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_freedom_commander_7005">
    <text>I think that this flamethrower will be more useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1000">
    <text>Hey Screw, here you go, look at this thing. Totally busted up flamethrower. It's your friends who did it, don't look at me with such discuss. I helped them a little so they gave me this in return. They also said that only you could fix it. What do you think? Can you fix it?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1001">
    <text>God dammit... I spent a lot of time making this flamethrower! Imbeciles! I can't believe they trashed it! The fuel hose is missing, what the hell! Did they throw it into every anomaly in the Zone? Or did a bloody Chimera chew it up? Well my friend there's a lot of work to be done here. I've already worked like hell for a number of nights on it. But okay you helped my guys so I'll help you. Certainly not for your charm and beauty however. I'll make a list of parts that we'll need to replace. I already have most of the parts and some I can get off the guys around here. Think about it though, are you really gonna run all around the Zone with this thing?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1002">
    <text>Hell no! To hell with this piece of shit! Will you take it off my hands for 2,500 rubles?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1003">
    <text>Run all around the Zone? Well, what else am I here for? Tell me what you need.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1004">
    <text>Suit yourself, I'll take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1005">
    <text>That's good... here's what we need: \n\n 
Firstly an artifact called the 'Fire ball'. The flamethrowers got more holes in it than Swiss cheese! I could weld most of them shut but I wouldn't be able to do it until after winter! But with a Fire Ball there'd be no wait. Believe me there is an unknown feature in that ball. It's a useful thing indeed. \n\n 
Secondly we need new pipes and fuel lines. The ones I got are only good for WC, not for a flamethrower! So get some pipe. Talk to Sidorovich in the rookies camp. They often give him tons of garbage from ... well... from Garbage! And say hello to him for me. \n\n 
Thirdly we need a new Manometer or else you'll be the one getting torched. Jeez it looks like they opened cans with the old one. Morons, damn them. All right go find it all. I'd look for it in Agroprom. There was an Institute there, you know, so maybe you could find something there. \n\n 
Fourthly we need an ignition source, the main part. The original burner was made from titanium. I wonder who could've broken it, a Burer?! You can't get a burner from our guys. No way no one would give one up! It is the best way to smoke sausage too. Of course you can look for it in the Barracks without permission. But I think I know a better method. Go to Barkeep, he's a packrat, so he'll probably have something like that. So buy a burner, just don't say that it's for me. If Duty knows that I'm making weapons here they will not sleep until they get me! Why the hell would I need such a problem? \n\n
Lastly the most important part of our little repair here, Vodka, type 'Spiritus Vini', If you please. It has all kinds of uses. Making parts clean and making my head clean too. Got it? Bring me some Vodka will you? You see I need strong motivation for a task like this. I think five bottles would be nice. Maybe seven! Ah what the hell bring me ten bottles. As I said there's a lot of work to be done. \n\n 
That's all. I think you'll get everything. Your Strelok, right? Afterwards you'll have yourself a flamethrower. I believe in you and it would be wonderful if vodka could be the first thing that you'd search for.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1006">
    <text>Seems like I need to do some serious shopping. I hope it's worth the trouble.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1007">
    <text>Trust me it'll be worth it. By the way it will cost you 5,000 rubles. Not too much because I like you!</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1008">
    <text>Wait, you said nothing about money!</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1009">
    <text>Hey be reasonable! I could get a million for this thing that I'm going to fix for you! But I am a kind person Strelok. Look, who else except me would do it? So come on man don't be so greedy! </text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_1010">
    <text>Damn you. Alright I'll do it. Don't die from lack of Vodka before I come back.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Sidorovich I got some news from Screw. He want's to know if you remember him?</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1000">
    <text>Screw, huh, Screw, screw him! My memory is not as good as it was in my youth Strelok. But yes I remember a stalker named Screw. He was a real vodka drinking devil. He could drink my stock dry if I'd let him. I figured he'd of died by now from drinking. Heh... but he brought me some rare things in his younger days and his hands are, you know, hands of a real master. He could fix everything that was broken, everything from TV's to Dosimeters. So he is still alive?</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1001">
    <text>Yes he is. He sent me to you and he told me you might you have something that I need. I'm looking for an Iron pipe, not very big. Its not necessarily to say why, but Screw is helping me repair something. Do you have something like that?</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1002">
    <text>What? What the hell would I need iron pipes for? I don't keep things around that I don't need or can't sell!</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1003">
    <text>How much I need to pay you for some pipe then?</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1004">
    <text>Strelok is the radiation going to your head? I'm telling you that I dont have any freak'n iron pipes! I can only give you a tip. You really made me glad letting me know that Screw is still alive. So my advice to you is to meet with Alexey Tambovsky. He's always making something from all kinds of trash. He is in Garbage now looking for some parts for some kind of detector that picks up life forms. I'll give you his coordinates.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1005">
    <text>Thanks, you mean your actually going to give me advice for free? Unbelievable.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1006">
    <text>Say what? It seems I have problems not only with memory.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1007">
    <text>I said thanks a lot! Thanks for the info. And stay well Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<string id="escape_trader_flamethrower_dialog_1008">
    <text>Yeah my health isn't as great as it used to be.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_0">
    <text>Hi there what do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1000">
    <text>Sidorovich told me you might have some sort of an iron pipe.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1001">
    <text>Iron pipes eh? Hmm, I saw several on those radioactive hills, but I can't get to them. I don't have an effective outfit. But I did write down the coordinates. If you really need them I can sell them to you almost for free. Up on the hills I decided to look for something else, but caught a wave of radiation, I just cleaned up my nosebleed. Listen to me, you get me some antirad. I'll give you the coordinates. Okay?</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1002">
    <text>Yeah sure, but I don't have any Antirad. Your on your own. I'll look for the pipe myself.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1003">
    <text>Yes, you should be careful around all this radiation. Here you go.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1004">
    <text>Give me your PDA. Well lookie there I made a marker. I'm sure the pipes are there, nobody could steal them. Go now.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_flamethrower_1005">
    <text>Thanks a lot. Good luck with your new devices.</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_0">
    <text>Hello! Listen, could you sell me a decent burner?</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1000">
    <text>A burner? Interesting question. I'm embarassed to ask, but just why would you need it?</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1001">
    <text>I'm dying to eat some smoked Snork feet!</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1002">
    <text>Oh really? Okay, okay, it's not my business. I have one, it seems to be working properly. Take it for 250 rubles.</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1003">
    <text>250 for this? Forget it. I'll get one myself somewhere else.</text>
</string>

<string id="barmen_flamethrower_task_1004">
    <text>Fair price, here is your money.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_0">
    <text>You got all the parts? I hope you got the Vodka as well.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1000">
    <text>I got everything, and your vodka too. Start working! I'm waiting for this flamethrower and my money is waiting for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="parts_completed_1001">
    <text>Take it easy buddy! I said I'll fix the damn thing. Just give me a day and you get to your toy.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1002">
    <text>It's a deal. I'll wait.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_10111">
    <text>Well how goes the repairs? Are you almost finished?</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1003">
    <text>Whoa, M... M... Strelok... heh-heh, how you doin' buddy? What you want from me? Oh, yeah, right! The flamethrower! You seriously think its done already? Uhh, sorry man, I think I had a little too much to drink and lost track of time.</text>
</string>


<string id="parts_completed_1004">
    <text>Are you kidding me? You said drinking helps you focus. If you'd work without drinking your whole base could have flamethrowers, hell with you, I'll be back when you've sobered up.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1013">
    <text>Alright, you sober now? How's my flamethrower?</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1005">
    <text>Yeah I'm good now, sorry, here is your flamethrower!</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1006">
    <text>Is that for real?! I thought you'd never actually fix it. Looks great, let me have it.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1007">
    <text>Hey hold on, I'm not so drunk today. We had a deal, 10,000 roubles for the repairs, remember?</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1008">
    <text>What?! Did you dissolve your brain in Vodka? It was 5,000 rubles. Or would you prefer me to remind you how interested Duty would be to know what you cooking up here?</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1009">
    <text>Okay, calm down, it's 5000 roubles. Take your flamethrower. Now you can make life a little easier. Oh yes, there is something else. That fuel canister holds enough for about a minute of torching. Then it'll be empty. Come back here and I'll refuel it for a price. It's not so simple, you must remember. I'll also need a gasoline canister and a canister filled with Colloid gas which is used in the Flamethrower. Yes I could get it all by myself, but it will cost you a lot.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1010">
    <text>A canister? And where could I find this?</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1011">
    <text>Colloid gas, I'm telling you! The eggheads brought a lot with them into the Zone for their experiments. It's perfect for flame fuel. You can get it in Agroprom and pretty much everywhere else. But better look for it now, Alright? Don't forget, a fuel can and a canister of that damn Colloid.</text>
</string>

<string id="parts_completed_1012">
    <text>Yeah, got it, thank you. Have fun with the rest of your vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_text">
    <text>I need to find some items from the list that Screw gave me: \n\n 
1. A 'Fire Ball' artifact. \n 
2. Pipe. Screw said Sidorovich might have some. \n 
3. Pressure meter. Take a look in Agroprom Research Institute. \n 
4. Burner. Ask Barkeep about it. \n 
5. Ten bottles of vodka for this alcoholic. \n\n 
It's going to be a long day.</text>
</string>

<string id="trubka_descr">
    <text>Steel pipe... bent slightly, but looks strong enough. It should be okay for a flamethrower.</text>
</string>

<string id="gorelka_descr">
    <text>Middle-sized burner. As stalkers say, sausage is wondeful when it's been smoked with this thing. It's used to ignite the high temperature gel mixture in a flamethrower.</text>
</string>

<string id="manometr_descr">
    <text>A simple pressure meter device, from some industrial mechanism of soviet time. It's glass is dirty, but it seems to be in good condition. It should work properly on a flamethrower.</text>
</string>

<string id="flama_descr">
    <text>Pitiful thing. Who knows what fantastic power this thing could of have when it was working. But maybe a good specialist will be able to repair it. Where could I find such a specialist?</text>
</string>

<string id="flame_descr">
    <text>Hand-made weapon based on thea army model flamethrower made by Screw. It's for close combat, and it's a devastating weapon. The best way for using it is to roast hordes of mutants in packs. Full charge will make it fire for about a minute or so.</text>
</string>

<string id="flame_no_parts_0">
    <text>Shit, I forgot something. I'll be back.</text>
</string>

<string id="item_flamethrower_bad_name">
    <text>Broken flamethrower.</text>
</string>

<string id="manometr">
    <text>Pressure Meter.</text>
</string>

<string id="trubka">
    <text>Pipe.</text>
</string>

<string id="gorelka">
    <text>Burner.</text>
</string>

<string id="flamethrower_basic">
    <text>Flamethrower - hand-made, but it was made with great skill. It can be refueled in the 'Freedom' base by Screw. It's not a wide spread technology, so fuel is rare. It consists of standard gasoline (stored in simple canisters) and special Colloid gas (stored in red marked canisters). Screw said that there are a lot of them in the Agroprom area, but they can be found anywhere. Of course Screw could find it himself, but it will cost a lot. And as always he will need a bottle of vodka for himself.</text>
</string>
</string_table>