<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
 <string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_01">
    <text>At last Strelok! This suit is amazing! We'll try to introduce their technology into our suits. We'll give you some recipes as a reward. We got a guy here, he's a genius I tell you, his name is Cook, and you probably know him. He could make a new and effective artifact from almost any worthless one, he works in wierd ways though, he took a blow to the head and he's been very poetic ever since, so try to understand, okay?</text>
</string>
 <string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_02">
    <text>Yeah sure.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_03">
    <text>And one more thing Strelok, I hope these things which bring benefits and causes kindness won’t reach the ears of Duty, correct?</text>
</string>
 <string id="mil_lukash_healing_armor_04">
    <text>I guarantee it.</text>
</string>

 <string id="trader_beads_1">
    <text>The reward I'm giving you is a worthy one and you'll soon realize the benefits of making one artifact into another. That’s right, it is possible. Don't believe me? Have a look at your PDA; I'm uploading info to you.</text>
</string>

 <string id="trader_beads_2">
    <text>I take it your never going to tell me where you got this info?</text>
</string>

 <string id="trader_beads_3">
    <text>Yes, that's correct, but surely having the recipes will satisfy you?</text>
</string>

 <string id="ecolog_prizrak_outfit_reward_1">
    <text>I want to thank you for this suit! Not only is it a nice one, but it's been helping research as well. Have a look at your PDA; I'm going to give you some very valuable info. Chimera Tears will build up your resistance to the psychological effects of Controllers, and probably will help you to pass through Pripyat! Take care Strelok. I hope that our cooperation will last for a long time!</text>
</string>

<string id="drunk_dolg_reward_phr_1">
    <text>Hey Strelok! Here in Duty, we never forget to pay back. Take this recipe, It'll show you how to modify an artifact. Trust me, this is some rare info! Use it well.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_1">
    <text>Thank you friend, you helped me out a lot. If I ever get the chance I shall try to return the favor, if I am still drawing breath. But for now I have but one thing I can say: South from here there is a ranch with a camp of lone stalkers. One of them sells some kind of 'Gauss rifle' at a very low price; I think it’s around 800 rubles. I wanted to buy it, but a damn Bloodsucker attacked me and threw me in here. If you have the money then let's go. Except for info on that rifle I can't give anything quite worth saving a life. Actually there is one more thing I can tell you. Have you ever heard something about the Acidic Porcupine?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_2">
    <text>Is this a mutant were talking about? I never heard about this mutant.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_3">
    <text>N-no this is a modified artifact! It's full of smelly acid shit, the rank fluid inside of it makes it impossible to hang on a belt, you'll need something like a bag, or a plastic container, with a lid that can fit tight. You'll understand once you create this artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_4">
    <text>How'd you get this recipe? You seem new to the Zone. Did you kill someone?</text>
</string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_5">
    <text>No! I've found it on a dead Duty stalker, B-but I didn't kill him. I wouldn't stand a chance against him. He had one of those exoskeleton suit things with armor and had no chance at all! He was killed by something powerful. The exoskeleton looked like something had chewed it up, and the armor was in terrible condition. There was no chance to repair it. But his PDA was intact and when I looked through it I found this recipe. I'll upload it to your PDA. Read it for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="val_sos_dialog_21_amk_6">
    <text>Well, thank you! Good luck!</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_zapiska">
    <text>Scribbled on piece of paper.</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_zapiska_s">
    <text>Note.</text>
</string>

 <string id="mil_freedom_commander_3001_amk">
    <text>Thanks Strelok I appreciate your help. My guys are exhausted. Two hours ago they had quite a fight with a Controller and some brain-dead Stalkers it took control of. It was a hard fight. I lost three good men and all the rest were complaining about ringing in their heads. You could tell just by how they were shooting, most of them usually shoot pretty well, but not with the Controller frying their brains. In thanks for the well-timed help I'll give you a recipe. Grisha Zvuk has recently returned from a spot-check, there his squad has taken part in some nasty business, they killed some Duty stalkers. And in one of their PDAs he found some interesting information. I think you'll understand once you read it. Well good luck I hope we'll meet again!</text>
</string>

 <string id="bar_dolg_leader_quest_rg6_finish_1_amk">
    <text>Good job Strelok. You helped me out a lot. As a reward you can take this suit. I think it'll be useful for you. And another thing, scientists gave a recipe to us in thanks for some of our work. You helped me out, so you earned it. Freedom won't know about this though, right? Take a look at your PDA; I've uploaded information to it.</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_hud_disabled">
    <text>Interactive HUD - off</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_hud_enabled">
    <text>Interactive HUD - on</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_hud_and_steam_enabled">
    <text>Interactive HUD - on + breathing</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_mat_disabled">
    <text>Bad language off.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_mat_enabled">
    <text>Bad language on.</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_rad_disabled">
    <text>Radiation scale - off</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rad_enabled">
    <text>Radiation scale - on</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_mus_disabled">
    <text>Dynamic battle music - off</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_mus_enabled">
    <text>Dynamic battle music - on</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_treasure_old">
    <text>Stashes - old (vanilla) mode</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_treasure_new">
    <text>Stashes - random content mode</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_treasure_rare">
    <text>Stashes - random rare mode</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_options">
    <text>AMK Options</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_rkd0">
    <text>Cool.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd1">
    <text>Hey, I have good and bad news for you. I'll start with the bad news. Im not sure what you've done, but it looks like it was something bad. I've been sent to kill you.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd2">
    <text>Huh...?</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd3">
    <text>The good news is that I don't really want to do it. Why? I'm not sure, but you have a good chance to save your ass. As you probably understand everything in this world has its price.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd4">
    <text>Up yours!</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd5">
    <text>You know, I knew that sooner or later this would happen.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd6">
    <text>Think man! Think!</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_rkd8">
    <text>Thanks man, I'll go now. Good luck!</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_1_text" >
    <text>Recording 1: "... During that we saw the whole process from beginning to the end, regardless of Monolith soldiers that have surrounded the Springboard in a tight ring, trying to cover the transmutation process and the artifact itself from any accidental witnesses. But Artiom was standing quite close, so using binoculars he could see the artifact, it had been thrown into the anomaly quite clearly. It was an Acidic Porcupine (quite a weird name, but that's what the Stalker that has created it called, we've checked that). After nine hours, at night, the artifact was thrown back out by the anomaly. Now we need to take it from the Monolith soldiers. Artiom has offered to do that during their next pray to the Monolith. It should start in around 40 minutes. After I return, I want to take care of that clever guy; I think you'll support me, Vladislav Leonidovitch." \n Recording 2: "... I will upload the fragments of data into a memory stick, making copies of it. We have dealt with the Monolith soldiers fairly quickly. While they were howling around the rucksack (at first I thought it was a rucksack, but actually it turned out to be a portable altar! I think that fact would be interesting for the Moscow centre and for the foreign colleagues, Vladislav Leonidovitch) that one of them has brought to the black right angle, Artiom has opened fire from his Vintorez, and I helped him with a couple of grenades. Regardless of our main worries, the modified artifact was left intact. After two days of our expedition I have noticed next properties of the Stone Porcupine: this artifact that I have put under the Absolute-class decreases the amount of radiation that a person gets by 60 megazivert per hour! Not only that, the Stone Porcupine reduces a person's sensitivity to electric damage and increases endurance..." \n Recording 3: "... we are being chased by the Monolith soldiers, about fifteen of them. They're walking well; we tried to run away, but didn't succeed. They're slowly surrounding us. I will leave the memory stick with data with Artiom Inkin and try to slow down them..."</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_2_text" >
    <text>Recording 1: "...They got me on the way out of the village... Five of them were... We couldn't even report our coordinates; the support group is just waiting... They shot Andrey Semionovith's leg in from of me, bitches! They have led us for a long time; I was carrying Andrey Semionovitch... I didn't even know that they had an underground secret place here. Andrey Semionovitch is coping; these bastards have made a bandage for him and told me that they will get their revenge from us for killing their brothers... Andrey Semionovitch was thrown into a cage next to mine, he was unconscious already... they've untied my hands and haven't even taken my PDA and my bag, just my weapon and ammo..." \n Recording 2: "... Don't know what this is... I don't know... It's not a bloodsucker; it's not a chimera... It's not a... It has crawled out of the pit when they started to sing! They've opened Andrey Semionovitch's cage door... It didn't touch them; it went for the cage straight away... it got in there... and... IT STARTED TO EAT HIM! HE WAS STILL ALIVE AS IT BIT DOWN AND HE SCREAMED!!! IT WAS EATING HIS FACE AND HE WAS WHEEZING AND TRYING TO." \n Recording 3: "... It will come back... They're gone, but it is sitting down there in the pit... I can hear its thoughts... they've gone and left my cage door open... And it has gone back into the pit and it's sending its thoughts into my head and... It tells me... And Andrey Semionovitch tells me... Also in my head... I will leave... I'll just take Andrey Semionovitch's hand... He says that even a hand, it's good anyway... The hand... is important, very important... But it... Doesn't crawl out... It's shining down there... in the pit... like a rainbow... and tells me in my head not to leave.... but I will leave... they haven't even closed the door... they've said that it wouldn't let me to get out... but it has left as soon as it has finished eating Andrey Semionovitch... just left a hand... Andrey Semionovitch tells me to go now... while it’s thinking down there... and take the hand... because it's very important to him..." \n Recording 4: "I've tricked it... its foolish... I've taken the Andrey Semionovitch's hand and the rucksack... and started going... it started to growl and to crawl out... It sent me its thoughts... It thought of anger and it was surprised... It didn't know why I was going... because I had not to... and I've sent it a thought that I really need to leave... Andrey Semionovitch wants to leave as well and he has left! It has believed me and didn't come out! It was just growling and shining in the darkness... I'VE TRICKED IT! I've tricked it..."</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text" >
    <text>Recording 1: "I found a dead stalker, all that was left of him, really, near a Springboard anomaly. He had a Gingerbread Man in his rucksack, a really strange one, it was freaking shining. I had a quick thought about it and decided to throw my Gingerbread Man into the Mosquito Bald and see what happens. It's a pity, to be honest, I could get a lot of drink by selling it, but... stuff it, I'll try the trick anyway" \n Recording 2: "I'm waiting for three hours already, shout a loner zombie. Now I regret that I have put the Gingerbread Man into the anomaly, damn it!" \n Recording 3: "Yes! Jumped out like a cork! Five hours have passed and it's here. Shining! I need to celebrate this with some drink!" \n Recording 4: "Phew! That was close! I'm always gonna walk around the Zone drunk now, I'd freaking die if I was sober! Met a bandit, he shot me with his pistol and his gun broke straight after the shot. So this bastard took out a knife and cut me! Killed it with a shotgun." \n Recording 5: "It's not that simple. When I'm thinking about it sober, it all doesn't work out. Well, from the PM he missed me, but the knife he ripped the leather jacket easily the blade strike I can remember, but on my stomach - just a scratch. Maybe my Gingerbread Man has helped? Steel Gingerbread Man... Shining, bloody bastards. Anyway, some Steel Balls would've been cooler..."</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text" >
    <text>Saratsin has brought with him some rookie that he has caught. He says that he hasn't killed him immediately because the guy was looking around in a weird way, as though he has been carrying something valuable. Stubborn milksop! We found an interesting Gingerbread Man in his rucksack. Well, it looked like a Gingerbread Man, but... There was something different about it. When we asked him what the hell the thing was in his bag, he kept silent. I respect that! Especially when he looked like a complete coward! Shved had to break a couple of his fingers, before he finally started to talk. He had told us that this was a Steel Gingerbread Man that has been changed in a Whirligig". Said that you throw it in, leave it there for five hours and after that it becomes different. He's also said that it keeps you safer from bullets, decreases fire and cuts damage, but it's fucking radioactive. I've made up a cool name for it - a Titan Gingerbread Man! Now I need to try out his trick and see whether he was telling the truth. But first of all, I need to find a Steel Gingerbread Man...</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text" >
    <text>This hyper modification can be obtained by the transmutation of a mesomodification Titanium Gingerbread Man in a Fruit Punch anomaly. It gives its owner's skin immunity to cuts, decreases fire and chemical damage. It's also interesting because it generates some sort of a field around its wearer. That field changes the trajectory of bullets that have been shot towards the wearer. The only disadvantage of this quite helpful hyper modification is that it gives off radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text" >
    <text>May he be in Eternity! May He change the World! Preceptor Viktor has told us of another success of his naturalists! Preceptor, as all of us is sure that He has again given us, His followers a gift to strengthen our faith! After a fight with a group of soldiers, that were guarding the scientists, Ostach, the phalanx leader has brought a Steel Scale along with some bodies and salvage. He had sacrificed it with all the bodies to His Flame, but the Watchers, brother Akim and brother Liocho have found the Steel Scale, that has been thrown out of the Burner anomaly after six hours. The artifact was giving off unusual light and that has proved to the Watchers that that was His sign. This changed Steel Scale has been in two battles with a naturalist, Roman. On the way back his phalanx has met and had a battle with four burers. Brother Roman says that this modified Steel Scale was making miracles - he has felt nearly no psy-attacks of the burers! He has also noticed that all the time he was wearing the artifact he didn't want to eat. Truly, He is giving us bits of Eternity even now! Further experiments have shown that this artifact, called Controller's Scalp by its qualities makes its owner feel better and saves from chemical burns. Our Faith is growing and becoming even stronger day by day, for He remembers of us! May He be in Eternity! May He change the World!</text>
</string>


<string id="amk_recipt_souls_text" >
    <text>About half a month ago, on the night of the seventh of July, in the No. 3 block a moving Burner anomaly appeared. It's only when I saw the flame moving across the wall, I've came out what's what, but it was too late - I had enough time to grab my G-36, which was hanging on the wall, but not to get the bag with the Soul, that I'd found two days ago. I got quite sad, drank a bit more. Then, after about four hours I saw my Soul drop out of the flame intact! It was quite weird, though, giving off light like a lamp. So I grabbed it and put it into a container. After I woke up in the morning and saw a couple of guys roasting a boar in the Burner, I immediately remembered about the Soul. I warned Max and went to scientists. The way to their laboratory wasn't the best one, but that's a different story. So, I came to them and gave them that Soul for measurements. Sahara had long thoughts about it... The artifact could make its owner healthier, and, as Sahara said, it could decrease the radiation doses that the wearer gets as well. Also this artefact (I called it Soul Drops, sounds cool) makes its wearer slightly tired. Sahara was even begging me to sell the artifact to him, but a clever idea has come into my head - I wanted to throw it into a Burner once more and see what would happen, and then bring it to the scientists for measurements again. He agreed, not immediately, though. So, I took the artifact and made my way to the tunnel - there are bloody loads of those Burners. I threw the artifact in and waited. In about six hours it jumped out, I got it out, trying not to burn myself; otherwise I would've been as Sahara... I brought it back for measurements and realized I had been right! This artifact, that I called Fiery Soul was twice as good at protecting from radiation! I even regret that I hadn't gone into university, could've become some sort of professor or something...
	So, I went the third time to the anomaly and threw it in. Shot several zombies on my way, one was Mika Cameroon, may he rest in peace. No, life is definitely a strange thing: I was drinking with him a month ago and now I've shot him in the head... may he rest... Anyway, I threw that Fiery Soul into the Burner, and the rest as usual. Only this time I had to wait for quite a bit - the artifact has appeared only in 10 hours, I even had some time to take a nap, some growl woke me. The artifact was shining, as though it was happy 'bout something. Again, I went to the scientists. There were already waiting for me with a massive group of people, gave me some coffee and brandy straight away and did all their work with artifact themselves. My Hennessey-and-coffee mood made me make up a new name for the artifact - Crystal Soul. Professors were so happy, crying, smiling, saying that this hyper... hyperdif... well, this Crystal Soul increases health and has an incredible protection from radiation. In the morning I went up to the Burner again, thrown it in. Waited for bloody ages! When it has jumped out, I was slightly surprised - its shine or anything hasn't changed. So, I thought, that's all right, stuff you. On the way back a moving Electro anomaly has blocked my way, and I couldn't get past it. I sat down, had thought and decided to throw that Soul into the Electro! This time it was like in a Burner before - the artifact has disappeared and was thrown out after just an hour. Was shining differently. When the Electro moved, I went on with my way. I've brought the Soul to the Yantar lab and gave it to Sahara. He's disappeared for a long time, but when he finally got back out his experiment room, he looked like a freaking psycho. He said it's some kind of Absolute. Before, the trans...transm... well, modified Soul was decreasing its owner’s endurance apart from increasing health and protecting from radiation, this time it was the other way round, it made the wearer more endurable. I got a lot of money from the scientists for their experiments with that Soul...</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_electra_text" >
    <text>The Droplets artifact needs to be put into an Electro anomaly. The resulting modification is Tears of Electra which speeds up the process of getting radiation out of its wearer's body (the wearer becomes immune to doses lower than 10 Rads/hour), and also makes its wearer less tired. No negative effects detected.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_fire_text" >
    <text>Modification of 'Tears of Electra' needs to be placed into a 'Burner' anomaly. The resulting mesomodification 'Tears of Fire' speeds up the process of getting radiation out of its wearer's body (maximum dose - 20 +-2 Rads/hour). No negative effects detected.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text" >
    <text>Medium-modified of 'Tears of Fire' is placed into the anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. This hyper-modified besides body radiation protection is also useful in blocking almost half of psi-emissions. Negative characteristics of 'Tears of Chimeras' is the deterioration of human well-being and poor wound healing.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>This information is necessary for every soldier of the Duty. \n Soldiers! Our comrades, the scientists have given us the information of the possibility of changing a Mama's beads artifact into an artifact with better properties. This artifact could only be changed in an Electro anomaly, in which the artifact needs to be put for five hours. After that it has a high chance of getting new properties. This is an extract from a scientific document: \n The resulting artifact, called Old Glass Beads increases endurance of its wearer, while the field it generates around its owner slows down all the bullets that get into it protecting its owner from critical hits. It is slightly radioactive and it decreases its wearer's immunity to electric damage. \n I recommend all soldiers to copy this file into their PDAs and, if met, to send this information to the quad leader...</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>I found Vanya Four Fingers in the village. I was hiding there from dogs, when suddenly I heard the Geiger counter sounding from the basement. Immediately I've pulled out my gun, who knows, there could be a bandit or a Merc down there. But when I looked down, I saw him, his face in a Fruit Punch, I've only recognized him by his hat - red with the sickle and hammer signs on it. It was only four hours since I last saw him - he went ahead and I remained to wait for Vadik, to give him the bag. I felt sorry for Vanya... Nevertheless, I've put on my gas-mask and went down to get him. I couldn't work out how he got down there, as he was an experienced stalker, four years in the Zone, until I saw that someone's twisted his neck. Of course, I've immediately changed my mind about burying him, hell knows what creature could've prepared him for its today's dinner, especially when that creature could be nearby. So I've quickly looked through his dead body, trying not to touch his clothes; took his rucksacks and artifacts. Didn't take his favourite TOZ - the Fruit Punch has left barely anything of it, and fled as quick as possible. He only had three artifacts: a Droplets, one Sea Urchin and Grandmother's Beads. The Droplets and the Urchin were on his belt, but the Grandmother's Beads got into the Fruit Punch. I started to think that the artifact is done for, but it actually was intact, was just shining strangely. I've tested it before I got to the Freedom base. It became different. I've called it bullet resistance's Beads. It stops bleeding, gives energy and has saved me from bullets, when I've met a soldier zombie. It gave off more radiation than Grandmother's Beads, though. I think I'd sell it and buy some new armour.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>Recording: "Phew, to be honest, I started to think that I wouldn't see my Aliona again. You know, I was a clerk at our base - spent my time sitting in front of a computer, did job with various documents and report. But then, when our guys started to kill stalkers every day, I couldn't stand that anymore! I was disgusted... anyway, that's not what I wanted to tell you - I've read a file there accidentally... well, by accidentally I mean... you know, I had to spend some time working with the code, until I've finally hacked the damn thing... I didn't make a copy, yet I still remember it clearly - it was a scientific report about artifacts', behaviour in anomalies! Do you understand, what that means? In that file it said, that if you take some meso... meso something... it was called bullet resistance's Beads - stupid name, don't even ask me, what that is, I haven't got a slightest idea - so, if you take one of those and put it in a Whirligig" then in ten, I think it was, hours you get a different artifact! Well, sort of different... it's actually the same, but with changed properties. It emits some kind of field, everything fast that flies into it is slowed down very much. And I thought that that must work with bullets as well! Radioactive. That's it. I hope, this information will be more useful to you, then to me".</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>To get the needed transmutation a Sea Urchin artifact needs to be placed in a Burner anomaly. If the transmutation is successful, in three hours the artifact becomes a very good protection from radiation. Its only bad property is that it increases the tiredness of the person, who's wearing it. Our further experiments have showed no possibilities in changing the modified artifact that has been called Porcupine in the Burner anomaly.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>Not for the general public! Only for members of 'Freedom'! This is a freaking top secret! \n Vitya Ruddy has created a new artifact! You need to take a Porcupine to start off, then you throw it into an Electro, and in five hours you get a new artifact. Ruddy called it Electro Porcupine, but it doesn't make a difference. The main thing is that the artifact gets the radiation off its owner and makes him more endurable. Weak, I know you're gonna ask me 'bout girls, you perverted freak, but if you send me a message 'bout it I'm gonna kill you! Oh, I forgot! If you put the artifact on and walk near an Electro it’s gonna hit you very hard - the artifact attracts electricity. So be careful with sockets, those things are fucking annoying now! \n Stepan Media Centre, Info Service.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>Gentlemen! The quad of mister Alexy Astronomer has done our laboratory a great favour. The courtyard of our laboratory had been full of boars and fleshes, it was their second wave after the last blowout, we already had some casualties among our personnel. The quad of Alexy Astronomer that has responded our call for help has killed all the mutants!  We believe that money as a reward wouldn't really be enough to show our appreciation and so, to support our future collaboration, we send you the information on how to create an 'Acidic Porcupine' hyper modification. We beg a pardon for such a colloquial name, but it has been given by the creator of this hyper modification and it describes its properties the best. I hope that the 'Duty' soldiers will react adequately to this name! To obtain Acidic Porcupine an Electro Porcupine needs to be put in a Fruit Punch anomaly for two hours. I want to draw your attention to the fact that the hyper modification has a rare quality of the radiation-blocking property - the person wearing it gets only 45% of all the emissions he would have got without the artifact. Apart from that, the artifact is effective at stopping bleeding and helps endurance. The bad properties of the artifact are that it decreases its wearer’s immunity to electric damage and that it is hard to carry because of the mucus it produces. This mucus is harmless but is quite unpleasant, I must say. In general, our community believes that this little inconvenience will not stop your soldiers' will of using this hyper modification! \n Regards, member of the Russian Academy of Science Professor Sahara.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text" >
    <text>Recording 1: "Just got away from the Dark Valley. We lost Yura Buyan - he was torn apart in a Whirligig", we hadn't even realized in the battle, bow he was pushed there by a Burer... May he rest in peace...? That's a terrible way to go. The squad is not full without him, which means we've got less chance of bringing this very interesting piece of paper to the Bar. It seems that burers have taken some poor scientists for their lunch into dungeons. In his PDA he wrote that he found a way to change artifacts into new ones, with different properties... modifications, or whatever he's called them... yeah, looks right... So, you get an artifact of some "absolute" class, whatever that means. The artifact is called Sphere and it is made in a Burner out of a Diamond Gingerbread Man. The scientist has written that this absolute decreases its owner's skin's sensitivity This is very interesting information, I think we need to bring it to Sahara and his team, just need to take some more people with us, at least two squads." \n Recording 2: "Those 'Freedom' bastards were in our way! Three of us got rid of them, five that was. As soon as we got their guns of them - those were very good, someone has shot Sasha Cooler in his head, I think with a Dragunov. We threw some grenades, but we didn't see the sniper, so I don't know whether we'd got him. Rinat tells me to go and that he'll cover me... The information is very important. Bloody sniper, still hiding. Anyway, I've got to go..."</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_shkura_text" >
    <text>Hi, Vova. You are such an idiot! Why do you keep asking 'How is it in the Zone?'. It's not exciting! Fucking boring, to be honest. If we didn't catch any of those freaks, who'd go there for artifacts,? I would actually die from boredom. Well, it could get scary sometimes, I wouldn't lie... especially when some freaking animal or something worse starts to howl near the post - I don't shit myself, but my hairs do bristle. Even on my arse... Even taking in account that I, as all, keep my Kalashnikov with me all the time. Recently we've had some fun - we've caught a guy who was coming back from the Zone. So, we got him. He was carrying a gem with him, it was shining like the bottom of your tuned car in the darkness! So, we 'kindly' asked him, what's that he was carrying and he told us that the stone he had with him wasn't an ordinary artifact - he said it had the ability of decreasing the damage from chemical burns, and that if you wear it you become kind of bulletproof. Well, not completely. We've checked the gem with a Geiger counter - the bastard was freaking radioactive! And the guy we'd caught has told us that he was carrying this thing to scientists, to make it a benefit to people. Then he started to tell us that you need to throw some Skin artifact, throw it into a Springboard and then in five hours you get this thing! He was talking a lot. Looked like a bloody vampire: bald, in scars, hell knows what else. We sent him to the army post, they'll deal with him. Anyway, bye Vova, I need to go to the assembly now, By the way, tell Yulia that I remember and love her, and everything. You know. Bye!</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_cheshya_text" >
    <text>Gentlemen, I am happy to tell you that a new transmutation example has been discovered! A 'Skin' modification needs to be placed in a 'Whirligig' for five hours. The resulting mesomodification with a temporary name "Scale" has got the following properties: it decreases chemical damage, increases health and makes its owner's skin less sensitive to bullet damage. Attention, important information! The Scale is radioactive and increases bleeding of the person, who is wearing it! We hope that this information will help you in your noble work and that this little present will make our friendship and partnership even stronger! \n Regards, member of the Russian Academy of Science Professor Sahara.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_pancir_text" >
    <text>Major, sir, a report from the centre about the Scale artifact has arrived. According to the received data, Steel Scale (reborn in a Fruit Punch from a Scale mesomodification) the person who's wearing it doesn't bleed as much, becomes healthier, gets less damage from bullet damage and doesn't receive most of the chemical damage. Its only negative property is that it is slightly radioactive. The transmutation does not take that long, just two and half hours. People from the Centre have said that they would like to get some more artifacts for experiments to gather the information about all the modifications, giving us access to level 5 data. Because of that I ask for your permission to continue the tortures of the Stalkers that we have caught recently. \n Captain M. Lubyankin.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_simbion_text" >
    <text>I hurry to tell you that the 'B' department has given us a very unpredictable result of their experiments! They have found out that if you place four artifacts (Jellyfish, Droplet, Stone Blood and Thorn) into a Fruit Punch, then after four Zone hours, twenty-one minutes and eighteen seconds you get a completely new artifact with amazing properties! This modification, which was called 'Simbion’, blocks 45% of the psy-emissions! We have tested it on the prisoners, who have been psy-attacked by our captured Archibald. I must say, that this Controller has been with us for a long time and without getting the blowout energy it became quite weak, but still the artifact gives amazing psy-blocking result! I have already written a report for sending to the Centre, all I need is your comments and your permission for sending the data. \n "B" department chief professor Sneghiriov.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_dummy_text" >
    <text>Report No. 14/7 on the "Liar" \n 
To the director of the 'K-32' research department \n 
For professor Sazonov Nickolay Dmitriyevitch \n Dear Nickolay Dmitriyevitch! Today we have finished our experiment series on the "Shell" artifact. During the course of experiments 7 (seven) Shells were destroyed, 5 (five) have degraded, 1 (one) Shell artifact has shown positive results in the transmutation series. \n The Shell artifact, if put into an Electro anomaly for 3 hours, 1 minute and 43 seconds gets following properties: increases immunity to fire damage, increases endurance and decreases immunity to electric damage. The temporary name of the artifact is Fire Dummy. \n If Fire Dummy is put in an Electro anomaly again, then after 6 hours, 3 minutes and 12 seconds the artifact gets following properties: majorly increases immunity to fire damage, increases endurance, increases sensitivity to electric damage. Temporary name of the mesomodification is Shining Dummy. \n If put into an Electro anomaly again, then after 8 hours and exactly 4 minutes the artifact gets following properties: strongly increases immunity to fire damage, strongly increases endurance and strongly increases sensitivity to electric damage. The temporary name of the artifact is Moonshine Dummy. \n We continued the experiments of the Shell in the same anomaly. Like 'Scrap', 'Sister', 'Invisible' and 'Lord of Flies' projects this experiment has been unsuccessful! \n But we tried on another anomaly, and we found that when the Moonshine Dummy hyper modification is put into the Fruit Punch it was 'accepted' by the anomaly. After 12 hours, 3 minutes and 56 seconds the artifact has received "Absolute" properties: it gives almost full immunity to fire damage, extremely increases endurance, greatly increases immunity to electric damage. Temporary name of the artifact is 'Pudding'. \n Further experiments have not shown any results - the anomaly rejects the artifact. \n I believe that our team has come to a tremendous result of the experiments on the Shell artifact. Therefore I believe that the 'Liar' projected is finished successfully. You can find all recordings of the experiments on the server. \n Chief of the research team '7' V. Avakyan.</text>
</string>

<string id="amk_recipt_fake_text" >
    <text>For artifact "Sunshine" is necessary to place artifact 'Moonlight' in the anomaly 'Burner'. After about four Zone hours the 'Sunshine' artifact is produced with the following properties: a strong increase in endurance, decrease susceptibility to high temperatures, a small decrease in sensitivity to electric shock. A side effect is a little bit of radiation. Information is not verified.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>'Porcupine' (modification resistance to radiation) \n Artifact 'Sea Urchin' put in anomaly 'Burner'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 3 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n -65 radiation \n -20 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 65% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 15%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_electra_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>'Electric Porcupine' (major modification endurance and resistance to radiation) \n Modification "Porcupine" put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n -63 radiation \n +100 endurance \n -10 electroshock \n Probability successful transmutation: 72% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 3%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_sopl_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>'Snotty Porcupine' (hyper modification endurance, resistance to radiation and bleeding) \n Major modification "Electric Porcupine" put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 2 Zone hours. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n -55 radiation \n +90 endurance \n -7 electroshock \n -400 bleeding \n Probability successful transmutation: 74% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 16%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_stone_dikoobraz_text" >
    <text>'Stone Porcupine' (absolute endurance, resistance to radiation, to bleeding and electroshock) \n Hyper modification "Snotty Porcupine" put in anomaly "Springboard". \n Time this transmutation takes is 9 Zone hours. Received absolute has following characteristics: \n -50 radiation \n +85 endurance \n +25 electroshock \n -350 bleeding \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 10%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_steel_kolobok_text" >
    <text>'Steel Gingerbread Man' (modification bullet resistance and resistance to breach) \n Artifact "Gingerbread Man" put in anomaly "Springboard". \n Time this transmutation takes is 2 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +5 breach \n +5 bullet resistance \n +7 radiation \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 5%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_titan_kolobok_text" >
    <text>'Titanium Gingerbread Man' (major modification bullet resistance, resistance to breach and burn) \n Modification 'Steel Gingerbread Man' put in anomaly 'Whirligig"'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n +7 breach \n +10 bullet resistance \n +15 radiation \n +25 burn \n Probability successful transmutation: 50% \n Probability extinction: 35% \n chance of rejection: 15%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_almaz_kolobok_text" >
    <text>'Diamond Gingerbread Man' (hyper modification bullet resistance, resistance to breach, to burn and chemical burn) \n Major modification 'Titanium Gingerbread Man' put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 8 Zone hours. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n +6 breach \n +8 bullet resistance \n +10 radiation \n +25 burn \n +15 chemical burn \n Probability successful transmutation: 78% \n Probability extinction: 17% \n chance of rejection: 5%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_soul_bengal_text" >
    <text>'Crystal Soul Bengal' (absolute health, endurance and resistance to radiation) \n Hyper modification 'Crystal Soul' put in anomaly 'Elektra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 1 Zone hour. Received absolute has following characteristics: \n +600 health \n -30 radiation \n +18 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 50% \n Probability extinction: 30% \n chance of rejection: 20%.
</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_soul_drops_text" >
    <text>'Drop of Soul' (modification health and resistance to radiation) \n Artifact 'Soul' put in anomaly 'Burner'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 4 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +600 health \n -10 radiation \n -18 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 5%.
</text>
</string>
 
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_soul_fire_text" >
    <text>'Fiery Soul' (major modification health and resistance to radiation) \n Modification 'Drop of Soul' put in anomaly 'Burner'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 6 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n +600 health \n -20 radiation \n -18 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 60% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 20%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_soul_cristal_text" >
    <text>'Crystal Soul' (hyper modification health and resistance to radiation) \n Major modification 'Fiery Soul' put in anomaly 'Burner'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 10 Zone hours. \n\n Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n +600 health \n -30 radiation \n -18 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 50% \n Probability extinction: 35% \n chance of rejection: 15%.
</text>
</string>
 
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_electra_text" >
    <text>'Tears Electra' (modification resistance to radiation and endurance) \n Artifact 'Droplets' put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. \n\n Modification has following characteristics: \n -10 radiation \n +18 endurance \n\n Probability successful transmutation: 75% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 15%
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_fire_text" >
    <text>'Tears of Fire' (major modification resistance to the radiation) \n Modification "Tear Electra" put in anomaly "Burner". \n Time this transmutation takes is 6 Zone hours. major modification has following characteristics: \n -30 radiation \n Probability successful transmutation: 65% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 15%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_tears_chimaera_text" >
    <text>'Tears Chimera' (hyper modification psi-protection and resistance to the radiation) \n Major modification 'Tears Fire" put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 2 Zone hours. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n -40 radiation \n +45 blocks telepathy \n +140 bleeding \n -150 health \n Probability successful transmutation: 55% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 20%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>'Grandmother Beads' (modification bullet resistance and endurance) \n Artifact "Mama's beads" put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +5 bullet resistance \n +250 endurance \n +5 radiation \n 15 electroshock \n Probability successful transmutation: 85% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 5%
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pra_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>'Beads Great-Grandmother' (major modification bullet resistance, endurance and resistance to bleeding) \n Major modification "Grandmother Beads" put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 3 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n +3 bullet resistance \n +150 health \n +7 radiation \n -380 bleeding \n Probability successful transmutation: 72% \n Probability extinction: 12% \n chance of rejection: 16%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_burer_grandmother_glassbeards_text" >
    <text>'Beads Ladies Burer' (hyper modification bullet resistance, of health and resistance to bleeding) \n Major modification "Beads Great-Grandmother" put into in anomaly "Whirligig"". \n Time this transmutation takes is 10 minutes of Zone time. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n +20 bullet resistance \n -450 bleeding \n +200 health \n +10 radiation \n Probability successful transmutation: 85% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 5%. </text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_giant_small_brother_text" >
    <text>'Younger Brother of the Giant' (absolute bullet resistance, stability to famine, resistance to breach, to burn, to chemical burn and radiation) \n Hyper modification "Diamond Gingerbread Man" put in anomaly "Burner". \n Time this transmutation takes is 3 Zone hours. Received absolute has following characteristics: \n +12 breach \n +10 bullet resistance \n -15 radiation \n +25 burn \n -45 famine \n +20 chemical burn \n Probability successful transmutation: 59% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 21%.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_shkura_text" >
    <text>'Skin' (modification bullet resistance and resistance to chemical burn) \n Artifact "Film" put in anomaly "Springboard". \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +35 chemical burn \n +7 bullet resistance \n +3 radiation \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 5%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_cheshya_text" >
    <text>'Scales' (major modification health, bullet resistance and resistance to chemical burn) \n Modification "Skin" put in anomaly "Whirligig"". \n Time this transmutation takes is 5 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n +42 chemical burn \n +7 bullet resistance \n +5 radiation \n +150 health \n +100 bleeding \n Probability successful transmutation: 80% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 10%.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_pancir_text" >
    <text>'Shell' (hyper modification health, bullet resistance, resistance to chemical burn and bleeding) \n Major modification "Scales" put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 2 Zone hours. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n +45 chemical burn \n +10 bullet resistance \n +50 health \n +2 radiation \n -130 bleeding \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 10%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_simbion_text" >
    <text>'Simbion' (modification psi-protection) \n Unique modification "Simbion" is gained by means of common transmutation in the anomalies of 'Fruit Punch' right away four artifacts: "Jellyfish", "Drop", 'Blood of Stone" and "Bur". \n Time this transmutation takes is 4 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +50 blocks telepathy \n +50 bleeding \n -25 breach \n -20 endurance \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 10%.
</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_puding_text" >
    <text>'Pudding' (absolute endurance, resistance to burn and electroshock) \n 'MoonLight Dummy' put in anomaly 'Fruit Punch' Time this transmutation takes is 12 Zone hours. Received absolute has following characteristics: \n +45 burn \n -20 endurance \n +50 electroshock \n +2 radiation \n Probability successful transmutation: 80% \n Probability extinction: 10% \n chance of rejection: 10%.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_fire_text" >
    <text>'Fire Dummy' (modification endurance and resistance to burn) \n Artifact "Dummy" put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 3 Zone hours. Received modification has following characteristics: \n +30 burn \n +36 endurance \n -10 electroshock \n Probability successful transmutation: 70% \n Probability extinction: 25% \n chance of rejection: 5%.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_bright_text" >
    <text>'Bright Dummy' (major modification endurance and resistance to burn) \n Modification "Fire Dummy" put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 6 Zone hours. Received major modification has following characteristics: \n +30 burn \n +73 endurance \n -15 electroshock \n Probability successful transmutation: 59% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 21%.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_amk_recipt_dummy_moon_text" >
    <text>'Moonlight Dummy' (hyper modification endurance and resistance to burn) \n Major modification "Bright Dummy" put in anomaly 'Electra'. \n Time this transmutation takes is 8 Zone hours. Received hyper modification has following characteristics: \n +30 burn \n +109 endurance \n -20 electroshock \n Probability successful transmutation: 50% \n Probability extinction: 35% \n chance of rejection: 15%.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_amk_recipt_controller_skalp_text" >
    <text>'Scalp Controller' (absolute psi-protection, of health, stability to famine, resistance to chemical burn and radiation) \n Hyper modification "Armor" put in anomaly "Burner". \n Time this transmutation takes is 6 Zone hours. Received absolute has following characteristics: \n +30 chemical burn \n +10 bullet resistance \n -20 famine \n +100 health \n +75 blocks telepathy \n Probability successful transmutation: 65% \n Probability extinction: 20% \n chance of rejection: 15%.
</text>
</string>

 <string id="blowout_not_sleep">
    <text>Blowout - no time to sleep!</text>
</string>
 <string id="not_need_sleep">
    <text>You don't need to sleep.</text>
</string>
 <string id="not_need_sleep_nrg">
    <text>You can't sleep because of energy drink.</text>
</string>
 <string id="not_need_sleep_enemy">
    <text>Can't sleep, enemies are nearby.</text>
</string>
 <string id="trans_finished_title">
    <text>The result of Artifact transmutation - </text>
</string>
 <string id="trans_finished_msg">
    <text>The result of Artifact transmutation - </text>
</string>
 <string id="stalker_died">
    <text>Stalker Died:</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_too_much_die">
    <text>Phew... too much to drink. Now I'm gonna die!</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_too_much">
    <text>I'm drunk... so much...</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_todo_alcoholic">
    <text>Well, I'm an alcoholic.</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_need_drink">
    <text>I need a drink...</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_need_drink_big">
    <text>Oh... I feel so bad! I need some alcohol!</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_coded">
    <text>At last, I get rid of alcoholism.</text>
</string>
 <string id="alc_no_more_need">
    <text>I don't need so much alcohol now... that's better. I need to survive about a week to get rid of alcoholism.</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_warn_trans">
    <text>WARNING!!! Buffer! Data in the transmutations not saved! Wait for the transmutation to end and try to save again.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_warn_trans_critical">
    <text>WARNING!!! Buffer! Initiated transmutation will not be completed. It is recommended to load the previous save.</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_warn_attention">
    <text>Attention! Number of stored data will soon exceed the allowable limit! Complete all outstanding jobs. Wait until all the transmutations are finished. Do not take a new job. Do not start a new transmutation.</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_sleep_title">
    <text>Sleep</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_sleep_one_hour">
    <text>Sleep 3 hours</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_sleep_three_hours">
    <text>Sleep 5 hours</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_sleep_five_hours">
    <text>Sleep 8 hours</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_sleep_until_full_health">
    <text>Sleep until healed</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_dots_title">
    <text>Enter tag</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_dots_done">
    <text>Send</text>
</string>

 <string id="amk_welcome_title">
    <text>I greet you stalker!</text>
</string>
 <string id="amk_welcome_msg">
    <text>%c[255,255,0,0]Welcome to Secret Paths with Autumn Aurora 2. Good hunting, Stalker...</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_no_weapon_in_slot_1">
    <text>No weapon in the primary slot.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_no_weapon_in_slot_2">
    <text>No weapon in the secondary slot.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_no_weapon_in_slot_6">
    <text>No armor worn.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_not_need_1">
    <text>Weapon in the primary slot does not need to be repaired.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_not_need_2">
    <text>Weapon in the secondary slot does not need to be repaired.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_not_need_6">
    <text>Armor you are wearing does not need to be repaired.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_watched_weapon_6">
    <text>Repairing of suit will take a while.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_watched_weapon_1">
    <text>Downtime for purging and repairing the weapon for a while is required.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_watched_weapon_2">
    <text>Downtime for purging and repairing the weapon for a while is required.</text>
</string>

<string id="rep_need_big">
    <text>Serious repair is necessary . You should go to the nearest technician.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="st_time_repbox">
    <text>Time to repair.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_mod_complete_w">
    <text>The modification of the suit is completed. Carrying capacity is increased to 250 kg.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_mod_complete_h">
    <text>The modification of the suit it is completed. The recovery rate of strength and health are increased 10%.</text>
</string>

<string id="nano_mod_warning">
    <text>In your inventory five or more 'Cobblestones' and 'Crystal Souls Bengal' simultaneously. Nanosuit is trying to assimilate the artifacts. Put temporarily out of inventory 'Soul' or 'Cobblestones' depending on the desired outcome modification.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
