<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>	
	<string id="flame_reload_1">
		<text>You said that you can recharge this flamethrower. Will you do that? I think it needs it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_2">
		<text>Yeah, no problem man, you got any fuel? Jeez, don't say that I gotta look for it myself! Listen, this ain't a big deal for me, really, but it's gonna cost 30,000 rubles. And only after a drink, and I mean a REAL drink, got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_3">
        <text>More vodka? You're going to drink the Zone dry. Look for it without me. And just so you know 30,000 rubles isn't even what the flamethrower is worth. Hell with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_4">
		<text>That Vodka will be the death of you. Here's the fuel, and a bottle of the Zones finest. Just make it quick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_5">
		<text>Hey I'm not a machine! Gimmie half an hour.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_6">
        <text>Alright just remember I need it as soon as possible.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_7">
		<text>I don't have any fuel. Just take 30,000 rubles and some Vodka. But you must work first, drink later, understood?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_8">
		<text>Well thanks. Don't worry, a day will be enough for this job.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_9">
		<text>What?! A whole day? You are supposedly a specialist? Maybe in drinking. lol. Later dude.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_10">
        <text>Hows the refueling going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_11">
		<text>Exellent! As all parts of my life... take it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_12">
		<text>All right thank you! Good man!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_13">
		<text>Hey don't be so hastey. It is not that simple. Come back some other time!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="flame_reload_14">
		<text>Alright, but hurry up man!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>