<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="ars-ak47">
    <text>AK-47</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak47_camo1">
    <text>AK-47 Camouflaged</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak47_m1">
    <text>AK-47 Mini-Dragoons</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks47">
    <text>AKS-47</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak74">
    <text>AK-74</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks74">
    <text>AKS-74</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks74_m1">
    <text>AKS-74 Cobra</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks74_m1_camo1">
    <text>AKS-74 Cobra (Camouflaged)</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak74m">
    <text>AK-74M</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak101">
    <text>AK-101</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak102">
    <text>AK-102</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak103">
    <text>AK-103</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak104">
    <text>AK-104</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak105">
    <text>AK-105</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak107">
    <text>AK-107</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak108">
    <text>AK-108</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-akm">
    <text>AKM</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-akms">
    <text>AKMS</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks74u">
    <text>AKS-74U</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aks74u_m1_camo1">
    <text>AKS-74U Assault</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-an94">
    <text>AN-94 Abakan</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ak5">
    <text>Bofors AK5</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aug_a1">
    <text>Steyr AUG A1 (AUG-77)</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aug_a2">
    <text>Steyr AUG A2</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-famas_f1">
    <text>FAMAS F1</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-famas_g2">
    <text>FAMAS G2</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-famas_p3">
    <text>FAMAS Prototype-3</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-fnc">
    <text>FN FNC</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-g36">
    <text>HK G36</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-g36c">
    <text>HK G36C (Compact\Commando)</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-g36e">
    <text>HK G36E (Export)</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-g36k">
    <text>HK G36K (Kurz)</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-galil_ar">
    <text>IMI Galil AR</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-galil_arm">
    <text>IMI Galil ARM</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-galil_mar">
    <text>IMI Galil MAR</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-hk416">
    <text>HK 416</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-lr300ml">
    <text>Z-M LR300 ML</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m4a1">
    <text>Colt M4A1</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m16a1">
    <text>Colt M16A1</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m16a2">
    <text>Colt M16A2</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m16a3">
    <text>Colt M16A3</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m16a4">
    <text>Colt M16A4</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-vz58">
    <text>CZ SA vz.58</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-rk95">
    <text>Valmet RK.95</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-rk95_camo1">
    <text>Valmet RK.95 Camouflage</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sg550">
    <text>SIG SG550</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sg551">
    <text>SIG SG551</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sg552">
    <text>SIG SG552 Commando</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-xm8">
    <text>HK XM8</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-xm177e2">
    <text>Colt XM177E2</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-mg36">
    <text>HK MG36</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-rpk74">
    <text>RPK-74</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-xm8_para">
    <text>HK XM8 Para-military</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aps">
    <text>APS</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-beretta92">
    <text>Beretta 92</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-cz52">
    <text>CZ-52</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-deagle">
    <text>Desert Eagle .50AE</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-fort12">
    <text>Fort 12</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-glock18c_sk1">
    <text>Glock 18C</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-glock18c_sk2">
    <text>Glock 18C Expert</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-gsh18">
    <text>GSH 18</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m1911a1">
    <text>Colt M1911A1</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-m1935hp_mk3">
    <text>FN Browning M1935 high powered MKIII</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-mp444-9x18">
    <text>MP-444 Bagheera 9x18</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-mp444-9x19">
    <text>MP-444 Bagheera 9x19</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-oc33">
    <text>OC 33 Pernach</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-p38">
    <text>Walther P38</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-p99">
    <text>Walther P99</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-p220">
    <text>SIG-SAUER P220</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-pb">
    <text>PB</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-pm">
    <text>PM</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-tt33">
    <text>TT-33</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-usp45c">
    <text>HK USP-45 compact</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sayga12k">
    <text>Saiga 12K</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ppd40">
    <text>PPD-40</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-ppsh41">
    <text>PPSH-41</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sr25_mk11_mod0">
    <text>SR25 mk.11 mod.0</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-hk417">
    <text>HK 417 Sniper</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-galatz">
    <text>IMI GALATZ</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-svd">
    <text>SVD</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-acog">
    <text>Scope ACOG</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-aug_a1_scope">
    <text>Scope AUG-77</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-g36_scope">
    <text>Scope G36</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-scope1">
    <text>Scope M16</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_9_p">
    <text>Silencer M9-P</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_762_p">
    <text>Silencer M7.62-P</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_9_pb">
    <text>Silencer 6P9</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_545_ar">
    <text>Silencer M5.45-A</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_556_ar">
    <text>Silencer M5.56-A</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_762_ar">
    <text>Silencer M7.62-A</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_762_pms">
    <text>Silencer M7.62-PMS</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-sil_1143_p">
    <text>Silencer M11.43-P</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-50_ae">
    <text>.50 AE</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p">
    <text>7.62x25mm P</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps">
    <text>7.62x25mm PS</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-7.62x39_fmj">
    <text>7.62x39mm FMJ</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-7.62x39_ap">
    <text>7.62x39mm AP</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-7.62x51_fmj">
    <text>7.62x51mm NATO</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-7.62x51_ap">
    <text>7.62x51mm NATO AP</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47">
    <text>The Kalashnikov automatic rifle of model 1947, using the cartridge of 7.62x39mm of Automatic weapon - classicist, known in the entire world. It is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation. Can be met both in the stalkers recently arrived before the Zone and in veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47_camo1">
    <text>AK-47, down the receiver group of applied the camouflage figure.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak47_m1">
    <text>Mini-Dragoons - creation of Rumanian armourers, created on the base AK-47. Is the automatic weapon, made in the form of sniper rifle.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks47">
    <text>The Kalashnikov automatic rifle of the collapsible of model 1947, using the cartridge of 7.62x39mm of Automatic weapon - a classic, is known in the entire world. It is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation, especially because of its compactness before the folded configuration. It is possible to meet in the stalkers recently arrived before the zone, so in the veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak74">
    <text>The Kalashnikov automatic rifle of model 1974, using the cartridge of 5.45x39mm is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation. It is possible to meet in the stalkers recently arrived before the zone, so in the veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74">
    <text>The Kalashnikov automatic rifle of the collapsible of model 1974, using the cartridge of 5.45x39mm is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation. It is possible to meet in the stalkers recently arrived before the zone, so in the veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74_m1">
    <text>Modification of Kalashnikov AKS-74 with the established collimating sight 'Cobra EKP-8-02</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74_m1_camo1">
    <text>Modification of Kalashnikov AKS-74 with the established collimating sight 'Cobra EKP-8-02', and carried out with the camouflaging camouflage plotting.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak74m">
    <text>The later version of Kalashnikov automatic rifle AK-74, accepted for the armament of Russian army at the beginning of the 1990s. From earlier version it differs regarding collapsible to the side plastic butt and plank for fastening of sight mechanisms by the left side of receiver group. A good automatic weapon for the night sorties in the Zone tons to is carried out in the black colour.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak101">
    <text>This automatic weapon, hundredth series of Kalashnikov automatic rifles, is intended first of all for the export. It is modification AK-74M under the NATO cartridge of 5.56x45.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak102">
    <text>'Shortened' AK-101. Is light, convenient, reliable - very good selection.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak103">
    <text>This automatic weapon, hundredth series of Kalashnikov automatic rifles, is intended first of all for the export. It is modification AK-74M under the Soviet cartridge of 7.62x39.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak104">
    <text>'Shortened' AK-103. Is light, convenient, reliable - very good selection.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak105">
    <text>'Shortened' AK-74M. Is light, convenient, reliable - very good selection.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak107">
    <text>Automatic weapon, made according to the scheme, which balances recoil momentum. High rate of fire, precision and an accuracy of automatic firing. It is designed under the domestic cartridge of 5.45x39.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak108">
    <text>Automatic weapon, made according to the scheme, which balances recoil momentum. High rate of fire, precision and an accuracy of automatic firing. It is designed under the NATO cartridge of 5.56x45.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_akm">
    <text>Kalashnikov automatic rifle modernised, under the cartridge of 7.62x39mm is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation. It is possible to meet in the stalkers recently arrived before the zone, so in the veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_akms">
    <text>Kalashnikov automatic rifle modernised, by collapsible, under the cartridge of 7.62x39mm is valued in the Zone at the point of the reliability even due to the most adverse conditions and simultaneously at the point of simplicity before the utilisation. It is possible to meet in the stalkers recently arrived before the zone, so in the veterans.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74u">
    <text>The shortened Kalashnikov automatic rifle of model 1974, under the cartridge of 5.45x39mm before the mass and to dimensions is close down the submachine guns; however, the operating principle of the mechanism of this weapon and the cartridge used before it make for the sake of its representative of the class of automatic weapon. The advantages include low dimensions, which is extremely useful with conducting of combat due to the urban conditions, and sufficiently high punching ability of cartridge. Central failures - low sighting range and tendency down to the rapid superheating with the fire in bursts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74u_m1_camo1">
    <text>Modification AKS-74U. Are established collimating sight 'Cobra EKP-8-02', suffered the camouflage figure. Longer gun made it possible to establish the barrel-attached grenade launcher OF GP-25 'Bonfire'.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_an94">
    <text>Automatic weapon Nikonov of model 1994. It is carried out according to scheme with the storage of recoil momentum. Very exact weapon with the firing before the cutoff conditions of two cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ak5">
    <text>This rifle is in service of the army of Sweden. It is created on the base of the Belgian rifle FNC.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a1">
    <text>Austrian automatic rifle, with the tight optical sight of multiplicity 1.5x and carried out according to scheme "Bullpup".</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a2">
    <text>Austrian automatic rifle, with the integrated plank picatinny and carried out according to scheme "Bullpup".</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_f1">
    <text>First model from a series of the automatic weapon FAMAS of French development. High rate of fire and scheme "Bullpup" made it sufficiently popular among the lovers of foreign weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_g2">
    <text>Modification of the automatic weapon FAMAS F1 with the standard NATO magazine from M16 down 30 cartridges. High rate of fire and scheme "Bullpup" they made its sufficiently popular model of small arms.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_famas_p3">
    <text>Prototype of new automatic weapon from a series FAMAS. Very rare weapon in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_fnc">
    <text>Belgian rifle, before 1980- e years supplied at the point of the export for the armament of different police formings, including in the USA. According to responses, FNC is reliable and convenient weapon with good combat characteristicss. About the fundamental characteristicss the rifle FNC is not inferior down other rifles, created at the same time; however, for the moment of its appearance on the market the large part of the bay was already occupied for the sake of other models, by which is explained its not widest dissemination.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_g36">
    <text>The assault rifle g36 was developed by German firm Heckler and Koch (Heckler of und koch gmbH) since the beginning of the 1990s of years under the intra-firm designation HK 50. In 1995 G36 was accepted for the armament of Bundeswehr (army of the FRG), and beside 1999 - for the armament of the armed forces of Spain. It is one of the best models of Automatic weapon - an ergonomic, exact and reliable.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_g36c">
    <text>Modification of the German assault rifle G36, with the universal guiding plank picatinny and shorter.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_g36e">
    <text>Export version of the German assault rifle G36, without the built-in collimating sight.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_g36k">
    <text>Modification of the German assault rifle G36, with the universal guiding plank picatinny and the shorter.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_ar">
    <text>The izrailky automatic weapon, after model to creation of which was used famous Kalashnikov automatic rifle. Reliable and unpretentious weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_arm">
    <text>The izrailky automatic weapon, after model to creation of which was used famous Kalashnikov automatic rifle. It is carried out before the version of light weapon gun with the collapsible bipods. Reliable and unpretentious weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_galil_mar">
    <text>Shortened version of the Israeli automatic weapon IMI Galil AR.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_hk416">
    <text>The assault rifle (automatic weapon) HK-416 is outwardly similar down the automatic weapon of a series AR15\M16\M4, but it is constructed on the basis of venting automation with the short course of the gas piston located above the gun, borrowed based on the German rifle g36. Blyagodarya at the point of this was possible to achieve greater reliability and failure-free performance of model.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_lr300ml">
    <text>Further development of the assault rifle AR15\M16. It is characterised by fair tactical-technical characteristicss.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m4a1">
    <text>This snap hook was came out in 1996 to order the forces of special operations on the basis of rifle M16A3, which was being differed regarding return to the full-automatic fire instead of the rate of fire with the cutoff on three shots.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a1">
    <text>At the beginning 1970's of years rifle M16 was the full-valued combat weapon, which has a whole series of the essential advantages (well and deficiencies in it also they were, it goes without saying,). In comparison with the principal enemy M16 before the world stage - by the Kalashnikov automatic rifle (AKM), M16 had high precision and an accuracy of the firing the single shots, it was more comfortable and convenient before the address. Based on the other side, M16 it required much more careful departure, more good-quality ammunition.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a2">
    <text>Another modification of rifle M16A1. Has burst mode using three cartridges, without full-automatic fire, and also larger magazines holding 30 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a3">
    <text>Another modification of rifle M16A1. Has burst mode using three cartridges, without full-automatic fire, and also larger magazines holding 30 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a4">
    <text>Another modification of rifle M16A1. Has burst mode using three cartridges, without full-automatic fire, and also larger magazines holding 30 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_vz58">
    <text>This weapon, is outwardly more similar down ateate of Kalashnikov, it is its own development of Czech armourers. It possesses higher, in comparison with AK, rate of fire.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_rk95">
    <text>This model is the development of the Finnish automatic weapon Valmet RK62, which is in turn licence copy AK-47, with the ergonomic changes.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_rk95_camo1">
    <text>This model is the development of the Finnish automatic weapon Valmet RK62, which is in turn licence copy AK-47, with the ergonomic changes. 'Camouflage' version.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sg550">
    <text>Swiss rifle, came out at the beginning 1980. Convenient, reliable and exact weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sg551">
    <text>The shorter version of the Swiss rifle SIG SG550.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sg552">
    <text>Shortened version of the automatic weapon SIG SG550.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_xm8">
    <text>Rifle, once only it was not become the replacement OF M16A2 before the American army. Very rare model of small arms, which possesses good combat characteristicss.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_xm177e2">
    <text>Snap hook, accepted for the armament of the number of the subunits of the U.S. Army as replacement to compact automatic weapon CAR-15.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_mg36">
    <text>The light weapon gun, created on the basis of the German assault rifle G36. Feed drums of 100 cartridges are used.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_rpk74">
    <text>The light weapon gun klashnikova of model 1974 with the circular magazine down 75 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_xm8_para">
    <text>The version of automatic weapon XM8 with the feed drum and the weighted gun, which converts this weapon beside the full-valued light weapon gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aps">
    <text>Pistol APS was came out at the end 1940 - beginning of 1950s of years by designer Ya Stechkin and it was accepted for the armament of the Soviet Army in 1951, simultaneously with the pistol of Makarov PM. APS (the automatic pistol Stechkin) was intended as the side arms of the self defence of some categories of soldiers and officers, to which the automatic weapon or snap hook were not assumed about the manual.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_beretta92">
    <text>Pistol of Italian development, accepted for the armament of the U.S. Army. As a whole the pistols of a series Beretta 92V deserved the reputation of sufficiently reliable, although several bulky weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_cz52">
    <text>Pistol, created in 1952 for the armament of the army of Czechoslovakia.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_deagle">
    <text>Very ambiguous model of small arms, shown before many films and plays, and obtained vast popularity. The pistol desert eagle uses a very rare for the pistols diagram of automation with the blocking of gun as far as rotary breechblock and the utilisation of energy of the discharged from the gun powder gases for the reloading. Very powerful pistol, with the vast output.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_fort12">
    <text>Pistol of Ukrainian production, accepted for the armament as replacement to the obsolete Soviet pistol of Makarov. As the base ammunition for this pistol was accepted already the available available and well familiar cartridge of 9x18PM; however, new pistol had to ensure in comparison with the PM the high precision of firing and the firepower (due to the great capacity of magazine). As the prototype for the creation of its pistol was selected Czech pistol CZ-83, whereas in the Czech Republic there was stocked up and necessary equipment for the production of pistols.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_glock18c_sk1">
    <text>The pistol glock 18 (18- from the magazine capacity down 18 cartridges) was came out by Austrian firm Glock for the Austrian army, in this case this was the first experiment of the creation of pistols for this firm. Nevertheless, pistol came out extremely successful, reliable and convenient, and it was accepted for the armament before the Austrian army. This version has a switch of the regime of firing with the cutoff beside three cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_glock18c_sk2">
    <text>The pistol glock 18 (18 - from the magazine capacity down 18 cartridges) was came out by Austrian firm Glock for the Austrian army, in this case this was the first experiment of the creation of pistols for this firm. Nevertheless, pistol came out extremely successful, reliable and convenient, and it was accepted for the armament before the Austrian army. This version of osnschen by the magazine of the increased capacity down 31 cartridges and by the switch of the regime of full-automatic firing.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_gsh18">
    <text>Pistol GSH-18 was came out at the end 1990's of years before Tula KB of instrument manufacture under the leadership of the well-known designers of armament (mainly - aircraft cannons) was mud Shipunova. Number 18 before the name indicates magazine capacity. To the advantages GS-18 can be attributed very light for its class weight, the great capacity of magazine, the low disposition of gun relative to hand Strelok, a good accuracy of firing.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m1911a1">
    <text>Legendary 'Colt', who, until now is armed with a number of the countries. It must be noted, that also is earlier, and now, the pistols of the given construction are produced not only by firm Colt. Both before the initial Brauningovskom version and down different degree modified, them are released ten, if not hundreds of firms throughout the world.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_m1935hp_mk3">
    <text>Up-to-date modification of the Belgian pistol FN browning HP (High power 1935), which was being released since 1935.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_mp444-9x18">
    <text>The pistol of MR-444 is intended for the armament of the army and police. The work of the automation of pistol is based beyond the principle of the short course of gun. Equipped with by the gun, designed under the domestic cartridge of 9x18mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_mp444-9x19">
    <text>The pistol of MR-444 is intended for the armament of the army and police. The work of the automation of pistol is based beyond the principle of the short course of gun. Equipped with by the gun, designed under the cartridge of 9x19.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_oc33">
    <text>Pistol OC-33 was came out before the middle of 1990s of years in TsKIB GSS (central KB of sport and hunting weapon) under IY Stechkin 's leadership for replacing the obsolete and long ago removed from production pistol APS of the construction of the same author. Pistol OC-33 - automatic weapon, constructed on the basis of automation with the blowback bolt. For decreasing the percept of output the gun of pistol is carried out mobile. At the end the cycle of recoil breechblock picks up massive gun, and the preliminary braking of breechblock before its collision with the frame before the end posterior position occurs because of its inertia.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_p38">
    <text>The pistol R38 was came out even before the second-half of the Thirties specially as army pistol. Its first user became Sweden, which stocked up in 1938 a small quantity of pistols walther NP (Heeres pistole, ie, army pistol), in 1940 this pistol under the official designation pistol 38 was accepted for the armament of Wehrmacht and widely it was used in the course of the Second World War. Walther R38 - semiautomatic pistol with self-cocking hammer trigger (double action). The automation of pistol is constructed according to scheme with the utilisation of recoil energy with the short course of gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_p99">
    <text>The development of the pistol R.99 firm Carl Walther sportwaffen gmbH began in 1994. Basic task it was create up-to-date pistol for the police and self defences, capable of achieving greater commercial success, than its precursor - Walter R.88, whom, disregarding besides the splendid characteristicss, proved to be is too expensive. The creation P99 was completed by 1996, and result proved to be is completely successful. It has excellent ergonomics, it is completely reliable, and it is released before several versions, which are characterised by the characteristics of work USM.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_p220">
    <text>The development of new army pistol for the Swiss army down the replacement to very to the good-quality, but also very expensive and becoming obsolete pistol SIG p210 was initiated at the beginning of 1970s of years. According to the demands of army, new pistol had to possess traditional for the Swiss weapon high reliability and precision of firing, small mass, self-cocking fast and well-lowering mechanism, and, which is important, by the moderate price. Well-known Swiss company SIG came out this pistol, and before the middle of 1970 it was accepted for the armament under the designation pistol 75. The pistol P220 uses for the reloading recoil energy with the short course of gun. The blocking of gun is accomplished according to the modified Brauningovskoy scheme of blocking, by one massive salient beyond the breech of the gun at the point of the port for the blowout of cases.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_pb">
    <text>Pistol noiseless PB (index of 6P9) was came out on the base of the pistol of Makarov PM for the armament of army reconnaissance parties and also personnel the KGB of the USSR, it was accepted for the armament in 1967. Pistol uses an integral Silencer, moreover in contrast to the majority of similar systems the sound damper of shot is made dismountable of two units. This decision makes it possible to carry and to store pistol with the taken forward section of the Silencer (nozzle), and before the application to rapidly establish nozzle beyond the weapon. In this case the pistol retains the possibility of safe for the Strelok of delivery of fire with the taken nozzle, which is important before the critical situations.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_pm">
    <text>The pistol of Makarov's system was created in response to the demand of the Soviet Army to work out new pistol for the self defence of officers, pain compact and safe before the address, than Tokarev pistol TT, but, in this case, that possesses the great stopping activity of bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_tt33">
    <text>Pistol TT (Tula, Tokarev), as it follows from its name, was came out at the Tula arms factory by legendary Russian armourer by Fedor Tokarev and it was accepted for the armament by RKKA (Workers' and Peasants' Red Army) in 1933. For its time the pistol TT presented the sufficiently perfected weapon, powerful and reliable, simple before the care and the repair. Its central failures were the lowered safety before the address because of the absence of full-valued protecting devices, a comparatively low stopping activity of the light of 7.62mm of bullet, and not too convenient a form of handle.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_usp45c">
    <text>Compact version of the pistol USP-45 of German development. However, as a whole the pistols of a series USP are characterised by the highest reliability and life, grow prettier by the precision of firing. From the insignificant deficiencies it is possible to note the considerable dimensions of weapon, even before the compact version, is sufficiently the highly located centre of gravity and the massive breechblock, which somewhat impedes the concealed carrying.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sayga12k">
    <text>Smoothbore guns saiga inherited overall design and construction of automatic weapon of Kalashnikov, with the venting mechanism and the blocking by the turning of breechblock. Naturally, lock group and receiver group were redesigned taking into account the utilisation of hunting cartridges, fast and well-lowering mechanism was deprived of automatic release, before the venting mechanism the gas regulator for the provision of a reliable firing appeared. Before the version saiga of 12K gun has plastic shank, and also pistol handle and collapsible to the left plastic butt from the automatic weapon AK-74M. Authorised sight mechanisms include sighting plank on the gaseous tube above the gun. The feed by cartridges is accomplished from the special removable circular magazines of different capacity. Safety device is analogous in design down the same in Kalashnikov automatic rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ppd40">
    <text>Degtarev submachine gun was came out before the first half of 1930's of years and accepted for the armament in 1935 under the designation MP-34. It was the typical system of the first generation, with the wooden of lies and the wide utilisation of weapon metal working before the production. Unfortunately, the then command of RKKA did not understand the role of submachine guns, but therefore MP-34, as its later modification MP-34/38, were released before small quantities and were used in essence before the frontier units nk VD. Before greatest domestic, in 1940, PPD was improved; however, its construction proved to be hardly suitable for the mass production of military time. and already toward the end 1941 MP-40 was replaced in the arsenal of RKKA for the sake of newer, cheaper and more effective submachine gun Shpagina PPSH-41. MP-40 is constructed on the basis of automation with the blowback bolt. Fire is conducted based on the discovered breechblock.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_ppsh41">
    <text>PPSH-41 (submachine gun of the construction Shpagina) was created in 1941 for replacing expensive before the production of submachine gun Degtarev MP-40. In the same year it is accepted for the armament by RKKA. PPSH-41 was the simple and cheap before the production weapon of military time, and it was released before considerable quantities - in all during the years of war were released the order of 5 or 6 million pieces PPSH-41. Soon after war PPSH-41 it was taken based on the armament of the Soviet Army; however, it widely was supplied at the point of the export beside the pro-Soviet disposed developing countries, and in Africa of it was possible to see even before 1980's years. The advantages PPSh include high lethal range, simplicity and cheapness. From the deficiencies is worth noting considerable mass and dimensions, high rate of fire, and also tendency down to the accidental discharges with the drop beyond the rigid surface.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sr25_mk11_mod0">
    <text>Rifle SR-25 was came out by Eugene Stoner (one of the creators of the rifle argon -15/m16) at the beginning of the 1990s of the years, when he cooperated with the American company knight's armaments cobalt. As the basis of rifle SR-25 (Stoner rifle of model 1925) lay the construction of rifle AR-15, modified under the cartridge of 7.62x51 of NATO. Basic purpose of the rifles MK11 mod.0 and XM110 - aimed fire on the live enemy target against the distances to 800 metres. From a tactical point of view these rifles are the analogs of the sniper rifle Dragunov SVD; however, the higher precision of firing (including due to the presence of more good-quality cartridges) and great tactical flexibility differs them.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_hk417">
    <text>The automatic rifle HK-417 calibres of 7.62mm of NATO is came out on the base of the automatic rifle Heckler-Koch HK 416 calibres of 5.56mm of NATO. The development of rifle nk -417 was initiated in 2005 on the basis of experience, obtained by the troops of international coalition before Afghanistan and Iraq, where under certain conditions the weapon of the calibre of 5.56mm showed insufficient lethal range and insufficient breakdown and stopping activity of small-gauge bullets. Send the rifles of a series nk -417 beside the series production in 2007 or 2008, and they are proposed for the armament of army and police forces. Rifle HK 417 has the modular construction, to a considerable extent repetitive the construction of American rifle M16, with one important difference - German rifle HK 417 has the changed system of venting automation, which uses a common gas piston with the short working course. There is the number of other differences; however, all basic controls and method of disassembly and assembly of weapon are inherited from M16. It is equipped for the sake of the optical sight of multiplicity 6x.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_galatz">
    <text>This sniper rifle (before the army of the defence of Israel - Tsahal it is known by the name TO GALATZ) before the essence, is the alteration of the automatic weapon IMI galil under the more powerful cartridge of 7.62mm NATO (.308win). From the point of view of tactics, GALATZ is nearer to such models "of the weapon of support" as Russian of SVD or German G3-SG1, in contrast to "purely sniper" of models, the type of American M24 either M40 or German Mauser 66 and 86, also used as far as the army of the defence of Israel.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_svd">
    <text>In 1958 Grau (principal Rocket-artillery administration) of general staff of the Soviet Army declared competition for the creation of self-loading sniper rifle for the Soviet Army. Before the competition conquered the collective, headed By Dragunov, and in 1963 SVD (sniper rifle Dragunov) it was accepted for the armament SA. For SVD was specially created 'sniper' cartridge with the bullet with the steel core; however, rifle can use entire nomenclature of the domestic cartridges of 7.62x54R. It is necessary to note that the tactical role, which was devoted and is devoted to rifle SVD before The sovestkie and Russian armies it differs from the traditional role 'of sniper' before the western understanding of this term. Rifle SVD serves for an increase in the effective fire range of the rifle squad as a result of the limitations of authorised automatic weapon, up to the distances beside 600-700 metres. Most common sniper rifle in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_acog">
    <text>the 4th multiple optical sight for the rifles of NATO.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_aug_a1_scope">
    <text>Lens of the optical sight of the rifle Steyr AUG-77.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_g36_scope">
    <text>Lens of the optical sight of the rifle G36.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_scope1">
    <text>Removable optical sight of old model for the rifles M16A1\A2.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_9_p">
    <text>Silencer for the pistols of the calibre of 9mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_p">
    <text>Silencer for the pistols of the calibre of 7.62mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_9_pb">
    <text>Silencer for the pistol PB (6P9).</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_545_ar">
    <text>Silencer for the automatic weapon of the calibre of 5.45mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_556_ar">
    <text>Silencer for automatic weapon and rifles of the calibre of 5.56mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_ar">
    <text>Silencer for automatic weapon and rifles of the calibre of 7.62mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_pms">
    <text>Instrument of low-noise firing for the rifles of the calibre of 7.62mm, in particular, for SVD.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_1143_p">
    <text>Silencer for the pistols of the calibre of 11.43mm (.45).</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_50_ae">
    <text>Pistol cartridge with the bullet of heavy calibre for the pistol desert eagle.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x25-p">
    <text>Soviet pistol cartridge of the calibre of 7.62mm. Simple all-metal bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x25-ps">
    <text>Soviet pistol cartridge of the calibre of 7.62mm. Bullet with the steel core, the improved armour-piercing ability.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x39_fmj">
    <text>Soviet automatic cartridge of the calibre of 7.62mm. Simple all-metal bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x39_ap">
    <text>Soviet automatic cartridge of the calibre of 7.62mm. Bullet with the steel core, the improved armour-piercing ability.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x51_fmj">
    <text>Rifle ammunition of the standard of NATO. Calibre - 7.62mm. Simple all-metal bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_arsenal_7.62x51_ap">
    <text>Rifle ammunition of the standard of NATO. Calibre - 7.62mm. Bullet with the steel core, the improved armour-piercing ability.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
