<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table> 
<string id="mp_autostation">
	<text>Bus Station</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_large">
	<text>A strange place. Silent. The building keeps its secrets. But here it attracks stalkers. This region is very rich with artifacts. Here you can get hold of some good samples, but you can loose your life. You must be quick minded and observant, then maybe good luck will certainly smile at you.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_agroprom_short">
	<text>A strange place. Silent. The building keeps its secrets. </text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_large">
	<text>Bus and trolley park located in the changing room areas. It froze all tractors, buses, trucks. Artifacts have been reported there, but this place is popular among looters who are engage in shooting and robbing newcomers. Shelter can be found in buildings and also some equipment. Beware of enemies on the rooftops!</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_atp_short">
	<text>Bus and trolley park located in the changing room areas. </text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_autostation_large">
	<text>Abandoned bus station building. If you look around it is likely that you will find the remains of equipment and supplies. Besides powerful anomalies there are snipers on the roofs of just about anything. All area are dangerous.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_autostation_short">
	<text>Abandoned bus station building. If you look around it is likely that you will find the remains of equipment and supplies.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_large">
	<text>Mysterious site which has a strange attraction, an experimental pool. It is not known by whom and for what it was built. Artifacts are not found. So the stalkers come here to check out strange machines and devices. Carefully watch the roofs, and remember that the radiation level is very high here.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_bath_short">
	<text>Mysterious site which has a strange attraction, an experimental pool.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_darkvalley_large">
	<text>Long Street and an abandoned institution. That's all the attractions of this dangerous place in Dark Valley. What was taught at the institute is not known, and now you can only learn to survive. And another thing, be very careful of the rooftops.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_darkvalley_short">
	<text>Long Street and an abandoned institution.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_large">
	<text>Grim abandoned factory. How many people perished here is unknown. Variety of anomalies is very much, but this place attracts stalkers like a magnet. And all because of valuable artifacts. Pay attention to the radiation!</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_factory_short">
	<text>Grim abandoned factory.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_firestation_large">
	<text>Fire station where all the forces which were sent to save the Chernobyl nuclear power plant in 1986 resided. Tower, a great battle position with a view of the whole area. The upper floors and basements of houses have been visited by few people. But maybe that's for the better. The factions waring for control of this strategic area have been fighting for a long time.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_firestation_short">
	<text>Fire station where all the forces which were sent to save the Chernobyl nuclear power plant in 1986 resided.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_large">
	<text>This is part of a large landfill. There are mountains of radioactive degris here caused by the explosion in 1986. In addition to the damaged buildings there are skeletons of vehicles and a huge hangar. This part of the Zone is located not far from Cordon, and it has many artifacts. Many stalkers are looking for easy profits there.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_garbage_short">
	<text>This is part of a large landfill.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_limansk_large">
	<text>A small area of the mysterious city of Limansk. Abandoned homes and and buildings. The news of valuable artifacts found here has quickly become known to many stalkers. Ever since the city opened up passageways there is not a minute that goes by without a shooting incident.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_limansk_short">
	<text>A small area of the mysterious city of Limansk. Abandoned homes and and buildings.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_large">
	<text>Abandoned, forgotten by God, a village in the depths of the Zone. Small rusty looking lake filled with skeletons of cars creates a subconscious fear of the surrounding area. Area is traveled by many brave stalkers, but watch out for snipers.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_lost_village_short">
	<text>Abandoned, forgotten by God, a village in the depths of the Zone.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_large">
	<text>Abandoned army base with permanently frozen trucks and armored personnel carriers, destroyed headquarters and barracks. However this neglected area is misleading because the richest deposit of artifacts can be found there, and also many enemy.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_1_short">
	<text>Abandoned army base with permanently frozen trucks and armored personnel carriers, destroyed headquarters and barracks.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_large">
	<text>An old village, a filthy rotten place. And though you managed to get here it's too early to relax. Be ready at any moment for a bullet to the forehead. There is nowhere you can feel safe. May you weapons never fail you!</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_military_2_short">
	<text>An old village, a filthy rotten place.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pool_large">
	<text>This is not a swimming pool, it's a blood bath. There are tiled corridors with echos of gunfire and explosions mixed with cries of dying. Not many people know how to find this place. Only a few have ever gotten out alive.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pool_short">
	<text>This is not a swimming pool, it's a blood bath.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railroad_large">
	<text>A small train station at the 'Rostok' plant. Rusty cars and locomotives are on the moors. A lot of artifacts here lure in desperate stalkers from all over the Zone.</text>
</string> 

<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_railraod_short">
	<text>A small train station at the 'Rostok' plant.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rembasa_large">
	<text>Repair facility near a small village. All equipment that has been there has been pilfered for parts. The area is dangerous for your health. A swampy swamp with reeds and radioactivity. But if you're lucky you can find something really valuable.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rembasa_short">
	<text>Repair facility near a small village.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_large">
	<text>An abandoned factory with piles of rusting metal and damaged concrete walls. In the last century it was a busy place with workers rushing to do their jobs. There were socialist slogans from loudspeakers. Now the plant has fulfilled it's own fate.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_rostok_short">
	<text>An abandoned factory with piles of rusting metal and damaged concrete walls.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_sport_center_large">
	<text>Sports center in Pripyat located near an abandoned school. Types of events there have changed greatly since 1986. Stalkers are still drawn there for artifacts.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_sport_center_short">
	<text>Sports center in Pripyat located near an abandoned school.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_training_camp_large">
	<text>A very strange place. Many laugh at stalkers who allegedly say that it really exists. Gravity anomalies have corrupted the land. The landscape looks ethereal. Three huge towers, remains of Army equipment, things hanging in the air, soil islands.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_training_camp_short">
	<text>A very strange place. Many laugh at stalkers who allegedly say that it really exists.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_large">
	<text>Outskirts of the plant 'Rostok'. A 'Duty' faction hangout. These places are very rich with artifacts. Empty hangars and warehouses always pose a danger. Be extremely careful and do not lose sight of the white tower!</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_workshop_short">
	<text>Outskirts of the plant 'Rostok'.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pripyat_large">
	<text>Few dare to enter the abandoned Pripyat. A former city of nuclear workers for Chernobyl. But here among the dead walls shots rang out. Parts of the city between the cinema 'Prometheus', the marinas and houses along the street, became a place of Kurchatov fierce firefights.</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="ui_map_desc_mp_pripyat_short">
	<text>Few dare to enter the abandoned Pripyat.</text>
</string>
 
</string_table> 
