<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_0">
    <text>The disaster in 1986, was it something to do with 'your' job?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_chernobyl_crush_1">
    <text>No we had nothing to do with it. Our experiments began after that Chernobyl accident.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_death_truck_0">
    <text>What is a 'Death Truck'?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_death_truck_1">
    <text>With this transport we deliver our agents to different parts of the Zone. Agents are introduced into the medium of stalkers and perform tasks for which they were programmed without even knowing it. Unfortunately more than half of the agents die during transport, as the area is very unstable.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_no_0">
    <text>No, I refuse to join you.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_11">
    <text>Hello Strelok. I see you have many questions for me. Ask them and then we will decide what to do with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_osoznanie_start_21">
    <text>The choice is yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_stalker_0">
    <text>What does the tattoo 'S.T.A.L.K.E.R.' mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_stalker_1">
    <text>S.T.A.L.K.E.R. - The name of the program about the conditioning of a person to perform certain tasks. On the approaches to the Zone's center we placed a few Psy units. The largest of them is known to you as a 'Brain-Burner' or 'Scorcher'. Everyone who tries to go to the Zone's center becomes under its control. Then they are conditioned, become our agents, and get a tattoo 'S.T.A.L.K.E.R.', and then sent into the Zone. They influence the course of events and ensure their safety.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_about_me_0">
    <text>What happened to me?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_about_me_1">
    <text>You dropped out of a cog mechanism. During one of the trips into the center of the Zone you were too close to us. Our defense against penetration was considered perfect, but you managed to find a path that we never suspected. Humanity is not yet ready to learn the truth about the reasons for the appearance of the Zone. So we immediately began to encode our agents for your elimination. For some unknown reason the equipment made it fail, and we did not notice that you were among the stalkers who were under our control. As a result you got a job to kill yourself!!</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_0">
    <text>What is the Zone? How did it come to be?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_is_the_zone_1">
    <text>Zone - this is the result of out-of-control experiment with the Noosphere. The information field of the Earth. We were going to connect to the Noosphere to explore the possibility to influence it. However during the experiment there was a breakdown and the energy of the Noosphere wnt into the Earth changing everything around. Thus was formed the anomaly which you call the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_next_0">
    <text>What's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_what_next_1">
    <text>What's next depends on you. The Zone is slowly but steadily growing. Our forces are barely enough to contain the flow of energy of the Noosphere. You can join us, our strength will grow and maybe we can get it under control. You can destroy us. Then the energy will flow freely into the Noosphere Zone, and where it will lead is unknown.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_who_are_you_0">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_who_are_you_1">
    <text>We are the 'C-Consciousness', a group of researchers who have set a goal to change the world. It is known that the Earth now has a particular information field the 'Noosphere'. It is closely associated with all life on the planet and keeps all their mental images. We decided to connect to the Noosphere and make a change to remove all the negativity which has led humanity to make the world not perfect. No human mind has the power to interact with the 'Noosphere', so we pooled our consciousness.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_0">
    <text>Why happened here?</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_why_chernobyl_1">
    <text>The Chernobyl nuclear power plant was the most suitable place for our experiments. Firstly, after the 1986 accident, there remained very few people, so we could work safely. Secondly, the station provided us with the energy required to operate equipment. Thirdly, near the station were powerful antennas that were used in experiments on the effects on people's minds.</text>
</string>
<string id="oso_yes_0">
    <text>I agree to join the 'C-Consciousness'.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
