<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>

  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_0">
  <text>Oh where am I? Oh my head aches... ah, but who are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I'll ask the questions, who are you and how did you get here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I... I do not remember... there was a flash ... then nothing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_3">
    <text>If you want to live you better remember fast. Oh, and if you even think about lying to me I will shoot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't shoot! All I remember is that last evening, my big brother his friends and me came down on a trip, by bus, to look at the 'Dead City'. We were told so many interesting things about the City's mysteries that we were going to solve - we wanted thrills, to play paintball in the ruins and so we took all the necessary equipment. There were ten people with us... In the city centre we were meant to meet a guide- instructor that we'd arranged by phone, but when we entered the gate, suddenly something flashed, it dazzled us and... I can't remember anything else.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_5">
    <text>What fucking excursion? What paintball? Stop lying to me. The zone is long closed - let alone the centre with the lethal anomalies and mutants that live in this burning hell on earth. The last excursion here was 3 years ago.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_6">
    <text>What? I'm telling you the truth! It was only yesterday, on the bus with my brother and with the guys. 2000 kopecks we paid the guide to bring us along this deserted road. But where's everyone else? What's going on, eh?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Eh, you don't look too good. The last time people came here was in the autumn of 2008. I was once a guide here, until the second blowout at the CNPP happened, and then an even worse one; it's all coming back to me... damn it... Is it three years already? Now I can remember - the nightmares...</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Well then, what year is it now?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Today is October 5, 2011... Fine! I do not know why, but I believe your delusions. Maybe the zone is fucking with you - playing an "evil joke". If so, that means you arrived exactly at the same time as the blowout itself, and for some reason the zone is now sorry... Like me then... Only I don't know why... It is better for you to forget everything that you mentioned to me and don't speak about it to anyone - this is the zone, and any miracles here are better not spoken of. Now let's go; you come with me, you should get your head back into shape, it is dangerous to stay here for too long.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Where are we going? And who are you?</text>
  </string>	
      <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_11">
    <text>I am Forester - a recluse... We'll go to my cottage in the forest, it's not far. It is necessary to consider what has happened here. I have the sensation of some strange deja vu. Your questions satisfied then? Well, are you ready to go? Only, do not lag behind, and don't run ahead, it is better to follow my trail, in order not to walk into something lethal. The main thing is that we get away from this disastrous place. We'll talk more there.</text>
  </string>	
      <string id="lesnik_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, it seems, I don't have a choice... Go on, I will not lag behind.</text>
  </string>
  
        <string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Forester, is this city dangerous?</text>
  </string>
          <string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>First, there are the lethal anomalies. I hope you would have noticed them as we walked. In addition, mutants, pseudo-dogs they are called, are one of the many sinister creatures of the Zone. They are active, especially at night. We are fortunate that today we have not met one of them. Even after emissions there are zombies. Where they come from is unclear, but here it is dangerous.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>I understand. Well, have we arrived yet?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, left of my old gate, there is a transition point to the Forest. You go first, and I will follow you. Do not rush as you get in, just wait for me.</text>
  </string>
       <string id="lesnik_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I'll go then.</text>
  </string>

        <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_0">
    <text>Is this where you live?</text>
  </string>   
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, this is where I pass away the days and nights. I go to the Forest a lot and sometimes I visit the Dead City. I collect various roots and artifacts, and then exchange them for medication and food with the scientists. I live quietly here away from everyone. Well, let's talk about you. It's so strange that I found you in the bus. How did you get there? Some sort of mystery, I guess. I'm at that place once a week. The bus has been there for about three years, since the last explosion at the Chernobyl NPP. Only it has been empty all this time.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I don't understand how it happened. I've told you all I can remember!</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay okay, do not worry. Listen to me now. You seem to say that the last thing you remember is that you came to the Dead City, along with your elder brother and his friends on the bus, right?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, exactly. And I don't know what happened to him and the other guys, and I don't understand what happened to me - and why, what I last remember, was three years ago...</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_5">
    <text>What happened to the others, I do not know, but about your brother, I'll tell you what I do.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_6">
    <text>So why were you silent the whole way? I ask you, do you know anything or not?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_7">
    <text>Do not shout, so much time has passed since that day, and your story is too devilish for what it sounds like. Well, listen. Three years ago as I told you, there was a second explosion at the Chernobyl NPP, and then there was a violent eruption. Almost everyone within range, including those in the City of the Dead, lost their lives. I managed to escape by hiding in the basement of a high-rise building. When I went up two days later, I did not recognize the place where I worked as a guide for the curious onlookers like you. Suddenly everything had changed and the place had become waste-land, I cannot even explain it properly; well, it was as if not 2 days had passed, but twenty or thirty years...</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_8">
    <text>So what happened next?</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_9">
    <text>Well then I realized that I urgently need to get out there, without any special equipment I would not survive as the radiation level was pretty high. I went to the Forest through the south gate, and as I was almost there I saw the bus, the one where I found you this morning, and in it - no one. And then I saw; by the roadside, in the lowlands, a guy that seemed to move. I went up to him, felt his pulse and luckily - he was alive! I had to save him from the radiation, and brought him here to the Forest. The guy was very much like you. I suppose that it was your brother. Later, in this house here in the woods, he told me how he found himself there, where I had found him. His story was the same as yours, so I believe you. He introduced himself as 'Captain'.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, that's right, he was my brother - during our childhood we each had nicknames: he was 'Captain', and I was 'Strelok'. Our juvenile nicknames then developed into the names which our friends began to use. Well, what happened to my brother, and where is he now?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_11">
    <text>He lived with me for about a month, helped around the place, greatly lamented the loss of his friends and brother ... Kept wanting to go in search of them, as brave as he was, he knew that it was not safe to go to the Dead City - it meant certain death. I went with him once and we nearly reached the southern gate, but we heard the howling and screaming of monsters, and he decided not to risk it. After the second blast, the zone changed into the form in which it remains to this day: mutated animals and lethal anomalies, artifacts with unprecedented properties and constant emissions. The Zone changes after each emission with the anomalies moving and growing stronger and stronger. Five people later arrived at my forest lodge; they were called Stalkers, searching in the zone for valuable artifacts to sell. 'Captain' joined them and walked away, hoping to find you and his other friends. I see that it did not work ... He never returned. Then, six months later, I heard from scientists, camped near Lake Yantar, who had come to learn about the Zone and mutants, of a group of brave men who went to the Sarcophagus in search of valuable artifacts and to solve the mystery of the Zone. Among them, was a stalker, called 'Captain'. That's all I can tell you.</text>
  </string>  
       <string id="lesnik_izba_dialog_12">
    <text>Thank you for what you've told me. I hope he is still there. I must find him, well, or at least find out what happened to him during this time. Maybe he still is still looking for me. If you need help in something, tell me, I'll do anything.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_0">
    <text>Forester, why are you so grim?</text>
  </string>   
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, there was a problem while you were absent.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_2">
    <text>What happened?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_3">
    <text>Yesterday, a courier from the ecologists was to arrive bringing medicine and food, and to pick up the different roots and a few artifacts which I scraped together for the scientists in the past week. But a recurrent surprise emission happened yesterday, I thought that he simply would not move out of the camp and come within a day or two. But it turns out, he was on his way when the emission occurred. While you were searching for the Mandrake root, he went on the radio to communicate, and heard it was bad. He knew that he had to find shelter in a cave on the edge of the Forest. While he was looking for shelter, he ran into mutants and barely escaped with his life. He's afraid to leave the cave, having also lost the map of the area. He has asked me to come to him.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, it is necessary to go and rescue him.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="vasiliev_dialog_5">
    <text>I must get the drugs that the scientists have sent, but my health is poor you know. Listen my son, help an old man and find that ecologist. Help him get here with the medicine and food while I lie down here and let the pain ease. The name of the courier is Associate Professor Vasiliev. I've put the coordinates into your PDA. Find the entrance of the cave, it's amongst the high rocks, and watch out for anomalies and mutants. Now take another med kit, some bandages and a couple of boxes of buckshot just in case.</text>
  </string>
        <string id="vasiliev_dialog_6">
    <text>All right, I'll go look for Assistant Professor Vasiliev.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="yantar_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you all right? I didn't expect courage from a scientist! You have a dangerous job here. Have you seen many zombies?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="yantar_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I'm in one piece. We have to go to our bunker, dry off and relax. At the same time you will get acquainted with Professor Sakharov - he's my chief; he will give you the medicine for Forester which I was unable to deliver. For helping me, you will be rewarded. I have Sakharov's word. And when we get to the bunker, find and talk with Dan first, introduce yourself. He's the commander of the protection unit for the scientist's base.</text>
  </string>
       <string id="yantar_dialog_2">
    <text>Well let’s get going to the bunker, even though I'm wet to the skin getting to you through the swamps. Then I can take back a cure for Forester.</text>
  </string>   

   <string id="dan_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good morning! Are you Dan - the commander of the protection unit for the scientist’s base?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Thank you, Stalker, for helping Vasiliev get out of the woods.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Not at all, but I'm not a fighter. The reason I'm here is that I need to pick up a cure from Sakharov for Forester. Vasiliev told me to come to you first. And another question I have: I must find my brother, or at least find out what happened to him. We parted a few years ago under very strange circumstances, but it's a long story ... Have you accidentally met a man who called himself 'Captain' or a name that is similar? We were given these names in childhood; many people were confused, though brother my brother was 2 years older than me.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We all happen to be here for one reason or another ...  I've never met a person like you, nicknamed 'Captain', even though we've been here for more than a year. You'd better ask Sakharov, he has met and known many - he is the chief of local scientists and has been in the zone from the very beginning, and another thing: we need very brave fighters, if join us in the 'Clean Sky' faction, it will benefit science.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I cannot, I have to go back to the Forest, to Forester, I promised to come back, he needs the medication I'm bringing, I'm in his debt - he's saved me and brought me back alive from the Dead City.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_5">
    <text>OK, it's up to you. But if you change your mind, then come back to us.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_6">
    <text>OK, I'll think about it. Can you show me the way back to the Forest?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Only Sakharov can give you those details. When he sends some of his staff to the Forest, he always carefully calculates the safest route to their devices. So go to him, at the same time you will get a reward for helping Vasiliev and you can ask about your brother.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="dan_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, I'm going to see Sakharov.</text>
  </string>

   <string id="sahar_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day, Professor.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="sahar_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes, I expected you. Here is a reward for helping us.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I didn't do it for a reward. I came for medicine for Forester, and I also need some information.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, young man, you should keep the reward for helping us. As for your questions, I will try to answer them. As the drug won’t be ready for a few minutes, we have time to talk a bit.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you, Professor.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_0">
    <text>I have two questions for you Professor.</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_1">
    <text>You ask, and I will listen to you.</text>
  </string> 
       <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for my brother, who must be somewhere in the Zone, we were separated a few years ago, if you can call it that, in the Dead City. And in very strange circumstances.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_3">
    <text>What was your brother’s name? Did he have any distinguishing marks?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_4">
    <text>He always called himself 'Captain'. Forester found him, like me, three years ago in the Dead City, and sheltered him for a while, then my brother left to search of me. Forester never heard from him again. My brother and I were like as two peas in a pod, like twins, though he is two years older than me and a little taller. The only thing - he has a big birthmark on his upper lip, right in the middle.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_5">
    <text>You know, young man, I remember, maybe two and a half years ago I met a stalker named 'Captain'. He and several others with him came to us in the bunker to stock up on science kits and powerful anti-radiation drugs, before the big hike in the centre of the zone. These were the first courageous stalkers who were not afraid to go to the Sarcophagus, in the heart of the Zone to identify its most important secrets. It was said that they did find the Sarcophagus, and made their way into it, but I have no more information about this.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank you, Professor. I've learned something. I will find out the fate of this expedition, and what happened to my brother. And the second question: how do I get back into the Forest? I need to go back to Forester.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_7">
    <text>As you probably already know, in the zone you cannot go the same way twice. The zone is constantly changing and we have to look for and to calculate new routes and find new paths to travel. More or less stable transitions exist only in some places, such as the Bar, the Agropron, the Garbage, and the Cordon. But I'll be able to help you. If you walk to the eastern part of Yantar, to the right of the road into the valley you will see an old damaged bus. Somewhere near it there should be a 'Secret Path' to the Forest. Look closely, but, if you do not find it, come to back to us, we can find a place for you here: the protection of a brave man is always needed. If you can get back to the Forest, pass on my greetings to Forester and give him the medicine that Vasiliev was unable to deliver. Tell Forester that the exchange of artifacts and roots for provisions will take a week, when the courier will return. Food is scarce at the moment so tell Forester to be patient.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="sahar_nachalo_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood, I will find this secret trail leading to the Forest.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="lekarstvo_dialog_0">
    <text>I've returned. Sorry it took so long, Vasiliev lost the drugs while running away from the mutants. I had to go with him back to Yantar and get new drugs from Sakharov.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="lekarstvo_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, things recently went from bad to worse with my health, a stroke of bad luck. Anyway, give me the medicine and food, I can hardly wait, I'm so hungry.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lekarstvo_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, take this quick remedy. But with food being scarce at the moment, Sakharov has asked you to wait a week.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="eda_dialog_0">
    <text>Forester, where are we going to get provisions? I see that your stocks are running low.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="eda_dialog_1">
    <text>We'll think of something ... I hid some in a secluded place, a box of provisions for a rainy day, so to speak. That day, apparently, is upon us. You'll have to go and pick up that box of food. However, it's hidden in the Dead City. </text>
  </string> 
   <string id="eda_dialog_2">
    <text>Give me the coordinates, I'll go.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="eda_dialog_3">
    <text>I don’t want you to go alone, but you probably should. Listen to me carefully: I hid a cache in the Club building. The building is one with the columns, just near the place where I found you. I was on my way there when I stumbled upon you. Get in, get the provisions and get back here as quickly as possible. Understand? Oh, my aching heart tells me something is wrong, but it can't be helped, it is necessary for you to go. Here, take another box of buckshot, just in case, and a med kit.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="eda_dialog_4">
    <text>Do not worry, Forester, I'll be careful. All right, I'm going.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="eda_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Forester, I'm hours late again, I'm sorry, but there was an unexpected situation.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="eda_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Strelok, I'm glad that you're back safe; I thought you were attacked by mutant dogs. Tell me what happened.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="eda_dialog_est_2">
    <text>In the Dead City, the Club building was occupied by a group of people who called themselves 'Wanderers'. Their leader is Leila, a stern, but beautiful woman. They found your cache but they gave me the remains of the provisions in exchange for doing a job for them. They also provided me with an assault rifle and an armoured suit, which they let me keep as a reward for helping them. And Leila said that soon, a person who can help me find my brother will be back from a raid.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="eda_dialog_est_3">
    <text>It's good that you have made some friends. You don't have to stay here with this old man. You'll see, they will help you find your brother ... Well, show me what provisions we have.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="eda_dialog_est_4">
    <text>There is still half a box, it should last for a week or two, if we ration a bit. Here, take this box.</text>
  </string> 

   <string id="skit_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I'll ask politely, and don't try to run. What's your business here? Answer briefly and clearly.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, okay, don't worry. I came here at the request of someone to retrieve a cache of supplies.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Who's the fool who decided to hide his cache in this rotten place?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_4">
    <text>He is not a fool - his name is Forester. Have you heard of him?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I've heard of Forester, he's a good guy ... Okay, let's go to our base, it's our home - don't abuse it! There, Leila will deal with you. Follow close behind me. Don't attempt to run. If you stray more than ten metres from me - this would amount to an escape attempt, and you will be shot. Got it?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="skit_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes I understand.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you and what is your business here?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I came here on behalf of Forester, to pick up a cache of provisions. He himself could not come because he has a bad heart. In general, I live with him, and help him. Our food supply is running low, so he sent me to bring it back.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I know Forester ... And where and has he hidden his cache?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I see I have to be perfectly frank, you guys are serious. Forester’s cache, by his description, is in this building on the first floor, inside the piano.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_5">
    <text>So now I believe you, because we have already found the box of provisions. Forester hid it poorly, probably thinking that no one comes here. Wrong - this now is our sanctuary. We are called Wanderers, have you heard about us? Did Forester tell you anything?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_6">
    <text>No, I've not heard of you and Forester did not say anything. I only arrived in the Zone recently. Forester found me under strange circumstances. I am looking for my brother now. Have you heard anything about a Stalker, nicknamed 'Captain'? He is very similar to me.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No Strelok, I don't know this person nor have I heard of him. We have only been in the zone a year and a half, and during this time, except for enemies and the envious we've met no one. We do not attempt to make acquaintances here, we have other goals. People with noble causes tend to stay away from us.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_8">
    <text>I see. What are you doing in the Zone?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_9">
    <text>We here unofficially on a mission for an important scientific company. We can't tell you more. We have a peaceful mission, but sometimes you have to shoot, as the zone has many surprises. We must constantly be alert and vigilant. By the way, if you want to buy provisions, ammunition or weapons, then talk to Mozart - he is our 'Trader', he's on the first floor in the room with a piano. He's the one who found Forester's hiding place. Understand?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, I understand.</text>
  </string>
      
	<string id="leila_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Tell me, do you have Forester's box?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Quite simply, we do not need someone else to tell us its location, we found the cache ourselves. This is our territory, and all that is in it, belongs to the brotherhood of Wanderers. I'll give you Forester's box, but only on condition that you help us with one case.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I'll work for the provisions. What should I do?</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Quite simply, Strelok, go to Demon - he is our head of security; you'll find him in a former labour building, 'Glory to Labour', adjacent to monument to Lenin. We are currently conducting an operation to clear the city from any evil. He will help you. In short, Demon will tell you everything, and give you an automatic weapon with ammunition. I will warn Demon you are coming.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll go to Demon.</text>
  </string> 
  
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I have fulfilled your condition, give me Forester's box.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You are indeed courageous, Strelok. We, the Wanderers, keep our word. Take your box, though we took some things from it. I hope Forester is not offended; it should have been better hidden. We honour and respect your bravery so now you are free to come and go. As for your business about your brother, we have a team member named Grieg. He was in the zone for a long time, joined us from the very beginning, he was employed as a guide, and then permanently joined our ranks. He is now on a mission, but will soon return; maybe he knows something about you brother. I'll let Forester know by radio when he arrives.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well, I'll wait eagerly to meet him. How do I get back to the Forest?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Go to the guard who brought you to me. He's waiting for you near the entrance to this room and will tell you everything. Without him, you will not find the path to the Forest.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="leila_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes, of course. I'll go talk to him.</text>
  </string>

	<string id="postovoy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Commander!</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="postovoy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>How can I help you?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="postovoy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Leila said that you would show me the trail back to the Forest.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="postovoy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Follow me closely and when get near the Forest transition point, I'll mark the spot on your PDA.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="postovoy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>All right, let's go.</text>
  </string> 
 
     <string id="demon_start_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm looking for someone called Demon, is that you?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes it is I, Strelok. Leila told me about you. Are you prepared for a job?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Always ready! What do you need done?</text>
  </string>
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We must monitor the entire city; the houses are full of zombies. They constantly appear after blowouts... From where they come we don't know? After the last blowout, my guys cleared a large part of the city, but there is still one five story building to be cleared. It's next to the angular five-storied house with the broken roof. Over there, in one of the entrances, you will find the zombies. Zombies although sluggish, are better not met in close quarters. You'll go alone, my guys are too exhausted from the last mission, and you will prove that you are capable. Here, take this armour, assault rifle and four magazines for it and you be careful, don't be a hero.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood. I'll kill these creatures.</text>
  </string> 

   <string id="demon_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I cleared that house of Zombies.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Excellent, Strelok! Keep the rifle and the armour as a reward.</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="demon_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thanks, now I have to see Lelia, to pickup something that she promised to return.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen, Forester, among the Wanderers a trader exists, they call him Mozart...</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>Did you check his inventory?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I looked, he has many provisions and some good weapons, and the main thing - the ammo is cheap. But how do you get money around here?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I can offer you money. Scientists from the Yantar bunker need all sorts of roots and artifacts. Especially the Mandrake root, which you got for me recently. They are out of it. What they are preparing is a protective potion so they can enter a lab, where the mind boils from some unknown powerful influence and as yet is unknown to science. As they have no time to search themselves, they are constantly offering me money for every root I find. Mandrake grows only here in the Forest, in places not everyone would look. Why do I charge them? I need the money to buy provisions and ammo.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>It's interesting. How much is possible to earn from these roots?</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>For each root they pay fifteen thousand. A lot of money. I can tell you where you can find some roots.</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>Come on, tell me!</text>
  </string> 
   <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, I know where you can find three Mandrake roots. Do not take them to the scientists - they are highly prized. Sell or exchange the roots only with me personally. I've got the money - about two months ago, I scraped together a large number of roots and artifacts for the scientists, they not only gave me provisions, but also insisted that I take the money. The money lies idle, and I see that you need it. It would be simple to just give it to you - but this would be incorrect, I prefer that you earn it. Agreed?</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>Of course I agree, tell me where to look for the plants.</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>Do you remember the place in the swamp where Vasiliev showed you the transition to Yantar? Well it's no longer the transition; the scientists have temporarily closed the short road from the Forest to Yantar. Now there's just a hole - the entrance to an underwater cave. Over there, in the cave, you'll find the Mandrake. Find the three roots, bring them to me, and I'll give you money, 45,000 rubles. I'll give you some buckshot and a med kit to take with you, just be careful out there! The exit to the cave will lead you straight to the slope of the ravine, near the lake.</text>
  </string>  
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>Understood. I'm going.</text>
  </string> 
  
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Forester I brought the three roots!</text>
  </string>
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Honestly speaking, I was afraid to go into that cave.</text>
  </string>  
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>You had every reason to be afraid, there were some kind of evil flying creatures in there. Scary! As I took the third root a monster appeared, a hypnotist or something. I barely got out of the cave alive.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Flying creatures - they're poltergeists. They are cowardly, but dangerous if confronted face on. The hypnotist - is the Controller. He is a terrible insidious creature. It is agreeable then, give me the roots and keep the honestly earned money and go rest.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_poisk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here take the roots. I'll go walk for a little, as my hands still shake, when I think about the cave.</text>
  </string>
   
      <string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Forester, was there any news while I was in the cave at the swamp?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_1">
    <text>Leila told me that the man you were expecting has arrived. So again, you must return to the City, you may not return for some time...</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_2">
    <text>Come Forester, don't worry. You have provisions and the roots. I must go quickly to find out about my brother. And return soon I hope.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay Strelok, do not worry about me. Go to Leila she's waiting for you. The secret path from the Forest to the Dead City you already know.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="lesnik_grig_dialog_4">
    <text>I must go now Forester. I will definitely be back!</text>
  </string>   
  
      <string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_0">
    <text>Hail soldier!</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_1">
    <text>If you are going to Leila do not divert, go to our sanctuary, you know the way. If you are going to the Forest, then you may leave.</text>
  </string>   
       <string id="postovoy_fraza_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm on my way.</text>
  </string> 
   
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Sister!</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_1">
    <text>Don’t get smart with me Strelok. Do I look like your sister? Are you still looking for your brother?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_2">
    <text>I got your message. You told Forester that your guide may be able to help me. Did he show up?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, he’s back from a recent raid at the Swamps where we have a checkpoint, and Grieg was in charge. Before you go to him, I ask for your help with a simple matter. He’s not far from here in the building of the former regional committee. It has big red letters above it.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_4">
    <text>What's the matter you need help with?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="leila_grig_dialog_5">
    <text>Here in the City of the Dead, there's a gang of looters hanging out. They are street boys, thugs of course, but yet still, youngsters. Living in the abandoned houses, trying to sell all they can. Recently their ringleader has appeared - someone called Razuvaev. An ex-convict. But with his arrival, their antics began to get more serious. The gang began robbing not only abandoned houses and shops in the area, but started killing. More recently, one of our brothers, who came back from a raid, was robbed and murdered. We staged a raid on them, but to no avail.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, how can I help? Don't you have a small army here?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_7">
    <text>It's true, but the matter is delicate ... My warriors have sworn all caught will be destroyed. Demon has put a bounty on Razuvaev's head for 100,000 rubles. For the rest, the order is to kill him on the spot without a trial. I don't want to intervene and break the code of the Wanderers, but I don't want needless deaths. I'm not prepared to kill youngsters, even if they are criminals. Do you understand?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes I understand. So what do you want from me?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_9">
    <text>According to my information the leader of the marauders, Razuvaev, together with a group of inveterate murderers and criminals are away for a while from the Dead City. There's a small group led by young kid named Minor. I want you to quietly talk to this band and gave them my offer. Don’t worry; although they are scumbags, they are not killers. Unlikely to shoot a lone Stalker.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, what do you offer and where do I find them?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_11">
    <text>Conditions are simple: I'll give them twenty thousand rubles - for them it's good money, but they need to tell me everything they know about their ringleader: Who is he, where he hangs out, etc., and then get of the Dead City and never return. Otherwise, they will be shot by Demon's soldiers. I’ll note on your PDA their location. Not a word to anyone, except the Khan kids. Understood?</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="leila_grig_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, I understand. Put a marker in the PDA, give me the money and I will negotiate with your 'kids'.</text>
  </string>  
  
     <string id="maloy_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you the one called Minor?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I am, and who are you, my uncle?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_2">
    <text>It does not matter. I was sent to you by Leila, with a proposal.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_3">
    <text>What proposal? Does she want to invite some young boys around for some fun?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_4">
    <text>Idiot! She offers you a deal to save your useless life.</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="maloy_dialog_5">
    <text>You're the messenger of good will? What does our 'saviour' offer?</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="maloy_dialog_6">
    <text>You rejoice in vain, young man. The Wanderers are preparing to raid your camp. So what choice do you have? Leila proposes this: Tell her who Razuvaev is and where he can be found, and leave this place forever, and in return you will be paid twenty thousand rubles. Otherwise you're history. You choose.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, I'm not a fool, everything is clear. I've got to talk it over with the guys.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_8">
    <text>OK, I'll wait.</text>
  </string>

     <string id="maloy_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, what did you decide?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_est_1">
    <text>In short, Uncle, we agree. About Razuvaev we know little. I only know that he escaped from the slammer and is in the Zone, he's assembled a gang and operates on the sly. We met him accidentally, as we had nowhere else to go he took us in. Bear in mind we have no allegiance to him! Where to look for him, we do not know. They say, he hangs around somewhere in an abandoned village near the Peacekeeping Corps, that's in the South Zone.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_est_2">
    <text>OK, I'll take your word for it. Take the money and get out of here. Understood?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="maloy_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yeah OK, Give me the money, and then go 50 metres into the bushes, so that you can't see which way we go. We don't trust you.</text>
  </string> 
     <string id="maloy_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Okay here's the money. I'll stand 50 meters away. Then I'll come back and check. If you’ve cheated me I will personally hunt you down and superglue your cracks together.</text>
  </string>  
 
  <string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_0">
    <text>Well, I dealt with the Marauders.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_1">
    <text>You persuaded them, and they're gone?</text>
  </string>   
  <string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_2">
    <text>Yes they're gone, they promised not to come back. Sassy guys. Young, still green, but bold. Accepted your proposal and took the money. As for his boss, Razuvaev, they really didn't know much. They say he went deep into the Zone with a group of experienced criminals, and may return soon to the Dead City, but so far no news from him. They say they've heard that he hangs out somewhere in an abandoned village near the Peacekeeping Corps, in the South Zone.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_3">
    <text>Well, I hope these young idiots have enough brains not to come back here. Thank you, Strelok. Now it's time to go see Grieg. Talk to him, as he is going back soon. He is located near here, in a former party committee building, 'Glory to the Party'. As for the leader of the marauders - we'll catch him in time. If suddenly you meet that young reptile - Razuvaev, in your travels, hand him a flaming firearm 'hello' from me.</text>
  </string> 
       <string id="leila_grig_dialog_new_4">
    <text>Okay, agreed. I'll go see Grieg now. Thank you!</text>
  </string>  
  
     <string id="grig_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Grieg?</text>
  </string>
       <string id="grig_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
  </string>
       <string id="grig_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Leila said you might be able to help me with something.</text>
  </string>
       <string id="grig_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, she warned me you were coming. How I can help you, Strelok? Speak.</text>
  </string>
       <string id="grig_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll get to the point; I'm looking for my brother. Several years ago, here in the Dead City we became separated under strange circumstances. Forester, and then also Sakharov who is based at Yantar, said that earlier they had met a man like me by the nickname 'Captain'. All they know is that he and a few desperate guys were planning to raid the Sarcophagus at Chernobyl. Maybe you know something or may have heard of 'Captain' and his team of Stalkers?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, Leila briefly told me about your business. No, I did not personally meet this person, but I do know about that team of 'suicides', who two and one-half years ago attempted to get to the heart of Zone - to the Sarcophagus. You know that very close to the Chernobyl NPP is the city - Pripyat. My partner, also a guide as I was then, led them to the Hotel in Pripyat. No one went there in those days. He returned, and they went on. My companion, God rest his soul, soon succumbed to a high dose of radiation he received in Pripyat ... That's all I know. I do not know where you'll find your brother, or a trace of the group of Stalkers, but in any case, the search should begin in Pripyat. I advise you not to go there though. Disastrous place: high radiation, all teeming with anomalies, and on top of that, about six months ago, some kind of mysterious group, of semi-humans or semi-zombies arrived there. Recently anyone who went there never returned.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Hell...I vowed to find my brother or what happened to him, so I have no other way. I have to go to Pripyat. Will you be able to accompany me there? I'll pay you or work it off somehow.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No, Strelok, I can't be your guide; I have other important matters to complete. But, I can show a path leading from the Dead City to Pripyat, if you do something for me first, agreed?</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Of course, I agree! What do I need to do?</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes, this is a breeze. It is necessary to bring me ten dog tails. The ravine on the outskirts of the Dead City is full of blind dogs.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I'll return shortly.</text>
  </string>  
  
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Grieg, I shot the dogs. Here are your ten tails.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Thanks. You can get to Pripyat through the Dead City sewer tunnels. We had to close all the entrances to stop mutants coming. Right behind this building in the square there is an old fountain and a white car to the right. Search for the hatch, which is next to it. Be careful out there. And remember, this pathway is one way only, the way back, you will have to find yourself. Well, good luck to you, Strelok. I've been here a while, and will soon leave for the Swamps, where we have a checkpoint. We'll meet again.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="grig_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thank you, Grieg! Until we meet again.</text>
  </string> 
  
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Sergeant!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, we have been waiting for you, time is short and we must act now. Our hands are itching to ass kick these bastards! Do you have the map of the Bar? </text>
  </string>
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure do, here's the map Sergeant.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_3">
    <text>Good! Now let's decide how to distribute our resources. Aha, all is clear. Enter the Bar and split up into three groups. All right, it's time to act. Are you with us?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll follow you. Let's go.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_5">
    <text>You have special assignments if you wish to do them. Clear the bandit guards at the northern checkpoint to the Bar. I think you can deal with it, and if you take them by surprise they won’t realise what's happening. Then you can eliminate the bandit leader Duke, the guys in the Bar, and the guys in the Prison. I will send in my assault group first, then my snipers, and them me. If you cannot perform one or more of these assignments, them my assault group should be able to do them. I'll send one of my guys to the northern checkpoint, and another to the southern checkpoint. Try not to shoot any of my guys. And if you can help protect me, that would be good. Understand everthing?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_6">
    <text>Aaahhh, yeah, I think so.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well Sergeant are you happy with how everything turned out?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, quite so. But we're not here to visit! We'll soon catch up with the rest of General Voronin’s troops and establish a strong Duty base here.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="dolg_attak_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well good luck to you.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="about_voronin_dialog_0">
    <text>How else can I help you?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="about_voronin_dialog_1">
    <text>General Voronin with three guards and another person have moved from the Garbage to the southern outpost. A few of the bandits led by Borov have managed to get into the Bar area on the south side. It is necessary to protect and accompany Voronin's group, and bring them to me.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="about_voronin_dialog_2">
    <text>I understand, I'll head towards the Garbage, and I hope I will have time to warn the General about the danger.</text>
  </string>   
  
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, General!</text>
  </string>
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok! Well, Plichko reported that the Bar territory is now ours, very good news! Has he sent you to escort us?</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, exactly. There could still be some aspiring gangsters in the area. Incidentally, Borov made a last-minute escape. We searched but could not catch him. I'm to escort both you and Barkeep to the Bar.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_3">
    <text>God willing, we'll catch Borov. The main Bar is now ours. We have Barkeep with us, you can't have a bar without a barman. Let's get going to our new residence.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, let's go. Follow me, General.</text>
  </string> 
  
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, here we are. How did you like it?</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Nice bunker! No worse than the scientist's at Yantar. Beauty! You Strelok really deserve a great reward. Take this, it's from me personally. Visit Barkeep, he has a special gift for you as well. Now it's possible for our remaining brothers, headed by Colonel Petrenko, to move here from the Dark Valley.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="voronin_bar_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Thank you, General. I'll go to Barkeep. I hope we meet again.</text>
  </string>  

  <string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Doctor!</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, young man. You, apparently, are Strelok. Feldsher, my pupil and assistant told me about You. Thank you for helping Ghost. We are in your debt.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_vstrecha_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you Doctor, but it's I, that's in debt to Feldsher, he cleared my brain and returned my memory while I was in Pripyat.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor I have a very important question.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes go on.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_2">
    <text>Have you heard of a Stalker by the name of 'Captain', who two and a half years ago, accompanied by several other courageous Stalkers, tried to penetrate the Chernobyl Sarcophagus near Pripyat, and further? He is my brother. I'm trying to find him, or at least find out what happened to him. A man by the name of Grieg told me that his partner - a guide, accompanied this same group to the centre of Pripyat, they went further on their own, and he returned, but died shortly after from a strong dose of radiation...</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, it was a long time ago ... Indeed, a few Stalkers attempted to get to the Chernobyl NPP and the Sarcophagus. But I see that you know this already. Leader or the group was a kind of Captain. Maybe your brother, I do not know, but his friends called him Captain.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes Doctor, Ghost and Feldsher were right, you really know a lot. Maybe you know some more relevant details? What happened to them?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_5">
    <text>How this campaign ended and what happened to your brother, I can't say because I do not know. This story is shrouded in mystery and darkness. Now, after so much time, it all seems a mystery or just a fairy tale. But there is one detail that only I know, and that makes the story very real. In general I've told this to no one. Here are some details may be useful in your quest.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_6">
    <text>What is this information? How did you find out?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_7">
    <text>Grieg, whom you mentioned, knows a lot of things - he's an 'old experienced wolf' in a scrape. But he did not really give you accurate information; rather, he simply did not know about a nuance ... that his friend the guide actually brought the group directly into the territory of Chernobyl NPP not the centre of Pripyat. Risked and paid for it with his life...</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_8">
    <text>How did you know that?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_9">
    <text>The guide, already near death, came to me for help. I couldn't save him ... He stayed with me a week. God knows I did everything possible, but alas, it was all in vain ... So, before his death he told me that he took the risk and, together with those Stalkers moved across the Pripyat River to Chernobyl. He did so because they found in Pripyat several unique artifacts that give a very powerful protection against radiation and Psy-effects. They were all in the belief that such protection would be sufficient for all. Once in the Chernobyl NPP, they found that the background radiation was far too high, and all the protective properties of the artifacts were simply not enough. The group split up. In the Sarcophagus, the artifacts could only provide protection for two, the 'Captain' and Yuri Semetsky. The others returned to Pripyat, and waited for the return of those two. He soon felt a sharp discomfort and had to return from Pripyat. How it began is not known: after a couple of days all hell broke loose, there was a powerful outburst of Psy-energy, which changed the Zone forever. 'Captain' and Semetsky never returned. What happened next no one knows for sure. Then, after some time on stalkers PDA's came the message about the death of Yuri Semetsky that comes to this day. One of the 'old men' claimed to have seen Semetsky alive and well after six months, and then a year after these events. Is it true, I do not know. Soon after people stopped believing the story and it became a legend, and the situation with constant reports of deaths blamed on Semetsky, another unexplained phenomenon of the Zone. There is a simple answer, Strelok. Try to learn from leading figures, can someone still be alive from that group? To do this, you have to go through the entire Zone, starting from here, in the Swamps, and up to the Cordon.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="doctor_one_dialog_10">
    <text>Thank you, Doctor, you have given me hope! I believe that I will find a trace of my brother, and perhaps him.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor, what can I do for you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_1">
    <text>There is a matter, exactly for someone such as you, Strelok.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm happy to help you.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_3">
    <text>Here, in the marshes, until recently things were relatively quiet. Well, maybe a pack of dogs or some tushkanos would appear. But these are trifles. And then suddenly there appeared a swamp creature, all my 'patients' are scared. Two barely survived with only broken bones after their encounter with this monster. And last night this brood from hell devoured all the kittens at my refuge. I can tame any animal, but this ... This creature is not amenable to any effect or hypnosis. You have it.</text>
  </string>   
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_4">
    <text>Do I have to find this mutant that lives in the marshes and destroy it?</text>
  </string>   
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, that's correct Strelok. You be cautious. I suspect that this beast is one mean machine. It must be a very rare creature. Let us hope it is not like a Tricephalous - meaning you chop of its head and two grow back. Wanderers, well you know them, as I understand you once met Grieg. They have a small base in the western area of the Swamps. They are afraid to even approach the spot where there is supposedly the lair of this Bonebreaker. They have lost a lot of people trying to destroy it. Grieg has said some fantastic things. He indicated that for every bullet entry point into this creature, out pour small spider-looking mutants, and they are very tenacious, and fast. This monster is frightening! Fire and chemical compositions, including acid, do not seem to bother this thing. But I know you'll think of something, you're savvy. But once again I beg you to be careful Strelok. If you feel that you cannot overpower this beast, and then return to me and we will devise a plan.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_6">
    <text>Do not worry Doctor I've met all sorts of strange things during my travels while you were getting a suntan. So whatever is out there I can handle it.</text>
  </string> 

  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Yes, I saw ... But this! I've never seen a creature such as this before.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Really young man, did you destroy the 'Bonebreaker'?</text>
  </string>   
  <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, but I had to work hard, very hard!</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well thank you, Strelok! You've saved us from great danger.</text>
  </string>
     <string id="doctor_kostolom_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Come on, Doc, don't mention it. It will be good not encounter this incarnation of the devil again.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="doctor_skit_dialog_0">
    <text>Doctor, I need to get out of here and move on in search of my brother. How do I get out of the Swamps?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="doctor_skit_dialog_1">
    <text>You see, young man, moving to Pripyat is not possible. After the latest emission, everything was turned upside down. In fact, you do not need to go to Pripyat at all. From the Swamps you can still get into the Forest and from there on into the Zone. But this path, only the Wanderers know. You need to talk to Grieg about it.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="doctor_skit_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, Doc, I'll go to the Wanderers checkpoint and speak with Grieg. I have to go to the Forest anyway, to call on an elderly man in poor health. His name is Forester; he's helped me a lot. Do you know of him?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="doctor_skit_dialog_3">
    <text>I know Forester - he's a good man, intelligent and courageous, not afraid to live in a Forest full of anomalies, deadly traps, and mutants. He will tell you how to pass from the Forest to the Zone.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="doctor_skit_dialog_4">
    <text>All is clear. So my way back is through the Forest. Thank you, Doctor, I'll be seeing you!</text>
  </string>  

    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Grieg! Long time no see.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok! Well, did you find your brother?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_2">
    <text>No, Grieg, I haven't found him yet. The Doctor gave me some details that give me hope though, but I need to get back to the Zone. He said that you know the path to the Forest; can you help me get there?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, Strelok, I can show you the transition to the Forest. And from the Forest you can get to the Military Warehouses. Forester will help you get there. But let's have an equal exchange my friend.</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, great! All I want is to get back to the Forest to see how an old man is ... What do you need?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_5">
    <text>Like last time, a mere trifle. It is necessary to check a piece of scientific equipment, what and why - you don't need to know. All that is required of you - is accompanying our expert, Kent, to an abandoned village so that he can test the device. And then, to protect him on the way back, you never know, there all sorts of rubbish around. We would be able to handle it ourselves, but for now, we can't spare anyone from the checkpoint. We recently lost a few people - 'Bonebreaker' tore them to shreds ... We are waiting for Leila to send replacements from the Dead City. If you help us out, then I'll help you, I'll show you the path to the Forest.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_6">
    <text>I'll do it. By the way, I eliminated the 'Bonebreaker' at the Doctors request, so you no longer need to fear that beast.</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_7">
    <text>You killed the 'Bonebreaker'? Well, Strelok, you're either incredibly stupid or very brave. Anyway as for the escort, if I'm not mistaken, it is better that you do it. It's time to go. Kent is waiting for you, next to the truck at the end of the bridge. Follow and protect him.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_8">
    <text>I'm on my way.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="zamery_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, are you Kent?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="zamery_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
  </string>  
      <string id="zamery_dialog_2">
    <text>Grieg asked me to escort you to a place where you're going to take some measurements. Is that the instrument you're going to test?</text>
  </string>
        <string id="zamery_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, it is. I was waiting for Grieg to send me some men. I thought that he would send at least three - this is a dangerous place.</text>
  </string>
          <string id="zamery_dialog_4">
    <text>Do not worry, the two of us can handle it, just stay close to me, I'll protect you. Let's go.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_0">
    <text>I told you not to worry. We overpowered those creatures without to much hassle. So, is this the place?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_1">
    <text>Yes this is the place. Now wait a minute while I quickly check the settings. Then we can get out of here.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zamery_dialog_mesto_2">
    <text>Okay I'll wait.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="zamery_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Have you finished taking the measurements?</text>
  </string>    
    <string id="zamery_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes everything is fine. I still have to make a few adjustments to the settings and everything will be ready. Thank you very much for your help. Go to Grieg and inform him that the job is done, and that the device is functioning properly. I need a couple of hours to finish the calibrations, and then I'll return to the checkpoint.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="zamery_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Another job well done. Take care of yourself.</text>
  </string>   
  
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Task accomplished Grieg. Your man is alive and unharmed.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well that's good! Look I have marked on your PDA the transition from the Swamps to the Forest. However the path is in one direction only. If you need to go back to the Swamps you will have to find Pathfinder at the Bar. He will help you find the Secret Path back to us here. Understand?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="grig_swamp_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes everything is clear. I'm going.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_0">
    <text>Forester it looks as if I arrived at the right time.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_1">
    <text>Ah Strelok, you did, I got distracted and these forest cats came down on me - they would have gorged me alive, if not for you. Ugh, these creatures are ugly.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_2">
    <text>You see, I proved useful to you. Here, take a med kit.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you my son. Here, let me give you something in return. It's a rare recipe for transmuting artifacts. It will be useful to you.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="lesnik_cats_dialog_4">
    <text>Please do, thank you.</text>
  </string>  

    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_0">
    <text>How have you been all this time?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm better now, but where did you go? Did learn anything about your brother?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, Forester, so many things happened during that time, there's so much to tell.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, then briefly tell this old man what happened.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, in short, I was in Pripyat. I lost all memory of who I was. I fell into a 'Crater' anomaly. Then salvation! I was saved by a 'sorcerer' whom they call Mervin. While I was mindless, I was a puppet soldier in the Monolith faction at Chernobyl. Then a pupil of the Swamp Doctor healed me and helped me to get out of Pripyat and to the Swamps. Then I became acquainted with the Swamp Doctor, and learned something about my brother. Now I'm here in the Forest and I need to get back to the Zone.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, my son, over there your life turned. Well, at least now you're alive and well. What plans do have?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I need to get back into the Zone. I was told that you can show me the path leading to the Military Warehouses.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_7">
    <text>I myself do not know this path, I've never been. But there are some guys, Hunters, they come sometimes to the Forest, to hunt mutants. They collect some of these, and then sell them to the Scientists. They were here just yesterday, they came to my house - we talked about this and that, drank some tea. They have a camp near the big swamp. Their chief - is an experienced hunter named Slouch. Find and talk to him as he knows exactly how to get to the Military Warehouses. I'll mark their position on your PDA.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_hunters_dialog_8">
    <text>Good! Give me the coordinates and I'll go find the Hunters.</text>
  </string>  
  
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Slouch?</text>
  </string>  
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I am. Who are you and Is there something I can do for you?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Forester told me you could help me and show the transition from the Forest to the Military Warehouses. I'm wandering through the Zone in search of my brother, a man called 'Captain'. Have you heard about this Stalker and his team that a couple of years ago made a bold attempt to get to the heart of the Zone, the Sarcophagus?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, so that's it ... Well, a different matter. About 'Captain', I have not heard anything, we normally don't socialise with anyone, we're hermits. The path from the Forest to the Military Warehouses I can show you, but only if you do something for us. I've sent a couple of fighters to shoot wild boars and collect their hooves for sale. My proposal is this, you help them shoot the mutants, and I'll show you the Secret Trail to the Military Warehouses. Agreed?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_4">
    <text>What choice do I have? I agree. Tell me what to do, and who to see.</text>
  </string>  
     <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Here's the deal! The chief of the operations is Greek. He's the bored looking one. His assistant is Zahar and he's a bit of a blockhead, but knows his stuff. Follow their lead. The mutants should be somewhere in the habitable zone, so that's where you're going. Give them a hand. Oh, if you gather up the right mutant parts then go to Mazai or Zahar. They will exchange all sorts of tails and hooves for ammo and med kits. Okay, now back to business: Go to Greek he will give you the instructions for the forthcoming operation. After the mission is completed talk to Greek again, then follow Sahar to the transition to Warehouses. Agreed?</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="sutuly_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes everything is clear. I'll go see Greek now.</text>
  </string> 
      
    <string id="grek_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Greek.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grek_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello stalker. Well, are ready for the big hunt?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="grek_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I am always ready for anything. Tell me, what's the plan.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="grek_start_dialog_3">
    <text>It's simple: the three of us will advance together to the location of the boars. You, me and Zahar. Don't get ahead of me as we will have to sneak up on them quietly. The location is close to the swamp. We tracked down a pack of wild boars there this morning. Let's go hunting, but be careful they are insidious creatures. After we've finished, Zahar will take you to the transition to Military Warehouses. Here take three packs of armour-piercing ammunition for the AK, a couple of packs of 'darts' for the shotgun, and I'll throw in a couple of scientific med kits. Ready to go?</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="grek_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, like a Pioneer, I am always ready. Hand over the ammo and let's get going.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="grek_ohota_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Greek, we shot all the mutants.</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="grek_ohota_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, another job well done. Now as promised, Zahar will take you to the place where the trail begins to the Military Warehouses. Don't get ahead of him or lag behind.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="grek_ohota_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you and good luck.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Zahar, are we there?</text>
  </string>   
    <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes we are, most psychic one. The path leading to the Military Warehouses begins here between the boulders.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>Thank you. Do you have any requests?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes, there is one request. I overhead while you were speaking with Slouch that you are looking for your missing brother. With your question, I can't help you, but please bear with me as I have a situation very similar to yours. I'm trying to find someone too. His name is Sobolev. He's a retired military man. We were neighbours for over twenty years. Before the CNPP accident we would go hunting and fishing together, our families were friends too. After the catastrophe our families perished. Since we had no one left, Sobolev and I decided to stay here in the Zone where our families are buried. We began to look for work as guides, first for onlookers, and then for the Stalkers. We knew the place well. But then our paths diverged. I had a falling out with him once, we argued, and I decided to quit and joined the Hunters, and he remained a guide. Where is he now? Oh, for a long time I did not hear anything. I know that he's still in the Zone, but where?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Well there is a network of Stalkers you can search through. Do you have a PDA?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>No Strelok I don't. I don't know how to use one. Please, a request from me to you: if you meet Captain Sobolev gave him this letter personally. I want to make peace with him. I miss his friendship.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="zahar_perehod_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay Zahar, if I find Captain Sobolev I'll pass on your letter. Now I must go, show me where the trail begins.</text>
  </string>
    
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_0">
    <text>General I've just arrived here in the Dark Valley.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_1">
    <text>And what led you here?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I'm looking for my brother. I have information that he is in your ranks, as a working guide. He's called 'Captain'. Is he here with you?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_3">
    <text>Yes he is. We do have in our ranks a person called 'Captain'. An experienced guide who knows the entire area. Just he never mentioned he had a brother. He is a strange guy.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_4">
    <text>Well he could be my brother. We have long long ago lost each other. So where is he General, where can I find 'Captain', my older brother?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_5">
    <text>Take it easy, he is here. Go into the courtyard, there is a small building where you'll find him. Then come back to me. I've got some work for you brave one.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="voronin_about_sobolev_6">
    <text>Good! Wow I finally found him! I'll be there in a flash.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Uh-e ... 'Captain'??</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, Captain Sobolev at your service. How can I help you 'grasshopper'?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Damn! You're not my brother are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_3">
    <text>What do you need? What's going on?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I have trodden the entire Zone in search of my brother. I had suffered so much. In the end I just wanted to end all my suffering and the risk of going mad. Lord, why are you not fair to me?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Stop the hysteria soldier! What's your problem?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Despite the fact that my brother's name is 'Captain' I came here to the Dark Valley to find him. I had received information that a Stalker named 'Captain' was working here for Duty. But here's some irony in fate. I met 'Captain', but not only that...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah, well fate sometimes plays bad jokes on us. I regret that I have become an indirect cause of your frustration Stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Well Captain it's not your fault excuse me for my momentary weakness.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_0">
    <text>How do I find my brother now? I have no idea.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Don't give up hope Strelok! I'll try to help you. I've remembered something...</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_2">
    <text>What? You know something about my brother?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes I know something. Zahar has probably already told you, we were once guides in the Zone, for various onlookers and Stalkers. At about the same time, we heard rumours about an expedition to the Sarcophagus, which was led by your brother, 'Captain'.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, Zahar told me.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, I wasn't involved in the raid, but I know a lot about this sortie from a friend of mine, he was their guide. He has since died. He told me that only two went to the Sarcophagus, 'Captain' and Yuri Semetsky. Neither returned, nor were their bodies ever found. All were convinced that they were killed. Sometime later, I met a digger in the Red Forest, near Pripyat. He told me that he saw Yuri alive and well, and allegedly talked with him. Where he saw Semetsky, he did not say. I did not believe him, because the legend of Semetsky had already begun 'The Eternal Stalker'. You probably know yourself about these constant messages on the PDA about his death. In addition to this, he claimed he was a participant in the expedition itself and all, but he and Semetsky, perished. You need to find this digger and ask him where he met with Semetsky and about what they spoke. If Semetsky is still alive and the digger was part of the same group, then maybe your brother is alive too, and you can find him.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_6">
    <text>Where can I find this Digger?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_7">
    <text>I don't know, all I know is he calls himself Mahomet. Check with the traders, Barkeep or Sidorovich. They might know something.</text>
  </string>
      <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_8">
    <text>You've given me new hope Captain. Thank you! But is there a shortcut from the Dark Valley to the Cordon, and then to the Garbage?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_9">
    <text>Probably. As for the transition from the Dark Valley to the Cordon, you need to talk to Voronin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sobolev_one_dialog_10">
    <text>I'll talk to Voronin about the transition to the Cordon, he has some work for me anyway.</text>
  </string>  

  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello! Who are you?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_1">
    <text>We're tramps and I'm called Tanker. We were recently attacked by Bandits, they left us barely alive. Now we stay here licking our wounds. But who are you and why do you come here?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Strelok. I am looking for my missing brother. By the way, while I was in the Dead City I found a dead body, more a skeleton, of a Stalker, and beside him a journal. In it, among other things, there was mention of a certain instrument called a 'Bioradar'. And it said that a stalker named Tanker knew where a version of this instrument could be found.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_3">
    <text>So that's it. Was his name Krol?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_4">
    <text>It could have been Krol, the journal was signed by that name.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_5">
    <text>I knew Krol. He was a meticulous and attentive man and his journal proves it. As for the 'Bioradar' several prototypes were stolen, and then disappeared into thin air. By the way I had nothing to do with it, if that's what you're thinking. I knew a low-life who participated in this robbery. He then sold one to me. It was a good deal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Do you have this device now?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_7">
    <text>No I lost it. Dropped it when we fled from the Bandits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Why don't you try to find it? It would be a shame to lose it.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_9">
    <text>It's too dangerous out there. I'm afraid I value my life too much. I can offer you a deal, you locate and bring me my unique gun, a Groza Storm which I also lost, and I'll give you a tip where you can find the 'Bioradar'. You're a man I see who's not afraid to search for items, and to locate this device. I'm sure it will be useful in finding your brother. And I, frankly, want to clear out of the Zone. Are you interested?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_10">
    <text>You're a dickhead ... 'Bioradar' dropped, Storm weapon lost... and where is your T-38? Also lost? Ahhhh come on, I'm only kidding with you. Your offer suits me fine. Where do I search for your weapon?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_11">
    <text>It was like this: the boys and I went into the underground Lab X-18 in the Dark Valley. We wanted to get hold of some old documents on a tip from one of the Military guys. He promised to pay well. And there in the darkness we encountered a bunch of mutants. We got cold feet and got the hell out of there. Along the way I stumbled and dropped my gun. You need to search the lower level of the laboratory. I don't remember exactly where I dropped it, it was dark. The gun will still be there mutants that do not need weapons.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Got it, wait here. I will to find your Storm.</text>
  </string>

  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello T-38, er, I mean Tanker! I found your Groza Storm. It's in good condition.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Thank you! I really thought that I wouldn't see my favourite weapon again. Come here my 'beauty'.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well you're smart fellow. Have you forgotten what you promised in return? Come on then be honest, out with a tip about the 'Bioradar', and then you can have this weapon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So listen, the boys and I were hiding from the Bandits in the Wild Territories near the Rostok plant. It's a scary place, normal people don't go there, they tend avoid it. That's where I dropped it. The place is easy to find: you go to the Bar and then go towards the transition to Yantar. You'll reach an unfinished building, continue on 'till you see a green car that blocks a small area. In the courtyard behind this small car is where we hid for a while. That's where you should look. I'll take the journal you found in the Dead City, you won’t need it.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="tankist_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Well I'll take your word for it. Here's your Groza Storm and Krol's journal. Now I must go.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="parol_dialog_0">
    <text>Good morning!</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="parol_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you? This is a closed area. To pass you need a special electronic Military permit. Where is your permit?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="parol_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm working for the Military as a guide in the Cordon. Here's my badge.</text>
  </string>

  <string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Sidorovich.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Why so sad? I have not seen you before. Who are you and why have you come?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm called Strelok. I've not been here before. I'm on a long journey and my path has not been easy. Now I'm here. I bring you news from Barkeep. After the last emission he lost all communications. He asked me to deliver you a secret message. Here take this coded letter.</text>
  </string> 

   <string id="sidor_one_dialog_0">
    <text>Sidorovich I seek your help in a personal matter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait a minute, while I read what this Sly Fox has to say. So-so ... interesting theory. Yeah ... he laid it on the shelves, you see! Okay what can I do for you?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for my brother, he's called 'Captain'. We were separated more than two years ago under very strange circumstances. Well, it's a long story. I have walked almost the entire Zone in search of him, and spoke with many old timers about what might have happened to him, but so far all is in vain. I still have hope of finding him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_3">
    <text>How can I help you? I don’t venture out into the Zone too much these days. I get the latest news and gossip from Stalkers and Diggers that come here from time to time, or from Stalker radio chatter, which no longer works here.</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_4">
    <text>Barkeep told me that you know a Digger called Mahomet, an X-Jihadist. He often comes to you. I need to locate him and find out what he knows about my brother.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes I know Mahomet. He was just here two days ago. Sold his loot and went back to the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_6">
    <text>There's something I don't understand, how do Stalkers get in and out of the Peacekeeping Corps? This is a closed area, you need a permit to enter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_7">
    <text>You're a smart fellow, you say you passed through the whole Zone. So you know that there is always a Secret Path by which you can pass unnoticed. Know what I mean? Do you think everybody goes through the checkpoint? No, of course not, in the Zone there always other trails. Peacemakers, they're good guys, though a bit slow in the gray matter. They think they have everything under control, but actually they're wrong. The area is large so they can't control all of the key points and they don't know all the routes. While things are quiet and peaceful they're confident the area is secure. They often come here for a drink. We are, as you say, good friends. It's not their area and who comes into my store does not concern them. The guys from the nearby villages have long gone. They do check everyone's documents. However, since the last emission, all this has changed. Look, anomalies began to appear here and there and the guys told me that they had seen mutants in the Forest. Such is the state of affairs. Surely now the Peacekeepers have their hands full.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_8">
    <text>Now I understand. But where can I find Mahomet?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_9">
    <text>How would I know where the hell his legs take him. He's a Digger, he goes where he can smell a profit. You can wait for him here in the village if you like. He should be back within ten days.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_10">
    <text>No I don't have the time. Is there any way I can get in touch with him? Oh yeah, I forgot, there is a communications problem. What can I do? I desperately need to talk to him.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay I'll help you. There's a man coming here soon, he and Mahomet have scheduled a meeting somewhere in the Zone. I'll try to find out where. 'Quid Pro Quo': while you're waiting you do something for me.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_12">
    <text>Oh, now there's lawyer talk! He-he! What should I do?</text>
  </string>  
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_13">
    <text>Well, I have to reply to the Barkeep. But first, I must think of his proposal. Now you have to see General Smith, at the Peacekeepers base and deliver five bottles of Brandy that he's asked for. It's necessary in these times to stay friends with the Peacekeepers, or they will close me down in no time. Tell the General, that you are my messenger. I'll radio him and tell him you're coming. Fortunately, having connections within the territory works. Ask him if you can help him in any way. Tell him that you're a local, and live not far from here, a place they know well. When asked why you have a weapon, say - you work as a guide for the Military, right. Well, I've prepared what I'll probably say to the Barkeep. When you're all done, come back here.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="sidor_one_dialog_14">
    <text>Yes everything is clear. Give me the Brandy.</text>
  </string> 

  <string id="smith_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello General!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="smith_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you the courier from Sidorovich?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="smith_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, please call me Strelok. I brought you something from him. Here take it.</text>
  </string>  
  
  <string id="smith_one_dialog_0">
    <text>How can I help out General?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="smith_one_dialog_1">
    <text>Well I see you are a complex fellow and armed to the teeth. You're not a saboteur, right?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="smith_one_dialog_2">
    <text>No I'm not a saboteur. Consider me a local guy. I work as a guide for the Military in the Cordon. Now I'm here with Sodorovich’s help. My name is Strelok.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="smith_one_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay Strelok we trust Sidorovich. Local you say? People like you are an asset. We've had an emergency arise. One of our soldiers has gone missing, Corporal Foster. We sent him with secret despatches to the checkpoint. He delivered them but never returned. We want you to find him. All the details you can get from Colonel Brown. People who help us are paid well.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="smith_one_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm glad I can help.</text>
  </string> 

  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Colonel Brown. The General hired me to find your missing Corporal.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>We were looking for a person such as you who could help us. The Corporal took the secret despatches to the checkpoint, but never returned. He’s been missing for the past two days. We've tracked the signal from his PDA. The signal is weak, but steady. It's impossible to make contact due to the constant interference. We combed the entire area, but to no avail. He's vanished into thin air. In short, my people are ordinary soldiers, so we need an experienced Stalker like you. I understand you're a guide and work with the Military, correct?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Ah sure, that's right. My name is Strelok. Give me the coordinates of the location where the signal might be coming from and I'll try to find the corporal, or find out what happened to him.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Strelok give me your PDA and I will mark the radius where to search. Be sure to look everywhere, and if you find him alive bring Corporal Foster back here to the base. We will forever be in your debt. Foster is a good guy, and we miss his jokes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood, mark the area where I should search.</text>
  </string> 

  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Colonel I found Corporal Foster alive and well and brought him back here. He'll tell you what happened.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done Strelok. My soldiers spent two whole days searching, but could not find the Corporal, but you found him quickly. The leaders of the Peacekeeping Corps express their gratitude. Here's a well-deserved reward from us. You are always welcome here.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Glad to have helped! Thank you!</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="kapral_poisk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Don't be too hasty, there is another matter.</text>
  </string>

  <string id="foster_plen_dialog_0">
    <text>Well hello Corporal.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="foster_plen_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you, you are my Saviour! There I was thinking that I was a goner, and that these creatures would eat me for lunch. What is your name?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="foster_plen_dialog_2">
    <text>Call me Strelok. How did you manage to become lost?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="foster_plen_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, do not ask ... I don't understand why. I went the usual way as always. Then I had this freak'n buzzing in my head and a feeling that something was controlling me, and more importantly, I did not want to fight back. Well I can't explain it any better. And then suddenly a miracle, and you're standing in front of me. How long have I been here?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="foster_plen_dialog_4">
    <text>About two days, I suppose. This is what happened to you. There was this Controller, he took over your mind and brought you here, but apparently he wasn't hungry, and left you for later. Well, it's time to get out of here they're waiting for us at the base. Let's go!</text>
  </string>  

  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Colonel, do you have more work?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes! Just for an experienced Stalker like you.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Well you are obviously exaggerating my abilities Colonel. What's the job?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>As you probably already know this used to be a completely normal territory, a common safe area. In other words, a passing point. And after the last emission everything has turned upside down. It seems that this area and this site were affected. Everywhere there is abnormal activity, and we have repeatedly seen mutants. There's got to be a new reason, so another problem has arisen.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah I have noticed that. I'm not a fool. So what do you need?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_5">
    <text>You see, my people they are only soldiers. Just soldiers. They are not supposed to think and make decisions. You're different, you're an experienced loner, you survive, you don't just live, you think and weigh every step, every action. After all you are always making life decisions. Am I right? You can think for yourself. I'm like you, a loner. It’s always on my mind. Oh well, your experience is needed now.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_6">
    <text>Colonel, that's enough philosophy, get to the point.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_7">
    <text>Well I agree that this is no time for philosophy. Where we are now, it's a forced coincidence. We need to do something. Our main base is at another location; not far from here, east of the town in which we are now. We had to evacuate it because after the last emission very strange things started to happen. Everything went mad, officers and soldiers started shooting at each other, the survivors ended up shooting themselves. And then it got worse. We had a scientist with us. He went mad and damaged the radar. Without the radar we are helpless. We are cut off from the rest of the world. There are no communications, the food is all gone, and we cannot get medical aid. This area used to be part of the 'Mainland'. I'm afraid that this territory is becoming part of the Zone. Then finally some mutants attacked the base. We had to hastily retreat from there. We blocked the gates when we left. I can just imagine what's going on in there now.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes, it's not much fun here now Colonel. What do you want from me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_9">
    <text>They must be eliminated at any cost to win back the base. Then we need to fix the radar and establish communications. You can help us. You have special skills and know all sorts of tricks, as there are abnormal things we have to face. I and five soldiers will go with you. I can't spare any more. We can't go to this base with regular troops it's way too dangerous. Well do you agree? I will not wait long, and you will be rewarded.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay I'm in! When do we go?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_11">
    <text>We go now! No need to hurry, just stay close. Five men are already waiting for us there. When we reach the gates to the base, assess the situation and make a decision on what to do next. Here take this weapon, five packs of armour-piercing ammunition, three F-1 grenades and several med kits. Your going to need this stuff.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay hand them over.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_baza_dialog_13">
    <text>Here take them and let's go.</text>
  </string>

  <string id="brown_vorota_dialog_0">
    <text>We're all ready.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_vorota_dialog_1">
    <text>Good! Well the plan is: I'll remotely unlock the gates and we'll start the assault. May God and the Virgin Mary save us all!</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_vorota_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood Colonel. Let's do it!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_vorota_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's be extra careful.</text>
  </string>

  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well Colonel it's done, the base is back under your control.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes it was a glorious hunt. Now we must put everything back in order, and most importantly, fix the radar and establish communications. Thank you, Strelok, you saved us, but there's more to be done. Here, take this well-deserved reward - a universal repair kit with a bio-electronic damage level scanner. It is intended for repairing any type of small arms. It restores 100% functionality. It was created by the Peacekeepers in a secret Military laboratory. The principle of operation is based on the anomalous properties of the Jellyfish artifact. To activate the repair kit, it is necessary to have a Jellyfish artifact in your inventory. After each repair procedure, the Jellyfish artifact evaporates, having transferred all of its properties to the bio-electronic scanner. It is very rare item, use it well.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_baza_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Oh I've long dreamed of such a thing, thank you!</text>
  </string>

  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_0">
    <text>Colonel you said there's more to be done. What did you mean exactly?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_1">
    <text>It's good that the base is back under our control, but south of here, there is an abandoned factory with repair shops. They were ... The place is full insidious creatures; they took over the place when we had to abandon our base. Before you came, General Smith sent a small detachment of special forces to explore the place, but they never returned. We don't even have a weak signal from their PDA's. How shitty is no connection ... We urgently need to repair the radar and restore communications.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you going to raid the place?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_3">
    <text>No, I don't have sufficient forces for an assault. I need you to quietly reconnoitre the place. You're good, I know. I've see you in action. Well, will you help us again?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes of course I'll help you. What exactly do you want done?</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_5">
    <text>Get in close to the factory and see what's happening now and what happened to our people. Find some trace of the missing group. Then get back to General Smith and tell him the situation. Take this pair of Army med kits just in case, and a couple of F-1 grenades.</text>
  </string> 
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood. I'm going to investigate.</text>
  </string> 
  
  <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello General!</text>
  </string>  
   <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_1">
    <text>I see you are in good health Strelok.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Colonel Brown asked me to reconnoitre the old factory, where the repair shops are, where you recently lost your scouts. </text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well what was there? What did you learn?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_4">
    <text>The factory was full of zombies. And I found a Controller there as well, a really dangerous creature, I tell you. Apparently, it took your scouts. I found only one dead body. He had a PDA on which his last words were recorded. Errie to say the least.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Oh damn, we lost a lot of people in the last week. Well we need to repair the radar and get these helicopters back in the air to rid ourselves of these mothers of all evils.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Yes General I copy that. If I'm no longer needed I need to get back to Sidorovich. There is an important matter awaiting me.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_7">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok, you saved us, but now we're on our own. I can't give you much in way of a reward - we ourselves, have to do without: ammunition, food and medical supplies are running low. Well, except that I can guarantee you a free pass into our territory at any time. Oh, yes, I have here an automatic carbine M4 machine gun with 100 rounds, I'm sorry, that's all I can spare. Ammo is tight around here.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brown_fabrika_dialog_est_8">
    <text>Thank you! I'll drop back later, but now I have to go. See ya and good luck! Oh, here, take this PDA I found.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="sidor_two_dialog_0">
    <text>Sidorovich you ugly bastard. I'm back.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_two_dialog_1">
    <text>So your back Jack! Good for you! Did General Smith take the brandy?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_two_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes he accepted the Brandy happily. It was necessary to do some jobs for the Peacekeepers. I had to find someone who went missing too. Christ. They even got me to help them clean out their old base from mutants. Now they will try to fix the radar and restore communications. I helped get their affairs in order. Now I have them as friends.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sidor_two_dialog_3">
    <text>I see, but you don't have time to relax. While you were gone I've written a response to Barkeep. Here, I want you to deliver this encrypted message to him.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sidor_two_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay I'll deliver your message.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="about_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>What did you find out?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="about_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>So listen, the stalker came, the one who was going to have a meeting with Mahomet. They have scheduled a meeting somewhere on the outskirts of the Dead City. You'll find him there so don't delay. As to how to get to the Dead City, you'll figure it out.</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="about_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>How do I get into the Dead City? I have an idea. I'll go see the Wanderers in the Swamps. Grieg says he has a stash in the Dead City. He certainly should know how to get there. Oh and then there is the Swamp Doctor, first I need to get to the Swamps, but how?</text>
  </string> 
      <string id="about_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>Good idea you should talk to him. You'll have to go to the scientists in Yantar. They may know a safe path to the Swamps, and perhaps even to the Dead City.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="about_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood and thank you! I'm going to Yantar now.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="about_magomet_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't forget you agreed to deliver a letter to Barkeep at the Cordon.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="about_magomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Do not worry I'll take it. See you soon!</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day! Are you Mahomet?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>No no, I'm Fima. Who are you and why are you seeking Mahomet?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I need to talk to Mahomet about a personal matter. Sidorovich told me I could find him here, and that he had an arranged meeting with someone, probably with you.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah, so that's it. Yes Mahomet was here and we did have a meeting. But you're a little late Mahomet has left. Where he went I do not know.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Shit! How was it that I was late, oh well? I really need to speak with Mahomet. Are you really sure you don't know how to find him? I'll pay for good information.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_5">
    <text>No I don't want your money. I really don't know where he's headed. Mahomet doesn't say much, he's a loner. Sidorovich told me that a Stalker called Strelok was seeking a rendezvous with Mahomet. So there you are.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, that's me. What am I going to do now I can't even imagine.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_7">
    <text>You'll survive. I told Mahomet about you Strelok, that you were desperate to meet with him. But Mahomet could not wait so he went away. He will find you. As the saying goes: 'If you can't bring the mountain to Mahomet, then bring Mahomet to the mountain'. So don't worry!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_8">
    <text>How will he find me? Do I have to sit and wait in one place?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_9">
    <text>Believe me he'll find you! You just don't know Mahomet. If he says so, he'll find you. Moreover he said that he's heard a lot about your exploits and he was not averse to meeting you.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="drug_magomet_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay I understand. I really hope that he finds me. Thank you. Be that as it may. See you later.</text>
  </string> 
      
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Leila!</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Long time no see Strelok. Were you successful? Did you find your brother?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>No I haven't found him yet, but I will. I'm here about another matter.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>And what brings you to us?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>I do not know where to begin. I was slightly aware of your relationship with Clear Sky. I even learnt about your sister Karina. Okay, more to the point. Sviblov has sent me here. Karina went missing a few days ago. She's just vanished.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>What are you talking about?! She was here with a guide. They left here three days ago. Has she not returned to the Radar?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>No, she did not return. Sviblov sent people to search for them, but they vanished.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>Sviblov, that idiot! Never liked him. Things are not going smoothly in my relations with Clear Sky, but he could at least have told me about my sister. That schmuck! As if evil is not enough, we have to deal with stalkers like him.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay don't get angry. Which way did they go back?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>She said she knew the way. She and a guide went to the Forest. There is a path from there to the Radar. She said that it's no more than a mile, and then, it's on the edge of the woods, supposedly a safe place somewhere near Forester's hut. I wonder what happened there? We need to find someone who knows. My people don't know the area, and they have never been to the Forest.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_10">
    <text>I'll tell you what: since I volunteered to help in the search for your sister, then I'll go to the Forest if that helps. The territory is familiar to me, especially since that's where Forester lives. And the hunters are there, they may know something. By the way, is the path into the woods at the same place?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_11">
    <text>Yes, the passage to the Forest is still at the same place and still being used. Here, just in case, I'll mark your PDA with the beginning of the transition. Please, I beg of you, as soon as you find something about my sister, let me know in any way. Deal?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="leila_karina_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes of course. I'm leaving for the Forest now.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Forester. It's been a long time.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you Strelok. How goes your search?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>No luck so far, but there is still hope. I need to find a skilled Digger named Mahomet. He may be able to shed some light on this whole complicated and mystical story about my brother. By the way, do you know that Digger, or where I can find him?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>No my son, I've never heard of him. What brings you to visit an old man in the Forest again?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>Well first to visit you and see how you are doing, and secondly something has happened. A girl Has gone missing, Leila's sister. She and her guide went from the Dead City to the Radar by way of the Forest. They have been missing for three days now. Nothing has been heard or seen of them since. Do you know anything about it?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>No, I have not seen a girl. Ask the Hunters, they are still here. They've stayed longer this time, maybe they wanted to gather more tails and hooves, or maybe something else.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="lesnik_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>Well thank you. I'll go to the Hunters and see if they know anything, they may be able to help me find Leila's sister.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Slouch, long time no see.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok, yes it has been a while. Have you decided to join us or are you on other business?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>I've done enough hunting while I've been in the Zone searching for my brother.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>Well then tell us why you're here.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm searching for a missing girl. Three days ago, she and her guide left the Dead City for the Radar, by way of the Forest. They never arrived. Do you know anything, did you see them?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>Listen, I'll come straight to the point. Just yesterday evening, Greek and Mazai went to the swamp looking for dog's tails, when they returned, they say they saw from a distance, three people. It seemed like two old hags, and a girl with them. They walked along the road towards them, and then turned to the right. Well, Greek and Mazai decided that they were locals, from the nearest village on the outskirts of the forest who had wandered in. They did not approach them, we try not to interfere. Although, they say, something seemed a little bit strange, a young girl like that being with them.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>Where did they see these three?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>Close by, come on, I'll mark the place on your PDA. There's an abandoned trailer and a broken armoured personnel carrier there, you'll find the place easily.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Thank you, I will go and catch up with them.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sutuly_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>Cheers Strelok.</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="babka_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello you ugly old skank.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="babka_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello dear little rude handsome man. What brings you here?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="babka_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for a girl, her name is Karina. The Hunters told me that they recently saw a young girl in the company of two older women. I understand that you are one of them.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="babka_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, you filthy beast! You want a girl? Well we have what you want. We have a girl, young and beautiful. She's cheap, only 3,000 rubles. Come and amuse yourself with her, relax. She's very pretty, you will not regret it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="babka_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you mean! I did not come for that. I have a job to find a girl named Karina. I have to talk to her. Let me go in, I need to see if she is Karina.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="babka_dialog_5">
    <text>O-oh, my dear, you're so cunning. Look, speaking to her will cost you. You're so sly. First you pay, and then come in and do what you want with her. Our Grand-daughter is affectionate and responsive. If you don't agree my sister will blow your damn head off! So you will pay?</text>
  </string>
     <string id="babka_dialog_6">
    <text>I have no money now. I'll try to get some from the Hunters.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="babka_dialog_7">
    <text>Well to hell with you, you pervert. That'll cost me three thousand rubles.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="babka_dialog_8">
    <text>Here take it!</text>
  </string>

    <string id="karina_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello Karina.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_1">
    <text>O-oh, my head hurts ... what's wrong with me?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't worry, it'll soon pass. You must drink some Vodka, it helps.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_3">
    <text>And who are you? Where am I?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Don't worry, I'm a friend. You were captured by controllers, they decided to use you as bait. But now all is well. They no longer exist. My name is Strelok. I came for you. I was sent by Sviblov.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_5">
    <text>Lord I'm all in a daze ... who is ... Sviblov? And where am I now?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_6">
    <text>You are in the Forest. You came from the Dead City, your sister is Leila, and you were going to the Radar with your guide. Do you remember that?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes, now I remember ... the guide ... it’s the same ... he was killed by these creatures! There, on the hill. Only he knew the way.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes, I understand. Don't know you how to get back from the Forest to the Radar?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_9">
    <text>Am I a Stalker or a Digger? Of course I do not know!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_10">
    <text>Well I thought as much. But we need to get out of here. Do you have any thoughts? I know there is a path to the Military Warehouses somewhere. Do you know where?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_11">
    <text>No, no not there, there are enemies about. We must find the body of the guide. He should have in his pocket a PDA with the encrypted data of the Secret Paths. I know the code. If we find the PDA we can get out of the woods somehow. We should look. Come on I'll show the place where these creatures had attacked us, I remember now. Get me to the place, and then I'll should remember where to look.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_help_dialog_12">
    <text>Well let's go. Oh, by the way, you have a nice ass.</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_0">
    <text>Is this the place?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I remember now, this is where the guide was killed. While I was still conscious I saw that he was dragged down somewhere. There must be some kind of cave, I guess. I think so ... look on the slope. We need to find the corpse of the guide and pick up his PDA, otherwise let's get out of here. I'm scared!</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay I'll try to find him, wait here and don't be afraid. If anything happens, just scream, then I come to the rescue.</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I have found the guide's body.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Did you find his PDA?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, here take it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Let us look, where these paths from the Forest exist.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Well, have you found it?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Don't rush me ... yeah, here goes: you can get out of the Forest, but only to the Swamps. You can't get to the Radar from here. Okay, I'm sick of everything, my sister and Sviblov. I'm bored with them, always squabbling among themselves like dogs. I'll go to the Doctor. He's a good man. Moreover, I have helped him in his clinic. So I've decided. Let's go to the Swamps, to the Doctor!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_pda_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Well to the Swamps we go. Lead on my beauty.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="karina_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>All right all right don't be afraid. The creature is dead. Apparently it was quietly following us all the way here. Well! What have we here, the transition to the Swamps?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>U-uh, I cannot describe my fear. Yes the transition is here. There's a hole beside me to the left, you have to go down there. Where you end up in the Swamps is unknown. Every time you go through you will end up at a different place. Let's agree, you go first, and if I don't appear within a minute, I'll meet you at the Swamp Doctor's house. Oh and I may not have thanked you for my salvation, I'm sorry...ah ... well... thank you Strelok! You saved my ass.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>Don't mention it. To save your ass was a pleasure! By the way, I had to pay 3,000 rubles for your release. After I killed the skanks I forgot to retrieve the money. Buggers!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>So I was cheap, huh. Well maybe I will give you a reward later. Okay then it's time to go.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, sounds good, let's not waste any more time.</text>
  </string>  
  
   <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_0">
    <text>Karina you've arrived before me. I am glad to see you are safe.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_1">
    <text>I was thrown out right near the gazebo in front of the Doctor's house. Shame there wasn't a hammock to land in rather that on the wooden floor. What took you so long?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_2">
    <text>I found myself in the southern part of the Swamps, so to get here it was necessary to swim. Though time is short, I'm soaked through and I need to dry off. We have much to do.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_3">
    <text>No, things can wait and we need to rest. This is probably the most peaceful place in the entire Zone. I probably will stay here at the Doctor's. I'll help him.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_4">
    <text>What about Sviblov and Leila? They're worried about you. I have to inform Sviblov that you are alive and well.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry, the Doctor will communicate the news to Leila through Grieg, as for Sviblov I'll contact him later.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay. But listen, how do I get out of the Swamps?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_7">
    <text>That's between you and the Doctor. Ask him.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="karina_bolota_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay I'll talk to him. See ya!</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Doctor.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you Strelok. Thank you for saving Karina, she briefly told me about your adventures.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_2">
    <text>It was nothing. I've been in tougher scrapes. Besides, I don't pass up a nice ass.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_3">
    <text>Well Strelok, a Stalker like you I have not seen before. You have a brave heart, a kind soul, and pure thoughts. These qualities are not often seen in the Zone.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you for the compliment Doctor, now I have a question for you. How do I get out of the Swamps to somewhere close to the Bar?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_5">
    <text>I can help you. I have a guide dog named Mongrel. He will show you to one of the most secret and longest paths of the Zone. A transition from the Swamps through to the Dead City and down to Military Warehouses. This path was opened by my loyal friend and guide Pathfinder. But first I ask that you do one thing for me.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_6">
    <text>I'll listen to you carefully, Doctor.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_7">
    <text>In the southern part of the Swamps, in one of the old wooden houses, I installed a transmitter and antenna there. This is the best part of the bog for receiving a signal. Well in recent years three times the antenna broke, it had never happened before. The first time I went out to repair it, and a second time to fix everything. Well I think the wind or birds break it. Relocated the transmitter to another location and again the same thing. I went there a third time and there is no transmitter. I walked around and found it in a different place. I had a feeling that someone was watching me, I looked back, turned around and saw no one. I listened and heard some barely distinguishable sounds like a quietly sobbing child. Certainly not a bird, then I thought, maybe water? The whole problem could be rain. I had long not been afraid of any living creatures, but then ... in short, I quickly moved it again and put the transmitter and antenna in another location and left. But shortly before your arrival with Karina, again the same old song.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_8">
    <text>Sounds like devilry!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_9">
    <text>That's what I thought ... Well Strelok I beg you to go and find a reason for who or what keeps breaking my antenna. Get the transmitter. I'm sick of this mysticism. Although there is a signal, but not a very good one, I'm better off with Grieg's contacts at the Wanderers checkpoint. It will make me feel better. Strelok, I'll mark in your PDA where my transmitter is located.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay I'll go take a look to see what's happening and I'll bring back your instrument. I'm out of here!</text>
  </string>

    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I'm back Doctor. You were right when you suggested that it could be water.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_1">
    <text>I don't understand, Strelok. What do you mean?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_2">
    <text>In the place where you installed the receiver there were these little creepy spirit creatures wandering around in the water. Almost invisible, instead of blood they have acid, horrible.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So that's the reason. How many more miracles are in store for us today in the Zone? Anyway have you retrieved the unit?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_karina_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes, here's your instrument, take it.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Doctor can your guide dog lead me to the Dead City now?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes Strelok. Now you can go. The guide dog will lead you. Just remember to find a way back from the Military Warehouses to the Swamps. I'm sure it will come in handy later. You'll have to talk to Pathfinder, give to him this flash drive, he will understand and show you the path. That's all. And now as the saying goes, follow the 'White Rabbit'. My dog is waiting for you in the gazebo near the house, it will take you to the place where the path begins. Take care of it, make sure nothing happens to him, this is a very valuable dog. I found it as a puppy, tamed and nurtured its instincts as a guide. It is an unrivalled seeker of the Secret Paths. Oh and note that it is very dangerous out in that area where you are going. Make sure Mongrel survives.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay Doctor. I will seek Pathfinder and will give him the flash drive. I got to go!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="doctor_povodyr_dialog_3">
    <text>Goodbye Strelok, go with God!</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Pathfinder!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_1">
    <text>What do you want Strelok?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_2">
    <text>I've brought you something from the Swamp Doctor.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_3">
    <text>You saw the Doctor at the Swamps? How did you get there?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_4">
    <text>It's a long story. I had to bail someone out of trouble. The Doctor sends you this flash drive. Here take it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_5">
    <text>Let us look, what's here... aha, I see. And what else did he say?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_0">
    <text>He said that you could show me a secret path from Military Warehouses through the Swamps to the Dead City. I've just come from there, but I need to get back.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_1">
    <text>Well since the Doctor helped you then I'll help you. This path is very convenient and can greatly prove to be useful. But there's one thing, to open this route is possible only with the help of the very rare artifact, called a 'Superconductor'. It has ability to displace time and space, thus creating space corridors, so-called Secret Paths, through which you can navigate previously inaccessible routes. It differs from its 'little brother transitions', the conductors of a lower order that activates the transitions on several routes. To activate it you just pick it up. For one thing to find this artifact is extremely difficult. It appears for only a short period of time, approximately for an hour, somewhere between one and two o'clock in the morning. If you do not find it in this time period then the artifact vanishes. So that's it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_2">
    <text>Very interesting. I will try to find this 'Superconductor'. Painfully, finding the pathway is important; it's sure to come in handy in the future. Can you at least give a rough idea where I might find one?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_3">
    <text>Well, if the path you want to open begins in Military Warehouses, then you'll have to look around there. I've only ever found one in the Zone. Possibly look in the swamp or in the gully behind the abandoned farm. Precisely where to look is hard to say, but I think probably, in the almost inaccessible places. Just remember, time is limited for searching, just one hour, between one and two in the morning. If you find it, bring it to me and I'll open your transition to the Swamps through the Dead City. You have only three maybe four days to find it. If you don't find it in that time you'll have to wait a month to search again. So don't waste any time.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_post_4">
    <text>Everything is clear. Yeah a small problem, but I'll solve it. I'll find a 'Superconductor' and bring it to you.</text>
  </string>  

    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello Pathfinder!</text>		<!-- Guide or Pathfinder -->
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_1">
    <text>What new Strelok?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I found a 'Superconductor'. Look!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wow! You're really an experienced searcher. Come on let's see where this trail from the Military Warehouses begins.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sverhprovodnik_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Take it.</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_0">
    <text>What's the matter Barkeep?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_1">
    <text>While you were gone, I agreed with Sidorovich to muscle out another big business man. Only a few details remain. All the former strife I had with him is in the past. We are now friends. In short, Strelok, we need your help. If we succeed you'll get a very large reward for your labour.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_2">
    <text>What do I need to do?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_3">
    <text>I can't give you all the details yet, but one of the most important conditions for our case is the support of Duty. I have agreed to almost everything with General Voronin. Now we need to meet with Sidorovich personally. The meeting is scheduled for the near future at the Peacekeeping Corps in an abandoned village. Sidorovich most certainly will have bodyguards. I also need one with me, someone I can trust. You are the best candidate.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_4">
    <text>You want me to accompany you to the meeting with Sidorovich, right?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes yes, but first I ask you take this encrypted note to Voronin in the Dark Valley and give it to him personally. You will need to secretly go to Peacekeeping Corps, and it's not necessary to go through the checkpoint down here, and they don't need to know you're there. Then go from the Peacekeeping Corps back to the Dark Valley after our meeting. Remember, Voronin will tell you of a secret path back when you give him my message. And I will already be on my way. I know a short path to the Peacekeepers. I'll see you there near the abandoned village. I’ll let you know exactly when to leave the Dark Valley. I'll send a message to your PDA. Understand?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_zapiska_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, okay. Give me the letter, I'll go to Voronin.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>General, I have a coded letter from Barkeep.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Glad to see you Strelok. You're just like a spy these days.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>Barkeep encrypted it. He says it's very secret, and that nobody should know.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_3">
    <text>Yeah, he started a venture with Sidorovich, big freak'n deal. It just so happens that we have an interest in this case. Therefore from time to time my people will be involved. No one should know anything, otherwise it will fail.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand everything, so I won't bombard you with questions. Take the message from Barkeep. Incidentally, Barkeep said that you would show me a path out of the Dark Valley to the Peacekeeping Corps.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, here I'll mark your PDA with the location of the transition point.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo_dialog_6">
    <text>Here's the PDA, mark it, and I'll go.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="barman_strelka_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Barkeep, where are we going?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_strelka_dialog_1">
    <text>Stay close, follow me. While I'm talking to Sidorovich, you're not to talk or listen. When I'm finished I'll tell you what to do next. All clear?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_strelka_dialog_2">
    <text>Copy that! Wasting time here!</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="barman_posle_dialog_0">
    <text>Well is everything okay?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_posle_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, all the issues were discussed. Soon everything will be decided.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_posle_dialog_2">
    <text>What's the next step?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_posle_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen to me carefully. I still need to talk to Sidorovich face to face about something, and you need to go back to Voronin and give him another letter, the last one. In it are the final instructions as they say, and passwords for our common cause. Then later I will go to see Duty. Sidorovich is to take my place in the bunker at the Cordon. This is the first step in our plan. Once you give Voronin the message he will give you an answer for Sidorovich. By then Sidorovich should be at the Cordon. Take him the answer and he will say what to do next. Okay?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_posle_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes everything is clear. I'll go to Voronin.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello General.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_1">
    <text>Well Strelok how are things?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes everything seems fine. Barkeep met Sidorovich in an abandoned village at the Peacekeeping Corps. I understand they had finally discussed all the details. Here's another coded message from Barkeep explaining the overall plans. You're to read it, then send a response to Sidorovich. He has moved to the Cordon. Barkeep has said that he'll meet with you soon.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_3">
    <text>Give me the message. Let's see what these sly dogs are proposing.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_4">
    <text>Here's the letter General.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's see what Barkeep has to say ... ah, they both offer ... it is clear, understandable. Okay, so let's try ... Strelok here is my answer to Sidorovich. Take it to him at the Cordon.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="voronin_pismo2_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes sir, General.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Sidorovich! You have a new store, congratulations!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks, but I need to do a stock inventory first, and it wouldn't hurt to tidy the place up a bit. After a couple of days I can start trading. Have you brought a response from Voronin?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes of course. Here's the letter.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's see what our gallant General writes. Well, very good! Voronin is ready to begin. Well it's time for great achievements.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_4">
    <text>Have you finished with me? Barkeep promised me a reward.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_5">
    <text>Wait a minute Strelok the deal has not been finalized. The most difficult part still lies ahead of us, and we really need your help.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_6">
    <text>And what do I have to do?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, I'll explain everything so that you understand the importance of what's happening. Earlier on Barkeep and I had bitter disputes over influential matters. He always claimed that I lured away his clients and underestimated the price of goods and so on. I, in turn, also had a list of claims. Working in this spirit had become unbearable, and Barkeep took the first step and proposed the following: I move to the Cordon and do fair trading in his old place. Some of his clients will be automatically transferred to me. He in turn was eager to move to the Bar. But as you know it has long been run by bandits. He then came up with a cunning plan to get rid of them.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_8">
    <text>And what is it? The Bandits are well entrenched in the Bar.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_9">
    <text>Just recently there has emerged a new militant group called Duty who would want to make a strong base at the Bar. But until they defeat the bandits they cannot. They can't do it single-handedly. Barkeep did not have connections among the Dutiers to get them to join forces. I at the time was a caterer for Voronin and his men, and had earned their respect. Barkeep asked me to discuss his plan with Voronin. The three of us talked and decided to work together. Barkeep will arrange the movement of a secret Duty strike force in the northern deserted area of the Bar, and I'll organize diversionary tactics against the Mercenaries at the southern outpost. The Bandits and their hirelings the Mercenaries will surely put up a good fight. Then a surprise attack from the north and the capture of the Bar by Duty, and Barkeep can take his rightful place at the Bar.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_10">
    <text>Look at what you've stirred up. Holy shit! Feel free to tell me more. What do you need from me?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_11">
    <text>Strelok you are actually the key person in this. We don't have enough details to carry out this plan. For a successful attack we need a detailed map of the Bar. You need to have someone draw you one, and you, as far as we know, have a good reputation among the lads, right? So please get us a map of the Bar and pass it to the Duty assault squad commander, Sergeant Plichko. The lads in the Bar have started to respect you more so they will help you overcome the Mercenaries at the southern checkpoint.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_12">
    <text>You guys have drawn me into some kind of feud! Okay I can dig it! Where do I get the Bar map, or are you suggesting that I survey the area and draw one up?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_13">
    <text>Firstly just listen. The plan is awesome. We thought of everything to the last detail. Borov has a map that's for sure. Once you help to eradicate the southern checkpoint of the Mercenaries suggest to Borov to strengthen both checkpoints and to protect against further such dangers. Tell him that you have friends, former construction workers, professional engineers, who at best can organize and budget. The Bandits won't help you, but if they offer, then be happy to accept, though they are scumbags they're not stupid. Tell Borov that to do everything properly, you need a map of his territory, which you supposedly need to plot the necessary dimensions and calculate all the details. He will be happy to give you the map.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_14">
    <text>Okay, you've talked me into it. I'll help you. I hope the reward will be decent.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_15">
    <text>Well that's good! So it's a deal. Now go to the Bar and see Borov. I'll let you know when to give Duty the go-ahead. When you get the map leave through the northern checkpoint and go to the right towards the Military Warehouses transition. Wait there for the Duty detachment and give the map to the Duty commander.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_16">
    <text>What have I become involved in, eh? One cannot escape the fact that many will be killed. There at the Bar I have many friends. We ought to warn them of the impending slaughter so that they can escape in the confusion.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_17">
    <text>Strelok if you're talking about Earl and Pathfinder then you need not worry. They are in the know. With Earl's help we succeeded in inciting an attack on the Mercenaries at the southern checkpoint. If you have any business left with these two do it now as most likely you won't be able to find them later in the Bar.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_poslanie_dialog_18">
    <text>Okay I'll go.</text>
  </string>
  
  <string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Something else?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, there was a person who came to me, he was looking for you.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_2">
    <text>Who was he?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_3">
    <text>It's a surprise! He's waiting for you at the entrance to my bunker.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_magomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, I love surprises.</text>
  </string>  

    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_0">
    <text>Something else?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes Strelok. Intelligence has it that you did something wrong at the Peacekeepers, that you stole a bulletproof vest. I was also told that something has happened to my old sidekick Mahomet.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_2">
    <text>Shit! I am looking for him. What happened?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_3">
    <text>Because they're always running into ambushes, once anyone steals Peacekeepers armour, they will have a seething hatred for you. But Mahomet was just someone who showed me the path to the Dark Valley, the same one I told you about. And you, apparently for a trophy, have led them to the transition. Did you take it?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes I did, but I had no other choice then!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_5">
    <text>You always have a choice Strelok. You just don't want to think about it. Because of this, a good man has died. The Peacekeepers killed him in their ambush. He ran and got shot in the forehead. He was out there waiting for you Strelok and was caught by accident.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="sidor_nomagomet_dialog_6">
    <text>Damn it I’m sorry about Mahomet, forgive me. Now I cannot find my brother.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello and who are you?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I am Mahomet. Didn't you expect to meet me here Strelok?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Damn! We finally meet! I've sought for a long time, Mahomet!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You were told I would find you, and now I have. So tell me why are you looking for me?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I have a very important task Mahomet. I'm looking for my brother, his name is Captain. Several years ago he was a member of a group which first attempted to enter the Sarcophagus at the Chernobyl NPP. With him were a few courageous Stalkers, including Yuri Semetsky. I have information that you have since met Semetsky, who was alive and unharmed. So, if Semetsky is still alive, then perhaps my brother is also alive, because they were the two from the group that went inside the Sarcophagus. Tell me what you know about it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_5">
    <text>So that's it, Strelok! Actually, no one believes me that I have seen Semetsky alive, but it's true, and I met him twice. The first time was about one-and-a-half years ago. I saw a glimpse of him briefly in the forest at the Radar. He looked, well, not real. Whether it was a Zombie or a person, I couldn't tell, but it was him, I'm sure. There in the forest, it's full of anomalies and mutants, and he quickly disappeared somewhere.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_6">
    <text>When was the second time?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_7">
    <text>The second time was more recent, about two months ago. I was in Pripyat at the abandoned hospital. I was taking a small group of stalkers through the hospital on our way back from Pripyat to Yantar. That's where I met him and ... yes, his appearance was not for the faint-hearted. There was little left of him that was human, a walking corpse. He didn't let me get close to him. He muttered something about the Monolith, that they have long been held hostage by some 'dark forces' and their own stupidity. He said that he must fulfill his mission to destroy this 'evil stone'. In short, some kind of nonsense ... yes, I thought, he's not talking to me, but to himself. So if you want to find out what actually happened many years ago with your brother then you need to find Semetsky and somehow try to talk to him. Only he can help you.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_8">
    <text>Yeah, the story ... What do you think, where can I find him?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_9">
    <text>I think at the Chernobyl NPP, in the Sarcophagus. As I understood from his words, he is going to go there. Carry out his crazy mission.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Back to the Sarcophagus ... Yeah, it's a disastrous place, but I can't do anything about it, I'll have to go. There's just one more thing to finish here, with a bit of luck, I'll learn something.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_11">
    <text>Well, good luck to you Strelok. I'm glad we met.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="magomet_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Thank you for everything, Mahomet, it's time to go.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="barman_new_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, Barkeep! Well, it feels good.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_new_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, my friend, you have helped us, thank you!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_new_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, your thanks is not enough.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_new_dialog_3">
    <text>Don't be offended, I have not forgotten my promise to reward you generously. Here, take this from us all for your invaluable assistance - a hundred thousand in cash and a VKS snipers rifle.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="barman_new_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, that's really generous. Thank you!</text>
  </string>

    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello gorgeous!</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_1">
    <text>You're funny Strelok, such a flirt.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, the Zombies are dead. Life is getting better!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_3">
    <text>Thank you Strelok you helped us get rid of the Zombies once again, but we are moving away from the Dead City.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_4">
    <text>Why? Is something wrong?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_5">
    <text>No, it's just became too dangerous here. The City has now become not so dead. It's continually filling with crawling Zombies. In short we're leaving, we’ve had enough.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_6">
    <text>Fine, but I don't think that you're in danger from Zombies. There's something else here isn't there?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_7">
    <text>Yes Strelok, you’re almost right. We are leaving the Zone. We’ve had it. Now we can tell you the truth. We were looking for a very rare artefact, a 'Compass'. This artefact could have helped thousands of people to get rid of terrible diseases, but we could not find it. Apparently it does not exist, it was all a legend. So good-bye, but don't think badly of us. As for a reward for helping us we have nothing to give you.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="mg_nechist_dialog_8">
    <text>C'mon do not worry Leila. Farewell I must go now.</text>
  </string>   

    <string id="kristall_dialog_0">
    <text>I came for my brother!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_1">
    <text>That there Stalker, is no longer you brother. He has been freed from all superfluous and mundane things, an enlightened mind now. A mind that is capable of performing miracles, a mind that can rule the world.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother! I know you're there ... you're inside. Fight it! They took your mind, but you're a man! Fight back!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_3">
    <text>Stupid monkey. You cannot change anything! Go away and don't bother us. I suggest to you, before death, to see and enjoy this great spectacle. Soon we will begin our presentation. It won't be long. This will be a big show, the celebration of the force of the liberated mind!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_4">
    <text>Brother, wake up!! Wake up, Captain!! I know you can hear me! It's me, Strelok!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't waste your energy, it's all in vain before his death. It's far better to relax and enjoy this great and grand spectacle. After today, the world will be different.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="kristall_dialog_6">
    <text>I didn't come here just to surrender and observe, it's not that simple! I've learnt too much. Here Captain, catch! This is a 'Compass', with regards from Semetsky!</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="brat_dialog_0">
    <text>Brother, it's you!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, little-one, you've found me. Boy am I glad to see you! How did you find me?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother we can talk about it later. I also have lots of questions for you, but first we must get out of here real fast.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_3">
    <text>Little-one, I'm too weak to go anywhere now ... my head, my head ... is ringing like a bell ... legs ... my legs are weak. Listen to me brother, there is practically no time. The fact you set me free from this captivity does not change anything. The process of the regeneration of the Zone has already begun. All you've done is delayed its start. Go on save yourself! My place still seems to be here. Go brother one of us has to stay alive and get out of this damned Zone! Not far from here at the northern gate, there is a transition to Chernobyl-2. There you should take the road out of here. At least I hope you do.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_4">
    <text>No Captain I will not give up! Hear me now, I have a one-time personal Teleporter which can teleport you from any place in the Zone to the Swamps, to the Swamp Doctor. Therefore the plan is this, you take the instrument and teleport to the Doctor, you need his care right now. I will come later. I'll get out, do not worry. I got in here that means I can get back out.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_5">
    <text>Strelok, you don't understand who you're dealing with! They won't just let you leave, believe me, I know what I'm talking about. Time's running out.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_6">
    <text>Captain, let’s not waste precious minutes! Take the personal teleporter and go to the Doctor, I'll be alright. Don't worry! I have an idea.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="brat_dialog_7">
    <text>Little-One, you've grown up. You are no longer a young romantic, you have become an adult, a soldier. I can see the fire in your eyes. Okay, so be it, I'll do as you suggest. But please do not get involved in anything, just run and don't look back. Go to Chernobyl-2, somewhere near the northern gate there is a portal. Oh, my heart feels for you. They will not just let you go. Okay, give me the teleporter and I'll go. God bless you my child! Time is running out - the sooner we begin...</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="brat_dialog_8">
    <text>Here take this personal teleporter and I'll see you brother.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="end_dialog_0">
    <text>Wtf!</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="end_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello again! Unexpected, yes? We had warned you not to waste your time and energy on dubious activities. Have you really thought that here in the Zone you can make decisions and act independently?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="end_dialog_2">
    <text>I always make my own decisions and act on what my heart and mind tells me!</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="end_dialog_3">
    <text>I'm afraid in this regard we have a different opinion. Oh well. You freed your brother, that's good, well done! So it was planned. For now you've delayed the Great emission, but there is nothing to worry about.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="end_dialog_4">
    <text>What do you mean, it was planned?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="end_dialog_5">
    <text>That means that you have once again proved your great power, though you were not clever enough to run away from us. Well that's good! And your brother ... we don't need him anymore, he has fulfilled his life. Now you will take his place!!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="end_dialog_6">
    <text>Noooooo!!!</text>
  </string>  

    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good day! Are you Sorcerer?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_1">
    <text>That's right, Stalker. What's brought you here?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I was told that you can revive the dead. I do not particularly believe in it, but for interest sake, I came here to find out.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You were not fooled, it is true. Here in the Zone there are more miracles than you ever dreamed of. Virtually every person who dies within areas of abnormal activity, I can bring back to life, or rather create a clone. However, it won't actually be human, but a Zombie. But most importantly though, his mind and memory, for a while, will be in the state that it was before his death.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Is this really possible? But how?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_5">
    <text>How - this is not your concern. I was 'on the other side of the world' and came back with such knowledge. So if you want to return the dead to this world, I am ready to help you. Only it will not come cheap. The cost of my 'work' - 100,000 rubles. And yet, to resurrect the man you request, is possible only if it does not kill you, okay?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_start_dialog_6">
    <text>I understood everything. If I suddenly need to revive someone, at least for a time, then I am sure I will return.</text>
  </string>
  
      <string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive a dead man called Noodles.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Noodles to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little 'out of it'. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lapsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Miser.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Miser to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little 'out of it'. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_skryaga_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>
    
    <string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Screw.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Screw to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little 'out of it'. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_shurup_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Lukash.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Lucas to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little 'out of it'. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_lukash_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>  
    
    <string id="koldun_dan_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Dan.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_dan_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Dan to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a 'little out of it'. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_dan_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_dan_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Lefty.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Lefty to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little out of it. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_levsha_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive the dead, a man known as Sviblov.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Sviblov to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little out of it. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_sviblov_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_0">
    <text>Sorcerer, I need to revive a dead stalker called Snitch.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, I knew that. Give me 100,000 rubles and I will return Snitch to this world. He will appear right here, close by, so do not be alarmed. For a while he will be a little confused. After a few minutes you will be able to talk to him normally.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, I don't have enough money on me. I need to raise some more.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="koldun_osvedom_dialog_3">
    <text>Agreed. Here, take this money.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, Screw!</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok. What do you need?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_2">
    <text>I want to recharge a homemade flamethrower from Baker.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, let's try, but you understand, is not free.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_4">
    <text>How much are you asking for the job?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, firstly, to recharge this flamethrower I need one bottle of colloidal gas and a canister of gasoline. Secondly, for my work, a modest fee: two bottles of Vodka and 10,000 rubles. Is that Ok? If yes, give me the flamethrower, I'll start preparing for the recharge, and you go get what I need and bring it all back. Then I can recharge it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I won't haggle with you. Take the flamethrower and I will get what is required and will return. Don't go anywhere!</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Screw, I've brought what you need to recharge the flamethrower.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_est_1">
    <text>That's good. Have you got the money and Vodka for me?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes all of it.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well let's have it and I can begin recharging your flamethrower.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="zapravka_flame_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here take it.</text>
  </string>    

    <string id="vano_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you awake Vano?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh dear! How do you know me? What's your name?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well the whole area knows about Vano - the most notorious boozer and brawler - a useless person. My name is Strelok.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Hey Strelok why are people saying bad things about Vano, eh? What have I done wrong? Vano is kind and cheerful. He hurts no one.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Look at you, you're a drunk - it will kill you if you don't stop drinking. Baker - he's a good guy, he cares about you, but it up you to change. There are many serious jobs he would like to give you, but he can't, he doesn't trust you..</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Come on friend, I'll show them, Vano is in control of the situation. Vano is not a harsh person. Vano soon will go to Freedom, there Vano feels at home. Vano misses the place...</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_6">
    <text>You wouldn't get a kilometre; you’re better off just putting a bullet in your head and be done with it. Freedom - these guys are serious, they don't tolerate rabble.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_7">
    <text>Vano not rabble! Vano is a Scout. Vano spent a whole week stalking Marauder whores. Vano found something very important.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_8">
    <text>And what did Vano find that is so important?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_9">
    <text>Don't mock me. Vano pursued the Marauders from the very base of the Peacekeepers. They had stolen a Peacekeeper's box of mines and were carrying it to the abandoned village. But they didn't get there ... in the swamp they were chased by some sort of phantom creatures... If Vano had an automatic weapon, then I would have dealt with them, so I just hid and watched, as they skedaddled out, dropping the loot.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Well have to go pick up that box and return it to the Peacekeepers. These guys are generous and reward well.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_11">
    <text>No no! Peacekeepers are evil; they once did something bad to Vano. Vano does not like them. This is what Vano proposes: you're the one with the weapon, Vano has none and is scared and a little sick. So now you go to that eerie swamp, find the box and bring it to Vano. Vano will take this box to Freedom. Doing this, Vano will gain some respect. Well, will you bring it? Vano will be in your debt forever and I will give part of the contents of the box. Vano is an honest man.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, to hell with you. Give me a marker as to where to search for this box and I will go.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_13">
    <text>That's good! It's simple, the swamp is not far from here. Vano can put a marker on your map. You should look for the box in the swamp near an old sunken row boat, it's not deep there. Look down in the water. Look Strelok, just be careful out there. And on the way back be careful as well because there are constantly Marauders nearby. Although they are cowardly creatures many of them are dangerous.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_14">
    <text>Give me a marker so I can go find the box of mines in the swamp.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="vano_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Enough drinking, Vano. You'll die from too much vodka.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, you're right Strelok, I must give up drinking.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I found the box of mines in the swamp. On the way back I ran into some Marauders. I should have dealt with them, we've brought Baker some trouble.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Holy shit! Jackpot! Give them to me; I will give you two kinds of mines, five of each. If you want, you can secretly mine the entire base of these freaks - the Peacekeepers. That would be fun to watch, as those bastards soar into the air! But you must first read the instructions for how to use them.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="vano_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thanks for the wise advice, yes you could do it to the Peacekeepers, but I advise you not to. Okay, keep the box of mines.</text>
  </string>  
  
    <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Stalker, have you recovered?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, you sewer rat! You're a cowardly creature, you only know how to sneak up from behind.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_2">
    <text>You're behaving like a juvenile, Stalker! The only reason you're still alive, is because we have a very important question for you. As you've probably noticed, we have your swag. Do you want peace, and your belongings returned? Well, we want that box that you pulled from the swamp, it belongs to us.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_3">
    <text>Had you met me face to face you louse we would have worked out who's who.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_4">
    <text>I see! You're half a step from death, and you show impudence. Are you a fearless hero or what? Huh?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="maroder_meet_dialog_5">
    <text>Asshole!</text>
  </string>
  
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_0">
    <text>You call me an asshole. What's next, some sort of heroics?</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Oh, you bastard! Well let's finish this. What do I need to do?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_2">
    <text>That is another matter. So listen here: I understand that you can easily walk in to the Peacekeepers base, right? I know for sure you can. So, you can fetch for us two SCAT-11M bullet-proof vests, from the Peacekeepers. Finding things is in your genes. The body armour should be in a house that is close to the entrance to the base. I'll mark its location on your PDA. I don't think that the Peacekeepers will just let you go, if they see you steal their body armour. So here's my advice to you: after you take the body armour, find a different way out of the base, or be shot by the Peacekeepers. There is another way out. I don't think you want to fight with them, but that's your problem. And don't try to scam us - you'll regret it!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay you rat, I'll get what you asked for. Just take care of my stuff.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes hombre, you've got work to do. But there’s more. Don't interfere with Baker anymore, we'll kill you on the spot. He is our client. We have been watching him for some time. Soon a parcel will arrive for him and then the bunker will be history. So if you get it in your head to warn him, you will die.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes I understand everything. I'll be back!.</text>
  </string> 

    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well the hero returns. Have you brought the two SCAT-11M body armours?</text>
  </string>
      <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_1">
    <text>I've brought them.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_2">
    <text>That's good. Give them here.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Where are my possessions?</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Like I said they're being guarded. Give me the armour!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Okay, here's the body armour, take it. Now give me my suit and weapons.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Well, you're a dickhead, man!</text>
  </string>
    <string id="maroder_start_dialog_est_7">
    <text>I don't understand.</text>
  </string>

    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello General! I have something to tell you.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_1">
    <text>Tell me what it is Strelok.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_2">
    <text>I was captured by the Marauders and taken to the abandoned village. They stripped me to the bone. They took everything, my weapons and armour.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_3">
    <text>Bad luck, Strelok. Well, at least you got out alive.</text>
  </string> 
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_4">
    <text>General, you don't understand. In order to my gear back the Marauders ordered me to get two sets of SCAT-11M body armour, to steal them from your base. But I didn't want to do it so I come to you for help.</text>
  </string>  
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_5">
    <text>You are an honest man Strelok! How exactly can I help you?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_6">
    <text>Give me a weapon and some ammunition, five grenades and a couple of fighters and we will rid the village of these Marauders.</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_7">
    <text>Well Strelok I can't spare any people because we have planned a major operation in the southern part of the territory. So that every weapon counts. I can give you an M16 rifle with an integrated optical sight, some ammo for it, and a couple of grenades, a first aid kit and bandages, and another set of SCAT-11 M body armour. I think you can handle these Marauders yourself. Okay?</text>
  </string>
    <string id="smith_maroder_dialog_8">
    <text>Good General. Well, it will be even better to deal with them myself and get my stuff back. Thank you very much! I'll go and deal with these rats.</text>
  </string>
 
</string_table>	