<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="artefact">
    <text>Get the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1">
    <text>Protect the stalker's camp in Garbage from a bandit's assault.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Protect the stalker's camp at the Garbage from a bandit assault.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_text">
    <text>A group of stalkers are coming to visit me, and I am personally interested in their safe arrival. They'll stay not far from the Bar. A penitent criminal voluntary informed us that they are going to be attacked soon. So head in that direction and protect their camp from the assault.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2">
    <text>Help stalkers fight off the bandits in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Help stalkers fight the bandits in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_text">
    <text>So here's the deal. Recently a group of stalkers went to Agroprom. The last time they were contacted they said that there was something valuable in the underground, but they were pressed hard by the bandits. They're holding on, but they can't hold out. Will you help them out?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Wipe out the bandit gang that settled in Garbage. It has to be a quick and efficient operation.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>A job, eh? Let’s see what we’ve got... aha, here you go. Can you knock out that group of bandits in Garbage? The 'Duty', with all their speeches about law and order, just can’t get to it. Those are some rare scumbags, so they won't last long anyway. But the guy who gets them first will score big, and the booze is on me of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Eliminate the Mercs and bandits in Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy the group of Mercs and bandits that block the passage through Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>There’s a gang of Mercs not far away in Rostok. They hit it off with the bandits, so now they’re scheming to block the passage through the plant. I don’t need to tell you what a nuisance that is going to be. It’s got to be resolved straight away. The 'Duty' guys and some of the old-timers have already gone to teach them a lesson. But we haven’t heard from them in a while. So why don’t you... eh... go and check on them. The money's good too.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits at the farmstead.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>It's simple, clear the farmstead of bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>There’s the farmstead by the old warehouses. Used to be a perfect place for rendezvous for exchange of goods, you know... that sort of thing. But now the bandits have occupied it, and by the looks of it, they are not about to leave. Now that doesn’t suit me at all. I need this farmstead ASAP. I don’t care what happens to the lodgers.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4">
    <text>Purge the bandit's camp in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
    <text>Kill of the bandit's in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_text">
    <text>There are bandits in Wild Territory. We can't let these dregs of society cause problems near the Bar. It's essential to wipe out their camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5">
    <text>Destroy the lair of wild mutant dogs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
    <text>Kill the lair of wild mutant dogs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_text">
    <text>A few of our guys went on an expedition and only a few came back. All torn up, bloody, glassy eyed. Ran into dogs, most likely. There's a whole pack of them there. So find their lair and kill every last one of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6">
    <text>Destroy the group of bandits in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
    <text>Kill the group of bandits in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_text">
    <text>I remember how in '94 the racketeers latched on to me - cough it up they said. Man I went through hell then. I had a restaurant and all. Back then there was no case against them. And here I find out that the same gang is working in Agroprom making a profit off of the artifacts they find there. But here I can do something. I even know exactly where they're hiding. Do me a favor and punish them.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7">
    <text>Destroy the lair of snorks in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_descr">
    <text>Kill the lair of snorks in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_text">
    <text>Yeah...It seems that the ones who say that the Zone is expanding are right. They spotted a few snorks in the Dark Valley, but before they never saw them there. And here some started to panic. The Dutiers promised to destroy the snorks, but they can't seem to get around to doing it. Will you take it on?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Find the Meat chunk artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Find the Meat chunk artifact that heals ailments and injuries.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>Some guys have stopped by, left an order for a Meat chunk. You know, they have a certain interest in this healing artifact. Those rotten miracle-workers! Anyway, you gonna do it? It’s up to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find the Crystal Thorn artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Find the Crystal Thorn artifact that protects against Psy-attacks.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>A 'crone'? No, that’s not it. 'Crystal corn'? No, wrong again. Buggers! 'Crystal Thorn', that’s it! So here’s the deal, I have an order for this artifact 'Crystal Thorn'. Have you heard of it? They say that if you’ve have one no creature will be able to mess with your brain. So what do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Find the Night Star artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Find the Night Star artifact to help the national military research effort.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>I need a Night Star artifact. I'm sorry to say it doesn't grant any wishes, been there done that, but it can make you wealthy. Scientists pay a lot for it. They say they make some military things out of it. So are you up for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Find the artifact Flash.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Find an artifact Flash.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>The assignment is simple and the pay is good. You have to find an artifact Flash. Don't even ask who ordered it and why. Well, will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5">
    <text>Find the artifact Goldfish.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_descr">
    <text>Find an artifact Goldfish.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_text">
    <text>Strelok you know the story about the fairytale about the Goldfish? Yeah yeah that's the one. There are a bunch of jokes about it too. So anyway there's this old man who keeps on wanting to catch it. Bottom line is that I need the one-of-a-kind artifact called Goldfish. The client is not from around here but is respectable. Will you help out?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1">
    <text>Find a Psy-suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Find a suit that provides efficient protection against Psy-emissions. The place to look for it is the deserted labs in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1_text">
    <text>In those labs in Dark Valley they were trying to find a way to protect human brains from Psy-emissions. They were taking their time, that’s for sure. Anyway one of their attempts actually was a success and there’s supposed to be this suit somewhere that you can wear. You could get close enough to kiss a Controller. Yep, it’s that good. So if you get me this suit I won't forget it.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2">
    <text>Find the foreigner's gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2_descr">
    <text>An interesting assignment. The name rings a bell, but where do I know him from?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2_text">
    <text>There once was this foreigner in our neck of the woods. Gordon was his name? He really hated the Combine. His whole manner was that of an experienced stalker. He said he’d never been to the Zone. Anyway that’s not the point. He did vanish somewhere in the Zone eventually. But he had this rather curious thing, the 'Desert Eagle'. If I could just take a closer look at it.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3">
    <text>Find the modified Vintar.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3_descr">
    <text>Find the modified Vintar. Apparently, the place to look for this is in the Red Forest area.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3_text">
    <text>There was this odd story. This one fellow pops up, pockets full of dough, and sets off hiring himself a gang, not the old-timers though, but more of the nippy type. Bought tons of gear. I had this one brand new Vintar, a marvelous gun! So I was foolish enough to sell it to him. I won’t lie to you, I made quite a bit of money. But this whole crew got knocked out close to Red Forest. What can I say, they died for nothing. Well a good lesson for all to learn form. You can’t pave your way through the Zone with money. But anyway I can't stop thinking about that Vintar. Such a great gun rusting somewhere. Won’t you find it for me? I’m paying good money!</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill the soldier.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>A soldier has to bite the dust. The job is a piece of cake, except... it’s weird that the target’s a man in uniform, and the customer really has his dander up.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>I need you to take down this grunt. Don't ask me who he is, what do I care! Just do it. So? Can I entrust you with it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill the stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Do in one of the stalkers. Death to the cheater, that's the trader's revenge.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>You know there’s this type of man that you could never say a bad word about. You trust him as you trust yourself, right? You bank on him. But suddenly you find out that he is the vilest and meanest son of a bitch. So here’s the deal, there’s this one case that needs to get sorted. Do it and I’ll take care of the rest.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill the stalker from the Monolith faction.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Find trader's ex-friend and help him die.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>I used to have a friend... hard to believe, eh? Ah, we came to the Zone together when none of this stuff was here. The things we used to do, the places we used to go to. Oh well, we were young and didn’t give a damn about anything. But he could never get enough. He wanted to go to the center of the Zone and was trying to talk me into it. But I refused and did the right thing. We had a falling out and he left on his own. And now I hear someone saw him. He’s with the Monolith now and I am sure he suffers somehow. So the deal is, Strelok, as a friend do this for me and find him and, well, don’t make him suffer. Just do him in quickly. He was like a brother to me you know?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Kill the stalker called Vampire.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Find and kill the stalker called Vampire.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>That's it, I’ve had enough of this scumbag! I mean Vampire. Do you know him? That bastard! Sucking luck out of people instead of blood. Whoever goes with him, they all die. But he always comes back safe and sound! Done it five times now! That’s evil, don’t you think? I’d love to put some flowers on this Vampire’s grave. So, do you take the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill the stalker called Sparrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>Find Sparrow and avenge the death of another stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>Damn musketeers! Playing D'Artagnan, assholes! As if surfing around anomalies and bowing to bullets is not enough the oafs have now taken to fighting duels! Get this, there was this duel... no one can remember what started it. So these two dumbheads decided to shed some blood. And there you go, one dropped dead. A fine stalker he was too! And the other one, Sparrow left because he knew I’d be the first one to put a bullet in his head. Find him. I’m sure he’s still in the Zone. Will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1">
    <text>Obtain the Flesh's Eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Obtain a Flesh's Eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>Soon we're having a party, there'll be a fancy dinner, and certain local gourmets who are in especially high spirits (we don't need to point fingers) will definitely want to try my special recipie - 'Flesh Eye' under a pork sauce. That is, in its own juices under mayonnaise. Basically I need an eye of that beast and quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2">
    <text>Bring the hoof of a boar.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Bring a hoof of a boar.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Do you know that we prepare horns and hooves? This is a big rarity. They make great jewelry from the local mutated hooves. I know a jeweler, he's interested. So go on ahead find a Boar's Hoof and there'll be cash in your pocket.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1">
    <text>Protect the security post of 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Protect the security post of 'Duty' in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_text">
    <text>So you probably ran into our guys in Garbage. They're there as a sort of a preliminary post protecting the Bar from mutants coming down from Dark Valley. Information has come in that a sick herd of boar is approaching them. Help them fight off the boars and I'll owe you one.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Destroy the zombie.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Destroy the zombie that lives in Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>Recently we sent a group to Yantar. Unfortunately nobody from the group returned. I was informed that they saw a few zombied stalkers from the group not far from the mobile lab of the scientists in Yantar. We can't allow them to remain in that horrible state. Your assignment: find and kill them so they don't suffer.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10">
    <text>Get rid of the pack of dogs.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_descr">
    <text>Get rid of the pack of dogs in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_text">
    <text>We normally don't give assignments to foreign stalkers. On the other hand this is a simple task so there's no point making our guys do it. So listen up. You need to purge a small lair of beasts in Garbage. One of our groups is already working there. So in case of trouble you'll have a place to retreat to. On the other hand, there shouldn't be any problems because there aren't many beasts there. Not more than ten. Most likely dogs. Recently there were reports of a migration of a large pack of them in the area. You can carry out the assignment.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11">
    <text>Destroy the stalker's camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_descr">
    <text>Destroy the stalker's camp in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_text">
    <text>There's one delicate matter, and our guys definitely shouldn't be involved in it. The presence of neutrals in the factory at Agroprom isn't advantageous for our allies. Here's the assignment: free the area from the presence of stalkers, no matter who they are and what group they belong to. Understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12">
    <text>Destroy the detachment of Mercs.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_descr">
    <text>Destroy the detachment of Mercs in Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_text">
    <text>So here's the assignment: you need to destroy the detachment of snipers from a Mercs group. The situation: these snipers are holding the last floor of the building site complex. Assumed count: not less than two nor more than five. They're armed with sniper rifles. Suggestion: don't show your face there during the day.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13">
    <text>Protect the bandit's base.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_descr">
    <text>Protect the bandit's main base in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_text">
    <text>It is imperative to raid the bandit's main base and destroy the enemy. That's in Dark Valley. They are at an unfinished science center. The enemy is numbering around thirty fighters armed with light automatic weapons, guns, shotguns. Everything clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14">
    <text>Eliminate the snorks.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_descr">
    <text>Eliminate the snorks in the tunnels in the Yantar sector.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_text">
    <text>This time you'll need to get to purging. The tunnels at Yantar are simply rampet with snorks. There's around ten of them there. Yeah, now you can't weather the storm there as before.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy the herd of fleshes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy the herd of fleshes at the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>We tracked the migration of a large herd of beasts. Quite disgusting swine-like mutants whom everyone calls Fleshes. Now they're in the area of Garbage. All of our people are busy, and these beasts need to be destroyed. It's a special kind of job and we'll pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3">
    <text>Destroy the pseudodogs.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_descr">
    <text>Purge the lair of pseudodogs by the military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_text">
    <text>Our allies have notified us about the discovery of a lair of mutants in the territory by the military warehouses. We believe it's a pack of pseudodogs. We shouldn't be messing around in that area right now so it's an assignment for a neutral. Are you in?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4">
    <text>Destroy the security post of the Mercs.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_descr">
    <text>Destroy the security post of the Mercs not far from the military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_text">
    <text>Lately there's been an increase in the activity of Mercs. There's been a few attacks on the scientific researchers working in the Zone. We can't leave them unpunished. We need to carry out a small punitive operation. The goal: elimiate the security post of Mercs by the Military Warehouses behind the abandoned village.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5">
    <text>Destroy the Mercs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_descr">
    <text>Kill the Mercs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_text">
    <text>A group of scientists are planning to study Wild Territory. But lately it hasn't been safe there. The Mercs have benn active there. Make sure that there aren't any more Mercs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6">
    <text>Kill the bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_descr">
    <text>Kill the bandits who got into Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_text">
    <text>I'll make this short. The bandits got around our security posts  Earth  and are now located in the Wild Territory. They need to be eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7">
    <text>Destroy the Controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_descr">
    <text>Destroy the Controller in Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_text">
    <text>To carry out this assignment you need to have special skills. The scientists have reported to us that they noticed a Controller in Yantar by the entrance to the underground lab (in the center building). Controllers are very dangerous, but I'm sure you'll manage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8">
    <text>Purge the Freedomers.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_descr">
    <text>Purge the abandoned village not far from the Military Warehouses from the Freedomers.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_text">
    <text>There's been an increase in the activity of Freedom patrols in the abandoned village bear the military warehouses. Purge the village from fighters. After carrying out this assignment a special reward awaits you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9">
    <text>Destroy the bandits.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_descr">
    <text>Destroy the bandits in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_text">
    <text>The current situation is unfavorable, the bandits are gathering in the areas of Garbage and Dark Valley. The best solution is to carry out two preemptive strikes at the same time! Our fighters will take on Dark Valley, and you'll go to Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1">
    <text>Find the enhanced rifle.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Find the sample of an enhanced LR300 near the military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1_text">
    <text>Someone if helping the Mercs. Quite recently they got equipped with machine-guns enhanced for sniper fire. You understand that it's a dangerous toy? Well, I'm interested in such a gun. My gratitude will be rewarding, you can be sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Neutralize the bandit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Neutralize the bandit Poker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>Subject's nickname is Poker. One of the most cruel bandit leaders, a real swine. Evidently his head is not okay: they say he caught a rare disease in the Zone. Now he suffers quite frequent lapses of memory, and when he gains consciousness, he can't remember who and where he is. Nevertheless, he's always armed and very aggressive. Presumably locationed in Dark Valley. Ready for the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item">
    <text>Find the weapon of the Dutier.</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_descr">
    <text>The Dutier is asking you to find his weapon, he lost it somewhere in the Dark Valley during a scouting expedition.</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_text">
    <text>I shouldn't have freaked out like that. How the Zone messes with your head. Thought I had steady nerves, never afraid of anything, and here new this howling in the ears. Everything was going well. There was a scouting expedition to Dark Valley. We got down into the trench with Krivoi to cover the rest of the group and then once I heard this howling I was gripped by fear. Damn, I don't even remember how I got to the coordinates. When I returned to the base General Voronin almost shot me on the spot, he had just given me an enhanced weapon, for good service so to speak. And here I paniced and took off so fast that I left the weapon there. Could you bring it back to me, else where will I go now without a decent weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Purge the lair of Snorks.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Destroy the lair of the Snorks in Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>I want to offer you a small amout of money that you'll receive if the snorks living in the swamps will stop bothering me and my colleagues. Sometimes when we're carrying out our experiments we can't even concentrate.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy the lair of wild dogs.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Purge the lair or wild dogs in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>There's a mutant-dog's lair in Wild Territory. I want you to travel there and clear it. These mutants are particularly dangerous for our expeditions. I know that zoologists won't favor this, but this is not a zoo here, I must admit. Such beasts spread rabies, plague or god knows what.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Bring the Fireball artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Bring the Fireball artifact to the scientists for research.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>We've managed to obtain the artifact in laboratory conditions. This is a breakthrough! Now all the world will hear about our success. And the Nobel Prize will be close at hand. This is the unique artifact 'Film'. It's main quality is to protect from chemical burns. Do you want me to give it to you on behalf of science? However, I do have one request, in return I need an artifact 'Fireball'. do you know about it? Unique thermal qualities of its surface require thorough research.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find the Gravi artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Bring a Gravi artifact to the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>We've approached closely to the comprehension of the nature of gravitation. Soon enough we'll be able to create a new generation of engines on the antigravity basis and quite probably the path to the stars will open to us. For that we need Gravi artifact and fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Find the Jellyfish artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>The scientists need a Jellyfish artifact to carry out researches in the field of space-time.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>Our research team is on the brink of discovering the mystery of space-time. The possibility of teleportation is no longer a fantasy. The Vortex is an anomaly which squeezes space rather than just gravitationally affecting objects, as believed some of my ossified opponents-theorists who sit in the warm research facility earnestly chewing chalk. Their glasses will fog up when they find out what results science can achieve when you work in the field. Please get me the artifact Jellyfish.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Find the Moonlight artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Provide a Moonlight for the scientists in Yantar. A good artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>We desperately need materials for continuing our research in the field of energetics. You see we learned to generate energy with the help of artifacts. Granted this works but the efficiency isn't high enough. We were able to get the best results with the artifact Moonlight. Please bring us a sample for experiments.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5">
    <text>Find the artifact called Sea Urchin.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_descr">
    <text>The scientists need a Sea Urchin artifact to improve their suits.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_text">
    <text>You are probably aware of the fact that our suits provide the best defence against radiation. The secret lies in the fact that we saturate them with a lotion made out of quite a rare artifact. To manufacture another series of these suits we need such an artifact. It is called Sea Urchin.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1">
    <text>Bring the unique bodysuit.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Bring the unusual bodysuit from the underground laboratory X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_text">
    <text>We have some business with you. Recently we hired a stalker to get into the laboratory. Even then I noticed his unusual bodysuit, it gave off noticeable heat. The stalker said that the bodysuit itself can heal wounds. Bottom line is the stalker didn't return from the lab. Oh no don't even think it! We had nothing to do with it! And his bodysuit is most likely still there. I would be very happy to get it for research.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring a part of the snork's body.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>It's a piece of cake getting a fragment of a snork in these parts.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>We got acquainted with Semenov back in the university where I was giving lectures on genetics, and he was my student. Thus I became his scientific chief. Back then we were only slightly unveiling the curtain of mystery of genome modification. So, what was I saying? Oh, right. For genetic experiments we will need the samples of fresh cells of the muscular tissue of Snork. You will have to search the bogs for this genic material. There is a hypothesis that snorks as species are the new level of human's evolution. In order to know this for sure DNA tests must be made!</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2">
    <text>Bring a Flesh Eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>I'd better keep my body away from these eggheads just in case. Very well I'll get them a Flesh's Eye. Then they can do all they want with their volunteers.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Good news young man we have a very interesting assignment for you! I think as an intellectual being with quite a bit of experience you will be able to appreciate my colleague's theories. The thing is our research revealed the eyes of the creatures, called Flesh in the common language, are equipped with... are you following me?.. with olfactory receptors! Thus they can not only see with their eyes but smell with them as well! We're getting ready for an operation on transplanting this miraculous eye into one of ... one of our voluntary assistants. I believe we're about to start a craze! By the way, would you like to become a recepient of this rather amazing organ?</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3">
    <text>Bring the tail of a blind dog.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_descr">
    <text>Well, look at Science! Trying to find a second brain in humans?. Poor dogs, one of them will have to do without a tail now.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_text">
    <text>Welcome, eh... traveler! I'm so glad you dropped by, we are in need of a man to take part in a highly important experiment. My colleague Brenter wants to try and cook a meal using local fauna for a practical experiment to study the influence of mutated protein on the human body. For a start, we decided to try the boars. We need ham. A boar's leg, do you undestand? And if you agree to do it, please select the healthiest specimen.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4">
    <text>Bring the leg of a boar.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_descr">
    <text>Gourmet thrillseekers, alright I'll get them some ham.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_text">
    <text>Good day, colleague! I hope you know that dogs belong to the vertebrates subtype, meaning their vertebral column starts with the head and ends with the tail. And here's the catch! One of my young collegues proved theoretically that the spine of the blind dogs, this is how you named this type of animal, starts from the tail not from the head! Think of it, it totally turns upside down our assumptions pertaining to this area of knowledge. There are already some rather daring theories about human beings having around their sacrum a... well, this is a subject of many discussions. In short we need the head of the dog, a Blind Dog, which through ignorance we considered to be its tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5">
    <text>Bring a Bloodsucker's Jaw.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_descr">
    <text>What they are going to do with a bloodsucker's jaw. Well I don't care. I care about the reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_text">
    <text>Oh, stalker, glad to see you! Listen you already met bloodsuckers on your adventures, right? If not, then we want it to happen. Bring us the Lower Jaw of the representative of this species, with all his so to say, tableware. Unfortunately I can't disclose the details of the experiment. Besides it will negatively impact the stability of your psyche. We'll be waiting.</text>
</string>
<string id="eliminate_lager">
    <text>Camp elimination.</text>
</string>
<string id="find_item">
    <text>Find the item.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1">
    <text>Protect the stalkers in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Fight off the bandit's attack at the stalker's camp in Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_text">
    <text>There's a group of stalkers that live in Agroprom. Average guys, they understand that the Zone is a place of freedom, that laws don't apply here and you just have to live right, based on your own morals. And now they're thinking about maybe joining us. Yeah, so help them fight off the bandits? And we'll send you some ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2">
    <text>Protect the border.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Protect the border near the Army Warehouses from mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_text">
    <text>Here come the mutants again from the side of the Scorcher. Help the guys at the border hold them off. I guarantee a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Destroy the military camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Destroy the military camp near the Agroprom Research Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>The military are staging a gradual Zone takeover. We need to slow them down otherwise the Zone will turn into a research zoo. One of the military camps is right by Agroprom. If you manage to purge the place a bit, it will slow down the Zone's takeover by the army.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Destroy the Merc camp.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy the Merc camp near the warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>Listen, here's the deal. The Merc camp needs to be destroyed. We could leave them be, they're good shots... except they've been really asking for it, sneaking into our territory, trying to bribe my people. It's time to teach them a lesson. Can you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Destroy the Duty detachment.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>Destroy the Duty clean-up group in Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>How 'bout going on a hunt? Duty's clean-up detachment showed up at Rostok. This is a great chance to take them by surprise. Duty keeps sending guys hunting for monsters, but in the process they don't hesitate to shoot whoever isn't up to their likening. This detachment needs to be finished off before more Duty comes to Rostok. There shouldn't be too many of them, three or four veterans and a couple of rookies.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4">
    <text>Destroy the Duty outpost.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
    <text>Destroy the Duty outpost in Garbage as soon as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_4_text">
    <text>There's a very urgent job. The passage from the Garbage to the Bar needs to be cleared of the Duty unit... They've taken to hiding there and robbing the passers-by. We're expecting a very important package, but now it must not be ruled out that Duty already know about our courier and will try to waylay him. We need to wipe off this roadblock, even if for a little while. Ok?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5">
    <text>Clear the village.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
    <text>Clear the village of bloodsuckers and if possible eliminate the controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_5_text">
    <text>Have you noticed all those bloodsucking mutants swarming in the village? No one gets within a hundred meters of it, except complete tards. And some say they've been seeing things there. A Controller is all we need right now! Anyway, it's high time we put an end to it. I'm not forcing you to go. I wouldn't go there myself. But if you're not afraid then my gratitude won't have any bounds.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6">
    <text>Destroy the herd of boars and fleshes.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
    <text>Destroy the herd of boars and fleshes near the military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_6_text">
    <text>Our sniper sits at the entrance to the base. He sits there on the tower at night. It's quiet, it's night-time, then suddenly there's an explosion, wild screeching, a flash! What the ...?! It turns out, boars and fleshes got into the habit of wandering around by the minefield. Only the devil knows what makes them go there. But sure enough at least once every week one of those beasts gets blown to bits by a mine. The assignment is simple, kill all of those suckers off. Will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7">
    <text>Destroy the herd of rodents.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7_descr">
    <text>Destroy the herd of rodents in Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_7_text">
    <text>There are no rodents anywhere near our base but those these creatures can get anywhere and just recently there were so many of them here you wouldn't believe it. Two months we dealt with them. hehehe. So we figured out where the rodents came from. From Wild Territory, you follow? There's a fear that these jumping rats will multiply and return. We need a man to take care of them for us. Will you go?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_1">
    <text>Steal the sniper rifle.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Steal the modified SVD from the Duty warehouse.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_1_text">
    <text>There is this special assignment, and pretty tough too. You'll need to retrieve an improved Dragunov from the Duty warehouse. This piece even has a name of its own, but never mind. The main thing is that with its awesome scope and recoil canceller you can shoot a squirrel in the eye from 400 meters. So I trust you'll do it!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_2">
    <text>Obtain the modified SPAS 12.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_2_descr">
    <text>Obtain the modified SPAS 12 from the scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_2_text">
    <text>I hear the eggheads managed to improve the SPAS 12 shotgun by using an artifact. The knockdown power of this thing is the same as a howitzer. So why don't you pay them a visit and see if you can make a bargain. I'll make up for all expenses!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3">
    <text>Bring the bulletproof vest.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3_descr">
    <text>Bring the new model of the bulletproof vest.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3_text">
    <text>Some of the grunts are sporting a new type of bulletproof vests. The inside lining is soaked in some healing ointment or something like that. Anyway it makes small wounds heal up very fast. And imagine the luck, just the other day ten of those guys ran into Yantar and only six returned, with three on their shoulders. You follow? One of them got left behind. If you get us his bullteproof vest we'll examine it and make us a lot of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill Duty's security chief.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Kill Duty's security chief and try do it as quietly as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>It would be well for Duty's security chief to quietly disappear. And when they're in a deep mess I'll be able to plant a few of my guys in their gang. And then the devil can pull off a stunt... alright, I better shut up. I suggest you take care of him from a distance without kicking up a fuss.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill Captain Ivantsov.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Kill Captain Ivantsov, the closest aide of the Duty leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>It's a tough job, I'm warning you right away, but it's worth it. Ivantsov, a close aide of the Duty leader, has been asking for it. He does the dirtiest jobs, punitive operations, raids. If you only knew how many of our guys he's killed off! It's high time we did away with this slimeball. So if you make up your mind to do it, I suggest you get yourself well armed.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill Colonel Petrenko.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Kill Colonel Petrenko, one of the founders of the Duty faction.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>Colonel Petrenko, I don't know if you've heard the name or met him but it would be good for the two of you to meet. This man is one of the Duty founders and one of our worst enemies. Try to make sure your conversation ends as fast as possible for him. Can you handle that?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Kill the neutral stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Find and kill the neutral stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>There's a fellow who's walking around not far from here. He shot one of ours down once. And an action like that can't be forgiven. Will you take the job? We'll pay, don't worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill one of the Duty commanders.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>Kill one of Duty's commanders.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>I'll pay for the head of any Duty leader! Knock one off and come back for reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6">
    <text>Kill the stalker called Scarecrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_descr">
    <text>Eliminate the stalker called Scarecrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_text">
    <text>We eliminate monsters, except for us it's a matter of survival, not profit. Mutant populations are not as numerous, besides they're living beings too, so we can't permit their annihilation. Some individuals refuse to understand it. An apt illustration is the stalker called Scarecrow. He got his nickname for a reason, selling stuffed mutants. We've warned him before, but all for nothing. So can you do a good deed for mother Earth?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7">
    <text>Kill the stalker called 'The Barin'.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_descr">
    <text>Kill the stalker called Barin, chief quartermaster of the Duty faction.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_text">
    <text>A cad, bootlicker, hypocrite and coward, that's stalker Barin for you. As you can see a man with a marvellous character which helped him get to the top of Duty. Currently supplies the faction with weapons and foodstuff, though he takes part in raids from time to time. We need to get rid of him, especially since all the clues regarding Duty logistics lead to Barin.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring a boar's leg.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Bring a boar's leg.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>We're planning a dinner party to celebrate Bob Marley's birthday. So why don't you get us some delicious ham? The more the better! Jah will never forget you!</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager">
    <text>Destroy the lair of bloodsuckers.</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_descr">
    <text>The hunter is asking us to purge the lair of bloodsuckers in the village near the military warehouses, and in return he promises a rare artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_text">
    <text>Have you ever run into a bloodsucker? Horrible thing, isn't it? Well the other day I went to the village by the military warehouses, thought I'd look for some artifacts, and imagine this, suddenly I see a bloodsucker, black, and with scars all over. It's sitting over a corpse, doesn't see me. I freaked out and made a run for it. I shouldn't have started running though, because it heard me and went after me, and there was all this howling all around me and then I understood that it wasn't alone. I think they have a lair there. If you could chase them away from there, I would give you a rare artifact that I found a couple days ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="kill_stalker">
    <text>Kill the stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker">
    <text>Kill the traitor.</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>The Bald One wants you to kill one stalker who took off with a very rare artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>A while ago another stalker and I went looking for an artifact right next to the Scorcher. We found so much stuff, even found a couple of artifacts that I'd never seen before, not even pictures of them. So that son of a bitch tricked me. During the last night he snuck off and hid the most valuable artifacts. And then tried to tell me that they disappeared on their own. A couple of days ago I saw one of those very rare artifacts  that the Barkeep had. I was so pissed, anyway stalker, if you could find him and airmail him a lead greeting from me. And while you're at it maybe you can find out where his secret stash is and get the second artifact. It's worth it, believe me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker">
    <text>Kill a master stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>The Mercs will pay for the assassination of a master. The fewer masters there are, the easier it is for the Mercs.</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>We're not interested in the fact that walking dreadnoughts might wander across the Zone... stalkers in exo-skeletons armed to the teeth. The work becomes even more dangerous and harder for us because of this. The fewer of them there are the better it is for us. Kill one of them and receive your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="monster_part">
    <text>Get a part of a monster body.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker">
    <text>Destroy the stalker from Freedom.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>One stalker, a former Dutier, who had a lot of important information about objects in Pripyat, recently came over to the Freedom side. He needs to be killed before he says too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>Listen to me. We have maps of Pripyat, not up-to-date ones, rather old ones, made in the early 90's. The most important thing on them is the marking of all military objects such as underground warehouses and bomb shelters. Now the map offers little use, of course, but if we find a road to Pripyat then this information will become priceless. Here's the problem though. One of the officers went over to the Freedom side and he knows about this information. Bottom line is that he needs to be silenced before he says too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="return_for_reward">
    <text>Come back for the reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="return_for_reward_bring">
    <text>Bring the customer what's been promised.</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item">
    <text>Find the perfected suit.</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item_descr">
    <text>Nimble told us about a bandit stash where they stashed some stuff. He's asking to bring back the stolen suit, for a reward, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item_text">
    <text>While I was incaptivity I heard the bandits talking about their secret stash, where they keep their possessions. Heard that they hid a cool coat there, and the next day some monster got his eye on the stash. And it became so interested in it that now they're afraid to go there. Do me a favor and bring me the suit and I'll pay you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_has_no_job">
    <text>I can't offer anything at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_ask">
    <text>What do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_complete">
    <text>Great job, a reward well deserved!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_what">
    <text>What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_list_job">
    <text>Look what we've got now.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1">
    <text>Cover the Duty detachment from an attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Cover the Duty detachment from an attack by bandits in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_text">
    <text>I finally managed to get it into the thick heads of the Dutiers that it's high time to purge Garbage of bandits. The Duty will get to enlarge its territory and they won't hurt my regular clients as often. Well, here's the deal, the leadership of the Duty decided for starters to cut off the flow of bandits from Dark Valley. So they sent out a blockade detachment and discovered that the bandits didn't like that. Who would have thought?! So what I'm wondering is, could you help them secure the entrance to the Valley? I'll thank you handsomely.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_has_no_job">
    <text>There are no jobs available right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_ask">
    <text>What do you want to discuss?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_complete">
    <text>Good little stalker! Job well done!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_what">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_list_job">
    <text>Here's the job update:.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_ask">
    <text>What assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete so here is the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_list_job">
    <text>Is there something to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_has_no_job">
    <text>Sorry, but we don't have any jobs at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_ask">
    <text>What job would you like to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_complete">
    <text>You did a great job! Allow me to present you with your reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_what">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_list_job">
    <text>Here's what I can offer.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Destroy the bandit camp in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits in Garbage who rob stalkers on the way back from the Zone. The trader will be happy.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>The bandits have rallied lately, getting in the way of honest people trading. So make a beeline for Garbage. I've been told those scumbags have settled down near the scrapyard. You look into this matter and everyone will be grateful to you, and I'll be generous with the reward. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Destroy the bandit camp at the Auto park.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits at the Auto park. Apparently, they're new to the Zone, so the job is gonna be a piece of cake.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>The bandits have been hanging around the Auto park again. So did you guess already what the job is about? Well then jump to it! Pass our warmest greetings to them and come back. I'll thank you then. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits near the Agroprom Research Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>Eliminate the bandits near the Agroprom Research Institute. Best to stay on friendly terms with the trader.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>Some bandits turned up near the Agroprom Research Institute. They're disturbing my diggers when they sort through the rubbish. You solve the problem and I'll owe you.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4">
    <text>Purge the area of mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
    <text>Purge the area of mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_text">
    <text>There is one task, fairly easy. They want to bring some foreign tourist over. He paid some dough to my homies to get a look at the Zone. And the area where they're gonna show him around needs to be cleared of mutants. Will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5">
    <text>Eliminate two bandits in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
    <text>Make the road to one of the best places in the Zone accessible to all.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_text">
    <text>Recently one of the best places in the Zone became inaccessible for lovers of the wonderful. In Garbage, yeah, in Garbage. There's a quaint little place like nothing else where all your sadness leaves you, where you forget about the danger, about money, about blood. Forget that is, because now there are two dirty freaks sitting there who threaten to kill anyone who doesn't pay them for being able to enter the place. Get rid of them. I have no other place to take the tourists.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6">
    <text>Kill a bloodsucker in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
    <text>Kill the bloodsucker in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_text">
    <text>They say that the troops left Dark Valley. And then mutants started pouring out of every crevice. The stalkers already spotted a bloodsucker there, and an extraordinary one at that. It's not afraid of open spaces. Any way, once word gets around to the scientists, they'll definitely want to study this bloodsucker. And I want to be the person who hands them over the body. Your job is to kill the bloodsucker and I'll take care of the rest.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Find the Jellyfish artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Find a Jellyfish artifact formed in the Springboard anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>Some guy from the 'Mainland' asked for a Jellyfish. It's not a lot of money, but it's a milk run. Take it!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find the Stone Flower artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Find the Stone Flower artifact formed in the Springboard anomaly. The pay is supposed to be pretty good.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>I have a request for a Stone Flower. The order is from the jewellers, by the way, so let's try to make the pretty ladies happy, eh? If you get it then you'll get the money and a bottle to drink to your health.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Find the Night Star artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Find the Night Star, a rare and expensive artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>There is this one little job, a rather unpleasant one. Apparently it's coming from the military that they're working on some new form of protection. Anyway there's an order for a Night Star. It's quite a rare artifact. It provides pretty good protection from bullets. So will you get it? I'll pay you well!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Find the artifact called Meat Chunk.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Find the wound-healing artifact called Meat Chunk.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>There's an order for an artifact, the kind that heals wounds, called Meat Chunk. There is a clinic of some sort that wants one. If you get it you'll get paid and help people at the same time.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1">
    <text>Find the perfected pistol.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Obtain the pistol called 'Fort' that has, rumor has it, a larger amount of cartridges in its magazine. It's last known owner was the commander of the military checkpoint under the broken down tressel.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1_text">
    <text>Man, now there's a fad about using modified weapons and nobody wants to shoot from normal weapons anymore, not even the newbies! Anyway, there's an order for an improved machine gun. Rumor has it the commander of the soldiers, the one who collects money for passing under the bridge, has a 'Fort' with a fat cartridge magizine. Will you get it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_has_no_job">
    <text>There's no job right now, really.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_ask">
    <text>So what is it that you want to discuss?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_complete">
    <text>Here's a fine young man! Excellent job, here's your money.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_what">
    <text>What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_list_job">
    <text>Here's what I've got.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_ask">
    <text>What assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete so here is the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_nothing">
    <text>It's alright. Some other time.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_completed">
    <text>I executed the mission.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_refuse">
    <text>I refuse to do this job.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill the bandit leader.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Kill the bandit leader who crossed the trader. Most likely he won't be alone. Tough job, but the pay covers it all. In Garbage is the place to look for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>You'll have to finish off one of the bandit leaders. The other day the bandits, by his order, intercepted my courier and shook him up and I don't waste words with those who touch my people. In a word, if you get it done, I'll return the favor. So are you up for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill the trader stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Kill a stalker. Well, it's not the best job, lifting a hand against a fellow worker. But the pay is pretty good and this may be what matters the most.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>I'm having a confrontation with this one trader. Well, if he doesn't want to cooperate, the hell with him! But I won't let anyone start filthy rumors. In short he needs to be wasted so the others don't get out of hand. Let them all know who's the boss here.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill the rookie stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Finish off a rookie stalker, who may not be a rookie at all. Then who is he? Ah, who cares! As long as the job's not messy.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>There's this one guy here loafing about, pretending to be a rookie, and he's rather weird. So anyway, if he suddenly disappears, you'll be doing me a great favor. You know what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Kill the stalker called Fiend.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Eliminate one of the trader Sidorovich's rivals, a stalker called Fiend.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>The Fiend, aka Oleg Gusarov, used to serve in Spetsnaz. As long as he minded his own business I had nothing against him, a loner is a loner. But I hear he's mustering a gang to take over Cordon to control the smuggling operations into the Zone. Now this is a major problem and it has to be solved quickly. So will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill Father Diodora.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>To kill a man preaching in the Zone against gathering and selling artifacts. Exactly!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>I always said business and religion can't go together, they can never cross, and should never ever meddle in the other's affairs! It's just this padre, Lord forgive me, Diodora... well... he just can't see the simple truth. He keeps raving about artifact hunting, says that trading in them drives people to sin not just in the Zone, but in the whole world, on and on along those lines. Get this, he preaches the destruction of artifacts altogether. See what he is up to? The worst bit is that he's actually got some converts. I've tried to approach this Diodora one way or another, but he just keeps at it. Here's the deal you're going to send him upstairs where he can preach all he likes, you get the point, right? And I'll give you a cool artifact. So, we've got a deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6">
    <text>Kill the sales representative.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_descr">
    <text>Kill the sales representative. The trader is looking after his reputation.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_text">
    <text>Imagine this: there's some weirdo running around here who introduces himself as my sales representative, uses my reputation, and then tries to hand off second-rate stuff! Broken weapons, armor that's falling apart, expired canned goods. I've already had to deal with a few unhappy clients. Bottom line is I need a man to have a little chat with that sales representative, whatever it takes.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_ask">
    <text>What assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete and here is your reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing for the currently.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_ask">
    <text>What task do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_complete">
    <text>Task complete so here's the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_what">
    <text>So what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring the jaw of the bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>So the jaw of the bloodsucker brings good luck? Let's see if it'll bring luck to the bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>I heard a superstition that the jaw of a bloodsucker brings good luck. As if the one who wears that tooth around his neck gets past the anomalies, and artifacts fall right into his hands. Anyway, it's all bullshit, but there are some idiots who believe it all and are ready to pay well for it. If you bring the jaw of a bloodsucker, I'll pay you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2">
    <text>Bring a Pseudodog tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Bring the tail of a Pseudodog.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Winter's coming soon. And what do chicks like to wear there on the 'Mainland' during winter? That's right, furs. So now there's a new fashion going around making various accessories from the tails of pseudodogs. It's some sort of special fur! Bottom line, there's an order for such a tail. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_ask">
    <text>Which assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete and here is a reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_reward_job">
    <text>I'm here for the job.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_abandon">
    <text>I'm not interested in that kind of job.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_no">
    <text>Some other time.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_yes">
    <text>I'm up for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_reward">
    <text>What's my reward?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_new_job">
    <text>I need a job. Do you have something for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_ask">
    <text>Which assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete so here is the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_has_no_job">
    <text>There's no job right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_ask">
    <text>What job do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_complete">
    <text>Job's done... and here's the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_what">
    <text>What about the job?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_list_job">
    <text>Here's something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_ask">
    <text>Which assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete and here is a reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_has_no_job">
    <text>For the moment there's nothing.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_ask">
    <text>Which assignment do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_complete">
    <text>Assignment is complete and here is the reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_what">
    <text>And what about the assignment?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Destroy the boar lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>The boars made a lair next to the place where Wolf and his friends camp. Wolf asks to purge the lair and promised to handsomely reward you.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>My friend and I had a storage place here not far from the car park, where the forest is more dense. Basically, just what you need. But recently the boars made a lair there, and now we can't get to the storage. Help kill the boars, and I'll thank you, for myself and for my friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy the mutants at the farm.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Wolf asks to purge the farm from mutants. He wants to set up an outpost camp there.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>Though this is the border of the Zone, newbies have it tough even here. The bandits are only half the problem, they at least understand Russian. But the mutants are really tough on them. They made themselves a lair at the abandoned farm, took over the only good place for an outpost camp. If you manage to purge the farm from the mutants, I'll owe you.</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager">
    <text>Purge the dog lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_descr">
    <text>There's a pack of dogs by the South checkpoint at the Bar. The head of the checkpoint asks to purge this lair. Promises to reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_text">
    <text>Despite our efforts some mutants still manage to break through from Garbage. Well you yourself probably saw a pack of dogs to the south of us. If you kill them you'll get a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="defend_lager">
    <text>Camp defense.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_screw_flamethrower_descr">
    <text>I need to find several objects from a list which gave to Screw: a artifact 'Fireball', a tube (possibly Sidorovich has one), a Manometer (will have to search the institude), a burner (ask the Barkeep). And it is still necessary not to forget to take ten bottles of vodka to this drunkard.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1">
    <text>To get an artifact Slime.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Get for Sviblov Slime artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>Strelok, to us here scientists ordered one sufficiently rare artifact, a 'Slime'. To find it will be not simple. If you take this task you will be thanked properly.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2">
    <text>To bring artifact Slug.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Get for Sviblov artifact 'Slug'.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>Strelok, again to us here scientists ordered an artifact, 'Slug'. Terms and conditions as always. If you find this artifact you will obtain some little things.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3">
    <text>To bring artifact 'Crystal'.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Get for Sviblov artifact 'Crystal'.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>Rescue, marked, again scientists down the neck mudflow, remove yes positive by it artifact 'Crystal'! But where it to take? You will find - before the duty I will not remain, decoration appropriate!</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4">
    <text>To bring artifact Battery.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Get for Sviblov artifact 'Battery'.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>Strelok, there is a matter for you. An order for another artifact. Sakharov lately requires a good artifact. And good artifacts simply do not roll around on the road. It is necessary to find an artifact 'Battery'. You will bring it to me and I will pay generously.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2">
    <text>To find the Cat Tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Bring the Cat Tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>I received an order for a Cat Tail from the mainland from an artist friend. He visited us once to write 'The place of complete decadence and fascination'. However we did not take him deep into the territory. He wants the cat hair for brushes. Of course I know this is risky because these creatures are not easily found. But money is money. You are no greenhorn. Well will you undertake this task?</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1">
    <text>To bring a Jerboa head.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>To get a Jerboa (rat) head.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>Work you say? There is job. A tourist was invited. It has been promised to this tourist a souvenir from the Zone. So here you get me the head of a Jerboa. It will be this tourist's souvenir. My kids would like to have one too.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3">
    <text>To find Poltergeist Eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3_descr">
    <text>To find a Poltergeist Eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3_text">
    <text>Hello Strelok, hope you are healthy. A 'Poltergeist Eye' is urgently required in the Mainland. Preferably intack. I know that you are experienced so I think you will manage this mission without to much trouble. Fee is worthy. Well if you do not wish to do this speak immediately. I will not try to force you to do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4">
    <text>To get a Chimera Claw.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4_descr">
    <text>To find a Chimera Claw.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4_text">
    <text>If you want a mission then speak up. There is a mission, and it suits you well. Seen any Chimeras in the Zone lately? There is a guy that wants one. Pays good money. Well, interested?</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5">
    <text>To get a Controller Hand.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5_descr">
    <text>To find a Controller Hand for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5_text">
    <text>Busy Strelok? I need a Controller hand. You see I have been getting headaches lately, migraine type. I have all the ingredients to make medicine except a Controller Hand. It would please me if you could find me one. I know you can do it.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6">
    <text>To get a Pseudogiant hand.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6_descr">
    <text>To get the hand of a Pseudogiant.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6_text">
    <text>I have a mission and it is not an easy one. You'll sweat through this one. Do you do want it? Some scientist want a Pseudo-giant Hand. What do you think? Up for it? They will pay well for one. But as we know this creature is extremely dangerous. I had already sent two guys out and they barely crawed back. But you stalker are a serious dude. You know your capabilities. What you will say?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_has_no_job">
    <text>There is nothing against the given moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_ask">
    <text>About what mission you do wish to have a talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_complete">
    <text>Mission is carried out so here again some stuff!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_what">
    <text>Any missions?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_list_job">
    <text>There is something .</text>
</string>
</string_table>
