<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="dm_action_info_0">
    <text>How can there be anything new here? Think of this as kindergarten, preschool even. Granted if you don't stay around here you'll get sacked in five minutes in the Zone, so there. The smart ones stay here a while and then they go somewhere, and only the devil knows where. Besides you can make it here with ammo and weapons, there's no question about it. Everyone does it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_1">
    <text>All I have to do is wait for those pansies in uniform to go out for lunch. There's no point to hang out here. I need to go to the Mainland, but they won't let me, no matter what. I'm not the only one trying to get out either, but still we can't slip by them yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_10">
    <text>Not far from here the fellows in uniform needed something. They didn't used to come here. But they cleared everything out spick-n-span before I got there right down to cutting the cables. And then they saw me. I couldn't get even close to the building they noticed me right away and started shooting. Glad I made it out without a hole in my hide.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_100">
    <text>Not much. Trying to make it, that's all.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_11">
    <text>We're getting together a team of those who can't get enough of going underground in the Zone. There's an old factory, and under it there are these powerlines. They say there's a bunch of goodies there. Always something new to check out. Very interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_12">
    <text>Not new - old! They say that Strelok's old base used to be located here. I wonder what kind of stuff one could find from that time, if they really looked hard.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_13">
    <text>Can you believe it an hour ago I almost got into a mess. I was here half a year ago, there was peace and quiet, but now these razorheads in their outfits are under every bush! It's crazy, man!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_14">
    <text>You're lucky stalker that the bandits didn't get you. They have a base pretty close to here. Oh how I would have trashed it if I could. But for now we're just observing. This is their supporting base. The headquarters are located closer to the center of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_15">
    <text>They say there used to be an impressive lab here, camoflauged. It would be great to find the entrance. I bet there are lots of goodies inside. On the other hand, it gives me the heebie-jeebies.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_16">
    <text>Did you know that in what's now the Dark Valley before the catastrophe there used to be an underground scientific research complex? I don't know what it was meant for, but I'm sure nothing good. They say different things about it, but mostly it's bad. Terrible place!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_17">
    <text>And so what? What do you want to hear? I'll tell you this much: 'Dutiers' are definitely the cops, and they know how to keep the order, that's for sure. But overall I don't like them very much. They're like the landlords everywhere, don't take this don't carry that, out of the Zone. Not only that but they've already determined what you're allowed to say in the 'Mainland' and what you're supposed to be hush-hush about! They blab and actually want to destroy the Zone little by little. Well that doesn't surprise me coming from former soldiers... they're all dreamers. What's worse is that they say their support comes all the way from the top.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_18">
    <text>This territory is now controled by 'Duty' and their rules are the law of the land. We monitor the borders of the Zone and cool off the hot-heads. The poor fools come here in whole caravans, amateurs, romantics... and then die off in groups on the very first day.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_19">
    <text>Were you at our half-way camp? Granted, it's not just ours, you can run into most anyone there. What's important is that it's a good place, without any trash, and all the news about the Zone funnels in there. You can almost always hear something useful, or at least chat with folks about nothing in particular. Too bad that Baldy with his group left the day before yesterday, so this time I didn't even get to see him.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_2">
    <text>Let's head to camp, you'll hear all the rumors there. All who are doing this for the first time, the rookies like you, usually drop by to pick up some pointers, or rest a while. There are soldiers standing nearby, don't be too afraid of them, but don't get in their way either. They will shoot and not think twice about it. Here there is a trader, well, retailer of the local merchandise. There's a nice calm little place where you can make camp. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_20">
    <text>Right now stalker this place is safe and we're trying to keep it that way. There are many people here. Some who've made it their home don't go beyond the surrounding area. Others who are preparing for yet another raid. Such a shame that Mohawk didn't come back. He loved to set rookies like yourself on the way of the righteous. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_21">
    <text>Did you hear that 'Duty' has announced that it's recruiting new members? I thought about it a minute, but then decided the hell with it. Before long they'll draft me. Don't need that kind of discipline. I served my two years along time ago in the army and that was enough for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_22">
    <text>If you haven't heard yet, I'm letting you know that we're recruiting new members. If you have some experience, come, you won't regret it. At the base ask for Petrenko.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_23">
    <text>Did you come to look at the matches too, want to place a bid or something? Well what do you know! There's an arena here somewhere, and you're a total zero! So check this out, members of the Duty squad catch mutants, right? After the research, if the beasts are still alive, they let them loose in the arena. And these mutants come in all shapes and sizes. Some you'll look at them and die laughing, others you'll wet your pants.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_24">
    <text>They just provided the arena with new meat. Entertainment for the people, and for us a good way to earn a few rubles from the bids. We'll prove to the stalkers that the Duty isn't just wagging its tongue, but that we do the real thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_25">
    <text>Hey listen, have you been to the Rostok? It used to be quiet there, but now it's tough going there alone. Your average wild field has way too many mutants. Let's go together, what do you say? On the other hand I don't know you and you don't know me. What if... yeah dude, sorry. Let's split.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_26">
    <text>We're just back from Rostok. You don't need to show your face there, especially if you're alone. Want to stay alive? Then you better not go.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_27">
    <text>Well I was thinking of going to Yantar, but then thought, screw it. There the eggheads that set up a full-fledged scientific base in the Zone. They're digging all over the place and only the devil knows why. While zombies are romping all around outside the complex. How idyllic, my goodness.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_28">
    <text>They were purging the Yantar Zone recently...yeah, cleaned it up pretty well. There are research laboratories there, but too many zombies all over the place. So we have to regularly haul over there to help the scientists out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_29">
    <text>By the old warehouses, you know, the Freedom base. They're happy fellows, have some soul. It's such a pleasure to chat with them over a bottle of wine. And Duty isn't there all the time like they are around the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_3">
    <text>There's an old factory nearby, and we keep on cleaning it of bandits, and they always come back again! It hasn't even been a month since last time, and they're already back. You better be more careful there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_30">
    <text>'Freedom' is hiding out behind the old warehouses, break them all down, these freak'n...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_31">
    <text>Leave before it gets dark! During the day it's more or less okay, but once the sun sets, look out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_32">
    <text>Stalker leave! We're going to Cordoning. For now we travel only during the day, and camp for the night. It's too creepy here at night.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_33">
    <text>You see, during the night you need to keep yourself hidden, and preferable behind a good set of doors. During the dark part of the day we find ourselves basically under seige.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_34">
    <text>Well buddy, it seems you're not up to date. During the night you have to snooze somewhere far away from here. Here during the night even a granade launcher doesn't always help.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_35">
    <text>You know what, let the 'Duty' guys and the 'Freedom' guys and the 'marauders' figure out who this area belongs to. What is it to me? To hell with it all.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_36">
    <text>We're working here now stalker. Not only is there a bunch of these wretches breeding here, but also those asses the mercs and the retards from the Freedom faction get in the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_37">
    <text>I have to warn you that it's not very safe here even during the day. Once in a while there is a shoot-off as far as I understand. There has been some long-standing conflicts between the various local bandit factions.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_38">
    <text>Listen, why don't you tell me that this is our territory, right? It's easier for us to hold off the wretches that come here from the center of the Zone, isn't it? The eggheads can mess around trying to figure out who's bothering them, but the Duty and the marauders can get the hell out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_39">
    <text>And you don't know? They created a new path here to be able to get past the Duty patrol right to the perimeter with all the goods. Get there from Yantar, and then using the backway all the way to Agroprom, and you're there!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_4">
    <text>Nothing. I don't know squat. I grab a bite here and there, trying to make enough for my daily bread. It's too creepy going into the Zone itself, to hell with it. And there's no work at home, my wife's on my case, gotta live somehow. Here in Garbage, if you look around for a day, you can get some artifacts. And it'll do for your bread and butter.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_40">
    <text>And why are you here? Planning to go to Yantar, or are you trying to sneak some artifacts past a brother?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_41">
    <text>I won't conceal the fact that here your stalker colleagues offer us from time to time some quite interesting anomalous formations, artifacts is what you call them. Because of... shall we say... the uncertain level of control over them... these places form a kind of highly active smuggling trail.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_42">
    <text>What's wrong with you man? We laid a path just so that we wouldn't have to run into the fellows from the Duty faction if we wanted to get to the 'Mainland' for something. Though they still hang around here from time to time, at least they don't know anything for now, and so you can get around them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_43">
    <text>I'm just coming back from Yantar. Thought I'd pass something off to the scientists as usual, but they're all locked in their bunkers, they don't even go out even during the day. So if you're planning to head in that direction, might as well change course.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_44">
    <text>There is research going on in the Yantar zone, but recently there's been more zombies that are hanging around those parts. So we're defending the entrances.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_45">
    <text>I don't even know what to tell you. I wanted to get back into our complex, it's called Yantar, as you probably know. And here there's this: they say that while before it was just plain dangerous, now it's simply impossible to get through. Maybe they're exaggerating?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_46">
    <text>I was in Yantar, the science is completely dead there: sneaking around, hiding. They're living off the supplies the helicopters drop. On the other hand there really are a lot of zombies there now. If you spend a week living there among them, you'll start sneaking around yourself. That's the kind of place it is. Not very pleasant.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_47">
    <text>To the dogs with him. Who does he think he is to be hanging out with zombies?! So many of them in the stupid complex, and they keep on coming. And there's more and more of them there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_48">
    <text>We're trying to stop the movement of zombies from the laboratory complex. To say honestly, I totally wouldn't mind if you joined, we do have a shortage of men.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_49">
    <text>You know we're also gathering various data. For instance, I'm researching the main pathways of the quasi-alives...that is, zombies according to your terminology... spread. Would you be willing to share your findings?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_5">
    <text>Yeah that's about it. Some feed off the Garbage, collecting little junk, others penetrate deeper into the Zone. Naturally there you can find much better items, but not everyone will want to go there. That's no place for rookies, and if you don't have any ammo, don't even think about going there. It's a lost cause. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_50">
    <text>Did you get to shoot at the zombies climbing out of the laboratory windows? Well you better watch it because they're not afraid of anything, don't feel any pain, in other words, wretches without any brains.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_51">
    <text>I'm going to apply for a position in the laboratory. Hey man, relax, I'm kidding. You know that if you wander into these parts, you're as good as dead. Best case scenario, you'll turn into a zombie.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_52">
    <text>I'm warning you don't go into the lab. Well if you really want to go then go, I won't hold you back by force. Just that stalkers don't come back from there alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_53">
    <text>You see, I would like to warn you. You shouldn't go into the laboratory. In fact nobody should go there. It's linked to major alterations in the psychology and metabolism of an individual, and I'm afraid these affects are not reversible.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_54">
    <text>There! Now I'm going to shed some light on you, enlighten you, basically will save a lost sheep. So here's the deal man: don’t aim your travels towards the laboratory complex. It's shady there, very shady. People disappear there, and then at times come back to haunt you at night. Only these aren't some vampire horror stories, but the real truth about zombies. That's how it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_55">
    <text>Have you seen our smart asses? Lately they're completely chickening out. Gotta call in the whole regiment along with the air force for protection just to take a few steps off the base.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_56">
    <text>And what's in it to you? Don't bother them with stupid questions, and then they'll leave you alone as well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_57">
    <text>You see we usually don't leave the bunker without the necessary protection. The conditions of the surrounding territory don't permit it. I'm a sort of an exception, don't really like large expeditions, all this fuss, soldiers. But in any case I'm afraid I can't tell you anything helpful for the time being.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_58">
    <text>I get a kick out of our happy scientists. I just totally dig it, man! They usually don't show their faces out of the bunker. And even if they do, like they did the other day - my goodness! Troops everywhere, helicopters, armor technology. They might as well haul a battleship here, or at least an armored train.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_59">
    <text>It's already the third day that I'm still hanging out here observing. There's a laboratory here, right? Nobody's gone in it from the very beginning, the Dutiers used to purge zombies and now stopped completely, right? But scientists had to go in there. That means they found a way to protect themselves. Only the devil knows from what. So I'm thinking why not snoop around and find out. I bet there are so many goodies there that you may as well collect them in with a shovel.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_6">
    <text>In the last few days packs of animals are coming out of the Dark Valley. What's forcing them out of there is unclear, but they're really pushing out of there, as if from a fire. And in the eastern sector the mutants are breeding like flies. All we can do is keep shooting them down. So that's the news.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_60">
    <text>And what are you looking for here? Also trying to get into the laboratory? Did you hear a fairy tale about magical instruments and piles of artifacts? Man, when will you guys ever learn?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_61">
    <text>I work here, young man, simply work here, carrying out my duty for science and humanity. And if you wish to find out about the abandoned laboratory, the same thing that every stalker I meet thinks I know, I will tell you - I don't know and don't want to know. This topic doesn't interest me and never interested me. Is that clear?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_62">
    <text>Maybe the brainiacs really did come up with some sort of instrument? I wonder what's hidden in that damned laboratory. Even if there aren't any goodies there, still it's interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_63">
    <text>I'm wondering, maybe I should join 'Freedom'. There's their base in the old Army Warehouses. And why not, seems like they are pretty smart guys, and so what if they're a bit disorganized. It's even better that way. I don't need to be disciplined. I know what I'm supposed to be doing. It's not like this is my first month here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_64">
    <text>You're not too friendly with 'Freedom' are you? Yo don't get all upset. I think that soon we'll run them out of the warehouses. They don't have any organization nor any discipline. A big herd of meatheads at best. And they dare stand up against us, those NATO fledglings.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_65">
    <text>I met up with one of the 'Duty' men when there's a ceasefire. We shared some info. The man's actually smart, but shit, narrow-minded like your Tanker. You see our philosophy is completely different from theirs. You can only tame the Zone, assimilate it, but not destroy it. To do it we need open access to all of the information. Someone will come up with something eventually. But they're all about 'close it', 'lock it' and 'don't spread it'. Tards, complete retards. On the other hand it does makes sense to them. When the whole political machine is behind you, you're not supposed to think outside of the box.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_66">
    <text>There's a little cottage here, used to be a calm place, but now there are some creeps breeding there. Better go around, so that's what I am going to do. Hey man, I warned you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_67">
    <text>I want to warn you, stalker. Right now the bloodsuckers have long since made a nest in the village, and maybe something worse, so be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_68">
    <text>There's nothing new. There are no more artifacts here and nor bloodsucker in those little cottages. We shot them off best as we could. Now I came here, and just couldn't ever go back to that place. Intuition maybe, but I can't and that's it. No way! There is death there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_69">
    <text>I'm getting the hell out of here! Bummed for four weeks around the border, and that's it, enough for me. Freaks are constantly coming over here from the direction of the Scorcher, and each day more and more of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_7">
    <text>Now many have become trashmen. Before they didn't used to even look in the piles of stuff. Such high radiation that it'll hard-boil eggs for you in half an minute. And now that it's gotten harder to find the goodies, they'll wrap themselves in protection, take some chemicals, and climb in the trash to look. There's all sorts of stuff that comes up there, though usually it's little junk.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_70">
    <text>If you're coming here to our blockade with respect. If not get the hell out of my sight! We need real men and not sissies, got enough of those already.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_71">
    <text>You're here for the blockade man? All the better, at least one more normal person will be here. We organized this thing and held it together pretty well, but then all the beasts had to come our way! Now it's tough and every weapon counts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_72">
    <text>Aren't you up to date? The way to the center of the Zone has been opened! Either it opened on its own or someone tried really hard. If so, thanks to them whole-heartedly. Now all you have to do is gather the finest goods!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_73">
    <text>You might have waited, stalker. Don't run after everything. Just tell me do you know what's over there? That's right you don't know. Don't know whether there's anything there or not. What kinds of traps await you, you don't know either. Then why the hell are you trying to break through like Rambo?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_74">
    <text>The way to the center is free, understand?! Now there's a straight path right to the center! Now everyone is gonna haul over there. What's important is to be among the first, and gather the first fruit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_75">
    <text>Keep on trucking ahead, you'll see everything yourself! Don't you want to see for yourself what's going on ahead? Well then you're totally blessed. There must be so many goods there! For example you heard about the Granter of Wishes, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_76">
    <text>Just like children, for goodness sake! 'Wish Granter', 'Klondike artifacts'... can't believe my eyes and ears!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_77">
    <text>I want to know what is on the horizon, dude! Suddenly, in one fell swoop, we'll find an explanation for all this garbage that you call the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_78">
    <text>Did you see the city with skyscrapers? That's Pripyat! The station is right behind it. Oh how I wish to get in there. It's just that it's hard to know what's roaming in there nowadays.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_79">
    <text>Let me explain. There's Pripyat. Behind it is Chernobyl NPP. What's going on there and who's inhabiting those parts is unknown. This is the place for us. We'll find something for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_8">
    <text>Not up to date. I'm getting ready to go to the Bar to chat with guys. What, you've never been there? Goodness! So here's the deal, the way you're heading, just keep on moving north. The Bar's just around the corner. It's very helpful to drop by there, especially for newbies like you. It's like advice from a doctor. There are experienced men there, who knows, they may help you, tell you something, how, what and where. One thing for sure you'll run into our buddies from 'Duty' on the way, and here it depends if you're lucky whether they'll like you. If not, well then they won't. And watch out for the bandit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_80">
    <text>Pripyat! Pinch me damn it! Finally! From here it's just a ways away to the station. Damn, hard to know who or what you will run into, or what critter is sharpening its teeth waiting for somebody to eat.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_81">
    <text>Listen friend, are you also hearing a voice in your head, or am I hallucinating? It keeps on murmuring something over and over again.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_82">
    <text>Damn, another one, so here's the deal. I'll try to explain for the billionth time what kind of telepathic effect people here experience. There are voices constantly calling stalkers towards the center of the Zone promising to grant every wish for the one who is able to touch it. What's it called? Oh yeah, the 'Monolith.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_83">
    <text>Do you hear a voice? Cool, just like a MP3 player in your head! Shame there's only one track though, 'Come to me and you'll have great happiness'. Two hours same ol' harping on the same song.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_84">
    <text>And you can't guess what it is? You're trying to break through to the station yourself too! Well so are we, what else is new?! Just as long as we can get these retards off the road.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_85">
    <text>The territory of the station is very close. For now we still can't deal with the resistance of the 'Monolithians'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_86">
    <text>There it is, Chernobyl NPP, within arm's reach. Just a little further. And these damned bitches are so stubborn, won't let us through! No big deal we'll clear them out in no time!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_9">
    <text>Listen friend you don't know about Agroprom? I wanted to go there, but everyone started mocking me. There aren't any goods there anymore, they cleaned the place out a while ago, and now only anomalies are left. Do you know if that is true, are they serious or are they just saying that to joke around? I'm pretty new here and I believe what the locals say. Maybe they're all together in on it, just to mess around with other stalkers? All they need is a reason to laugh their heads off, those jerks!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_94">
    <text>Wait! Go quickly, but don't hurry too much. There are Monolithians all over the place. They know the city threw and threw, and set up lots of traps. You need to be very careful. Don't forget to talk to Feldsher.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_95">
    <text>I'm warning you, for now a large portion of the city is controlled by the Monolith faction. Lots of traps and they know the city like the back of their hands. Keep a sharp eye out and check your weapons and supplies.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_96">
    <text>Oh, what I would gladly do is cover the city with carpet bombing, or maybe nuke it. Those swine... the only place they're not hiding is in sand boxes, flower pots and toilets. How many people have already died because of these creeps!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_97">
    <text>Listen, who knows anything about this 'Wish Granter' thing. Maybe it's not eternal, or there won't be enough of something for everybody? So what's one to do? Get down on all fours? And you, dude, I promise you this, if we get there, you're going after me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_98">
    <text>Duty will break through to the center to be first, if not one of the first! Just imagine stalker, what some psychotics, scientists, paranoics and oligophrenics would ask this thing to grant? And then what?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_99">
    <text>News of the century, 'everyone who can walk and carry a weapon is here now'! Anything can happen here! You just get it into your head that anything that you wish could happen! And then someone will come along and say 'I want for the Zone to disappear from now on and forever more'. Huh? Do you grasp the dimensions of the possible tragedies? We're all going to end up in a bag of shit, all of us!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_119">
    <text>Yes, where new, bandits chase us all the time, but scientists are helping us. It's all business.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_120">
    <text>Brother after yesterday's drinking my head is pounding. Might be best to pour a little one, and then we'll talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_121">
    <text>Hang on bro, now with the guys sitting near the smokey campfire, they would most likely start asking too many questions, and right now my head is not clear.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_122">
    <text>About Strelok, well yes do not worry, your on your own. You want to talk with a senior, no? Well he's been waiting for you and will get pissed if you don't show up, and when he gets angry he will kick his Mama. No whining.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_123">
    <text>I tell you I saw mercenaries take Rostok, and captured a brother and another stalker. Well you know they, if still alive, that they won't get released. I have learned from the scientists that it would be hell to pass through there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_124">
    <text>We need to assemble some tougher guys for the hit on this group. Yesterday this fooless guy got caught and the mercenaries threw him down a well. He is now gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_125">
    <text>Check us out brother, look at my team, drunken suckers. Attack the mercenaries with these guys?! Dolgovtsev only with words helps. Occasionally we get a squad to help out, but that is rare. Others usually go in the direction of Amber. So we don't get much help.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_126">
    <text>Yes there are beasts. Where do they come from? I was thinking from rushing into Amber to find out. It was at night the other day when I walked away from the fire, about 30 meters to take a leak, and a bloodsucker was behind me and almost devoured me. Luckily Vadik was the lookout and he stabbed the bloodsucker between the eyes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_127">
    <text>You should not walk here alone. We are here with a team of guys. Weird sounds here even from the toilets. Mutants come in twos and threes. If one travels alone, there is certain death.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_0">
    <text>Something new? To hell with your new, when there's so much old shit that you couldn't scoop it up with a shovel. The bandits went mad, the poor swine. We tread between the anomalies trying to get the artifacts, and then there are the ones stealing other people's goods... asses! Just watch out and don't wander into Garbage, that's exactly their kind of place.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_1">
    <text>I'm stuck here, you got it, stuck. I want to go home and they're not letting me. That's all the news. The guys that walk deep into the Zone, the ones that have been around a while, they say different things. And at times they bring the goodies too. You'd be jealous. They say that there are places with mounds of gold, all for the taking. Granted not many will get there, and even less will make it back with their findings.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_10">
    <text>A week ago Otter got burned by the Scorcher. It would make sense if he was some yellow-bellied rookie, but he's been a stalker for many years. They say he was even on Strelok's team. And then all of a sudden...</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_100">
    <text>I'm not up to date with all the latest news ... ask around.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_101">
    <text>These local critters come from all sides. I already think that the more we kill the more they appear. Nothing but victory will be ours because we have tougher guys. We would have put things in order here, but for the dead guys we had to retaliate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_102">
    <text>Damn this place, but not the Agroprom area in general. Fight, fight ... and with whom and against what? Can't be normal that mutants so quickly multiply. We kill so many and yet there are always more.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_103">
    <text>I've heard that many of the anomalies and artifacts are no longer visible. Perhaps it's because of emissions, they pump up the energy band too much. So beware, it's now not so easy to travel, a detector is now a matter of life and death. A descriptive artifact can be found only with advanced detectors. Good luck. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_104">
    <text>If seeking shelter know that this place here is one of the safest. You are either extorted in Landfill, or put up with crowds of mutants somewhere, or both in Agricultural Industry, or attacked by corrupt military. Even with anomalies and rare creatures this place is tolerable, compared to other places.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_105">
    <text>Hunt for mutants. For the bodies of some of these, merchants and scientists are paying good money. Don't believe me? Go see for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_11">
    <text>Tell me this stalker, why do you loners sometimes go nuts? Do you lack some basic discipline? The other week one decided to go past the Scorcher. And they say he was experienced too. There's an easier way to get rid of your brains, Russin roulette with a 9mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_12">
    <text>Screw these mercs. They've been drinking our blood for a long time and now they've turned on the eggheads too. And why did they give in? Because of some ransom, or to share the Nobel prizes?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_13">
    <text>Lately the mercs have become much more active. We also call them marauders. There's another kind of swine here, don't know if you heard of them. Like bandits except experts in the ways of war. Strange thing is they used to prefer to attack stalkers, but as of late have become more interested in the scientists. But you look out in any case. I wouldn't put it past them to blow your head off.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_14">
    <text>Heard a rumor that the eggheads dug up something awesome. And suddenly everybody went Mashogana. The military, mercs, and even the Duty guys aren't far behind.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_15">
    <text>If you want to know about the thing that everyone's been bugging me about for the last two days, then I'm telling you: go and take a hick! If I knew and they didn't forbid me, I would have told you. But as it stands I don't know. Don't know sheeet! What did those scientists find? Where did our leadership go? What do I have to do with any of it?! They're off doing their thing and don't have to answer to us nor explain themselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_16">
    <text>Ha! Everybody's gone nuts around here! A Confederate member with his group have returned from a raid, dragged a bunch of artifacts in. Mama mia! Of course Confederate is silent as usual, and all of his guys are joking around as if they went up to the Yukon and struck gold... the swine!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_17">
    <text>During the last few days there are all these beasts coming in from the Scorcher. The people by the old warehouses constructed a barrier and for now they seem to manage it. If it weakens they'll have to go for reinforcements. There's nothing else that can be done.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_18">
    <text>Did you hear rumors going around that the Zone is growing? I think it's true. I saw such a frightening humanoid monster right by the perimeter. Before you could just run into the center of the Zone, but it is very dangerous and you have to move slowly. Things don't look good, do they?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_19">
    <text>It is possible that they're not lying about the bloodsuckers by the border of the Zone. But what does that have to do with the widening of the Zone? A group wandered off towards the border, they got through. Sometimes we have to spend a few days patrolling for stalkers. Once beyond the perimeters nobody's screaming, 'Help, we're being surrounded by mutants!', there is only silence.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_2">
    <text>Yeah it is kind of sad after all. Just the other day Otter died, absolutely for nothing. Just can't believe it. Have you heard about Otter? Well he was practically a professor. Within a year he knew the Zone like the back of his hand. Just then like that, out of the blue! There are some real experienced stalkers out there, but the Zone still takes them. There are others who end up going back to the Mainland. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_20">
    <text>What do you think, does the Barkeep know the details about what the scientists dug up? Listen, maybe he even hooked up with  the scientists. Seems like lately he finds more experienced stalkers and gives them strange assignments. Doesn't explain anything, just says go here and there, and these places are dangerous, and no goodies in sight. So what the heck is he looking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_21">
    <text>Something strange is going on. The zombies that used to be afraid to go into the light are now trudging around all over the place. What the hell is that all about?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_22">
    <text>The zombies became more aggressive and active for some reason. Before we used to purge them right in the complex itself, but now we can only hold the entrances to the complex. But you didn't hear it from me, understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_23">
    <text>Be careful because these walking corpses have flooded the whole territory. Very dumb and aggressive. We are constantly under seige, day and night. So it's quite dangerous here young man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_24">
    <text>Oooh, I bet the eggheads have messed something up in that lab of theirs. Before it wasn't very easy to run into a zombie, but now they're just pouring out of the complex. What's most important is that they're wandering around as if they lost something and are looking for it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_25">
    <text>Rumors are going around that scientists hired one of ours to go down into the lab. Gave him something like protective gear, and nothing else. And there are no details about this.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_26">
    <text>They blab all sorts of things. They even say that some nut turned up who talked with a scientist and agreed to go down into the lab for them for some reason. Now there's some nonsense!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_27">
    <text>And here's the big joke of the week! The eggheads gave one of your guys a pretty good grant, and so he went into the lab with one of their instruments. Another victim, damnit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_28">
    <text>I think something's brewing again. The eggheads dug something up that has everyone standing on their toes, which means that you and I won't have any peace either. </text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_29">
    <text>Only the devil knows what is going on. They have been chasing us around twice as much as before, either a blockade, or a purge, and there is a significant increase in troop numbers in the Zone as well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_3">
    <text>It's all sad, that much I know. There's always been lots of people on the periphery, but half of them have never been deep into the Zone and there aren't enough artifacts for everyone. They even tore out and took away everything that they could from the laboratories and factories. Soon there won't be anything left to do here but open a restaurant with an exotic view and cuisine.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_30">
    <text>I don't even know what to tell you. There's always something going on here, and not within the bounds of reason. Although they don't think so on the Mainland, but you and I are, so to speak, in an anomalous Zone now.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_31">
    <text>The eggheads are sniffing something out. Only hell knows what secret they've stumbled upon, and they certainly have the troops wrapped around their little fingers. And many are searching all over the Agroprom and Dark Valley already, searching, searching, trying to find something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_32">
    <text>With every day there's more and more crap coming out of the Scorcher, and the guys from 'Duty' and 'Freedom' decided to fart around again. So they'll kill each other off, and then what? How long can we hold the border all by ourselves?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_33">
    <text>The mutants are trying harder and harder to get past the barrier. Lately it's been really hard. If some people put an end to their retarded ways, we would have had more success!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_34">
    <text>The 'Duty' keeps on screaming about their super-heroic deeds an the barrier. If only someone believed them. We began this deal, and we're the ones that keep it going, and on top of that many of the loners like yourself willingly stayed behind. But those guys from the Duty... the assess... to hell with them!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_35">
    <text>I heard that Duty has totally sold out. They keep on saying something like; 'We are all volunteers who want to establish safety and order in the Zone'. Yeah right, volunteers! Some sponsor gave these so-called volunteers such great weapons and ammo, that you'd die from envy. So they sold out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_36">
    <text>What rumors are going around? I'll tell you about the rumors; soon there'll be more order. We'll purge the Zone from all sorts of beasts, and certain asses too.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_37">
    <text>Did you hear what the guys from Duty are saying they'll do to us? 'Turn them to dust', and that's just the bare minimum. This whole situation worries me. Especially since, people say, they've rearmed themselves with state-of-the-art equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_38">
    <text>What news? We sit here, the mutants come at us, we kill them off, then they come again, only stronger. Granted a few times the military helicopters came by, and it seems they somehow flew past the Scorcher.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_39">
    <text>What news can there be... SOSDD. Mutants, Freedom, blah blah blah. Although recently soldiers started flying by in helicopters. At least they could have killed at a mutant once in a while; but nooooo, none of that.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_4">
    <text>News? Who cares what they say! You can't believe everything everyone says. For example they say that some experienced stalker came from the inner areas, brought something nobody's ever seen before, and impressed a bunch of granies. Well I can make up a hundred stories like that myself!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_40">
    <text>I saw some military helicopters: imagine this, they flew overhead and headed past the Brain Scorcher! Well I'm thinking they're gonna crash now. But nothing they just keep on going. Hung out there for a while, twirled around and then headed back. Typical, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_41">
    <text>Oh yea, now that there's a way to the center, there must be so much treasure lying right under your feet. Ah-huh, right!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_42">
    <text>Now that there are ways of getting to the center of the Zone relatively safely, stalkers are drawn to it like flies to honey. Yeah greed really isn't humanity's greatest quality.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_43">
    <text>Now this is the life! While all those from the Bar and the perimeter are still trying to get here, we'll get all the best stuff! We'll gather all the best goodies and let the others pick up the worthless junk after us.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_44">
    <text>Well they say that the Wish Granter actually exists. Somebody even managed to get to it already, and made a ton of wishes.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_45">
    <text>Listen buddy, I know that anything can happen in the Zone. Saw it myself many times. But these stories about the immediate granting of wishes like a private hotel room in the Carribeans is complete bullshit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_46">
    <text>Don't you know? Two of our guys, some of the very first who made it to the center, actually got to the Granter of wishes and wished! All their life they dreamed about islands and a warm sea, so now they must be sunbathing somewhere in the tropics.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_47">
    <text>We found a hero, the main guy from Freedom. Everyone thought that he went back to the Mainland, but actually he took a small team and somehow made it past the Scorcher. Now there's a man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_48">
    <text>In a formerly inaccessible area  of the Zone one of the Freedom detachments was discovered. How they managed to get through unharmed and then survive a few weeks there, I can't even imagine. I guess we underestimated these guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_49">
    <text>Imagine this, they found our Nicholai Miklukho! And the guys that were with him also had survived. They sneaked past the brain Scorcher, and then spent a month just killing time because couldn't get back out.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_5">
    <text>There's something sticky brewing. Rumors are going around that the leader of the 'Duty' faction, the head honcho, didn't just leave the Zone on business, but made a deal with the 'Freedom' faction. Well they could have made the same deal in the open, because now everything's a muddle. Things don't look good. On the other hand the experienced guys say that they started fighting back the other day for no good reason. I just hope the cabinet-freaks from the 'Mainland' don't drag us all into another meat grinder.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_50">
    <text>You heard?! Some troops are hurrying to get here. They'll be here soon. They found out that the Scorcher broke down and decided to take all the goods for themselves!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_51">
    <text>New information has just come in, there's going to be a massive size landing of army troops at the Station. My advice for you is this: if you want to snatch up some of the goodies, you best hurry.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_52">
    <text>It's complete chaos, that's what it is! But you see, the corridor has opened, they purged the Station from all kinds of shit, and there you have it, the military is ready to take advantage of it! No shame and no conscience.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_53">
    <text>I don't get one thing, how could the members of the 'Freedom' faction hold out for a month here? Do they have invisible cloaks or something? There's no way!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_54">
    <text>Do you understand what's going on here? Well I just gained new respect for Mikluha! Imagine trying to survive for four weeks in this shit, and not to lose any of your guys either!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_55">
    <text>Here some of them went crazy. And to think they all used to be pretty tough guys, but now are whining like the biggest retards. Scary.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_56">
    <text>The closer you get to the Station, the stronger the unknown telepathic force becomes. Some have started going insane, others are traumatized and are seeing things. Maybe this is a good time to retreat.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_57">
    <text>Listen, people here are really losing their minds. Somebody sees a stone and begins hollering that it is an artifact or a potato, that he saw it first, and that everyone should get the hell away from it. Another one sees Yahweh on a cloud embracing angels. Yep, there's definitely some sick shit going on here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_6">
    <text>The troops are bustling about searching and digging. Before the helicopters used to fly only to Yantar protecting the scientists, and carried supplies and technology. But now they're practically invading the place, planning all sorts of expeditions, driving around in APC's. Already saw them in Agroprom and Dark Valley. Don't understand it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
    <text>They say that again someone tried to get past the Scorcher. Well obviously he never came back. You never heard of the Brain Scorcher? What's wrong with you man?! It's the biggest danger in this whole area! Only problem is that all the horrors they say about it are mostly true.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
    <text>Here, besides the bandits, the troops started roaming around for some reason. Before you'd see a helicopter once in a hundred years, but now they're flying around the Zone all the time. Did they lose something or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_9">
    <text>I want to warn you stalker that the soldiers here lately seem to have gone mad. Before they used to calmly and quietly protect the scientists, but now it's as if their tails got burned or something, dashing around, bustling about. Not in the most peaceful mood either, they shot at our bro's more than once already, and even among us they've wounded two men in the last week.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_help_thanks_1">
    <text>Thank you very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_0">
    <text>What are you doing walking around without any protection? Tired of living, is that it? There's an anomaly behind every bush. Whack, and you're a gonner! Here they don't even pee without protection, you could get a dose of radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_1">
    <text>Seems like you don't know your way around well yet, so I'll warn you as a friend. Have nothing to do with the military. Once you spot one, get the hell out of there cuz they have no brains. First they'll put a bullet in you, and then check your id to see your name.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_10">
    <text>Here the 'Duty' guys rule. Our dear beloved police force, or something like that. Keep this in mind to avoid trouble.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_100">
    <text>Good day stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_101">
    <text>Ga-day mate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_102">
    <text>I wish you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_103">
    <text>Hey dude!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_104">
    <text>Hey.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_105">
    <text>Sup!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_106">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_107">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_108">
    <text>Hello stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_109">
    <text>Greetings stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_11">
    <text>You're located in an area where order is maintained by the 'Duty' group. Every demand of the patrol must be carried out without any resistance. All the necessary explanations will be given if need arises. Although the code of behavior here is simple, treat everyone with common courtesy and everything will be fine.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_110">
    <text>Hey you, stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_111">
    <text>Word!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_112">
    <text>Well who have we got here?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_113">
    <text>And who is this we have here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_114">
    <text>Hello, man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_120">
    <text>I came here recently. I am already tired of the local situation. Get out is much harder.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_121">
    <text>Well dear man! Also hiding? Everything is hidden, even a stalker's past life, and what they are escaping from.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_122">
    <text>You know about the 'Clear Sky' faction? Conspiring with secret agents. Only fragments of radio transmissions are heard about them, and stalkers tell different stories about them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_123">
    <text>There appeared here recently a group called the 'Avengers'. It is unclear what their interests are. I've seen many people in my life and learned to understand them, but these men are natural killers. Professionals in one word.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_12">
    <text>If you have questions then head straight for the Bar and don't bother me. They'll tell you all about it there, and answer your questions, and ask their own. But I'm tight on time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_13">
    <text>First time here? Then I suggest you go to the Bar. There your colleagues there that will tell you all the latest news.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_14">
    <text>Try not to get too close to zombies and don't go into the laboratory, got it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_15">
    <text>I don't recommend you to get near the laboratory, too many zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_16">
    <text>You know, I would suggest that you keep your distance from the laboratory complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_17">
    <text>You watch out for zombies, they're dumb and aren't afraid of anything. And better not go into the laboratory, they have their breeding grounds there.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_18">
    <text>You keep in mind that the Brain Scorcher is close. Don't even think about heading north.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_19">
    <text>Watch out if you don't want to lose your brains. Don't go any further north of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_2">
    <text>Be careful when you get past the bridge, got it? There are too many wandering dogs there. If you don't pay attention they'll tear you apart in no time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_20">
    <text>You look out for yourself! You know that the Scorcher is very close. If you go further north you'll be another dead tard.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_21">
    <text>It's as if we’re walking through a mine field, only worse. Only the devil knows what goes on in here. You can't relax even for a second.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_22">
    <text>I suggest you heighten your attention, and once you heighten it, keep it and don't relax. The minute you relax, you're gone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_23">
    <text>Here you have to be on your toes all the time! Sleep with one eye open! Shit can happen to you any minute here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_24">
    <text>Be careful with the dickheads! They're like cockroaches here, tons of them!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_25">
    <text>Destroy the so-called Monolithians as soon as you see them. They're very dangerous and are real fanatics!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_26">
    <text>There are some retards here, they call themselves Monoliths. Someone started calling them that a long time ago. well, no matter. Basically they're not afraid of pain. If they run out of ammo they will jump on you and literally try to gnaw through your throat. So if you see one don't think twice about it and fire right away.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_3">
    <text>Listen up. If you see a tunnel don't go in it. I'm telling it to you straight, cuz not everyone has the brains not to get themselves into deep shit. They won't even be able to carry you out afterwards. You'll be splattered in pieces on the walls. That's the Zone, understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_4">
    <text>Why are you low on supplies? Did you also run into the freaks under the bridge? Those bitches! They almost killed me just now. Had to give them almost all of my goods! They're sitting around patroling and guarding like theives. Might just as well be bandits at the checkpoints, makes no difference.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_5">
    <text>Why are you traveling alone? There are lots of skinheads here and they can catch you at any moment. Lately I heard they completely lost it and now they are attacking the security checkpoints.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_6">
    <text>I'm warning you that you're not up to date on the situation. Lately the bandits have been moving around in here. This is already the second shoot-out with them in just a week. Be careful and watch out. They've already sent six loners to the other side.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_7">
    <text>Did you by any chance hear what the troops needed in the Research Institute wing? Why have they become so active?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_8">
    <text>You be more careful here. There is a platoon entrenched in the main building. In one word, they're jackals with no conscience, no mercy, and they would kill everyone off it they could.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_9">
    <text>You shouldn't go into Dark Valley alone. There's a nice tight bandit group there in one of the buildings. They still can't be forced out of there. Be careful not to run into them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_1">
    <text>Help friend!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_10">
    <text>Somebody help!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_11">
    <text>Guards! I'm wounded! Come here!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_12">
    <text>Help! I'm dying!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_13">
    <text>Stalker ... give first aid kit ... dying ... help me - and I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_14">
    <text>Stalker ... Give me some first aid ... dying ... help - and I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_15">
    <text>Stalker ... Give first aid ... dying... help me and I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_16">
    <text>Stalker ... how about a bandaid ... dying ... and I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_17">
    <text>Stalker ... Give first aid kit... hurting here ... help - and I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_18">
    <text>Stalker ... Give me a first aid kit or mouth-to-mouth ... dying... help - then I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_2">
    <text>Guy, first aid kit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_3">
    <text>Bring the first aid kit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_4">
    <text>Anti-shock, guy! Hurry!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_5">
    <text>A first aid kit, stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_6">
    <text>Somebody, give me a first aid kit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_7">
    <text>Friend, a first aid kit ... a kit!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_8">
    <text>Help, dude!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_intro_help_9">
    <text>Hey friend, can you share your first aid kit, can you?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_128">
    <text>Ah, your mother ... things are not as they where. For a long time I was pretty lucky at everything, and then one day circumstances starting changing. You think I'm in this rotten hole for the fun of it? The zone was tiptop once, and the place was safer, and earnings where easier. Well all that is gone and my penpals are gone too.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_129">
    <text>Simple. I went back to the road and went away. There was a bounty on my head. I wish to live you know. That's why I moved here away from human eyes. I'll wait while everything settles. I will go back later. I'll have to talk about the matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_130">
    <text>I am in 'Clear Skies' by accident. They dragged me out of the quagmire in time. Taken to the base, talking with Sviblov. I think he is a smart guy. He knows about the Zone things that not every brain can comprehend. And the purpose in "Heaven" is correct. Here I am with then and joined. I am helping them the best that I can.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_131">
    <text>I became more experienced and saved up some money. How to get rich, buy myself a gun and armor, and go to the center of the Zone where the 'Wishmaster' is. There I wonder if anyone managed to get through. That's what I'm going to do. Oh how I hope to get there!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_132">
    <text>Heard plenty of stories and fables about all the evil going through Cordon. Here you can die at any moment, and carrying supplies is not so simple. But what kills me the most is the fact that there is no quiet and peaceful place. Even sleep should is hard to get.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_133">
    <text>I was fascinated by the Zone. Came here by accident, an illegal tour. And you know, I was hooked immediately! People here are real - enemies and friends. And the danger, gives a sense of imminent death. The Zone give one a strong feeling of life and death.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_134">
    <text>I have a friend here waiting for me. Must return to him some stuff. We missed each other out here. The paths around here are like pretzels. I think I'll go back to the Bar and try to find some friends.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_135">
    <text>Some schmuck sold me a map with caches marked on it. I'm beginning to suspect it is fake. I looked all over the place for these caches. Well, when I find that guy again I'll kill the bastard!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_136">
    <text>I was resting after this raid. Walked almost to the barrier. We are there to defend from evil spirits. The good guys grouped together. Shaggy Sergei, Lech, Malden - all the guys with soul. And I'm still getting supplies. There is a trader here. So I decided immediately to stay. Life is easier here than in the larger part of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_137">
    <text>It's like going through a minefield, only worse. Here only the devil knows what's going on at times. Even for a second you can not relax.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_138">
    <text>Why? What do you want to hear? I'll tell you this: Dolgovtsev, the policemen and his guys, are able to restore order by force. So basically I do not like them. Everywhere they go they show force. Moreover, they just want to rule the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_139">
    <text>Why? What do you want to hear? Most of the stakers here are just dreamers.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_140">
    <text>I've heard 'Duty' makes radio annoucements.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_141">
    <text>Recently Amber was cleaned out of zombies. There is a research laboratory there. The scientists there can be helpful.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_142">
    <text>You know what? Let 'Dolgovtsev' and 'Svobodov' handle the marauders. I do not care!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_143">
    <text>I love the sciences! Going to the bunker is not easy. The area is full of warriors, helis, etc!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_144">
    <text>Be careful, because these walking corpses have flooded the entire district. They are very stupid, but aggressive. All the time we're on the defensive, night and day. So there is quite a bit of danger here young man.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_145">
    <text>Have you hear that 'Dolgovtsev' has been boasting a lot lately? To be honest, it bothers me a bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_146">
    <text>You never know what they say. Some believe anything they are told. Here it is best to talk to the experienced.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_7">
    <text>I heard that a group of stalkers made their way to the Zone center right before the big release. Interestingly, they managed to get to the Wishmaster. When there they all perished in a fight.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_8">
    <text>Possessions these days do not come easily. When ya come out alive from the clutches of the mutants and anomalies, there will still be the patrols of bandits, and then with the military. In the end you come back poorer than you left. Let's do something with these bloodsuckers too. Hopefully stalkers will now address these monsters.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_101">
    <text>Fuck those Monolith! They turned completely crazy. There was a time when they were quite peaceful. I remember once when I met one of them, he started telling their usual rubbish about the Monolith, he said something like: 'Brothers, the Monolith has summoned me last night. I talked to Him. He was beatiful in His magnificence. His light has nearly blinded me, but it filled me with great power! I know, I feel that His power is among us! He told me that only strong faith can defeat the forces of evil. He also said that His power will be only with His true followers. He told me that our victory is close'. I replied to that guy: 'Go away with your Monolith BS!'. He became very angry and shouted: 'The time will come when we will clean the Zone of all the untrue!' and stuff like that. Looks like he wasn't telling lies then because the followers of 'Monolith' are coming in crowds from CNPP, shooting everyone, fucking weirdos!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_102">
    <text>Got any matches? Ah, you don't smoke. Why am I so unlucky today?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_103">
    <text>Young stalker, if you see a message about Semetsky's death on your PDA don't worry about it, it's one of the Zone's legends. You will get that message many times. People say that Semetsky was one of those few who got to the 'Monolith'. And what did he ask for? Immortality, of course. So now he wanders around the Zone, dying and coming back to life over and over again. Some stalkers say that they've seen him near the 'Monolith', but they could be lying. The Zone is full of secrets and mysteries. You're not bored with my stories, right? Well go with peace. May you have good loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_104">
    <text>Okay, here's a joke. Three stalkers had an argument about who is the coolest. They've decided that the person who could get the most people out of the Bar is the coolest one. The first one grabbed a massive machinegun and went into the Bar and shouted:  \n - Everyone get the hell out of here!!! - half of the people have disappeared, about ten stalkers remained there and they've beaten that guy up. The next day the second stalker has dressed up like a mutant and ran into the Bar grunting. Some people escaped through the windows, others through the door, but a squad of Duty soldiers stayed - well, they taught him how to behave. They shaved his nut sack. The next day the third stalker walked into the Bar and said \n - Any gay stalkers here? \n They all ran out like gerbals on crack.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_105">
    <text>Well, there is a story, although they say that this happened a long time ago, before I got here. So... once upon a time, a foreigner had decided to become a stalker to earn some money. I think he was a scientist. No one knows what he really wanted here, but he spoke nearly no Russian at all. Actually, it's not even known how he got into the Zone and how he fount the Barman. Looks like somoene had told him about that beforehand. So he spoke no Russian, although he thought he did. He started to annoy the Barkeep in bad Russian. He spent several hours with him. Maybe he needed to get somewhere or maybe find somebody, I don't know. So the Barkeep didn't understand anything and decided to send him to the Freedom territory and told him: 'go there and there, that area is controlled by the Freedom soldiers, they will tell you everything you need'. For some reason it was believed that Freedom members were good at English. That foreigner has liked Barman's word 'control', they say it's the same in English. I don't know if it's true. So when the guy got to the Freedom base he started to annoy everybody, repeating 'Control, Controler, Controller', waving his hands towards the 'Duty' base. They say that the Freedomers got scared, woke up the whole camp. It was at night so they kept watch till morning. Later that day they fed the guy to a bloodsucker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_106">
    <text>Nowadays many people have turned into 'trash-men'. Before no one had looked in the big piles in Garbage. The radiation is so high it can boil your balls. But now it's harder to find artifacts, so they get into protective suits, take some medicine and go searching. There are many different things in those piles, but generally not very good.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_107">
    <text>The rookies are really annoying these days. They get into anomalies and die. Can you believe it, five young stalkers have died in the last two days. And others don't learn anything from their example. Nothing! You know, Fly has taken three rookies into his squad and where are thy now? But he had found some really good artifacts lately. Maybe he shot them himself. No, probably not... he's honest... relatively. Anyway I see you're a new stalker as well so keep your eyes wide open. Good luck!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_108">
    <text>Have you heard of secret laboratories deep in the Zone? People say they still function ... yes, yes ... I can't understand how anyone could survive there ... without food and safety. Here's an interesting thought, maybe it's not people that worked there? I had an interesting chat with some guy the other day. He didn't see those laboratories himself. No, he didn't, but his PDA had received some strange messages in Yantar. They were about one of those laboratories. One guy was telling the other, swearing, that he had met a person in a uniform that looked like a stalkers' uniform, but different still. And that person was transparant, and had told him to get out of there; 'Don't disturb us, go away, we are working here'. Well the guy got really scared ... of course! If I saw something like that I'd run to. On the other hand the stalker that told me about that said that it happened somewhere close to Radar. So it doesn't seem likely to be true. But you know ... mutations can always be different and weird, right? Maybe those are not people but some kind of phantoms made of pure energy. What do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_109">
    <text>I heard that a couple of Spetsnaz fighters were invited to the Arena. I want to meet the brave idiot who'd want to have a battle with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_110">
    <text>A pack of rats is running. A stalker comes out in front of them asking 'Are there any cool ones among you? 'No!' Then everyone should give me an artifact and you can keep running'. The next day it's the same. So the rats decided to call a Blind Dog for help. So they're running. That stalker comes out, stops the pack and asks; 'Are there any cool ones among you?'. The rats let the Blind Dog move forware and it says, 'Well, I'm cool'. The stalker runs away. Then a Controller comes out as says; 'So, the cool one should give me ten artifacts, all the rest need to give me one each and you all can keep running!'</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_111">
    <text>Hey mate have you ever heard of the 'Interception'? People say those are army special forces! But have you seen them at work? They aren't like those morons in Cordon. Not only do they go into very remote parts of the Zone but also spend months there! And that's no joke. They've got several bases around the Zone, many secret places, and they get their supplies via helicopter. Their commander is some guy called Dr. Gromov. I don't think that's his real name. They also call him either 'Major' or 'Thunder'. You don't believe me do you? Pahomych once met the 'Interception'! His legs saved him that time, otherwise they would've killed him. Cause it's all secret! Everyone knows Pahomych! Those people aren't idiots, they are a serious team. Hell knows what they need here, but they work really hard. If I had a third of their attitude, no just ten percent, I'd already have a big house in Sochah. People say those guys have some device which detects mutants two hundred meters away. Any creature! Of course with that thing they can walk around the Zone as though it is a park. Oh, I've also heard of a stalker, not a soldier, is one of our guys. Well they got to the centre of the Zone. Not only that, people say they can tame creatures. They never go out of the perimeter to the Main Land and no one comes to them. Well except for those who are chosen to get to the Sarcophagus. They've got lots of artifacts. Duty members know about them. They know but keep quiet, bastards! And if you ask any of them they'd say 'that's not true'. Aren't they bitches!?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_112">
    <text>I had a very unlucky incident happen to me. I lost my rucksack with loot in it. Just like that! I thought I'd have a lot of money, but then this unlucky event happened. At night a blind dog had jumped out of the bushes and started growling at me. I nearly wet myself, that's how scared I was, at first I even thought it was a pseudodog because normally you can hear when the blind ones approach, but pseudos are silent. Anyway I dropped my rucksack and ran away. I thought that that thing will chase me but it grabbed the rucksack and went in another direction. Bitch! Now I'm going on a new expedition. By the way do you want to go with me? No? Fine then, see you later.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_113">
    <text>I heard that Controllers are really weak during blowouts and they can't do anything, so you can kill them easily.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_114">
    <text>Here's a joke, a bit stupid but I find it funny. Three stalkers are sitting in a pub drinking vodka telling each other stalker stories. The first one says: \n - 'I met this massive monster in the Zone, wasted all my bullets on it, but finally got it with a grenade launcher'. Everyone goes - 'WOW'! The second one says: \n - 'Yesterday I saw an enormous creature in the Zone, wasted all my ammo on it, grenades didn't get it, but finally I killed it with my flamethrower'. Everybody goes - 'WOW'! The third one says: \n - 'I've spotted a giant monster in the Zone...' Everyone says: 'and?'. The stalker continued: 'I had to wash me trousers!'. Everyone says: 'Eeeehhhhkkkk!'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_115">
    <text>Have you heard of the Guide? He's one of the oldest stalkers here. People say he was the first to get into the Zone and that he's still alive. They say he can take you to any place you want to go in the Zone. But it's hard to find him, he doesn't stick adverts up on trees, ya know. And he doesn't agree to work with everyone. Takes a lot of money to influence him, but if you found him and he agreed to help you, you can be sure he will take you wherever you want to get. That's who I want to talk to! He probably knows what's beyond Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_116">
    <text>You know what? You shouldn't sleep in this part of the Zone. I'm lucky, I can't fall asleep anyways. But other people have nightmares so terrible that they sometimes don't even wake up in the morning because they had a heart attack during their sleep. Some die, others become crazy. But there is a rumour that there is a solution to that. If you really want to sleep, find a bucket or at least a big pan. But it has to be unbroken, without any holes. Put it on your head and you will sleep like a log. Hey you can laugh but it will be me making fun of you in a couple of days when you go mad from tiredness. You think you're smart? Then tell me, why the hell do the soldiers wear those helmets? Yes, now you start to understand something! Before, about a year or two ago, they didn't, but look at them nowadays! They've got really strange helmets. Guys had found a body of a soldier wearing one the other day, they told me. In that helmet there was something like a net inside, made of thin copper wire, connected to the inside of helmet. And no one knows what that thing's for and why it is there. But I tell you, this buzzing has something to do with that. It's definitely not anomalies, there aren't many of those here, in other places there are lots more. I think the stalkers are finding their ways. Prepared for everything. Remember my words, they want to get to the Sarcophagus. Soon there will be a big bang and nobody will like it. Remember my words. I just hope I won't be nearby when this all happens.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_117">
    <text>Have you heard the news? Yesterday there was a big slaughter in a camp nearby, a Mercs' attack. They killed everyone. The guard had fallen asleep. They slit his throat and then killed all his sleeping buddies too. None of them even had time to shoot.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_action_info_118">
    <text>Did I tell you about the Dark Stalker? Okay, there's a legend about this Dark Stalker in the Zone and nobody knows where he comes from and what's his business. The legend says he wears a long black coat with a hood on so you can't see his face and nobody has ever seen him with a gun. To be frank only a couple of people have seen him at all and from far away only, and they say he gives them terrible creeps, even mutants run away from him. Who is he? Some people say he is a new mutant, others believe he is a ghost, and some people think he was just made up by drunk stalkers. Who knows. I wouldn't believe in him unless I saw him myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_58">
    <text>Listen to this story by a Controller. An old Controller teaches the young one: 'Do you see that soldier on the post? His belt is tightened, his uniform is new, shoes shiny - he's called 'Spirit'. You can take control of him even from here, but there is no use - he can't shoot properly, scared of everything, he's got no muscles. Now look at the guy standing next to him, smoking. His uniform is worn, his shoes aren't new - he's called 'Scoop'. He's hard to take control of, he shoots well, always alert and he's got a lot of musclel, butt ugly though. You can take him at night, if he falls asleep. Now do you see that guy sleeping under the bush without a belt and barefeet? That's 'Oldman'. He's got much muscle and fat, but it's hard to get to him, he doesn't sleep at night and can kill you without any weapon. You need to get him when he goes into the village for vodka or goes for some artifacts into the Zone. And the last one, do you see that soldier, with a tight belt, shiny shoes? No, don't you dare take him for 'Spirit'. I once got one of them and after that I spent two weeks cleaning my lair, hardly ran away from him, he's called 'Comrade Sergeant'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_59">
    <text>I've been told a new joke while in the Bar. A stalker comes to Sidorovich, and Sidorovich says: \n 'Listen, stalker. I received a costume with full radiation protection from a secret Institute in Kiev. But nobody has tested it yet. Put it on and go into the Zone, try it out. And if you survive I will give you a discount for it'... And the stalker agreed. He went into the Zone and did not return for a day, then two days, then three. On the fourth day he returns, angry as a snork and throws the costume on Sidorovich's table. Sidorovich was surprised: \n 'What's wrong, stalker? Does it not protect? \n -'It does!' \n -'Not completely?' \n -'Completely!!' \n -'So why are you so angry?' \n -'Everyone in the Zone drinks vodka to heal radiation in the morning and they laugh at me while I walk around in a suit like it's Halloween!'</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_60">
    <text>A few days ago I've seen Monolith members clearing up the area near the 'Brain Scorcher'. There were about thirty of them shooting everything that moved: fleshes, boars, even dogs... and I... you know, got away from there, just in case. Don't want my butt filled with bullets.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_61">
    <text>Do you want a joke? A 'Niva' full of guys goes on a road towards the Zone, about 120 kilometers per hour. The policeman at the post whistles, the 'Niva' stops and a squad of 'Duty' soldiers gets out of it. They beat up the police guy, shoved his whistle up his arse and continued driving. The guy took his walkie-talkie out: \n -'Seven two-seven three! \n - Seven-two! \n - Seven-three! Some idiots are going in your direction and they don't respond well to whistles! Try stopping them with a pole! Copy seven-two?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_62">
    <text>Hey man, have you heard of Phantom? No? I'm gonna tell you about him then, you're not going to believe me. People say there was a stalker, no one knew his real name so everyone called him Phantom. He was an experienced stalker and had a good personality, understood people and people understood him, some people say he studied as a psychologist at a university, but that's irrelevant. The important thing about him was that he could get anywhere in the Zone without being spotted by anyone, army posts and anomalies weren't obstacles for him. He went into the centre of the Zone frequently but once hadn't returned, probably got killed by a blowout or something. Well, the legend is that he became something like a poltergeist, been wandering around the Zone for about ten years now, searching for stalkers, and when he finds one he looks into their soul, and if the stalker is a good person he will help him, point at a shelter or kill mutants around him. But if he finds anyone full of sins, then that stalker will not live for long, Phantom will rip him apart. That's a good-night tale for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_63">
    <text>Strelok, where did you get that gun? Bought it from Sid, I believe? Yeah he's got fine guns but they cost a lot. That bastard probably gets them for next to nothing from the army and sells them to us for three times the price! No mate, I'm not that stupid. I would rather find myself a gun in Garbage, it might emmit radiation ,but is going to be free.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_64">
    <text>Hey, stalker, I've been told a funny thing recently. Listen to this. There is a fight between Duty and Freedom members. So the Freedom commander stands up and shouts: \n -'Let's go, for Freedom!' - and everyone goes into attack. 'Duty' stalkers are on the other side: \n -'That's it, we're in shit, run for your life'. \n But an old experienced Duty soldier says: \n -'Wait, don't run -', gets out his gun: bang-bang-bang! 'Freedomers' lie down. After five minutes another 'Freedomer' gets up: \n - 'For the Zone! Hurray!' - and they start an attack. 'Duty': \n -'Now we're definitely in shit! We need to run!' \n The old 'Duty' soldier: \n - 'Just wait!' - takes out a Kalashnikov - bang-bang-bang - 'Freedomers' lie down again. Some time passes. The commander of Freedom stands up again': \n - 'For our brothers, for Freedom in the Zone, let's go!' - and the attack begins again. Young 'Duty' soldiers start panicking again. The old soldier repeats his actions. 'Freedomers' lie down once more. After five minutes the commander of Freedom stands up. His face is covered in mud, he's all dirty and he shouts:  \n - 'Fucking hell, now you are really asking for it!!?' \n Old 'Duty' soldier throws a cigarette away and says: \n - 'Now it's time to run!</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_65">
    <text>Have you heard of Mercs? No? Then listen and keep this in your memory: they are killers, are very serious and determined, they can get anyone, dead or alive. Have you heard of Sych's death recently? A direct shot in his heart, the body was burnt, no evidence left, trust me, it's their style. Those guys have no ethics behind their actions, they could kill a person as easily as they could squash a bug. The only thing they respect is money. There are rumours that they have a base in Dead City, but no one has ever returned from there. Mercs don't like unwanted guests. And do you know how they train? They catch a bandit or a stalker, take him to their place, give him a Kalashnikov with two rounds and let him go anywhere. If after twelve hours that guy is still alive, he can keep on living. That's what their fun is, comrade. During the whole time only Misha Squint managed to survive a meeting with them and that's only because he spent ten years working in Spetsnaz forces. So Strelok if you see people in blue uniforms, run away as fast as you can from theme. But if Mercs have an order to kill you, you stand no chance, they will get you even if you go underground.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_66">
    <text>I heard there is a group of people they sometimes call Shamans or Druids. They are believed not to bring any electronic devices into the Zone. They are in a way closer to nature and everything. Well they say that the Zone and electronics react to all those electromagnetic impulses, and it attracts mutants to you. If you believe that then maybe the Zone is a living organism. They say that you shouldn't bring any devices into the Zone. A clever person will find his way on his own without a device. But they carry weapons with them. After all they don't want to have to use their teeth and nails. On the other hand not many of them die in the Zone. No more than we do, certainly. So maybe they are right in their ideas. They mainly come from the Belarusian side. Anyway they should have been searched for artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_67">
    <text>Hey, the Barkeep told me that bloodsuckers have attacked the village near the Military Warehouses yesterday and no one survived. Those poor guys didn't even have time to send an SOS signal. 'Duty' people were there today and they said blood was everywhere, as though pigs were slaughtered there too. Just terrible.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_68">
    <text>Can I get a cigarette from you? You don't smoke? I see! That's good you know. Helps your health and you'll have enough breath to run away from dogs, he-he. He told me some experienced Mercs and bloody snipers were killing stalkers in a very interesting way. When stalkers group together and smoke, a Merc spots the light from the match and cigarette. Then, when the second stalker lights up his cig, the spot of light moved and the sniper could see both of them. Finally when the third stalker lights up his cigarette with the same match he immediately gets a bullet in his head. That's why stalkers now have a rule 'Three people don't light up cigarettes with the same match.' So it's all fun and jokes, but one's life could depend on that.</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_69">
    <text>I remember a few nights ago while walking to a camp I came across someone, I recognized his gear to be that of the army's, and in one arm he cradled a Spetsnaz rifle. He was acting weird, he didn't seem to notice me at first, he was dragging one foot and his movement was limp, he was gripping his rifle strongly though, so I kept my pistol pointed at him, he didn't seem to notice or care, in fact, he kept on walking by me, his eyes stared into me, and I knew something was wrong with him, as he past me, he attempted to say something it was mostly incoherent but I did make out 'Controller... Help'. As soon as I tried to help him I heard a heli, got scared and ran away. I got into a little grove. Then about seven soldiers had appeared and then I saw the helicopter. Three people had called to him and others ran to him and tackled him to the ground. Can you imagine, one of their own, face into mud! They were also shouting something about a helmet. Then they put him into the helicopter. It's all very strange. That guy, his words about a Controller... soldiers... did he actually manage to escape a Controller attack?</text>
</string>
<string id="dm_cool_info_70">
    <text>Recently, me and four other cold stalkers asked a lone Merc if we could join him by his fire. He turned out to be not that bad of a fellow, the Merc explained to us that he killed only under orders. Most stalkers treat Mercenaries with respect, and they can relate rather well. Mercenaries show respect to Stalkers, but consider themselves unsurpassed masters. But this Merc described his life's story to me. For his service he's in the 'Order of Courage' and has a medal showing it. He learned at a center for training snipers; 'In there they take everything very seriously.', he told us. Everytime they fired a shot, they were to check their weapons, and fire again, and repeat the process. He told us you can't really be a sniper til' you've had a years experience in the front lines. Sometimes one was taught really thoroughly for a long time but as soon as he got to exams (usually they were in Chechnya) no, the person just can't do it. You can prepare at school, shoot all targets but as soon as it all gets real something switches inside the brain and you stop. That's how it is. So Strelok be strong in the Zone.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
