<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="totalizator_0">
    <text>Hello Bookmaker. As much as I can, I wish to raise some money.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_1">
    <text>Well that is nice. Only take into account that you could win or loose. Place 50 pieces and you could win 500 rubles. You could end up in debt. And we expect to be paid or maybe you bones will be found in the swamp. So you understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_2">
    <text>Yes, it is harsh though. However the excitement is what matters. So...?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_3">
    <text>Are you asking me? You wish to take a chance? It's up to you stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_4">
    <text>Okay, what are the rules?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_5">
    <text>The rate can change and nothing is refundable. About winning or losing will tell you. You can play and if you are in debt, the amount of the debt will accrue interest every 12 hours. So the choice is yours: 'to play or not to play'. By the way, if you win the money you can leave me, I will give a good percentage.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_6">
    <text>Well, ok. What's are the stakes?</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_7">
    <text>Rates are constantly changing as the wind does over the Pripyat river. Even I sometimes do not know what the rate will be. Now let's a bet.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_8">
    <text>Stake is 1,000. We'll bet on, say, another rookie stalker will get intoxicated and fall into an anomaly in the swamps.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_9">
    <text>Stake of 5,000. We'll bet whether or not a loser will repay Timonu Kostopravu before the designated deadline.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_10">
    <text>Stake of 10,000. We'll bet on, who of these two novice idiots will be first to find a 'Stoneware Flower' for Hera of Tula.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_11">
    <text>Stake of 15,000. We'll bet, which of these two regular noobs will be the one to get to the cache for that had been the late Badger's, which is in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_12">
    <text>Stake of 20,000. We'll bet that, who of two novices will win when sparring with knives. Go to Cordon, you may have time to see this fight. It should be a spectacle to watch these two young morons compete.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_13">
    <text>Stake of 25,000. We'll bet on success or failure: that these two idiots who decided to travel into the Zone to go to the checkpoint where the soldier's are and survive. As for me, they are two new idiots, but you decide for yourself.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_14">
    <text>Stake of 30,000. We'll bet on 'Yakolku'. He promised to bring the head of a Chimera to Wolf. I think he is nutz. Although... who knows? They say he is not so bad with a knife.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_15">
    <text>Stake of 35,000. We'll bet on the success: the Coneheads sent their messenger into Dead City with a message for the Wanderers. Many think that he will not make it back. The choice is yours to bet. Who knows? He now runs the errand.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_16">
    <text>Stake of 40,000 rubles. Good stake, large. We'll bet on the success of one psycho, which promised to give five bottles of cognac to the 'Peacekeepers' to pay for Prince's debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_17">
    <text>Stake of 50,000. We'll bet large on success: of an experienced stalker, (however many have already tried this), to catch and haul back a living bloodsucker back. He is either mad or nutz, which one we have yet to know.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_18">
    <text>I refuse!</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_19">
    <text>Well the bet is made, now wait for the result. Good Luck, Stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_20">
    <text>Agreed!</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_21">
    <text>Are you the fella that collapsed by the oak tree? You've got more than a hundred rubles so you are prohibited from making bids. Come on, I am twitching here.</text>
</string>
<string id="totalizator_22">
    <text>Your evil...</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_0">
    <text>Hello, I came for the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_1">
    <text>Now lets see what's owed to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_2">
    <text>Well fork it over, no stalling. Get my loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_3">
    <text>Well now... let us open the safe first.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_4">
    <text>Take the money.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_prize_5">
    <text>Leave a deposit.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_dolg_0">
    <text>Good for you. Here a small payback.</text>
</string>
<string id="give_dolg_1">
    <text>Agreed, no more debt for you. It is free.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_0">
    <text>Pick up deposit.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_1">
    <text>Choose how much you wish to pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_2">
    <text>Pay 10% of the sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_3">
    <text>Pay 50% from the sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_4">
    <text>Pay entire sum.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_5">
    <text>Well, take this.</text>
</string>
<string id="take_deposit_6">
    <text>Thank you, that was well spent. I will go relax a little now.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
