<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="descr_yan_find_ghost_task">
    <text>Vasiliev: '... here are the coordinates to the entrance of Laboratory X-16. The entrance is in the basement of the central building. The reason for this building was not known. But presumably the telekenetic underground emitters are there. The study of documents text reveals some broken up statements... the purpose of this project is for a large-scale development of psychotropic massive output... all the necessary documents from us... we know how to turn off the radiation. Ghost is going into the laboratory. Zombies are everywhere, bad radiation... everything is going to hell, Ghost is going insane... it looks like he has been affected by the radiation. I dropped everything and went through the tunnels ... is this the moor where the bunker is? Damn, damn, damn! I cannot determine where I am! Sakharov - a coward does not answer! What's going on? Many zombies, I have run out ammo...'.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_find_lab">
    <text>Sakharov: 'All you have to do is find the corpse of Vasiliev and accurate information about the location of the laboratory. Then go to the lab to find Ghost. Ghost knew how to turn off the radiation and how to get out'.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist">
    <text>Sakharov: 'With current collected measurements I could configure a prototype outfit to protect you'.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_find_scientist_semenov">
    <text>Sakharov: 'If you are with us, then together with the measurements, I'll configure a prototype which will allow you to enter the lab'.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain">
    <text>Sakharov: 'Well done Strelok you got to the lab. It is very important to study the installation equipment. Try to disable it so that we can investigate it. Remember Strelok the prototype suit cannot long protect you from strong radiation. I provided for handling the strong radiation, but only for a while. Turn the timer on. When the time expires the prototype will cease to protect you. Be careful and do not forget about the timer. '</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_kill_brain_2">
    <text>Setting is disabled. That was easy, now to get out alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_provodnik_task">
    <text>Ghost: here are some document entries:: 'Guide: I will send to you a man, we have important information for the doctor. Help him'. Guide: 'Good. Only Ghost, not like last time. I want to talk with you. Waiting as usual, in camp near the bridge. Do not get lost, and army patrols are around so do not get caught.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_yan_scientist_return_task">
    <text>Sakharov: 'What happened? He died? Get the measurements and immediately get your buns back here!'</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_find_ghost">
    <text>I'm shocked! Ghost and the man in the photos on the PDA are the same person, and was assignment to kill Strelok. I do not understand. There must be some mistake. But who made it? While there is no answer. In Ghost's records I learned the name of a common friend in Strelok's group... the fourth member and his name is Doctor. He helped the team a long time and served, apparently, the role of a staff member. You can find him through a stalker known as Guide who often frequents Cordon. Well Guide do not die before our meeting. Ghost corpse had documents on the installation of 'Psy-Brain.' The whole district was under the influence of this thing. It made zombies of out stalkers in that area. I learned that there is another installation in the Laboratory X-19 and most likely it is the 'Scorcher'. I also learned that these machines do not always operate at full power. There are times when they lower the radiation power output to cool the units.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_find_ghost_name">
    <text>Another mystery.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_kill_brain">
    <text>After disabling the machine I lost consciousness. Evidently all the stress of these last few days has caught up with me. While I was out I had a dream and saw a photo. A gray-haired man and a huge dog. The man was staring into the distance and around him was a swamp, and the landscape bears no resemblance to what is shown in the photo. In the fog you could barely see a retreating figure. The man muttered, as if talking to himself 'why didn't you tell me what this place is and where you got the picture'.  Then I see a smiling young man at the door of a hut who eerily says: 'If only you knew where I have been and what I have seen!'. He holds out some amazing gizmo from which a light emits and iluminates the hut. The dog begins to growl and ran into a corner, and the gray-haired man muttered: 'One day you may not return.' Then another flash ... here is the same guy with a badly disfigured and bloodied face bursting in the door of the hut and falls on the floor ... outside the door a strike of lightning, pouring rain. A flash ... on a bed in a hut is the same guy, and his face is all scarred and bandaged. The guy is unconscious and the gray-haired man muttered 'Hold on, son!'. In a corner is piled of stuff and among them the strange picture ... a flash ... photograph is now in the hands of the gray-haird man. A man with scars on his face is walking away. The gray-haird man asks him: 'Where are you going now?' He gives a grim answer: 'To thee north.' Another flash and I wake up.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_kill_brain_name">
    <text>The second dream.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda">
    <text>Well here I am almost on the verge of finding one of the people in Strelok's group. Ghost and one of the scientists went to the underground laboratory X-16. Ghost died. The scientist came back and was killed near the camp. The scientists have given me some kind of protective device to protect against radiation. I hope it works. They want me to go inside and turn off the radiation source so they can learn more about it. I hope I survive.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_vasilyev_pda_name">
    <text>One step away from the Ghost</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_ghost_info">
    <text>Record N257 \n Guide, I will send to you a man, we have important information for the doctor. He needs help. \n Okay. Only Ghost don't do as you did before. I need to speak with you. Waiting as usual,in camp near the bridge. Don't die on me. There are army patrols around. \n\n N384 Vasiliev at the last moment chickened out and instead of having turned off the machine, simply ran away when the door opened. I should not have trusted him to do this task. Strelok was correct not to trust these liars. My only chance is to get to the door before the Comptroller bites my arse.</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_vasilyev_info">
    <text>... here are the coordinates of the entrance to the Laboratory X-16. The entrance is in the basement of the central building, the task of this building is not known. Presumably, it is where the underground emitters are. The study of the documents from the N*** reveals the purpose of this project:: a large-scale development of psychotronic massive effect on the brain ... \n\n ... the documents exposed how to turn off the radiation. Ghost went down into the laboratory. Zombies are everywhere and are affected by the radiation ... \n\n ... place is like hell itself... Ghost is absolutely insane. It looks like he was exposed to the radiation for to long. I dropped everything and went through the tunnels ... \n\n ... In the marshes I guess... where the damn bunker? Damn, shit, shit! I don't know where I am! Sakharov - a coward does not answer! What's going on? Freak'n zombies all over the place... and I have no more ammunition.</text>
</string>
