<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="stalker_story_1">
    <text>We were sneaking into a hangar. The place was a bigger mess than the Garbage. Our detectors didn't sense anything. Place seemed empty of all life. Come take a position on the perimeter: Sanya ahead, we camouflage ... And then - Wham! Beam, a hefty, steel, rusty ceiling, breaks down - and down! As Sanya ducked, he did not know, but this crap stuck right in the spot where he stood. Well, he is dropped and rolled, did not rise to their feet at all, and let's lay shmalyat! Others, too frightened, idiots, and myself went to plant a white light. Here Sanya started yelling something about a creature in the corner. I see - no creature can not see ... So there you go, no surgery, and this particular mess ... bordelero ... We went to the ruins of this walk, walk for five minutes - cautiously, so that under these beams do not come to be. And delirium, delusions full well: that one or the other of something prividitsya, they let in bursts polrozhka slash on empty space. And no two people are lucky, one was on a level floor and suddenly fell into a pit, the second door of the failed dragged across the back. Well, here we all wound up - Well clearly because that thing kind of fun! Kerf psy-defense, in all corners of the gas grenade - well, wait, who will appear, and the fingers on the trigger. We are waiting, waiting ... A beast, as it turned out, flying was that it ... While we are all in a heap at the bottom playing the fool, sitting quietly to herself from the ceiling and having fun, bitch ... It came down to us only later, and then only by accident almost. This snake has shaken a couple of bars - half a roof and welled. Straight at us ... Four guys in a cake on the spot ... That's where we got it, and! As Sanya heard sheburshanie above, so the machine and gave all - useful fucking jerk! Well here and scream! We are also, clearly, jumped, gave out all barrels ... Sypanula creature on top with cries that his ears straight. Well, here we really took the soul: who butt beat, who just walked down. Sanya, so he took out a knife, so she dumped offal pobolnee ... Commander, of course, all hard, but dragged, and then all this would have bastard spoons to scrape the floor had to be.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_1_name">
    <text>About the critters in the hangar.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_10">
    <text>Have you heard about the 'Guide'? The first of the stalkers to walk into the Zone. It is believed that he is still alive. It is said that he can take you anywhere in the Zone. Another thing is that he is problematic to find. No posters with his address are around. If he doesn't like you he will not take you anywhere. Note that he charges a lot of money. So he, perhaps, saw what was in Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_10_name">
    <text>Superconductor</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_11">
    <text>Ponty hit and loot to be - it's two different things ... Che dumali, then loot for so given? Damn! For so ugly you just some shavaet, or overwhelm the soldiers ... We must think. They think it is necessary, but here is even better. Most bulls are not here long stretch. Do not feed it, if not the attic ... In short, it is there. The three of us with bruises and a service yard Tsepoy deceased were - the road is shorter cut. Look - bandyuki some scratches. Well, we snykalis. And he goes past us - does not notice. Minor such as a bag pulls - whether it is healthy. And the machine hangs artfully: just what we nashpiguet olives. Well, Bruise me, 'Come let us touch mozglyaka, Th him there?' And I said to him: 'Hush, woodpecker! Better watch where he drags his loot.' Well Th ... Then the deer as a failure somewhere - we do not even understand. Well, wait. He got about twenty minutes. While shaking himself, to him flail back and quietly pulled out of the tapestry poltykvy demolished. They began with a black body gut: Armor on it was cool, and the wallet should be ... I cast away - my boys will give me always, I share in life. Here as heranet! .. In short, the suffering that was not simple: it is a human cunning twists, so that exploded when it with Armor Someone will shoot. I knocked out a quick - very few people right now on the shot and the explosion roll up ... Came a month later. By flails with bruises and a deer - if only bone. In general, the zeros. In short, I figured, where he dived into the ruins, and he climbed up there ... Well, went through three rooms - Golyak! Then look in the corner of a lot of beds in bulk. Why the dick there as lounges? In short, got to rake. Scraped away. I saw that my mother was a woman, the hatch! I lift, therefore, cover a candle lantern. E-pe-reh-se-te! I'm in paradise .. Well, there was a human - my business ... In the loser did not go. A hung ears would - would long ago have become blind man's buff, or are still running barefoot, cormorants ... As some ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_11_name">
    <text>Path to paradise</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_12">
    <text>They say there is a group of friends ... When they are called Shamans, Druids and whatnot. They say, generally with an electronic equipment are not - the nature of, say, closer, and so on ... Well, they say that the area of ??electronics ... electromagnetic radiation at all react strongly ... Yes, and monsters at you inciting. How to get in their language, so Area - a living organism. It is impossible, they say, to go into it with the devices - the right person and without any extra portions to cope. True, they are machines, goats, drag ... There is a tooth and nail to try ... On the other hand, killed them in the Zone seems to be not so much. No more than they have fins glued ... So it may correctly guessed ... They are, however, more like from the Belarusian side to enter the Zone ... And then it would be nice to have a look ... but at the same time to check how much they have artifacts in your pocket is found ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_12_name">
    <text>The story of the Druid battle</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_13">
    <text>Does anyone know about the secret labs deep in the Zone? .. They say that still work ... Well, yes, yes ... It is unclear as there is generally someone was able to survive ... without supplies, energy ... That raises the question - and maybe there are not people work? I then spoke with tipkom one ... He did not see the laboratory ... No, I have not seen, but the scanner caught negotiate some strange at Yantar. They on a laboratory it was. And the other guy that, first, he swore that came across as something to figure in kombeza stalkerovskogo type, but more featured ... And this figure is translucent told him that he was falling away from here. 'Do not bother, they say, go, here we are working.' Well, the guy peresral ... of course! Who of us had seen this? .. On the other hand, it seems to happen far from the radar ... Well, yes. So it is hardly true ... But on the other hand ... mutations, because they are different, probably happen? Maybe it's not people, but some energy entity? ..</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_13_name">
    <text>The shadow of Ghost</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_14">
    <text>You know what to say? In this part of the Zone is almost impossible to sleep ... I somehow luck, so I can not sleep ... and the people of these nightmares happen, that is, and waking up in the morning ... of a heart attack, for example ... Who moves the horses, and who tore the roof specifically ... Recently, however, the rumor went, that there is a remedy. If you feel an urge to sleep badly, it is desirable to find a bucket of old ... well, or at least a large saucepan ... extraction there ... The main thing is the whole ... Thrust his head back - and go to sleep himself as God in the bosom ... Well, laugh, laugh. I look at you in a couple of days, when the tired legs from the start to fall. Geniuses ... But do tell me, what, then, damn warriors here have recently started wearing helmets shastat clever? Well, yes! Previously, about two years so as no hearing, no spirit, and the recent frequent! Helmets are they some new - guys one body found and told. The grid is inside of a thin copper wire, attached to the liner. That and think - what a harness, the hell Ladi is she? In general, this 'g-g-g 'for a reason, like you say. Anomalies of choice here is nothing special - not the land, and at other sites pobezopasnee and meatier pieces still exist ... I think the approaches they are scheduled. Bridgehead cook. To break the Sarcophagus want, mark my words. Soon as figanet - nobody will not find it. Mark my words ... Most importantly, away from here at that time to be ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_14_name">
    <text>A nightmare without buckets</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_15">
    <text>Slyshte, guys, and you're about to 'intercept' as something to be aware? It is well, say spetsaki, human warriors! But how they work, and? How to work! This is not to cordon asshole! Not only that, in most zazhope climb, so more and sit in the Zone for months! Yes, I do not gonyu! Base them, several pieces at once, to figischa caches, and to the perimeter of them quartered turntable podkidyvayut supplies. The commander of their Gromov some ... I think the name - shit, not real. They did it 'Mayor', the 'Thunder' name. Do not believe me? So Pahomych intercept somehow caught! Caught and carried off his feet barely, but it would shpoknuli for nothing ... Secrecy, so it! Pahomycha something everyone knows? Well, that's it! No shit this is a serious team. Fuck knows what he then drew such an interesting, but they work - my mother dear! Up in the third ... not, at least ten percent of the way! Already have a house in ten floors Sochah would build ... They say such a thing is ... monstrov two hundred meters pinpoint. Any creature! Horseradish is clear, then go through the Zone-spitting ... But then again, they say, there are some figures ... Not warriors, and the like as in our ... In general, some made their way to the Zone center. Not only that made their way - they say, and know how to tame the beasts! They did a perimeter on the mainland, do not go - and they, too, no one ... Well, except, perhaps, to whom the Sarcophagus destined to get ... Already they have artifacts - even wipe! Dolgovtsy some of them are well known ... know, the bastards, fight and keep quiet! You ask any of these policemen, all say: 'Tales.' Well, do not bitch and?</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_15_name">
    <text>'Interception' - Inhabitant of the interior.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_16">
    <text>Brethren, have you heard that recently a few infidels getting to the antenna? Monolith has sent us, and the brothers time to get noticed. One we destroyed immediately. The other two fled. Briefs. They are all cowards. Only true faith leaves no room for fear! Two managed to escape, but the monolith is wise and omniscient. Hence, they need him alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_16_name">
    <text>About to have broken antennas.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_17">
    <text>Brothers, Monolith has called me at night. I talked to him. He was beautiful in its greatness. I almost went blind, but his light filled me with great force! I know, I feel that his force be with us all! He told me that he can only overcome evil with strong faith. He said that his strength will fill only the faithful. He also showed me that our victory is near!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_17_name">
    <text>About 'Monolith' in a dream</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_18">
    <text>Brothers, recently Monolith had my faith, and I nearly went astray. But I survived! Monoliths Praise! His temper test us! We came back from the Dark Valley, and I almost fell behind his brothers. Evil took advantage of this and suddenly start to play with me. I. .. I doubted. True distorted images; enemy whispered to me that Monolith uses us as slaves. But then I realized: this is a test. I thought about the power and radiance of the Monolith, and then the will and confidence back to me. Since I am not afraid of any tests and I do not know any doubts. Monoliths Praise!</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_18_name">
    <text>The test of faith</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_19">
    <text>I was in the Dark Valley. There's a lot wrong, because the strength of the Monolith has not yet reached these places. We protected. At night we were attacked. We fought fiercely with these animals. The merits of the brothers were great: Monolith soon called them to him. To me, he prepared another test. My weapon is not fired. But then the Monolith told me: 'You are with me, and my strength - with you. If you will be steadfast in their faith, the dash of my enemies close to me!' Then I became a shadow. I crouched down and walked to the right. Silly spies did not notice anything. They thought it was done with us and laughed at the empty bodies of our brothers. But I have seen them back. And then out of my hand hit the power Monolith. So he killed them all. I am happy to serve you, perfect! ..</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_19_name">
    <text>About the battle in Dark Valley</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_2">
    <text>We are a partner to one SRI long straight. Painfully lonely place. No beast in the district, nor mutants. But who would go go, or frightened vusmert or with coils moved down back, or do they no longer seen. Have decided to quietly explore. We left before dawn, and how to get to places already beginning to dawn. Left the car in raspadochke, went to the forest edge. They stopped at the bottom left partner and I climbed a tree with optics - look around, that's going around. I see - the body, and not so very very desolate, almost all the whole glass, a little grass in the yards, not like in other places - to the waist ... Around the left, that live here, but there was total silence, and the motion was not any. Suddenly a little to my right turn passed - someone with a machine gun beat short. I optics there. I see on the roof of one of the buildings strange man, hunted like a rat tossing, shooting indiscriminately in all directions. Who so scared - I look and I can not understand: he was there alone. And here ... started ... I saw everything clearly. Automatic out of his hands flew by itself ... If the glands have grown wings! .. A guy opened his mouth, apparently, yelled something, took out a knife and put it in front of him. And then, tree-winder, look, and before it itself hangs another. That's a sting in the air to him and hanging, and no one holds it. What happened next - this is not the night to tell ... Five minutes of the guy cut. Little by little, so females, their mother's leg: it cut, then a shot ... Poor guy is soon covered in blood was ... Then, as he too began to totter in the legs, it also knocked the knife, then lift a man into the air, roll it up like a couple of times ... I'm such a life have I seen - naturally, like a rag Berthelot ... I was wet for three seconds ... Then ... No, it's not going to ... In general, as I caught his breath, groping for another five minutes an eye on the neighborhood. Hands trembling, wet with sweat, optics has become ... Well, at least to one thing! And in the normal range and in infakrasnom - no-Th-th. As I cry, I looked for a partner, and asking his mind. And what came back to base, a week before I get drunk eyebrows, not been drying ... Then, like a bit away, our porassprashival - maybe someone about what is heard? Only the people in my glances askance began - an hour, did not move it? There you have it ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_2_name">
    <text>Horror at the Research Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_20">
    <text>Brethren, we patrolled the outskirts of the Black Forest and ran there for the wrong-alone. He began to turn, so we did not kill him, but he still was in his half-animal state ... I know, the wise Monolith have done this for us all, he once again showed us the true face of their enemies. Now, our faith became stronger! Nearing brothers ... nearing victory over the infidels, and then perform the Monolith our heart's desire! Truly faithful he will bring to himself and to his glory, his majesty! We will abide forever in the glory of it! ..</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_20_name">
    <text>The transformation in the Black Forest</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_3">
    <text>In general, my friend told me that's what Shout. Middle of the night raised his superiors: 'Run to the lab! Shipment came.' He was sleepy, not cut in: what cargo? They told him: 'Are you drunk alcohol treasury? Trupak fresh on the table, Bon appetit!' He to the table. And there is ... He is on the move, blind man's buff from the Zone has seen in his life: and you ripped and fried-varenye and mutants fell more than a dozen, and then once in the stomach dinner walk began. From the first vzglyada, two minutes a man's head just a normal guys are like: a healthy pumpkin bumpy. Well, the body - a concentration camp, a pancake. Skin and bones. But then he is made out, but first, he says, look, mash some all inside out, spattered with orange-red dirty trick, the blood type ... These weapons have not regretted honduras. This, he says, was a cross between a colander and torn warmers ... In general, they are clearly on his jackboots of their well-walked, did not object, and a piece of meat in black rags. In short, he rest of the night and half the morning hunchback. Along the way, it turns out, this is the creature, which the local magician to know: black cloth, with a vision stalkerov, chump meter in diameter ... Cool that his face, who saw, felt that this type of benevolent. Not a person he naturally is, only small at all: winkers are not opened, and the nose as a pin, but a hefty fall, straight jamb at the gate. Walks can be seen, and hangs his head on his chest - forces do not have to keep exactly ... Mozglyak ... And imagine what these creatures eat for lunch. Fungi! Mushrooms! In short, all seen - in the Zone of mushrooms completely, so 'old' give a tooth that these creatures are too tight juice. Gourmets, pancake ... And you know what he had in the bag was stashed on the side? Well? But where to you! In short, the brains there had been cured. Do you know whose? Kontrolerskie! ..</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_3_name">
    <text>Dinner with a Pathologist</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_4">
    <text>Profits were to us here in Durick a hike deep into the Zone. Cheshem, it means that the tabernacle in the five minutes of rest, and he at once on the fifth point and relaxes. And you go, so it's ass off the ground last tears. Well dorasslablyalsya ... Behind, and there his supervisor for brains DAC - and ready ... So, remember the history of morality. The rustle of a breeze there, or any suspicious ... Let it be a hare could run, but bunnies do not here give God ... In short, ready every moment must be. To shop, grenades and machine handy to have continuous. If we see that, once planted polrozhka. If the bushes something - too lupite, and then to ask. Here the course of this young soldier: no clothes hung, and with guts will eat, will not have time to fart! Yes, on the supervisors - is another story. Suppose you had shot at the rustle and fall immediately in the same second! Though on the back, as though. Comptroller for me, if he sees you, he needs to focus, I suppose. While sunbathing in the shade, listen to both ears - a rustling, is there any stuff to you. You can quietly pereschelknut gate, and pomegranates also worthwhile to prepare ... In general, if all quiet, count to three and lump! Bring down to hell! Well, suck? Oh ... Take care of himself every second - the only way to survive here and you can ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_4_name">
    <text>Easy extraction of a Controller</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_5">
    <text>I think that ... Not even what I think - so plain enough ... And suddenly everything - that's all there is - what experiment on human beings? This is, perhaps, some green little men ... So what? No worse than any other version ... It is interesting to me, if this is something like a landfill, what they here a trial run? Check for any artifacts we most drool admits? Or is it a bomb at all any, eh? Porastaschili them around the world on all kinds of laboratories, rich poraskoshelilis ... No, well, that's cool! .. Here it would be my pleasure! .. Bought under the counter some crap ... took away a lot of dough ... Type 'We coolest' envy, sheep ... but it ... it ... ka-ak heranet! .. Oh, class! .. Oh, I can not! .. Oh ... UV-f-f ... But in general, of course, FIG knows what really ... Is the one who went to the radar can about this porasskazat ... Well, yes, they, can, and know just can not say - moo and drooling allowed. Maybe it's because just let ... Oh ... That and climb all sorts of thoughts ... Sadly it at all ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_5_name">
    <text>Pitfalls</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_6">
    <text>So ... I remember someone me yesterday about something ask, but I forgot ... And, I remember. There is, therefore, curious, why in the Zone only our bigheads crawling, and foreigners and the nose does not seem, though here the material Nobelevok thousand and three ... Hence, corresponding to the points. First of all, why should climb by here when you can give to our grant with such conditions that they give you everything you need, bring yourself on a silver platter? But if the second, they actually visited here, and a lot. These are the last two years in zabugortsy Zone afraid to climb ... happened to them a major bummer. Now, just buy the materials but information. Generally pay well, so that many individuals are working on them, and looters, too ... What, never heard about this story? Well, give! The whole area was on the ears, and as you fall from the skies. In general, getting to a big one. Some thirty scientists from half the world ... all the lights, of course, here and there ... Preparing seriously loaded up money - at least one place you eat, the equipment - the mountains. Taken with a platoon of military experts for the protection of our three conductors shielded by armored vehicles pushed off and sank. What's that ... They returned a week later ... Twelve people killed in an armored personnel carrier into the trash. By the thorns came in rotten wood, and there they were waiting ... Marauders. Yes ... These do not care where people have escaped ... They put almost everyone. For perimeter only got three - two and one of our egghead. A man of experience powerfully moved the attic ... Well, it quickly by the collar - and treat. He now writes a book about a Zone. We did something else - the experience has helped. But ... also, probably, in his own way moved, one went to the radar and gone, and the latter moved to the mainland. Well, the other area has. About Town-32 heard? That's where they hit. At first everything seemed to quiet it was ... Well, within ... They're shot-measured, samples were collected in the anomalies pointed their instruments ... And then they began to insanity. Massive. The people began to go slowly roof. I ours - one that had gone to bed - told ... Who began his throat torn by nails, who currently heads smashed against the wall, but who simply - the barrel in his mouth, and ... And then there's poperlo beasts. Who in itself was barricaded in the house. Presented, is not it? Outside the night and all surrounding creatures, and in people with reels flies one after the other. In short, in the morning, those who have to think he could, somehow escaped. Back drove straight, with no roads, and even a couple of anomalies hooked ... We got to the rotten wood ... And of those who stayed there, no one has never been found. The guys just say that in those places abruptly added supervisors. Yes ... Since then, in town-32 no one agrees, as a foreigner in the Zone and Kalach not fetch ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_6_name">
    <text>The Chronicles of egghead globalists</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_7">
    <text>So that's what I say something like. When the illusion of Dolgovtsev taken, I was close Well! Yes, I happen to all of those places was! My cars flew right front: cut the bolts on the mound. And for parts a complete zero. I Pomaterilsya as follows, and then give, I think I'll go to the plant, pick up the right. Well, there has been kilometer to go, back and forth - for half an hour Delov! Yes, and I visited there before ... Then suddenly I see 'Duty'! And not just patrol and pieces polsta! Well, I think, a pancake-compote! .. As was so into the bushes and fell. 'If the notice and begin to comb, - I think - and here I tryndets.' Lay down, in short, in the hole and try not to breathe. And then the shooting! To such bursts shmalyali I only heard once in a lifetime ... when they took first base - old men, remember? In general, I lie, I listen to both ears ... It is currently Baha'is and then another, and as grohnet! .. After five minutes, subsides, and for me like no one goes. Well, I plucked up nerve, sensitive and stood looking through the binoculars. And they quickly pulled out of the shop ... creased such blind man's buff its a bunch of drag on the canvas and illusion ... clumps has remained one of the illusion ... Utyanulis a dell. Then I hear - Engines roared and the sound was gone. I have waited - like anyone. I am inside. Well, it is clear that after the 'Duty' fuck what you find? But it is interesting then. This, I tell you, it was something! The walls are almost through a hole. Beams across the floor roll, a piece of the roof collapsed. Sleeves on his knee - a natural range. Krovischa, scraps of some ... Useful, however, did not find anything - so, yes two horns full automatic lay, pinned beam, do not get ... About the screws I, of course, and think forgot ... He returned to the wheelbarrow, I thought for five minutes, removed the bolt on with the rest of the wheels ... well and drove slowly ... And I go out there for half an hour before ... Hmm ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_7_name">
    <text>The illusion of 'Duty'</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_8">
    <text>Yeah, so I was right up to the very outskirts of Pripyat reached. Well, first of all decided to look around. Found a higher point - there was a large boiler with a chimney. Well, went to a neat ... like, look, chiki all the peaks - the dust is, there is no trace of ... He climbed into the furnace and crawled: there were stairs inside the pipe. Normal climb, even snuff and has not spoiled - turned to stone ... Cautiously poke ... Beauty! Half of the city in your hand! He pulled out the binoculars and look around ... (Slight pause) Well, then ... Already assembled, then slide down and then jumps idea what's going on under their very noses, and do not look! Bend a bit over the edge, looking at one side, then to another ... Both-on! That's got to! The courtyard dwarf walks! The main thing I'm down Well almost useful! And then, all right, that he does not see me. Only the tower, I can not demolish him: AKS on the back hangs a narrow tube at all, do not turn around. From the PM, which under his arm, rotten thing - there is about fifty meters, differential in height to the same ... in short, if not make it right - and yet not make it - then just kerdyk. I sit, thinking. Well, look at the same time, what he was doing. And he does something funny. First bodrenko so, with a twinkle, rummaging in a pile of rubbish - only pieces scattered right and left. And then suddenly stood and froze. It seems to listen. Well, there quite a mess began. Garbage in the heap itself was moving. The dwarf sprang quickly became that way in a column, put his hands to his head, his hands like a cunningly twisted ... and in his ka-ak fly! From all sides! .. Glands, bricks, roofing material, twigs ... His way with head and cover. Well, I think that's all. Pipets kitten will not piss more ... A fig! Two seconds trash that lay, and then just ka-ak spurt in all directions! There were scraps of pipes, so they are right in the concrete fence povtykalis. He stood still for half a minute Carl, pokumekal yourself of something, and then turned and tramped into the building. I have a moment to translate the spirit. 'Well, - I think - well a little, throw away time.' Suddenly smoke was drawn. And then bake it became. Yes, you go to a stump! Fire someone threw up from the bottom! A minute later there was nothing to breathe already. Somehow vygreb on the edge of the tube, there is no ground, sitting, legs dangled ... Only smoke still eat your eyes, the air is not enough ... in short, blame must be urgently! Thank God I'm with you always repshnura forty meters dragged to any fireman case ... exactly what the fire ... In general, I folded it in half - it was not very thick - more or less fixed on the pipe, a scarf neck ripped in half, wrapped in bespalki top, and useful, praying to all gods ... At the head of one thought only it were not for break! No insurance, personal, hand cut the cord ... And, of course, Murphy's Law about five meters to the ground, it was not enough. Segal had. What to do? Oh, and I roared! Good luck, though not broken anything ... But right leg ripped off and pulled - be healthy! Then he thought that all ligaments torn. And then pulled out so that the gold medal in probably would have won ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_8_name">
    <text>Seryi in Pripyat</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_9">
    <text>And I did not believe his eyes. That would seem to have pretty girls, right? But this was ... it ... Perfection. Yes. That is. Perfection. Such was the feeling that the world around her black and white and fuzzy, it is only one in color and sharpness. As she moved! I am also a never seen before. I've already got lump in my throat. Well, she gave this science! With her here, in the Zone do? .. Well, in the Zone. By evening it was ... At the bus station, where nine-separate. First, something in the window on the first floor flashed. I machine quickly removed the fuse and then I saw - out of the doorway ... I wanted to rub my eyes - you never know what you can expect from the Zone? But it fits. And I stood there like a fool and his eyes ... Automatic, however, keep at the ready - a habit already ... Then she noticed me ... Smile ... Hello ... And I listen and hear everything on her watch. She was in blue overalls, bright then ... But do not balahonistom and almost skin-tight ... The figure in it - something fantastic! It was only then I realized that I do not listen at all, she says, standing and smiling from ear to ear ... It appears from the research team was. She asked me if I had the opportunity to help her. Her! Yes, I would be an anomaly for it useful! .. She said she deals with these as they are ... Endemic areas. Well, the plants are only found here. She said that she ran away from the guards, because with them there is no freedom of action, and came here alone. I do not know. I believe it. Agreed to help her haul something. Two days later came as agreed. Five times nearly covered, until collected. I'm going, but his head to one thought: now I see her again! And there is nothing! I am even at home where she was met, not seen. That's so ... But what it was! She just glowed from the inside ...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_9_name">
    <text>To be alone</text>
</string>
<string id="Stories">
    <text>Local folklore</text>
</string>
</string_table>
