<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1">
    <text>Any jobs?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11">
    <text>Hmm, what kind of jobs? Something special you are looking for? Or maybe you already found something? I've heard this area is full of goodies.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_111">
    <text>Sorry I cannot chat, no time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_1111">
    <text>Right, you just cannot wait to get going again. Aren't you tired of running around? You must have found something by now?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11111">
    <text>What I found is my business.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_11112">
    <text>Documents found in X-18. Barkeep promised good pay for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_112">
    <text>No I did not find anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2">
    <text>I sort of drifted here and cannot wait to get the hell out of here.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21">
    <text>Anything of interest found by chance? They say you can find information about experiments. For good paid too.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_211">
    <text>No, I did not find anything.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2111">
    <text>Yeah? And if you think real hard? Hiding something from me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21111">
    <text>No!</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21112">
    <text>What kind of question is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_21113">
    <text>You threatening me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_212">
    <text>To hell with all this information. I've barely stayed alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2121">
    <text>Well run away then. Sooner or later you will find that I'm needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_25">
    <text>Listen buddy I have been traveling the Zone for a long time through fire, monsters, anomalies, and I am still alive as you can see! So do not challenge me. I came for documents and without them I will not go away. If you have them then I advise you to give them up otherwise you will remain in this pit forever! Capisce?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_251">
    <text>Clearly!</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2511">
    <text>If you're lying to me you will have a problem, and if you have something planned you will have a problem, and if you give me any crap you will have a problem. Simply put, you have one big problem, me! And you better try harder to solve it! And now once more to be blunt: did you find the documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_2521">
    <text>That's good and next time choose a better expression. Go on now. Suddenly you find that I'm needed.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_253">
    <text>The conversation is over, get out of the way.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_26">
    <text>I have no documents!</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_271">
    <text>That's better my friend. And now give me all the documents. Every single document. And do not try to joke with me otherwise it will be your last joke.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_51">
    <text>Wait, I tell you! I fell in the hole and found them. Do not play me like a fool. Share, if ...</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_511">
    <text>I do not intend to share.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5111">
    <text>Well, well, well ... yeah here's a piece of advice: 'watch where you walk and do not stumble stalker'.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_512">
    <text>You're threatening me?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_5121">
    <text>Okay, okay don't get mad. Just curious, but you're right when behind a weapon! No more questioning. Just be careful, that's all.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_61">
    <text>Documents, that's exactly what I came for, for information. And now you tell me you might have given them away. Do you understand I need them?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6111">
    <text>Come on, say something.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6121">
    <text>Listen buddy do not fool with me. Lets come to an agreement. I normally help stalkers, you will not regret.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_6131">
    <text>Listen I really need these documents. Let's see, what have you ... I think we'll agree.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8011">
    <text>Dark here, a damn sight. Burers all around. And why did I agree? Do you like it here?</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8021">
    <text>Go on your way, stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8031">
    <text>I hate it when the conversation is interrupted. In short, I have come for important documents. If you know something then out with it, otherwise you will have problems. If you don't then get out and do not waste my time.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_8041">
    <text>I hate it when the conversation is interrupted! Give up the documents if you do not want to stay here forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_dialog_9">
    <text>I will consider.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
