<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="mil_actor_main_quest_descr">
    <text>According to General Voronin this gun is restricted to faction 'Freedom'. But how to I get one. I understand one way is to become friends with the 'Freedom' stalker Cook/Chef. So says the general who is a great lover of drink. So it is necessary to have case of vodka. Might be useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_blockpost_job_descr">
    <text>We must help protect the barrier from attacks coming from the area of the 'Scorcher'.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_blockpost_job2_descr">
    <text>Lukash: 'If you feel the courage then you can go to the gate at the entrance to Radar. There are some indications that mutants or Monolithians might attempt to break through the barrier. We must help the guys.'.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_courier_doc_descr">
    <text>In 'Freedom' there is a grenade launcher type RG-6. Two of them. One in the arsenal the other somewhere in the countryside.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_courier_job_descr">
    <text>Lukash: 'It is regrettable to that we have a traitor amount us ... Pavlik. He's sending information to another faction and we need to stop him. Your task is to follow him to the farmstead and find out who he communicates with. He left recently, so you will have to catch up with him. Remember not to kill him until you know what is going on, and then kill him and the other guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_crazy_flash_info">
    <text>Today we went to another village to hunt for artifacts. Just like we always do. Where did this creature come from? Probably slipped in from Radar. All were killed except me. I'll try to travel at night. I do not remember how I got back, it was hell. My head has a splitting headache and images and sounds. I do not know where they come from. Damn radiation too. And my sensor, the damn piece of junk is broken. I need to rest, then I'll feel better.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_dolg_kill_lukash_descr">
    <text>Enter the Duty base and eliminate the snipers and kill Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_dolg_kill_sniper_descr">
    <text>Kill the sniper in the tower. We need to act carefully so as not to get a bullet in the head.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_flash_bandit_descr">
    <text>Damn, those Duty bastards kicked us out. They dug in near the farmstead. We didn't even have time to get our supplies from the attic. No big deal though the Freedom base is nearby. So Duty should not hang around for too long.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_flash_max_descr">
    <text>Today we shook down a few soldiers on their way to Red Forest. Took RG-6s'. They are awesome. Lukash took one, and Seryi hid the other in a village in one of the building basements.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_flash_ugrumy_descr">
    <text>1. The Devil made me go to the Red Forest. I barely made it. A little slower and I would have been another exhibit for liquified brains. \n\n 2: Four thugs surrounded me. I didn't see their trap. I was only saved by their chattiness and greed. Instead of stuffing me full of lead, they jumped out and began disrobing me - got hooked on the suit. That was their last mistake. One of them caught me with a bullet. I'm getting old. \n\n 3: By the time I arrived Strelok's messenger was no longer breathing. Three bloodsuckers are a match for anyone, but this guy took out four of them, and a few more bloody trails lead out in different directions. The only information on him is a door code (19840519). But identifying the door it unlocks doesn't seem possible. \n\n 4: We intercepted a few army men on their way to Red Forest. They carried no documents or orders, but were very adequately equipped. I think I'll leave that RG-6 in the basement until I need it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_freedom_rg6_task_descr">
    <text>Voronin: 'Freedom has a couple of RG-6's. If you could manage to sneak into their territory and steal one grenade launcher then I will handsomely reward you with information. Since you're a military guy you cannot easily get to Freedom. You will need some combat skills to steal an RG-6. I'll forward you the info about the location of Freedom. There you have to find a certain Chef, a member of the group Freedom, he knows exactly where the RG-6's are stored. He has a weakness for drink so try to get him drunk. If you can't make him talk. Well I suppose you will know what to do. You don't want to have to search the whole area.'.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_go_to_miser_descr">
    <text>Hmm! Skinflint at the 'Freedom' base will give me my reward. A good guy. Maybe I can get some unexpired canned goods. He is a generous guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr">
    <text>Destroy the village bloodsuckers. Be careful, and maybe they won't get to drink my blood.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_hunters_task_descr2">
    <text>Destroy the bloodsuckers in the village. Act carefully, and then maybe I'll live through it. Don't want them drinking my blood.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_lukash_job_descr">
    <text>Lukash decided to counter-attack the Duty force at the farm. The operation was led by Max one of the veterans of 'Freedom'. My goal is to help them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_mad_flash_job_descr">
    <text>What, I wonder, would know this fool on this bog? Face it. The main thing is not to run into old mines, but they must be in terrible condition, that will explode on the bolt.</text>
</string>
