<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101">
		<text>Thank you ... uh-uh-uh ... Strelok, right? You helped my colleague Kruglov escape, and in gratitude I would like to present you with our work clothes. Very handy outfit you know. Maybe I have something else useful for you? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1011">
		<text>I am looking for Lab X-16. The Barkeep says that you may know of its whereabouts.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1012">
		<text>Laboratory X-16 has for a long time interested us. In particular the device inside which generates radiation directly influencing the consciousness of people. Sorry to disappoint you, but you can not make your way there without special psy protection. The result would be tragic. Even if it were possible to avoid the hordes of zombies around the entrance to the laboratory you still risk turning into one of them. However we have developed a device which helps to shield radiation, but for more exact adjustment it is necessary to take a number of additional measurements. If you help us with it, for a while perhaps, we can give you a prototype for field tests.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1013">
		<text>Measurements?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1014">
		<text>If you together with our associate take all the necessary measurements I will prepare a fully workable prototype of this outfit and will give it to you. It will most likely let you get inside the laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10141">
		<text>Ok, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101411">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and get going. He is already equipped with the necessary gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101412">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10142">
		<text>Ok, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101421">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and get going. He's got everything you will need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101422">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_10143">
		<text>No, right now I don't want to sign up for this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_101431">
		<text>That's too bad, a real pity. I don't know how or when we could carry out this measurement expedition on our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_11">
		<text>Yes Sir! What might you be looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_111">
		<text>Umma look'n for Lab X-16. The Barkeep told me you might have info about its location.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12">
		<text>Thank you Strelok for rescuing Kruglov. Take this pressurized suit as a reward for your troubles. Also I suspect you didn't come here for a simple reward. Am I right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121">
		<text>I'm looking for Lab X-16. The Barkeep told me that you might have info about its location.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_1211">
		<text>We have been studying the emission in Lab X-16 for a long time, but you won't get in there without special equipment. We've developed a psy-protection device that can help shield you from the emission, but needs some fine-tuning. If you could help us with that, I could give you a working prototype that you can use to get inside the laboratory.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12111">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121111">
		<text>Excellent, talk to Kruglov and get going. He's got everything you'll need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_12112">
		<text>No, I'm not up for this yet.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_121122">
		<text>That's a real pity. So far we've been unable to send a measurement expedition of our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21">
		<text>Yes, Sir! What might you be looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211">
		<text>We've long had an interest in Lab X-16 or rather in the mechanism inside it that generates emissions which directly affects people's consciousness. I'm afraid I'll have to disappoint you. The place is impossible to penetrate without special psy protection. The outcome is known in advance, and even if you could evade the swarms of zombies that infest the laboratory entrance, you still run the risk of becoming one of them. This is all very serious. However we've designed a screening device to help shield the emissions, but to fine-tune it we have to obtain additional measurements. If you help us with this task, we could probably provide you with a fully calibrated prototype for field testing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111">
		<text>Go on.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21111">
		<text>We have been studying the emissions in Lab X-16 for a long time, but you won't get in there without special equipment. We've developed a psy-protection device that can help shield you from the emissions, but it needs some fine-tuning. If you could help us with that, I could give you a working prototype that you can use to get inside the lab.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21112">
		<text>Ok, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211121">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Kruglov and get going. He is already equipped with the necessary gear.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111211">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21113">
		<text>Ok, I agree.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211131">
		<text>Excellent! Talk to Semenov and get going. He's got everything you will need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211132">
		<text>Ok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211141">
		<text>You don't understand, there's an emitter. No one has been able to come closer than half a kilometer - it makes a zombie out of anyone. Going there without a suit is just like suicide, get it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2111411">
		<text>Hmm, that changes things.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211142">
		<text>To hell with it, just tell me all you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211143">
		<text>Ok but don't say I didn't warn you. Vasiliev worked on the laboratory problem. About a week ago he and stalker by the name of Ghost attempted to get inside the laboratory. After several hours we felt a shake and emissions stopped. After another hour we got a signal from Vasiliev stating that he was coming from the swamp but then vanished. By the looks of things Vasiliev is gone. Try to find his body. He had accurate information about the laboratory, where it is and how to get in. He might have also known how to turn off the emissions. The laboratory entrance is most likely hidden in the basement of one of the buildings in the power plant area.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211144">
		<text>There we go, great.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_21115">
		<text>No, right now I don't want to do this.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_211151">
		<text>That's too bad, a pity. I don't know how or when we could carry out this measurement expedition on our own.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_221">
		<text>I thank you... eh... Strelok, so? You have helped my colleague Kruglov to escape and in acknowledgement I would like to hand over our working suit. Very convenient piece you know!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_231">
		<text>You have worked wonderfully Strelok! Disabling the radiation can allow new expeditions and exploring in many areas. You did - nec plus ultra, I doubt that anyone else could have done this challenge. And because you risked your life. I consider it my personal duty to thank you not only money but also with the most expensive thing in this crazy modern world - information. Moreover, information is in no way easy to get, believe me! We need to share information about artifact modifications. Basically artifacts that are changed will have new characteristics. You'll need to read and understand more about modifying artifacts. I trust that you Strelok will be satisfied. And from now on you, we, will follow the most favorable pricing.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_2311">
		<text>Thanks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_241">
		<text>Yes, Strelok? What are you looking for?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31">
		<text>You did an excellent job. If the measurements are correct then the prototype should provide you with maximum protection from emission.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311">
		<text>Glad to hear that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_3111">
		<text>Now your path to the laboratory is clear but if the source of the emission isn't destroyed and doesn't lose its power you may not have enough time to get back. So, my dear Sir, here is the deal. Our calculations have produced an estimated location of the source as well as the fact that it is under ground. With your permission I have already marked the spot on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_31111">
		<text>How exactly does one get inside Lab X-16? Where is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor and after another hour or so we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but he died. And Vasiliev died away with whatever info he had, it would seem. Try to find his corpse. He had the exact information about the lab and the way to get into it. There may even be info on deactivating that source of the emission. I've uploaded you all the data we have onto your PDA.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311112">
		<text>Ahem... It would be very interesting to take a look at these documents. So, you think Vasiliev has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311113">
		<text>Perhaps. At any rate you must start by finding Vasiliev's body. That is the only chance of obtaining accurate information about the lab's location. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be somewhere around there as well. You know it seemed to me like he knew a lot more about X-16 than he led us to believe. Had he somehow survived, well it's no use holding on to that hope of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_311114">
		<text>Ok, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41">
		<text>Why did he die? You were supposed to protect him!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411">
		<text>Kruglov got killed by the zombies. I couldn't help him, there were too many of them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111">
		<text>Oh, man...how could this happen? How could this happen??! Damn it, everything is going wrong again. Now we'll have to call for more people. We've got enough problems as it is... damn...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111">
		<text>Listen... Kruglov is gone, but I'm alive. Give me the prototype. I will fight my way inside X-16.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_411111">
		<text>Here is a prototype, be careful with it. It's not calibrated properly, but that's your fault. You failed to save our colleague. The device won't provide maximum protection, but at least it will lower the emission's intensity. So stalker you'll have to move quickly on your way to the source.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_4111111">
		<text>How does one get inside Lab X-16? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41111111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and after another hour we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. And Vasiliev died away with it, it would seem. Try to find his corpse. He had the exact information on the lab and the way to get into it. There may even be info on deactivating that source of the emission. I've uploaded you all the data we have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41112">
		<text>Anything else?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41113">
		<text>You must start by finding Vasiliev's body - that is the only chance of obtaining accurate information about the lab's location. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be somewhere there as well. You know, it seemed to me like he knew a lot more about X-16 than he admitted to us. If he has survived somehow... Well, it's no use holding on to that hope, of course.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_41114">
		<text>Ok, I'll give it a shot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51">
		<text>Why did he die? Weren't you supposed to protect him?!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511">
		<text>Semenov was killed by some zombies. I couldn't help it, there were too many of them to deal with.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111">
		<text>Oh, man...how could this happen? How could this happen?! Damn it, everything is going to pot. Now we'll have to call for more people. We've got enough problems as it is... shit.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51111">
		<text>Listen Semenov is gone, but I'm alive. Give me the prototype. I will fight my way inside X-16.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111">
		<text>Here is a prototype, be careful with it. It's not calibrated properly, but that's your fault because you failed to save our colleague. The device won't provide maximum protection, but at least it will lower the emission's affects. So, stalker, you'll have to move fast on your way to the source.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_5111111">
		<text>How does one get inside Lab X-16? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_511111111">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and after another hour we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. And Vasiliev died away with it, it would seem. Try to find his corpse. He had the exact information on the lab and the way to get into it. There may even be info on deactivating that source of the emission. I've uploaded you all the data we have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51112">
		<text>Ahem! It would be very interesting to take a look at these documents. So, you think Vasiliev has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51113">
		<text>Perhaps, at any rate, you must start by finding Vasiliev's body. That is the only chance of obtaining accurate information about the lab's whereabouts. The body of your colleague Ghost must be somewhere there as well. You know it seemed to me like he knew a lot more about X-16 than he ever admitted to. Had he somehow survived... well, it's no use holding on to that hope.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_51114">
		<text>Ok, I'll do it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_61">
		<text>Yes Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_71">
		<text>Ok Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81">
		<text>It's too bad that Kruglov died. Nothing can bring him back. It's most important that you bring us the measurement data. Did you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_811">
		<text>Yes, here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8111">
		<text>Ok let me adjust the prototype. Wait for me here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_81111">
		<text>Gotcha.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_812">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_8121">
		<text>Then get them, and quickly! I cannot calibrate the prototype properly without them.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_91">
		<text>You did an excellent job. If the measurements are correct the prototype should provide you with maximum protection from emissions. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_911">
		<text>Can you be a little more clear?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9111">
		<text>Stalker, now you will be able to get into the laboratory, but unless you turn off the emitter, you won't last long even with the psy-protection on. We've estimated an approximate location of the emitter. It is located in an underground facility. I have marked the spot on your map.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9112">
		<text>How do I get inside X-16? Where exactly is the entrance?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9113">
		<text>Vasiliev was working on the lab issue. About a week ago he and a stalker called Ghost tried to get inside. A couple of hours later we felt a major tremor, and after another hour we picked up a signal from Vasiliev coming from the swamp, but it died away. And Vasiliev died away with it, it would seem. Try to find his corpse. He had the exact information on the lab and the way to get into it. There may even be info on deactivating that source of the emission. I've uploaded you all the data we have.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9114">
		<text>Ahem! It would be very interesting to take a look at these documents. So do you think Vasiliev has them?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9115">
		<text>Perhaps but at any rate you must find Vasiliev's body first. That is the only chance of obtaining accurate information about the lab's location. The body of your colleague, Ghost, must be somewhere there as well. You know it seemed to me like he knew a lot more about X-16 than he admitted to us. Had he somehow survived... well, it's no use thinking about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_9116">
		<text>Ok, I'll try.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_101">
		<text>There's no time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11">
		<text>Okay, Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111">
		<text>The professor asked me to help out with the trip to the measurement site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111">
		<text>Now you're talking business! Let's move out immediately. It was no use getting there alone, but with you it's different. I think we'll manage quickly, just make sure not to let those cadavers get too close. So, you ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_11111">
		<text>Yeah.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_111111">
		<text>You know what, why don't you go first. You have a lot more experience than me. Yo! Those cadavers are starting to get up.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_1111111">
		<text>Sure, no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_21">
		<text>Wow! Strelok here on a personal visit! Finally you've made it to our area. Talk to the Professor he wants to thank you for rescuing me. And also check your PDA. I've uploaded some useful info. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_31">
		<text>Then, then!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_41">
		<text>Hey, Strelok! How are things going?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_51">
		<text>Yes, Strelok?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_511">
		<text>Professor asked me to take a trip to the measurement site.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_512">
		<text>Now you're talking! Let's boogie. It is not safe to go there alone, but with you I feel safer. I think we'll manage ok. Just make sure not to let those cadavers too close to you. Ready?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_513">
		<text>Yes sir.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_514">
		<text>You know what, why don't you go first. You've got a whole lot of experience. And those cadavers are starting to move again.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_515">
		<text>Okay.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_61">
		<text>I'm sorry, I have no time for this right now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_71">
		<text>Hey, Strelok! How's life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_81">
		<text>Wait a little bit. We need to finish talking.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_help_scientist_91">
		<text>Wait! I'm not done taking measurements!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_11">
		<text>Yike! Ouch... Argh.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_111">
		<text>You alive? C'mon, get up. Get up slowly. It's all over. It's behind us now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_21">
		<text>Hey, Strelok. How are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_211">
		<text>Done! Measurements finished, it's time to get the hell out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_wounded_scientist_31">
		<text>Hey, Strelok! How's life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_talk_start_231">
		<text>You did a splendid job Strelok! Now that the emissions are turned off we will be able to order new expeditions and explore previously inaccessible territories. And also from now on we will conduct a most favourable pricing policy toward you. Oh and I almost forgot, check your PDA I've uploaded some info about 'artifact modifications'. I hope you find it useful.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_1">
		<text>About it, smart guy, already have heard. And Sidorovich told you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_2">
		<text>Yes.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_22">
		<text>So you want to learn?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_23">
		<text>You participated in this expedition?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_24">
		<text>Should have, but did not participate. I find it hard to talk about this terrible tragedy. At that time I lost a lot of my friends and colleagues. It's been a while, so I hope I can remember the events. But since you are so interested then I think I'll start my story. As I said this happened two years ago. It all began with a scientific congress in Berlin, which was the main topic area, as well as its impact on the environment. As a result it was decided to equip a scientific expedition to the Zone led by leading experts to gather information and explore the nature of the Zone. Soon there were sponsors who have agreed with the Government of Ukraine, and after three months of preparations for the expedition on a military base at the edge of Chernobyl. Ah, then the whole world have gathered here the scientific world, famous foreign and domestic scientists: physicists, chemists, biologists, engineers, doctors, mechanics and ecologists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_25">
		<text>So what happened?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_26">
		<text>They had tons of supplies: different devices, specialized equiptment, mobile laboratories, protective clothing, food, medicine, etc. The government allocated two special police groups and even special BTR's. Also in the expedition were stalker guides, translators and even journalists. They all had a two weeks training and mentoring before the expedition to the Zone to City-32. That it should have this happen! One day before the shipment I got sick and had to lie down for four days in the hospital that in theory saved my life. I was sorry about not being able to go with the expedition. I was envious of my colleagues. At that time I promised myself that I would catch a helicopter and go to the scientific camp. Meanwhile, the expedition had reached City-32.  A helicopter crew that was at the research camp decided to established a relationship with the people at the base and took up studies. At first everything went perfectly. We started to measure the radiation levels, to study various features of the anomalies, and the chemical composition of artifacts. Every day we receive regular reports from the camp about the new discoveries and artifacts. A successful expedition so no doubt. Meanwhile, I lay on a cot in the infirmary, mad at myself for getting sick.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_27">
		<text>Continue.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_28">
		<text>But soon the camp began having weird things happen. Firstly we noticed excessive aggressiveness and irritability in the voices on the radio, but did not attach much importance to it. Then two commandos disappeared. Three days after the beginning of the expedition, we received a message stating that one of the scientists, Professor Rosenberg, was in an overly agitated state, and committed suicide by shooting himself. This news shocked everyone! And two days after that later radio messages stopped coming from the camp. We stayed in complete bewilderment, it was decided to send a helicopter to the camp, but because of the strong storm that was not possible. All we could do was wait. A day later we received a message from two stalkers who had found at night a BTR in the woods. They must have been ambushed by bandits. The military sent a special ops team. What happened there, who knows, I can only add that a few survived the ambush. Three members of the expedition were hidden in the woods. When we found them they were more like animals than people, wild, frightened, bedraggled. They initially looked like patients in a psychiatric hospital, not even hard to believe that a week ago they were normal. It took about a month of intensive treatment to at least partially restore their psyche.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_29">
		<text>And in the end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_291">
		<text>After analyzing the incident and the stories of survivors the commission concluded that the cause of death of the expedition was the psychotropic radiation of unprecedented power which in the Zone called the 'Brain Scorcher'. As a result of over exposure to this type of radiation the human brain begins to break down. The symptoms that appear are unprecedented aggression, rage and savagery. Some couldn't cope with the psychological stress and killed themselves, such as poor Professor Rosenberg. Some took out their aggression on others, attacked and killed them like mad animals. The camp was in shambles. A still here and mutants arrived, using the lack of protection. Those who have not yet gone completely mad are trying to return to the BTR, but halfway there were ambushed by bandits and killed in a shootout. So the expedition to City-32 was not really a success. Since then I vowed not to leave the Zone until I have studied this damn radiation, and find some kind of protection from it. Ok Spot, I chatted with you long enough, now it's time for work.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_292">
		<text>Yes, I will not detain you, professor.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_3">
		<text>No.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story_33">
		<text>Then ask later, I now have no time for stories.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_0">
		<text>Professor, do you have any useful info about mutants?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_1">
		<text>Yes, certainly, here Kruglov's last report on poltergeists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_2">
		<text>Very interesting to learn something new about them, before I heard only rumors.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_3">
		<text>So. What we know about the poltergeist: \n 1. These are people that were exposed to ejections. They have higher telepathic abilities and can subdue the people, animals, mutants, partially and even Controllers. \n 2. They are not easy to see. According to stalkers out in the Zone these poltergeists are lost souls. \n 3. Telekinetic abilities vary. They can throw objects, from small stuff to big iron doors. \n 4. Supposedly a Poltergeist can turn into a Controller. It is unknown how. Presumably a Controller is a person that for a long time has been under the influence of a Poltergeist. Poltergeist where reason and logic weave. A some point the Controller rejects the Poltergeist out of its mind. Controller then regresses in byurera. Information concerning this theory was lost 2 years ago. \n 5. Supposedly live in caves. Although this has not been proven to be absolutely true yet. \n 6. Energy analysis of the Controller finds that it is very intelligent. Presumably not like a Poltergeist that can kill by altering energy balances.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_4">
		<text>Uh-e ... Professor, can you repeat the last sentence slowly?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_5">
		<text>Shoot them bastards Strelok.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_general_ucheniy_story2_6">
		<text>Ah! It is now clear, thanks a lot for the info!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_0">
		<text>Yes Professor, you have something want to ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_1">
		<text>Strelok, I need the PDA of Ghost. So could you bring it to me? It has stored valuable information on not yet completely studied artifacts which can be found only near the center of the Zone. Of course I will thank you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_2">
		<text>If I find it, I will bring it to you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_3">
		<text>I hope so Strelok. For me and for the whole scientific world this information is of great value.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_0">
		<text>Hello Doctor, I have brought what you asked for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_1">
		<text>Oh you found it! I am very grateful to you Strelok. Here take this for the troubles.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_2">
		<text>The doctor wanted to know if in the PDA there was any writing about Fang from the group of Strelok. Maybe you know something about his death?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yantar_saharov_next_3">
		<text>To be honest, I do not know much. Ask General Voronin. Not long before Ghost went with Vasiliev into the underground lab he told me that they had some things in common. Perhaps General Voronin could tell you more.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
