<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- DR and GH -->
<string_table>

<string id="mervin_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh-oh-oh, where am I? ... And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I see that you’re alive. Well it’s the first time I've seen anyone survive after falling into a "Crater" anomaly. Even your suit was blown away. You should be thankful that I pulled you out.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks, but I don't remember anything ... Something flashed, and then I blacked out. Oh my head aches...</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I see you've come to your senses. Now tell me who you are and what you’re doing in Pripyat. Don't lie to me or I will shoot you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't remember anything, not even my name. I'm not lying. All my stuff and weapons were in my backpack, I think. And why I came here, I don't know.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, I see. Your protective suit, your backpack and everything in it is all gone. The anomaly ripped all your stuff into small pieces and scattered them all. And all your money ... Check.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_6">
    <text>It's gone... But who are you and why did you save me? As far as I understand it was an extremely dangerous undertaking</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_7">
    <text>My name is Mervin. I gather 'lost souls' such as you, and draw them into a great faith - the faith of the Almighty, the Monolith. They find I come in handy to find strong guys like you, very much needed as new soldiers. Prove yourself brave and obedient - and you can become one of us.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_8">
    <text>What if I refuse?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_9">
    <text>That is not possible. Now so let's see what you can do: if you prove that you are suited, I'll give you life and help you. But if you are a coward then death will relieve you from pain.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_10">
    <text>And how can I prove I am capable and not a coward?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_11">
    <text>Quite simple, you have to pass a little test: in the centre of Pripyat is an old Ferris wheel. Here is the home of some mutants, Snorks they are called, about five or six should be there. Go there and kill the creatures, then come back to me. For this assignment I will give you a Colt pistol and two boxes of ammunition. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_start_dialog_12">
    <text>Well, it seems I have no other choice ... give me the gun and I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="snork_start_dialog_0">
    <text>I've destroyed the Snorks.</text>
</string>
<string id="snork_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Well done, you coped well with the ordeal. Now come with me. You have proved that you are brave and agile, we need such men. It is agreed then, you will serve the great brotherhood - the brotherhood of the Monolith. Then I say thank you!</text>
</string>
<string id="snork_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, I have nowhere else to go.</text>
</string>

<string id="first_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>What kind of job should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Missions will be complex. With the help of the tele-portal given to us by the powerful Monolith, I will move you to different places from where you must return to me unharmed. But most importantly, in each of these places will be one of the manuscripts with our principal commandments. You have to get them, read and remember what is written there, and then bring them back to me. Only then will mission be considered carried out.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>I understand. What is the first task?</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>For the beginning, not particularly complex, I'll send you to Chernobyl-2, to the generators. Bring the manuscript back to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I'm ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I performed the first task,</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Good. Give me the manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="second_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>What will be the second task?</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Now this task is more complicated. I'll send you to the roof of the Sarcophagus, to the radar. Conditions are the same - you take the manuscript, and bring it back me. And another thing: be careful on the way back.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, teleport me.</text>
</string>

<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I performed the second task.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done! You returned quickly. Give me the manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, take the second manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Other assignments you will receive later. Now we have to interrupt them briefly, Charon is waiting for you - it's urgent. Then, after you perform his mission, Charon will tell you how to further proceed with your training.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_urok_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Well, then I'll go to Charon.</text>
</string>

<string id="new_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>What now, time for me to go back to Mervin?</text>
</string>
<string id="new_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, now you can safely continue with your training. Mervin is waiting for you in Pripyat, in the hotel. I will teleport you there. He is on the second floor in room number 26. Ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="new_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I am ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="tri_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Mervin! I'm back...</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, we extend the class. Here's a third job, warm-up: love to ride on the Ferris wheel?</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>As a child I loved it.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, now, you can relive your childhood!</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>I do not understand, what do you mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Mervin you wanker, I was nearly blown off the top of the wheel.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hard to learn - if the battle is easy!</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, prick, take the third manuscript.</text>
</string>

<string id="four_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, what's next?</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>What, not pleased? Don't be angry - learn to control your emotions. It will prove useful to you in the future.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, what's still too came?</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>I bet as a child you liked to climb into attics, eh? Well plunge once more into your childhood!</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>It's that again?</text>
</string>

<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I have a feeling Mervin that you are trying to kill me.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_1">
    <text>No I don't want you to die. If you perform all the tasks with obedience and bravery, I'll be happy, and ultimately, make you a mentor. So, all that I'm doing is for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Okay, understood. Here is the fourth manuscript.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_3">
    <text>That's good, now we'll move on together to another place.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_urok_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Where are we going?</text>
</string>

<string id="five_urok_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow! How did we get here?</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_1">
    <text>If you faithfully serve the Monolith, then I will teach you this science.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_2">
    <text>Thanks. Well, what's the next test?</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_3">
    <text>As a child, were you afraid of heights? Behind you stands a five-storey building. It is necessary to jump down to its roof and find the fifth manuscript. You don't have to return it to me - keep it handy and don't forget what you have learnt. Your training is now complete. As a final task, go immediately to Charon. He has important work for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh, that's it!</text>
</string>
<string id="five_urok_dialog_5">
    <text>All right, go jump. Good luck, hope we meet again. Pass on my greetings to Charon.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_graf_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Borov.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_2">
    <text>How do you know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, you have created such a reputation in the Zone, now everyone talks about you. Once you entered the territory of the Bar, I was immediately told of your arrival ... I knew it was you, Strelok. And now to business: recently, an important man has shown up, a type of intelligence officer, he's called Earl. Go see him, he has a serious matter for you to attend to.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_4">
    <text>And where do I find Earl?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_5">
    <text>He's in the entrance of the Arena, a brick building opposite the entrance to the "100 Rads" bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I'll find him.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello! Are you Earl?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. And who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. Borov sent me, he says you need my help.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Ahh, Strelok! I've heard a lot about you. Because of your sharp eyes they call you 'Werewolf'. You're a former Monolith, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yes I am. So, I assume that we've met before.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_first_dialog_0">		<!-- Prince or Duke -->
    <text>What is your interest in me?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok, I don't have time for small talk, we have to barter...</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I don’t have time to barter, if you have something for me, tell me if not I'll go - I've other matters to attend to...</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, okay, don't get angry ... People say that you are prepared to take on risky work for the right price. I have just the job for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_5">	<!-- Prince or Duke -->
    <text>I and my partners, Duke and Caesar, recently came across the trail of a group of the Mercenaries who tried to organize the import of a large batch of modern weapons and supplies into the Zone to build a strong base somewhere in Rostok, I do not know exactly where, they are planning to storm the Bar and Warehouses, so as a result, to control further passage by anyone into the Zone. We were able to help Duke's people, to detect and shoot down the helicopters carrying the cargo. Then, we ran into a Mercenary detachment covering them ... we had to split into three groups ... we barely survived. They pursued us and I came to the Bar for refuge. Duke and his group went to the Military Warehouses to search for where one of choppers might have crashed. Caesar was going to Yantar to find the second chopper and then to the scientists for medical assistance</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_6">
    <text>So, what do you need of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_7">
    <text>For starters, here's the first task. Not far outside the territory of the Bar, as if going towards the Garbage, where dogs hang out and a zombie hangs from a tree, go to the right toward the fence where the dirt mound is near the ditch, an old unfinished road is out past the fence, jump it, and go sort of left. 25 years ago it led to Yantar. The place is wild and unexplored. They say there is a strange spatial anomaly there where the laws of physics do not apply. Here at the end of this unfinished road to the left, a helicopter crashed. The chopper and crew vanished as if they were dissolved by an anomaly, but here are a few crates of weapons out there that survived. I wouldn't go there unless you have lots of ammo and medkits. There are many zombies and bloodsuckers out there. Good luck, you will need it!</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Interesting story you tell, Earl.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_9">
    <text>You've got to hurry! Find and bring me those weapons before the Mercenaries get them. And most importantly, look for the accompanying documents. They should be in a fireproof briefcase there too. We will be able to learn from these documents, who on the 'Mainland', sponsors these deliveries, and then, through our people, we will be able to influence the process, so to speak. As a reward, I'll give you a weapon. Oh, and please: kill all the mutants, they come here in droves from Yantar and try to get to the Bar. Here are a few F-1 grenades, they may come in handy.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_10">
    <text>I'm going. The mutants will be dealt with.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Earl!</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Did you find what I asked?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I found the road. What a freak'n place! It gave me cold sweats, I killed a zillion mutants. I've brought the arms and documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Fine job, Strelok! I didn't doubt you could do it. Give me what you brought. Take this gun and cartridges as agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here, take this stuff.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_second_dialog_0">	<!-- Prince -->
    <text>Earl, how else can I help?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Okay, while you were away, I heard from Prince. He is now at the Radar in hiding. He says he found the place where the second helicopter crashed at the Warehouses, but it was overrun by Mercs and he had to escape.  You need to find Prince and bring him his weapon and ammunition. These you will find at chopper crash site near the Army Warehouses in a ravine somewhere close to the Barrier.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Where at Radar can I find Prince?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_3">
    <text>He is hiding somewhere in an abandoned tunnel which is near the entrance to an old bunker. A small military base used to be there. But now it's quiet he said. So go! You must find the weapon for Prince. I've informed him you're on your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_4">
    <text>All is clear. I'll go find the gun and take it to Prince.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_0">	<!-- Prince -->
    <text>Hello, are you Prince?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, I am and you, apparently, are Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here's the gun Earl asked me to bring to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yeah, thanks! It'll come in handy, the Mercenaries have tracked me down so prepare. I had no assault weapons left, only a pea shooter.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Here, take this.</text>
</string>

<string id="prince_first_dialog_0">
    <text>What more can I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Earl probably told you that I found the place where the second Merc helicopter crashed. Well, here you can help me; I need you to retrieve the documents from the fireproof case. I saw the metallic case among the boxes, but I couldn't reach it. The Mercs had us pinned down, and I lost all my men and barely survived. The four remaining Mercs wiped out the Freedom forces at the Warehouses. I didn't know that at the time, because I had escaped to the Radar. I saw a couple of those freaks get through the barrier. I sensed someone was behind me all the time.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_2">
    <text>So where is the place where you're sending me?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_3">
    <text>The place is on a hill. Go toward the transition from Military Warehouses to the Bar. Pass the bus and turn right and go up the hill. On the ground there should be two boxes and a metallic case from the chopper. Find them and take them to Earl. He will give you the next transition point. But be careful, there is some sort of spatial hell there. The chopper seemed to have been dissolved, but not before dumping its load. It's a mystery as to what really happened. So be on guard.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Is that all?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Oh, a few boxes survived, I think there's a weapon there, because the Mercenaries did not have time to take it, nor I, because I was being pursued. If you find it, take it, as long as they do not get it. And be careful, those who pursued me, are somewhere near here ...  go with God.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_6">
    <text>I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Earl!</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok, what news do you bring?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_2">		<!-- Prince -->
    <text>I was at the place where Prince spotted the second crashed helicopter.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Did you find anything there?  Documents, perhaps?</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_4">			<!-- Prince -->
    <text>Yes I found some documents, also a special weapon Prince told me about that I could keep as a reward. I can sell it to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Well, I can buy it, of course. Give me the documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="prince_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_net_work_0">
    <text>Well Earl do you have any work?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_net_work_1">
    <text>Come back later when Caesar returns. Without him it's not possible to decipher the information you retrieved.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Earl! The Barkeep told me that you are looking for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I am. Good thing you came. I've heard from Caesar. He's at the scientist's bunker in Yantar licking his wounds. We must bring him something.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>What do I need to take to him?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>In short, he has three hiding-places here, not far away, somewhere in the rear courtyard behind the Bar. Find them then go through the transition from the Bar to Rostok, then to Yantar. It's necessary for you to find these caches and bring the USB drives in them to him. They contain the Mercenary's cipher codes. Caesar needs these codes to decipher the documents you found.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_4">
    <text>Damn it, I have to go back to that accursed place again. It's hell there. However I do wish to continue my journey... I suppose I must.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry it seems all quiet there now. Go on just like last time through the south and to the right post, over the fence, and then another to the right and come in between the buildings.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, Okay I'll do it. But how will I get to Yantar afterwards? I have other interests there.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_7">
    <text>I forgot, the road to Yantar goes through Rostok. It's not easy to find, but you will be able to, you have a gift for such things. When you find the three flash drives for Caesar, I'll mark on your PDA the transition from the Bar to Rostok. My people are clearing it now, we blocked it some time ago to stop mutants from coming through. But let's put security aside for now because there are better things to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_8">
    <text>You helped me with the Rostok transition, but how do I get to Yantar from there?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_9">
    <text>Strelok, you ask many questions! Once there, you will deal with the situation. Search for the Secret Path, it's out there. Go through the 'Burner' tunnel at the end of Rostok. Look for it around there. It's there but not always obvious. What kind of interest do you have there in Yantar?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I understand about the transition to Yantar. It's not the first time I had to blindly seek out a Secret Path. I'll find it. I'm looking for someone in the Dead City, but the road there is unknown to me. The scientists at Yantar know the way, so I was told.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_11">
    <text>So that's it ... Well with the transition from Yantar, those egg-heads are unlikely to be able to help you. Too much has changed in the Zone since the last emission including the paths. In short, deal with Caesar, come back and let's think how to get you into the Dead City. I'll help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay, understood. I'll try to hurry.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Caesar?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I'm Strelok, Earl sent me. I brought you the flash drives which contain the mercenary codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Hi, Strelok! Glad to meet you. Earl told me that you were coming. I was getting tired of waiting. Well give me the flash drives. As a reward I have for you a rare artifact. Here take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tri_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thanks for the artifact. Here are the three flash drives.</text>
</string>

<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Well then, am I free to go?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>No Strelok wait... there is one little matter that is not so simple. Did Earl tell to you about the Mercenaries' helicopters that we shot down?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, I am aware of that. Documents were taken from two of the crash sites and given to Earl.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Good, now down to business. A third helicopter is here in Yantar, just beyond the lake. The Mercenaries were faster than us and got there first and they tried to take the surviving cargo to a safe place in Rostok. But they were afraid to go through the scientist's base because Dan and his guys where there. So they took the bypass around the laboratory X-16 complex. But on the road they apparently got caught in a spatial anomaly. Well you already know about this for sure. I think there visors stopped working. I do not know precisely how those Mercenaries disappeared. The cargo is still there. Sakharov helped me to fix the signal. The signal is weak, but steady, coming from somewhere near the complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Can you be more specific?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't interrupt me. The place from where the signal originates is in the forecourt of Complex X-16, at the gate opposite the entrance to the underground lab itself. The gate that is locked. There must be some metal cases there, at least one for sure. Go past the swamp and crashed helicopter, up the hill, go right and follow along the buildings to the end, turn right, go to end of building, turn right, go to end of building, turn right, then left. Will most likely see some Poltergeists near a wall on the left. Look for three small coal bins. The case is there between them. As far as getting past the radioactive field, you will need a unique suit, a "Pegasus-85M". It has very good radiation protection and I'll also give you ten antirads. Help out by bringing the secret documents. They should be there, I just know it. This is very important. I'd have gone but I cannot until my wounds have healed. In the meantime I'll work on the cipher code. Oh, about the anti-radiation suit, don't forget to put it on before going up the hill. There are very dangerous levels of radiation there, and without that suit 300 Roentgens can cook your balls. If you have any artifacts that decrease radiation put them on your belt. Then return the suit back. I cannot do without it in Yantar. And beware of the Poltergeists.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, agreed, I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found the documents, Caesar.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Good for you, Strelok! I just figured out the codes.</text>
</string>

<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Now what?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Let's check the documents. I'll look at them quickly, stay, and wait a few minutes.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>All right. By the way, your outfit helped me a lot, here take it back.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, what is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Again, the same code ... These documents must go to Earl. I'll give you another PDA with a single code base, which was collected while you are away, show it also to Earl. He will decrypt the data and then decide what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Agreed, give me the documents and PDA, I will go to Earl.</text>
</string>

<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Earl!</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Caesar has already reported everything. Thanks to you it's all saved. Give me the PDA with the base code and documents, and let us look for some hidden information.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Aha, let us have a look, here ... so-so ... schedule of deliveries of armaments into the Zone ... a list of agents ... some data about the secret experiments ... oops, and here... this is really interesting!!! Strelok do not go away! Wait a while; in my opinion I think we have a serious problem. Everything must be carefully read to draw conclusions.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Well I'll wait Earl. Aren't I due something for this risky work?</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Ah yes of course please excuse me. Here from my friends and I beside the commendation take this rapid-firing automatic machine gun 'QBZ-97'.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Wow, thanks!</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_four_dialog_0">
    <text>Well what information is in the documents?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_1">
    <text>Simply put Strelok it turns out that the deliveries of weapons and supplies were carried out in preparation for a very large scale operation by Mercenaries. It refers to some installation which will influence the Psyche. With the help of this installation it will be possible to burn out the brain within a radius of several kilometres. The Mercenaries are preparing a massive attack to seize the Radar territory to establish this installation there and block the way to Pripyat and Chernobyl. It's not clear what the ultimate goal of this attack will be but you can be sure of one thing, that they will send in scientists. They won't be from the 'Mainland', but from right here in the Zone! Who they are and where to find them is not clear. But if they pull it off then it will be bad for us. The Zone will be divided into two parts and no one knows what will happen there in Chernobyl.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_2">
    <text>So that's the agenda! What do we do about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_3">
    <text>You should find one person they call him Fang. Give him this PDA. I have all the deciphered information on it. Maybe he can explain it all. Well... or at least advise what to do. He is smart and knows a lot of people.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh Fang! I know him, I met him once in Pripyat, and I'm looking for him.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_5">
    <text>Well that's fine. Find him and give him my PDA with decrypted information.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_6">
    <text>Ok give me the PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Earl what about my question?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>In case you think there is a solution. Exploration works for me well.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>Well briefly tell me, but then time is running out. I've got to find Mahomet.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen carefully: you need to get to the Dead City, right?  There's a simple solution, there are experienced Diggers who know the way. They might say they don't know, but you are a lucky guy. They have a problem with one their guys who disappeared. He went to the Dead City but never returned. They really need to find him but they have no one to go search. You could offer your services and then they might help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah, of course. Who are they and how do I find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>Yes, you may even know them. Clear Sky in the Radar, Sviblov and his guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>So that's it. I wonder why they went to the Dead City, the Wanderers control it.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay I'll tell you more. Few people know this, way back when the Wanderers and Clear Sky were one whole group called "C-Consciousness" that protected the scientific workers. The scientists where working on a closed project financed by a large pharmaceutical corporation. What kind of project, nobody knows. So far everything has been kept secret. The only fact known was that they were based in Yantar in a scientific base with Sakharov, and helped the scientists. Then something went wrong and they experienced internal conflict. It was said that problems began because of the women, two sisters: Leila and Karina. These two women had different ideological beliefs. I do not know precisely what that means but nevertheless I've always said that women have no place in the Zone. Always trouble with them. Well then, this big group was divided in two - one remained with the scientists in Yantar headed by Dan, and the second led by Leila. Leila's group left camp and went deep into the Zone calling themselves 'Wanderers'. Leila's sister Karina stayed with Dan at Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>I was at Yantar, but never saw any girls.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>But now the fun begins. They say that Karina and Dan were involved. And later she had an affair with Sviblov. Dan was angered and exiled Sviblov to the Radar, and Karina went with him too. In short, the second mistake she made involving Clear Sky. Soon the sisters somehow made up and Karina from time to time goes to visit Leila. The last time Karina went to the Dead City, she vanished. Sviblov sent his people to search for her, but they never returned. C'est la vie!</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>So this is how it all turned out.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_11">
    <text>Yeah. It's a real soap opera. Go to Sviblov at the Radar and tell him you heard a rumour about his problem and tell him you can help. It doesn't matter where you heard the rumour. If you promise to find out where Karina is he should give you the path to the Dead City. Capito? Through him is the only way to find out how to get there.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_poisk_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes I understand. I will go to the Radar and talk to Sviblov. Thanks Earl, now to the rendezvous!</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Sviblov!</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_1">
    <text>What's brought you here Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_2">
    <text>I heard a rumour that you need help finding a missing person. Is this true?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_3">
    <text>Well actually yes, we do have a problem. How did you find out about it?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_4">
    <text>How I found out is unimportant. The main thing is that I can help you. Well, try at least. I'll need complete information about this person and the transition to the Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_5">
    <text>You're a smart fellow. However we have no choice now. Do you understand the basic nature of this problem?</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_6">
    <text>Yes, briefly.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_7">
    <text>Well briefly, one of our girls has disappeared. Her name is Karina. Dark-haired, petite, and dressed in blue protective overalls with the label "Clear Sky" on it. She's hot too! And I mean HOT! She left five days ago to visit her sister Leila in the Dead City but never returned. She was to come back the following day. I sent some guys to search for her, but they too have vanished.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_8">
    <text>If I understand correctly, I need to find Karina or find out what happened to her.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_9">
    <text>Let's just say, find her and save her if possible, and bring her here, or at least take her to the scientist's bunker at Yantar. I will be indebted to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay I understand. I want nothing in return. Just show me where the transition to the Dead City is located. I must admit I have an interest in this too.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay agreed. I've never shown anyone the Secret Path to the Dead City before, but this is a special case. I'll mark the location of the transition on your PDA. The path leading to this transition and the transition itself are outside of the Radar. So getting to this trail can only be done through a secret teleport. You'll find it in the north-eastern part of the complex next to a breach in the brick wall. Just hurry up because this trail is not constant, it can be lost at any time. So go. In the Dead City you will find the Wanderers. Talk to Leila, Karina's sister. I beg you to please find Karina.</text>
</string>
<string id="karina_poisk_dialog_12">
    <text>Understood, I will try. Give me the location of the transition and I will go.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Fang, you ol' barker, I have something from Earl.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_1">
    <text>From Earl? I haven't heard from him in a long time. What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here's a PDA with information about an impending Mercenaries assault on the Radar. Check it out, maybe you can give us some advice.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_3">
    <text>So ... (checking the PDA) it's interesting, very interesting ... shit! I heard about it from Ghost, but not very much is believable and now I don't know what to think. There are a lot of facts here and they're all somehow interconnected. Let us do this, I have to think things through carefully about what Ghost and the Doctor advised. You need to get your priorities in order, then come see me and we'll think of something.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Okay Fang, I will see you later.</text>
</string>

<!-- Fang is in Army Warehouses at the pig farm -->
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Fang what have you found out?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_1">
    <text>I've talked with Ghost and the Doctor. The information that you brought me has been confirmed. It appears that a group of mad scientists are up to something very serious and dangerous. Their first step will include an installation at the Radar and to cut off Pripyat and Chernobyl from the rest of the Zone. To do this they will hire Mercenaries and arm them to the teeth. Then after the capture of the Radar they'll turn them into watchdogs. When they have no one to interfere with the Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant itself, somewhere in the Sarcophagus they will deploy some secret experiments associated with that 'satanic' rock, you know, the 'Monolith'. Well as for the protection of the territories of Chernobyl and Pripyat they already have a guard group, a Monolith faction. They cleaned their brains long ago. Oh, and it appears they've started training in the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_2">
    <text>And what do we do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_3">
    <text>Well Barkeep has already told you that we should find Swamp Doctor in the Swamps. He should be able to advise us on what to do. Just hurry up!</text>
</string>
<string id="klyak_final_dialog_4">
    <text>All is clear, therefore as discussed I'll go to the Swamp Doctor in the Swamps.</text>
</string>

<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Skinflint. Lukash said that you have something for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes Strelok I have a request for you. If you can execute it I will forever be in your debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_3">
    <text>As you can see we are thoroughly entrenched here. Everything: weapons, ammunition, canned food and vodka with breadcrumbs abound, having been left behind by our enemies, but what we desire is soft freshly baked rye bread. We love the stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_4">
    <text>You're kidding me! Where in the Zone can I find any fresh rye bread?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_5">
    <text>It's possible! There is a man they call Baker. He's right here in the Zone baking real rye bread. Baking this bread is not easy. Some clever baker came up with this recipe. It does not get stale for about a month and tastes just as fresh after being carried in a rucksack for a couple of weeks. What's in it and how he makes it, no one knows, but the fact remains that it is good. In short, bring me 10 loaves of bread from Baker and I'll repay you very adequately. Well it's in your hands now.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_6">
    <text>It's a deal. Only where do I look? I haven't heard anything about this guy before.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, now you'll know. Previously he had a bakery in the Agroprom in the southern complex, and then came the Mercenaries, so he had to get out. He spoke to the trader, Sidorovich, and said "I will create a new bakery". Well, you probably know Sidorovich, or at least heard of him. He's located in the Peacekeeping Corps territory. He'll know where you can find Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Well in that case I will have a talk with Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hey Skinflint I brought you 10 loaves of bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well you did a great service, thank you so much!</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here take the goods.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yeah give it here. And from me to you a special gift, take it, an FN2000.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yeah, wow, I long dreamed of such a gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Stay healthy Skinflint. Is there anymore work?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_1">
    <text>There certainly is, a matter that is personal and doubly critical. Anyhow I can't trust anyone, therefore listen carefully, I'll speak quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me, I'm listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen, there's a Stalker in the Zone they call Shuttle. He is occupied by the fact that he constantly travels to the 'Mainland' for those who hire him. His clients are usually the scientists based at Yantar and other experienced loner Stalkers. I had to turn to him recently for an important issue.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes, the work he does is serious.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I agree with you, but he receives a lot of money. Well, he was carrying a small suitcase for me with very important things, however I will not say it is irrelevant. But he is gone. Most likely the poor fellow perished in an anomaly or the mutants got him even though he was an experienced Stalker. If the contents of the briefcase he was carrying for me fall into the wrong hands, I'm in big trouble. I would have gone in search of him, but I cannot get away from the base. Well will you help me?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_6">
    <text>No problem, of course I will help you if you pay well. Give me the details and I will go.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Here is the situation. Shuttle's last trip was three days ago, since then no one has heard from him. I beg you to find Shuttle or what's left of him and, most importantly, bring me the attache case with the info. Shuttle's last trip was to Rostok. You know that uninhabited wildlife area where people disappear all the time. He messaged that there was no safe place and everything was in disarray. Dig up all of Rostok if you have to, but find my attache case and any information about Shuttle , I beg you. I will be indebted to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Bummer, well as far as this assignment goes... yes it is agreeable, I will try you to help.</text>
</string>

<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well Skinflint, I found your case.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Oh you are a good fellow Strelok! What happened to Shuttle?</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I did not find Shuttle, nothing of him remains except his PDA and this attache case. They were in the underground passage to Rostok, his last resting place is among the anomalies and monsters. He was trapped.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well, he knew what he was doing. May he rest in peace. Hurry, give me Shuttle's PDA. My gift to you is no worse than last time. Here take this M4 Carbine.</text>
</string>
<string id="skryaga_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thanks for the nice payment.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_pekar_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Sidorovich! I seek Baker. I was told you know where to find him.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_1">
    <text>That's right, Baker was here recently. Good man by the way, he bakes delicious bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_2">
    <text>No doubt about it. So where is he located?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_3">
    <text>He's in the deserted village. I will enter the location on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pekar_dialog_4">
    <text>Ah, ok, thank you. I will go down and introduce myself to Baker.</text>
</string>

<string id="pekar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, who might you be?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm Strelok. Skinflint asked me to get 10 loaves of rye bread which only you would have. How much?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Ahh, Skinflint, I remember this Freedom member, he's a good guy. I am not concerned about the money. Help me and I'll give you 10 loaves of bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>What you do want?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_5">
    <text>As you know, to bake bread, you need flour. Other ingredients I find myself but flour is rather scarce. I used to have a bakery at the Agroprom and Freedom delivered the flour to me. And then came these Mercenaries and everything changed. Lukash and his guys moved to the Military Warehouses and I had to look for another quiet place. I initially wanted to settle at the Military Warehouses, close to Freedom. I asked five Stalkers to help me move the bags of flour. As we approached the Freedom base from the abandoned village, the bloodsuckers attacked us. All my guys were torn to pieces. I barely had time to crawl to the Bar. I had to leave five 25 kg bags of flour. What a pity. I then asked Lukash to find these bags, but he was afraid to send Freedom into the village. Then, while at the Bar, I decided not to risk going back and came here - it seems a very quiet place, far from the centre of the Zone. Soon I will establish a direct supply of flour again.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, how I can help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_7">
    <text>It's simple enough. Bloodsuckers in fact do not eat flour. So somewhere out there in the countryside, you'll find these bags, they are likely to have been scattered by these creatures. You go to this village at the Military Warehouses, find and bring me the five sacks of flour. So that you don't have to make five trips, I'll give you a unique anti-gravity suit, wearing it makes it easy to carry 180 kgs. Bring the flour to me, I promised Lefty 30 loaves. So do not lose it!</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Yeah, I wonder how far I need to travel.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_9">
    <text>I'll help you. Listen to me carefully: from here it is possible for one to use a very clever mystery trail to get to the Bar, bypassing the Cordon, the Dark Valley and the Forest. Don't be surprised there is such a path, I came here that way from the Bar. Pathfinder showed me the way for 20 loaves of my bread. I would not have shared this secret route with anyone but the situation here calls for it. I can't get these sacks myself - I'm too old, my legs refuse to walk at all ... So if you do not want to go the long way through the Cordon and the Garbage, then use this path.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Interesting! This entirely changes the situation. If I can get to the Bar, then getting to the Military Warehouses is just a stone's throw away. Tell me where does this path begin?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_11">
    <text>From here you go to the southern area. There, in the south-eastern part, near the abandoned factory, there is a small swamp with a digging machine. Over there, next to the swamp, you can find the Secret Path, this will lead you to the southern entrance of the Bar. But if not you cannot find it you will have to go to the Military Warehouses and back, the same way as you arrived here. Well, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Well Baker, agreed. Let's suit me up.</text>
</string>

<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Baker, here are your bags, all five. I barely found them.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well thank you Stelok! We can say that you saved a small business in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Come on, no nonsense here. Take your bags and gravity suit. By the way, the suit was awesome!</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Here's your 10 loaves of bread, as agreed..</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Yeah, much appreciated.</text>
</string>

<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_0">
    <text>Baker listen, sell to me your gravity suit. I liked it very much and I can carry a lot.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_1">
    <text>Sorry Strelok I need it. I cannot do without it, you understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes I understand, of course. But painfully I liked it....</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_3">
    <text>Okay, if you want one the same, then listen here: in the Cordon at the Military base, there are still a couple of anti-gravity suits. I know that for sure. Here's my advice to you - procure these bulletproof vests and take one to Lefty, he'll upgrade it the same as mine. I'll let Lefty know that you are coming, Strelok ... He won't fail, and you can be sure! However, you'll have to do something for him, these are the rules of the Zone, you understand ...</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_outfit_dialog_4">
    <text>Well thank you Baker for the advice. I will surely take advantage of it.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi, Lefty!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_1">
    <text>Yo, Strelok what brings you here?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_2">
    <text>I have an anti-gravity Military bulletproof vest....</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_3">
    <text>Nice! Want to upgrade it? Is that right?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_4">
    <text>Exactly!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, I can do it ... Only out of respect for you of course, but for the modification I'll need - a "Firey Soul" artefact.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, here's the anti-gravity vest. When I get the "Firey Soul" artefact - I will bring it directly to you. I can see you're busy, so I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Lefty!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Ok Strelok, did you bring to me the "Firey Soul"?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yep, got it!</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Come on, let's see it....</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Your human, don't you believe me?</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Come on, do not get excited, everything is fine. Here, take this new acquisition.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Well, thank you! I hope this is what I need.</text>
</string>

<string id="pekar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything else I can do for you?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well actually there is one other matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Tell me briefly.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes indeed, the matter is simple: I'm here trying to organize a small bakery, and I need to fix the oven. It is quite useless as it is. To repair something in the Zone is not easy. When I fled the Agroprom, I left a lot of things behind. What a pity.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand, you need me to bring something from the Agroprom?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_5">
    <text>That's right. I've hidden the most valuable oven parts away in a secluded place. Packed in a wooden box. You'll have to find this place and bring me back the box of spare oven parts. There are different pieces inside like burner tubes and a pressure gauge.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, where do I look for it?</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Understand that I was travelling at night ... I crept along the edge of the swamp, through reeds, to the north, and put the box in a rusty hulk. I thought that soon I could return and retrieve it, but it's still there, at the Agroprom. It's necessary to search the marshes, exactly where it is, I don't know. You're my only hope, Strelok. My assistant is very drunk, I do not trust him.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_8">
    <text>You have an assistant? Living here..</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_9">
    <text>And what an assistant he is - drunk usually. His name is Vano. Sometimes he helps with the housework, but with serious business he can't be trusted. I found him somewhere, he was a little woozy at the time and wearing a Freedom suit. Said that he knows them and will go back soon. He staggered away about a week ago, but now has returned. He's out back, on the couch sobering up. Go, look at this 'miracle of nature', maybe you can reason with him with that strong man's witticism that you have. I'm sorry, but to be honest, this guy's a lost cause...</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Well Baker, agreed. I'll go to the Agroprom and find your box of spare parts. Now let's have a look at Vano.</text>
</string>  
  
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Baker, I found your box with the oven parts.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hey thanks, Strelok! Now I can repair the oven and start baking..</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well that's nice, here is your box.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Wait, let me thank you more. Here, take this flamethrower, it's fully charged. I made it myself out of available junk. It will give you an advantage against bloodsuckers and other evil things. When you use all the fuel mixture and you want to charge it again, or repair it - the mechanic at Freedom will help you.</text>
</string>
<string id="pekar_second_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you for the flamethrower. Well I must go, I have other matters to attend to.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Borov, the Mercenaries are wiped out.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Well Strelok, 'yo da man', that came to the rescue. Lives are saved.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, today I helped you - now it's your turn. That's the way in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait let me thank you. Here, take twenty thousand rubles, it is not excessive.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_help2_dialog_0">
    <text>Listen Borov, I have to proposal for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_1">
    <text>What is the proposal?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm here, in connection with the current situation with the Mercenaries at the southern checkpoint. Look closely at your defences and you will see they are not suitable. Another surprise attack, and you're all dead meat. The northern outpost is vulnerable.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_3">
    <text>I see it too. Well what do you suggest then?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_4">
    <text>I have some friends - free Stalkers. They previously worked as Military Engineers. Good professionals in various aspects of fortifications. We could arrange for a reasonable fee for them, so that they could rebuild and strengthen the checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_5">
    <text>And to think that's a good suggestion. The lads that are here, they can't fucking do it, they just guzzle vodka and curse eternally. What should I do?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I think first we must define the scope of work and make an estimate. Agree about the money and then get to work. I'll start talking with them, you need to clearly describe the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_7">
    <text>Well, send them to me, pronto.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_8">
    <text>No, not yet. Let me first outline to them the details of the situation, and come up with a proposal and budget. But for this I'll need a detailed map of the Bar and the surrounding area so that I don't have to explain everything to them with my fingers. You have such a map?</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_9">
    <text>Yes, I have this map. You can use it, but must return it.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_help2_dialog_10">
    <text>That's good, ok. Give me the map and I will go to the guys.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_0">
    <text>Borov, I'm looking for someone.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you looking for?</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_2">
    <text>They call him Antiques. They say he can get hold of rare ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_3">
    <text>There is a profiteer dealing in junk at exorbitant prices, procured from somewhere in the Military Warehouses. A rare arsenal from the last century, repaired guns, cleaned, and now provides them as antiques. He's there now. Look for him near the prison in a room that's to the right of the passage in and slightly beyond, where there's a walkway.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_antikvar_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks I'll find Antiques.</text>
</string>

<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Antiques?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes it's me. Do you need something?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, Noodles said that you have ammunition for a 'Ruger' revolver. Have any to sell?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>No, not selling, but I can exchange. I have one mag with six armour-piercing cartridges for 3 bottles of Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll trade you 3 bottles of Vodka for the ammo.</text>
</string>

<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Okay, take these three bottles of Vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Oh, there they are, give me those little darling bottles. And here, as agreed, a mag with six armour-piercing cartridges for the 'Ruger'.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Come on, you must have more cartridges?</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Yes, I still have armour-piercing bullets for the 'Ruger'. Bring another three bottles and the mag is yours.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Ok agreed.</text>
</string>

<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Antiques, I have Vodka to exchange.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_1">
    <text>That's good, give me three bottles of Vodka and take away one mag with the armour-piercing cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Sounds good to me. Here they are.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello. Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm called Pathfinder, and I have something to ask. In fact, Strelok, I've been waiting for you. But first let's have a drink, you don't mind? Simply, there's no one here you can talk heart to heart with, you do understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I understand, but only one glass, no more, I have little time to spare.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Shit, that's good stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Oh ... well ... gone, Now, tell what you need of me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_5">
    <text>... Yeah, good Vodka from the bar ... Well, Strelok, one very much respected person wishes to meet you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_6">
    <text>Who's that?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_7">
    <text>He asked not to be named for security reasons.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, so where is he waiting for me, this esteemed person?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_9">
    <text>There's a secret location in the Agroprom, deep in the subterranean catacombs. Only he knows the location. He said to me, "Tell Strelok to go immediately to the Agroprom. There near the northern base is an entrance to the catacombs, littered with debris. I will then open a passage when he gets close.".</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay now I'm intrigued. Okay I'll go find this stranger since I need him.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>And here you are waiting for me! Greetings Doctor! Why the secrecy?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hush hush Strelok, it's not so simple now. You probably already know or have heard that in the Zone that there is always danger lurking. Pripyat it is now full of restless Mercenaries. My heart feels that there will be tough times ahead.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>So you're moved from the Swamps now?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>No, don't be so dramatic, let's just say, I'm passing through, I came to the Agroprom to collect herbs. Before I head back to the Swamps I figured I would take a rest. It's quiet there and there's no one around, as you can tell.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>It's clear. But pathfinder, who is he?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Pathfinder - is my old friend and guide. I do not wish to disturb him. He has repeatedly rescued me from danger. It is good to have his guidance through the Zone. So visit him, have a talk, try to find a mutual interest.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Understood! I will visit Pathfinder at a convenient time. But why did you seek me? Is there an interest for me?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_7">
    <text>Listen Strelok you may need Feldsher, Ghost and Fang from Pripyat to move here in the near future, and possibly me. So that we have a secure place where we can be safe for a long time, you know? It may also prove useful to you too. We're now a team. I beg you to organize a cache here. Only a few of us would know about it. Nobody else would find this hiding place. Do it here just in case. Stock up on provisions and arms, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_8">
    <text>I hear you Doctor! I agree that this is a safe place. Not one creature here to worry about.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_9">
    <text>Well, that's fine. Use this place in any way that you consider necessary. This entrance is temporary, as it is unreliable, we will have to seal it permanently ... The teleport, which blocks this entrance to the catacombs below, is outdated, and will soon cease to function; so you, Strelok, must somehow secure this hiding-place from outsiders and monsters ...</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_10">
    <text>Okay, I'm going down into the dungeon. I'll block the entry beside the manhole as soon as the blocking teleporter stops working. So Doctor be careful when I'm not around. I will tell Feldsher, Ghost and Fang to be more attentive. The Agroprom top entrance to the cache will be blocked. But don't worry the new entrance will be at the lower level of the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_11">
    <text>Agreed, so be it. This teleport exit, you found at the manhole, from the cache to Agroprom, is still in use. When the lower teleporter blocking the entrance to the manhole is lost, then this one will be lost too.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_first_dialog_est_12">
    <text>All is clear. Well, I'll go to the rendezvous.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Pathfinder. I met with your incognito guy.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well that's fine we don't mention names out loud here.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Look, he told me that you are the best explorer in the Zone and that you know of many Secret Paths unknown to others. Is this true?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes it is. I know many Secret Paths. But all is not as easy as you think. If you are really interested in the opportunity to navigate the mysteries of the Zone, to move from one location to another where others cannot, I can assist you in this.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_4">
    <text>You ask me! Of course I am interested.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Well listen: the Secret Path in the Zone does not open often, and remains available for short periods of time, on average about a week. To find these paths we need a rare artifact called 'Explorer'. It is very rare and found only in places where it is quiet and uninhabited, and usually not far from the place where it originated, and will be near a path. On such tracks you can only go in one direction. You have to go back using another route, or search for a new artifact at the location at which you want to find a secret trail.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Interesting, not heard about that before. And what do you need to make sure this path is found?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Find the artifact 'Explorer', then bring it to me. I can determine the exact location where you can find this artifact and where the path will take you. Then I will enter a location label onto your PDA so that you can find the path. As payment for my services I will take this artifact..</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Sounds good, agreed. But what does this artifact look like?</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_9">
    <text>It cannot be confused with any other. 'Explorer' is of unearthly beauty. It has a Bordeaux red glow and rays. Most frequently 'Explorer' can be found around Rostok, around the Cordon, around the Agroprom and around the Military Warehouses. Anywhere else it is very rare.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I will find the artifact 'Explorer', and then immediately return it to you</text>
</string>

<string id="lektor_dialog_0">
    <text>What else is there?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah Strelok there is still one more complex issue.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_2">
    <text>Any complex matters - I can handle.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_3">
    <text>Well then listen carefully: I will soon advance to Pripyat, but will have to go through Yantar and then through the dungeons of Pripyat bypassing the Radar. The road on one side is quiet, desolate, and very few mutants; but on the other side there are anomalies of which many are impassable. And I need for my journey an artifact that is very, very rare, it is called a 'Liquidator'. When it's dropped on the ground it kills all known anomalies for a radius of 15 metres. You're the man I need. It would be very helpful if you could find such an artifact. Only one is necessary as it is reusable.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_4">
    <text>That is very interesting. Never heard of such an artifact. Where can I find one?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_5">
    <text>Here is the situation. There is a small group of stalkers, about ten guys, they call themselves 'Railroaders'. A very strange group of guys. The leader among them is a stalker known as Lecturer, (carries an M82), and the rest they say are like twins, and there are rumours that they are cannibals, and there is another guy in a weird suit. This group lives somewhere in the territory of the Rostok plant. They are the best hunters in the Zone for artifacts and mutants. The current thoughts about them are that they are reminiscent of zombies, but it is said they are slightly mutated, and that they adapted to the effects of radiation and psi, and that they can sense things like rare artifacts and mutants that are up to a mile away. They surely should be able to locate a 'Liquidator'. Find these Railroaders and have a talk with Lecturer. Make some kind of agreement with him so I can get the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_6">
    <text>All right. But how can I find these guys, can you tell me exactly?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_7">
    <text>As I've already told you they live somewhere outside of Rostok in the heart of the Wild Territories. To get to the Railroaders, use a Secret Path which starts at the Rostok plant. Only a few know about this path. Look for it near the concrete fence which is opposite the unfinished three-story building directly above the railroad cars, and between the metal huts. But remember this goes only in one direction. For the way back you'll have to figure it out yourself ... ask those guys. If you bring me the 'Liquidator' artifact, then I will be indebted to you and reward you like a king.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_8">
    <text>Understood, I'm on my way to Rostok.</text>
</string>

<string id="lektor_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Pathfinder, I've brought you the 'Liquidator' artifact. Oh, and those Railroaders, are so bizarre!</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well thank you Strelok you've bailed me out. I am indebted to you. Here take this pump-action Remington 870 shotgun, it's awesome.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Oh, I have long dreamed about this. Give it up! And now, keep your artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="lektor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Good afternoon. Are you Lecturer?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. What has brought you to these wild spaces Stalker? Decided to hunt for monsters?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>No, I came to see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, out with it, why have you come to see me?</text>
</string>

<string id="lektor_first_dialog_0">
    <text>They say you are the best hunter in the Zone for artifacts and mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_1">
    <text>We don't think about who is better or worse. We simply try to survive. But will take it as a compliment. Anyway, have you come to us?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_2">
    <text>A good man needs a rare artifact, a 'Liquidator'. But finding one, as they say, can only be done by an experienced stalker such as yourself. That's why I came to you for help. By the way, my name is Strelok. Will you help me?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_3">
    <text>You know Strelok had you come at another time, even though your flattering speeches are nice, I would have sent you to hell. But now we could use some help. You help us and we will help you. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Certainly, what kind of help do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, three days ago one of our brothers called Sledgehammer and two of his assistants went to Yantar to search for a drug called Antizombinom. As you can see we are not exactly healthy anymore. This is a consequence of a powerful emission we experienced a year ago. We need this drug to survive and not to become walking zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_6">
    <text>I understand, so what needs to be done?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_7">
    <text>As of yesterday morning, Sledgehammer and his guys have not returned. We have very little time left, we must urgently use these drugs, but we don't have any. Some of our guys are in critical condition. For example, we could not help Alex... It was necessary to shoot the poor wretch so that he would not suffer. Well, I have no one left to send out for these drugs, then you come along. Search for these missing guys, if they are dead, take the Antizombin drugs. We need 10 boxes. There is also a device, an Emission Detector, it determines the date and exact time of the next emission. The instrument is urgently needed. Sledgehammer carried it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Ok, where do I find them?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_9">
    <text>Well from Yantar they went to the Wild Territories, the last time they made contact, they were in a small forest just over the railway tracks. Search there, it's not far from here, just turn around head towards that huge tree and go left and over the three railway tracks. Search around all the trees and bushes. Find these guys or what is left of them and most importantly bring what I asked for.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_10">
    <text>Everything is clear. I'll go try to find the missing group and bring what you need.</text>
</string>

<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I have found the bodies in the woods, all three carriers. Apparently they ran into some mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Ah, another loss. Recently we lost six guys. Well, this is the Zone. Did you bring what I asked for?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I brought 10 Antizombin and the instrument. Is my artifact ready?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Here's the deal... the artifact which you want I do not have, but there is a man that knows exactly where to get one. He's the best searcher for rare artifacts and shooting mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>And who is this guy?</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>His name is Tutsan, my right-hand man. He is over there by the wall, have a talk with him.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Ok, take this stuff and I will go have a chat with Tutsan.</text>
</string>

<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Tutsan?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Sure am! Lecturer said that you are looking for me</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Nice suit! Well, I was told that you know where I can find the 'Liquidator' artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Listen, I'll tell you where to find a 'Liquidator', but please help us once more, I beg you. Recently a new species of mutant has appeared that is very similar to the wild boar but much more tenacious. Because of these creatures we have not been able to rest for a month. Two more of our brothers have been killed. We made arrangements to kill at least ten of these creatures but only found and killed two: A male and female ... but no offsprings. Now their offsprings have shown up and they are even more evil and dangerous. We cannot go after these because we need to tend to our wounded. But you, with your talents, I'm sure that you will be able to outwit and annihilate these mutants. And to cope with them on your trip I'll give you a type M-79 grenade launcher, dozens of charges for it and three F1 grenades.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Okay you persuaded me. Now to the details, where do I look for the 'Liquidator' artifact?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_5">
    <text>As I understand it you need the Anomalies 'Liquidator' to give to a client, right?  They are very valuable and a necessity, and I'm sure you would not mind getting one of these for yourself. Since you are helping us, listen here: 'Liquidators' are born in only one place in the Zone and that is here in Rostok. Look inside the boarded up house, though it's high in radiation, I don't think it will scare you. To get into the house try the hole in the roof, just be careful, there is also a hole to a deep pit. You will never get out of that pit. There are two artifacts there, and you can smell them, you cannot miss them.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_6">
    <text>No problem I will help you again. Where were these boars last seen?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Wild boars, you say ... you should have seen them, they were bigger than Chimeras. The last time we saw them was in Rostok near the tunnel on the way to the transition to Yantar. There were three of them. Kill the Super Wild Boars and get their hooves as proof. So go to Rostok. The shortest path is through a teleport. So go along the tracks, you know the ones you crossed over before, to the southwest and near where the rails end to the left in a gully you will see a teleport. It's quite a hike.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Ok give me the grenade launcher and I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>So treacherous were those creature. I could barely cope with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well you are a fine person! You freed us from danger, thank you very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Not at all, the grenade launcher was effective. I'm very pleased with it because it is light, doesn't take up much room, and yet it is quite powerful. Cool toy!</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Give me the hooves and keep the grenade launcher as a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thanks, here take the hooves.</text>
</string>

<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I still be useful?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, you can. We've recently found a Mercenary armed to the teeth. He fell behind his group and was apparently lost. He had a unique helmet which protects against the harmful effects of emissions and a special weapon. Well, we were going to send him to GITMO to be tortured, but then we changed our minds and decided to water-board him here instead. He told us everything. What sort of operations the Mercenaries were doing in the Zone, how arms and supplies were being transported. Well, one of their helicopters was shot down and now they are pursuing the offenders to get everything back.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_2">
    <text>So, I wonder what they had.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_3">
    <text>We elicited from him that there are three more protective helmets the same as his, and that they were hidden in Yantar, near the main entrance to Lab X-16. Around the area of the garages and excavator. These are the best helmets around, so we really need them. True, they must be adjusted individually, but we'll solve this problem with the help of the egg-heads.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_4">
    <text>By the way, where is this Mercenary now?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Where-where ... It's unimportant where. He's not here anymore ... In short, we want you go to Yantar and bring back those three protective helmets? Do this for us and I will give you the Mercenaries automatic Weapon - it's unique, you won't regret it. Well?</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, agreed.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_7">
    <text>And lastly to get to Yantar you must go through Rostok. First through the teleporter, which you used the last time, and then you will have to find your own way. There is a trail from Rostok to Yantar, but I don't know where. I'm sure experienced Stalkers at the Bar would know. Pathfinder or Earl, for example.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I understand everything, I'll leave now.</text>
</string>

<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Tutsan, I barely found these three protective helmets.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You're a fine person! Give them here and I will give you the Mercenaries gun, as promised. Completely cleaned, lubricated, and as good as new. Also, Lecturer wants to talk to you. Go see him.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_second_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Well that's nice, keep your helmets and I'll take the weapon. I am impatient to know what the Mercenaries are fighting about these days. I'll go speak with Lecturer now.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Pathfinder, I found the artifact 'Explorer' in Rostok.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_1">
    <text>Lucky you, let's see where your path lies and where it leads.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, take this artifact, but be careful, it is very hot.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, well ... yeah, that clarified the situation - the trail leads from Rostok to the Military Warehouses somewhere in the area of an abandoned base, near some rocks. And it starts at Rostok near the mesh fencing with some cars nearby. I will mark the location on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_rostok_dialog_4">
    <text>It get it, thank you. I will check this route later.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder, I found the artifact 'Explorer' in Military Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_1">
    <text>Well let's check the path.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, take the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_3">
    <text>So-so ... aha, all is clear. The path leads from the Military Warehouses to Yantar. At the Warehouses it begins at the abandoned base near a gate. I will mark the location on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_sklady_dialog_4">
    <text>I got it, thank you. I will check this route later.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder I found an artifact 'Explorer' in the Cordon.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_1">
    <text>Let's take a look at what secret path it will open for us.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, keep the artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, well ... yes, of course there is a path that leads from the Cordon to the Agroprom skipping the Garbage. In the Cordon it starts at the railway embankment where there is a tunnel with an 'Electra' anomaly. I will mark the location on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_kordon_dialog_4">
    <text>I got it, thank you. I will check this route later.</text>
</string>

<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder, I found the artifact 'Explorer' at the Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_1">
    <text>Lucky you, maybe you won a cookie. Strelok, let's see what trail this opens to embrace you.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_2">
    <text>Here, keep the artefact.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_3">
    <text>Well well ... interestingly the path of leads from the Agroprom to the Cordon, somewhere in the area of the tunnel. In the Agroprom it starts at the gate where there's a lot of radiation. I will mark the location on your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="sledopyt_tropa_agro_dialog_4">
    <text>It get it, thank you. I will check this route at a convenient time.</text>
</string>

<string id="potapov_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Regards, what do you need?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok I can propose to you, a mutually beneficial deal.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, you really know me. Well, fill me in.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I've been waiting for an experienced Stalker such as yourself, Strelok, for the very critical and secret mission. The Military at the checkpoint which leads to the Cordon, have assembled a manual for a light six-barrelled machine gun - the 'M134 Minigun'. Well, I do not understand the workings of this minigun. The manual was in seven parts, each in a separate folder. I say 'was' because a couple of months ago, some brave Stalkers lost their lives over the whereabouts of these manuals. They managed to steal six parts of the manual but one part still remains at the checkpoint, in a cache which they have not had time to go back to. The garrison there, remains on full alert.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Interesting topic. And then what happened?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Furthermore, these brave men, six of them, each took a part of the manual. The Military, throughout the Zone staged a raid to catch these six guys. They searched for a long time, but could not find them. But, nevertheless, none of the six survived. One, when he met with a small group of friends, was attacked by a pack of hungry pseudo-dogs somewhere in the Garbage. The second decided to take refuge in the catacombs of the  Agroprom and then disappeared. The third guy went to the Laboratory X-18 in the Dark Valley, and there he stayed. The fourth was lost somewhere in the woods at the Radar, he was on a mission and apparently before his death, said that he is hiding in some rocks. The fifth guy, their leader, an experienced Digger, went up to the Pripyat River. His trail is lost somewhere in the vicinity of the hotel. Sixth guy ... the longest being chased, was wounded, and went to Yantar, to mend his wounds. After his wounds healed he went to the scientists, in gratitude for the treatment and agreed to help them. But, as you can guess, from there he never returned, lost somewhere in the maze of the X-16 ...</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_6">
    <text>About this ... from where did you get all these details?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Before going to the checkpoint, most Stalkers come to me for guidance. We had agreed that when they brought the manuals to me that I would assemble the Minigun. Getting spare parts, for me it's not a problem. I was constantly in touch with them, so I know approximately where each of them had been. In short, you need to find the bodies of all six Stalkers and retrieve all six parts of the manual. It is also necessary to find the a hiding place of the seventh part, which is at the checkpoint at the Cordon. Bring all seven parts of the assembly manual to me. Maybe you will get the Minigun and ammunition. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes I will do it. I will find all seven manuals for the assembly of the minigun and immediately bring them back to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Everything Potapov! I found all seven parts of the manual for the minigun.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Hush, hush! Don't fuss about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Why, what's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Well, with all the eyes and ears around here we have to keep this secret. Some guys would slit your throat for these manuals.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Okay, understood. And now what?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Well, you give me all seven parts of the manual and I, as agreed, will gather all the Minigun parts and assembly the first one for you, understand? But I need some time ... come back at three in the morning, not earlier, and get the Minigun with a full complement of ammunition. Take note that I'll be waiting for you between exactly three and five in the morning, understand? You only have a two hour window, when all is quiet in the Bar. Don't bother coming at other times.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Ok! Agreed, here's the seven parts of the manual and at three in the morning I'll come directly to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, are you finished?</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_1">
    <text>Sssh! Yes, it's done. Here, take the Minigun and a container of ammunition for it. If you run out of ammo see me. I'll sell you the new, more precise ammo, eh? You can buy immediately if you want.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_dal_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, understood, give me the Minigun.</text>
</string>

<string id="semecky_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Wow! I do not believe my eyes, Semetsky himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes it's me. And as I understand, you are Strelok. Yeah, we meet in an interesting place and at an interesting time. I know why you're here.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm looking for my brother, and you are my last hope. How did you get here and what happened to you? You have long been considered a legend. One of the secrets of the Zone. I wonder where these persistent reports of your death come from. What do you know about the fate of 'Captain'?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_3">
    <text>I came here for the sake of the artifacts, damn him! I have been here since the beginning, at the time when there were maybe twenty or thirty of us all working here in the centre of the Zone. We wanted to get rich, selling expensive artifacts, we knew the mystery of the Sarcophagus and the Monolith, we had just escaped here from our worldly cares and concerns. And I ... I was young and wild ... I wanted to save the world. I'd been like that for some time now. 'Captain' drew me into a crazy scheme to go with him to the 'Sarcophagus'. I hate him for it! He was stubborn and fearless, but mostly crazy. He loved the area, now I know for sure, it became an obsession with him, he was in love with the Zone. And I ... I only wanted...</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_4">
    <text>So what went wrong, and is my brother still alive?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_5">
    <text>I wanted to find a way to destroy the Zone, but it was just too much to deal with. There were rumours that in the very heart of the Zone, in the Sarcophagus, there was a magic crystal, a Monolith which could fulfil your dearest wish. I naively thought that I could make a wish and put an end to the growing Zone. I believed in miracles, I was a fool. I thought that between the Zone and the Monolith that there was no connection and that this 'Artifact of Destiny' could help. We succeeded with Captain and our teammates to get inside the Sarcophagus and find this precious stone. Only Captain and I got near the 'Monolith'. I thought that we had a specific goal, but I was wrong ... I put forth my wish ... and Captain did too.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_6">
    <text>So what happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_7">
    <text>I was thrown like a blind kitten by the Monolith somewhere into the Red Forest area. After that, I found the Zone to be huge. What happened to our friends with whom we went with to the Sarcophagus, I do not know. And Captain ...</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_8">
    <text>What happened to him? What do you think?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_9">
    <text>He seemed to meld with the Zone's great strength, he was ready for this, even content in it. He knew exactly what the Monolith and Zone were about. He became 'one with the Zone', so to speak ....</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_10">
    <text>How's that? I do not understand ... so is my brother alive or dead?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_11">
    <text>It is hard to understand. He is not alive, but then again not dead. He is now part of the Zone, as he wanted. I don't know what he thought. 'He' became the most powerful artifact, with properties and strength that no one can dream of. In short, I cannot explain it to you, it must be seen to be believed.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_12">
    <text>Yes, but first I have to find him! Where can I find my brother, whereever, whatever or whoever he is now?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_13">
    <text>It won't be easy to get to him. You're going to the Control Bunker, right? You also seem to be interested in what is going on there, to get all the answers, including facts about your brother. Only I advise you not to go there. Forget about it, and while there is still time to get away from this place! It's unlikely that you can help your brother, all will have been in vain if you ruin your life as we have done, and turn into some original miraculous creation of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_14">
    <text>No, I have to go see this through to the end! I believe in luck, it has always been with me while I was here. I swore to myself that I would find my brother or just find out what happened to him. So until I have all the answers and evidence I will not deviate from my quest.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_15">
    <text>Well, as you wish. I can see that you're stubborn and crazy, just like your brother. I will give you some advice, in the bunker where you are going, you'll be in great danger, try not to lose self-control or the ability to reason. Your best weapon there is your own mind. As long as your will is strong, you will have a chance.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_16">
    <text>Okay, I'll understand. But tell me, what happened to you?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_17">
    <text>This damn Zone has played a cruel joke to me. It's turned me into what you see before you now. Instead of granting my wishes the Monolith blinded me, plunging me into eternal darkness, it gave me aggravated animal instincts and immortality. Hundreds of times after that I died and rose again from the dead, wandering in eternal darkness, not being able to change anything. My body has so many holes and scars that no living skin remains. I've been killed by mutants, caught a bullet many times and have been ripped apart by anomalies. I am no longer a man, I'm just another 'Miracle of the Zone', just like your brother, and the Zone does not let go of its 'favourite Zombies'.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_18">
    <text>But why did you return here, to the Monolith?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_19">
    <text>I must destroy it or let it destroy me, it doesn't matter either way. I've waited for this moment for a long time and you helped me get here, clearing the way to the Sarcophagus.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_20">
    <text>Wait, maybe you have some other way?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_21">
    <text>I have no other choice. You go, and good luck, but for me ... this is my war ... oh, and here, take this, it's a gift from me to you as a token of gratitude for helping me get to Sarcophagus quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_22">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_23">
    <text>This is the 'Wind Rose' a rare artifact possessing magical powers. No man has ever found one and never will because the 'Wind Rose' is only found in places a mutant can reach. If you manage to find your brother, or rather what he is today, this artifact will be able to help. It will briefly reduce the force of the 'shackles of the mind'. If Captain can still think and decides that he wants to get rid of his captivity, then maybe it will work. Now go, go on, I say!</text>
</string>
<string id="semecky_first_dialog_24">
    <text>Okay, I'm going to the Control Bunker. Thank you and good luck.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_final_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Solomon, long time no see!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Strelok, I have an urgent matter for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_3">
    <text>So much evil has spread recently, especially near the generators and in the eastern area of Chernobyl-2. Yesterday I went on reconnaissance mission to the eastern part and ran into a ton of mutants. I accidentally lost my PDA while defending myself. It is necessary to find it, it contains a lot of important information. It shouldn't be difficult, it lies somewhere on the asphalt path. Will you get it? I will give you an exoskeleton, machine gun and cartridges. You will need these to mow down a lot of mutants and enemies. Oh, and there is a transition next to the Sarcophagus, guarded by us, well, you remember. In short, do unto them as you want, Charon is gone, and now I'm on my own.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_4">
    <text>Well you're in good hands. Give me the gun and I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I brought by your PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Strelok, I never doubted you, you're awesome!</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I'm returning the machine gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Please keep it as a reward. Thank you for everything! Oh, you're also going into the control Bunker, right? If so be careful there is something serious going on with the egg-heads conducting new experiments, personally I don't trust them. I don't understand how they got in ... maybe they used the cleared Sarcophagus entrance. Well, good luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_final_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Thank you, and see you soon. Well, in any case, goodbye!</text>
</string>

<string id="gromov_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_1">
    <text>We have been waiting for you for a long time, Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_2">
    <text>How do you know me? Have we met before?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_3">
    <text>No, you and I have not had the honour to meet, but we all know about you! In a sense, we are gods ... well, almost. We can make people happy, and vice versa, it will depend on their behavioural instincts and the willingness of mind to accept the data pulses to it. But, it takes a long time to explain.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_4">
    <text>You're the ingenious ones ... But, if you're gods, why do you need me?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, you got the job from the Doctor to get into the Control Bunker and find out all the secrets and mysteries. Welcome, come in. We do not bite, we will show and tell all. We have no secrets for those who do come to us. Or maybe you decided not to know everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_6">
    <text>No, I won't change my mind. I always finish what I start!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_7">
    <text>Well then, to begin with I will show you the first truth. Are you ready to see what it actually is, rather than what we want you to see?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_first_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, as I said, I am prepared. I came here for answers!</text>
</string>

<string id="gromov_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Was that a joke?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well Strelok, do we look like clowns?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Since then, all this time, you created the illusion in the minds of all those who tried to learn the truth about your intentions?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I told you that we are almost gods, and neither you nor anyone else could have guessed.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_4">
    <text>And what is your purpose?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_5">
    <text>We have only one goal, this is our area and we are its masters, and people. These monkeys, figuratively speaking, have no place here. We will never get along with them. Therefore we will close access to humanity to the centre of the Zone and stop any attacks on our Shrine. Any who would dare to venture and disturb us will be destroyed.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_6">
    <text>But why have you not killed me? Indeed, I'm just a man!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_7">
    <text>But you still do not understand. Listen to yourself, you the same as we are, a creation of the Zone. Remember how you got into the Zone Strelok, what happened to you after the Chernobyl Big Bang. Where, when and most importantly how you got to where you were found. You simply decided not to think about this and you chase any thoughts about what happened to you. Did you ever wonder why the Zone let you live? The Zone created all of us. You're still one new form of life capable of surviving in the Zone. Suppose you have a human appearance but the essence of a mutant! In addition, you're here in the Bunker, no one else would have been able to get here, and you pushed and pushed and found your way, not only because you were sent here, but more because your here in the heart of the Zone, because it pulls you like a magnet. You see, hear and feel not as a human, but as a mutant. Your instincts are superb, you're dexterous, have great endurance and are as daring as a beast, your mind is as sharp as a razor blade. Simply put, you are afraid to acknowledge it. Fool! You struggle with yourself, trying to remain a man, you suppress the fact that the Zone gave you new abilities. Let go of yourself, let go of who you think you are, do not torture yourself and live in harmony with your new home - the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I do not believe you. I'm a man! A man in appearance, essence and thought!</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_9">
    <text>And you are also stubborn and stupid like your brother.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_10">
    <text>What? ... you know my brother</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Your brother is now no longer your brother, he is a part of us and the Zone. His inner strength and mind now serve us. Want to join us? We can easily arrange it. This might not make any sense, but believe me, in our reality everything will be as we want.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_12">
    <text>What are you talking about, I came here to save him.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_13">
    <text>Okay don't worry too much about it, soon you will understand everything. There's a release coming, an explosion, very powerful and dangerous for everyone. It will change the Zone and many things will be back in their rightful places. Then it will become clear who you really are. But for now we must take shelter and wait it out. We can help you. The way back from here is closed because we have blocked all the exits from the Sarcophagus and the Control Bunker. So decide: come with us to the shelter and we'll protect you from the approaching release and you will be saved, or would you rather go straight to your brother? But what might happen to your bifurcated mind when you meet with your 'brother' is a complete mystery even to us. Honestly we ourselves are afraid to approach him. And we are running out of time to save you. Well what have you decided?</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_14">
    <text>Apparently I have no other choice so I'll go with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="gromov_second_dialog_15">
    <text>Go to hell you deviates, along with the Zone! I will save my brother!</text>
</string>

<string id="lazarev_dialog_0">
    <text>Sakharov told me that a staff member of yours is missing and you need my help to get him back.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes Strelok, we need your help. What happened is this, we sent Lazarev, one of our laboratory assistants, to the swamp in the Agroprom. He was to conduct some tests with a new instrument which fixes levels and dynamics of an increase in the anomalous activities. Well he has not returned. The last time he made contact with him was when he arrived there and was in the swamp. We heard a noise and then silence.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_2">
    <text>Understood, so how I can help?</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_3">
    <text>It is necessary to learn what happened to Lazarev. Any information is important. Go to the Agroprom and find out what happened there. Then report back to us.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_4">
    <text>I got it, I'm on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Well I was at the Agroprom. In a trailer in the swamp I found your technician Lazarev's corpse. The creatures there were really strange. Similar to Snorks, but far more tenacious. As for his body, they really worked it over.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yeah, Yeah, Yeah ... the instrument, did you did find it?</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, here is it.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_3">
    <text>It's good that you brought us the instrument. Here's your reward for it, a very rare artifact, a 'Moonlight Dummy', all right? Oh, and ... please talk to Dan, we've got one more important matter that we cannot solve.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_dialog_est_4">
    <text>'Moonlight Dummy' is certainly satisfying, a rare artifact indeed. And now I'll go speak with Dan.</text>
</string>

<string id="vypolzen_dialog_0">
    <text>Can I help you?</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_1">
    <text>You can. Not far from here under the bridge is a swamp, there are creatures breeding there. They are very similar to Snorks, but the bastards are far more tenacious. At night they circle our base and attack in droves. We refer to them as 'Marsh Tsunamis'.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_2">
    <text>Do you want me to eliminate these mutants?</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_3">
    <text>Quick-witted aren't you, precisely! Annihilate all the creatures. Can you manage? We will remain in your debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_4">
    <text>Certainly! I'll manage, so prepare my reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Those 'Marsh Tsunamis' are gone, they won't trouble you guys anymore.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well done. Here, take your reward, a powerful 'Protecta' shotgun with a feed mag that holds 12 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Okay, hand it over.</text>
</string>

<string id="izlom_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything going on?</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, Strelok there is one other little matter, however it's dangerous.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_2">
    <text>Dangerous ... right up my alley, lay it out, tell me what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_3">
    <text>Here, near the base, in the bloodsucker's village, we've got a little family of Fractures. They're insidious creatures. They are forever trying to get into our base. It is necessary to cleanse this place of them. I'll pay. Will you take the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_4">
    <text>I'll do it. I hope the payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>

<string id="izlom_dialog_est_0">
    <text>All the Fractures are annihilated.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You take a lot of risks, Strelok, alone on missions ... It's unlikely any of my guys could have done it. Here, take your reward - an SVD-C Dragunov sniper rifle, with a short barrel and side-folding stock, a cool weapon! Oh, and some sniper ammo, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I'll take, thanks. I've got to go, I have matters to attend to.</text>
</string>

<string id="fokusnik_dialog_0">
    <text>What's up?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_1">
    <text>There was a Stalker here recently looking for you, his name was Magician. He said, "If Strelok appears, send him to me.".</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_2">
    <text>Magician you say. I don't know him. What did he want? Where can I find him?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_3">
    <text>What he wants from you he didn't say. He just said that he wanted to see you. He will be waiting for you in a trailer in Pripyat. He said go in the direction of the garages, in the south-western part, where the transition out of Pripyat is located. He is on the other side of the wall.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_4">
    <text>Clearly, okay, I'll try to find this Magician. Hum, I think I know who it might be.</text>
</string>

<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Oh Mervin? I thought it was you again.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Well hello student. I've been waiting a long time to retrieve a small debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_2">
    <text>What small debt?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_dialog_est_3">
    <text>And here it is!!</text>
</string>

<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_0">
    <text>Mervin, you once extended to me friendship from the heart, and now you take all my possessions. Why?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_1">
    <text>You should have been killed for betraying the Monolith brotherhood. I feel sorry for you. I like you, and I think that this Feldsher is a bastard and that he must be killed. Well if you agree I'll assume that we're even.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_2">
    <text>I suppose so, we'll be even huh. And then what?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Furthermore if you want your possessions returned then you'll have to do something for me. You don't want to walk through Pripyat in a sweater, sneakers and a knife do you? So since this is our second meeting I will once again give you a gun and two boxes of ammunition.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_4">
    <text>Enough bullshit, what do you expect me to do?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_5">
    <text>To kill Feldsher!</text>
</string>

<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Feldsher, hello, I must speak with you ...</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_1">
    <text>What's so important Strelok?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I'll be brief. Mervin lured me to him, then stunned me and took all my weapons and supplies, and has now sent me to kill you. He promised to return all my stuff if I did this, but do not be alarmed. Certainly I won't do it. I came to you for advice as to how to get rid of him and his curses, and to get my possessions back. But Mervin is a sorcerer and it's not possible to kill him using normal weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Thank you Strelok, for your loyalty. About the fact that Mervin cannot be killed, I'll say this: "there is no reward if there is no challenge". I just have something that will help you defeat the sorcerer. As the saying goes: "I am not a magician, I am only learning, but it helps if you can create miracles".</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_4">
    <text>And what kind of weapon is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_5">
    <text>This weapon, the 'Mosin-Nagant', will give you the advantage. I have modified it and developed a special cartridge that's a destructive force against any evil and devilry. This weapon is exactly what you need for this task. I see the hour is upon us. I'll give you this weapon and three cartridges, although I think that one cartridge will suffice. You go and kill Mervin, and free all us from one more danger. About your things, don't worry, Ghost knows where Mervin's hiding place is. I'll ask him to go there and get your stuff. Well, you go kill Mervin now, then go to Ghost about your belongings. What do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Feldsher, give me the 'Mosin-Nagant'. I will execute this mission with pleasure!</text>
</string>

<string id="vozvrat_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Ghost! Feldsher said that you found Mervin's hiding place. He took my stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I have it all. Feldsher told me what happened, so I went and picked up your stuff from Mervin's hiding place. I spotted that mystical nutcase hiding it.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_2">
    <text>That's good! Well, please return everything.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes of course, but there is just one more thing I need you to do, okay?</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_4">
    <text>What... again! I have already searched the entire area on your whims, and now you ramble about another job in order for me to get my things back. It shouldn't be necessary! What the hell do I need to do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_5">
    <text>C'mon don't get angry it is a simple task. Find the Pripyat Theatre. There's a box of the dynamite there which belongs to the Mercenaries. Find it and bring it to me. I couldn't find the box myself, but you're an eagle-eyed man so I'm sure you will find it. Then I'll give your stuff back. Oh here take this suit, two F-1 hand grenades, an AK and some ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_6">
    <text>Well I guess I have no choice, so I will do it.</text>
</string>

<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_0">
    <text>I found the box of dynamite.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Good, give it here and take your stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="vozvrat_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Here take the box of dynamite.</text>
</string>

<string id="disk_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey Dan, do you need any help?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_1">
    <text>I have a very important mission. Sakharov gave it to me. I cannot get away and I have no one else to send, I'm in a predicament. We must find three laser discs with information that is of great value to the scientists. These discs have about five years of information stored on them. I not sure, but Sakharov said that they might hold old archival records. He read many years ago, that after the second explosion occurred and the violent eruption of Chernobyl, that a team of Military scientists accompanied by a detachment of Special Forces, was sent into the Zone. They were tasked to study the strange phenomenon that began immediately after the emission. This group had spent about three months in the restricted area when something happened and all communications with them was lost. About a week later, two Special Forces soldiers from the detachment of guards came, or rather crawled, to the checkpoint. They were in a terrible state, saying things unintelligible and improbable. They were found to be insane and were sent to a mental hospital. We immediately organized a search and rescue operation but no one else was found.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_2">
    <text>Are you talking about the first expedition to study the Zone?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_3">
    <text> Yes, the first expedition. So listen up. The two soldiers who escaped to the checkpoint soon died in a hospital from excessively high doses of radiation that they sustained in little over a week. One doctor who watched over them in the hospital wrote down everything in his diary whenever they spoke about their adventures. This doctor was a friend of Sakharov, and when he learned that he was going to work in the Zone gave, him his diary. Amongst other things, there was information those first scientists were conducting surveillance on a strange metamorphosis that was occurring in animals. Judging by the entries in the diary, under the supervision of scientific experts, they kept a few animal specimens in their laboratories: dogs, pigs and rats, which they kept in cages and were constantly being taken for analyses. These animals changed before their eyes. They mutated at a frantic pace and turned into horrible creatures.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, that's interesting. But where are the disks with this information?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't interrupt! The data reveals that within a month, after they began monitoring the mutants, there was an emergency. Somehow, the creatures managed to escape and they smashed and damaged the majority of the laboratory research equipment, including computers on which all the archives of the studies were stored. Three guards and a scientist were bitten. Two of the dogs were shot, the rest fled into the woods near the camp. So, then it was decided to minimize the work and return immediately, as to delay and wait for help to arrive was too dangerous. All test results and observations that were made seemed to have been lost, but it turned out that one of the scientists, the day before the tragedy, recorded all data on three laser discs. Two Special Forces guys were assigned to take these discs, as soon as possible, and deliver them to the 'Mainland'. The remaining members of the group planned to gather the rest of the equipment, and leave the camp and move out a day after them. But as we now know, none of the others survived. And those two on the road were attacked by the mutants. Fleeing, they had to dump all their gear, including the backpack that contained their provisions and the laser disks.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_6">
    <text>These are the facts! Where do I find a rucksack with the three disks lost five years ago? And by the way, why is this five year old information so important now?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_7">
    <text>Those findings - they are priceless, as they should disclose the secret and the root cause of mutations of living organisms in the Zone, as performed at the earliest stages, immediately after the release in 2006. Finding the disks will be not easy, but possible. The backpack will be somewhat decayed and mutants hunting for food have probably got into it, but the disks are in special high-strength plastic cases. Animals don't eat plastic, so if someone from the Stalker community found them long ago, we would have known. The place where Special Forces lost the backpack, is described as similar to the territory which we now call the Garbage. As a reference, you should find it somewhere in the ravines of the Garbage heap. Well, will you try to find those three discs? I will be indebted to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, I will try to help.</text>
</string>

<string id="disk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Dan! Well, I found the bloody discs.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>That's great! All three?</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>Yes, all three. Oh, and I had to climb up a ravine in the Garbage to get them. Filthy place.</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>Needless to say, here, take this reward, a 'SKS rifle' and a couple of packs of cartridges for it..</text>
</string>
<string id="disk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>A good rifle I cannot refuse, thanks! Here are your three laser discs..</text>
</string>

<string id="klondayk_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings Lecturer. Tutsan said that you have a deal for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I have something interesting for you. You're a Stalker, surely you've heard that there is a place where you can find real 'Klondike' artifacts. But you probably not believe it, right?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_2">
    <text>Yeah, I've heard something like that. There was talk of such a place, but it's a little hard to believe.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_3">
    <text>Believe me, this place really exists, and it does have rare 'Klondike' artifacts. To find these is a must. I can tell you how to find this unique artifacts and maybe a secret. Do you wish to know?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_4">
    <text>I don't reject such offers. However, what do you want in return.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_5">
    <text>In return for this information, bring me a Heart of the Controller artifact. Get one, and I'll reveal to you a secret I know.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I will bring you a Heart of the Controller.</text>
</string>

<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Here, I've brought you a Heart of the Controller artefact. Now tell me the secret on how to find these unique artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_1">
    <text>You're smart boy! Well, listen here: the place, as you probably heard by hearsay, is in the Dark Valley, near the X-18 Laboratory complex. There is a depression over the hill, and here, you will find the 'Klondike'. Not everyone is destined to find the artifacts there, because you need to carry something with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_2">
    <text>And what is that?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_3">
    <text>It's necessary that you have an artifact called Snake Eyes. It's a catalyst for that place. Actually, that's how they all began. Specifically Snake Eyes was in a place where several anomalies and unprecedented transmutations were formed. To find this artifact is very difficult. I had one... But I gave it to one of the Lads called Walnut, in exchange for medicines he brought me. Well, I know where you can still find one such artifact, and then you can open the 'Magic Valley'.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_4">
    <text>Quickly, tell me more.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_5">
    <text>Don't be impatient! Well, listen here, you can find it in the forest at the Radar. It's next to a small gap in a barbed wire fence between two boulders. Find the Snake Eyes and then go to the Dark Valley. Seek low ground and collect treasured artifacts. Understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_dialog_est_6">
    <text>Yes everything is clear. Thanks for the valuable information. I will go look for the Snake Eyes in the forest at the Radar.</text>
</string>

<string id="amulet_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings! Sviblov said you can tell me about a curious little thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_1">
    <text>And good health to you, Stalker. What thing, show me?</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_2">
    <text>Here look, an amulet or something.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_3">
    <text>Very rare thing, I tell you, and very valuable. I even know what it is and what it's for.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_4">
    <text>Well spit it out, briefly.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_5">
    <text>So this: This is one of the six ancient magical amulets. I saw a similar one on an old digger had in Pripyat. He then told me the story of these amulets. In short, as I said, only six of these exist, the one that you have, it's an Amulet of the first order, and one that I saw on a Digger was the Amulet of the third order. The Digger was a cunning peasant, and with young Stalkers, he was hunting for all sorts of unusual and rare stuff and any riddles of the Zone. Now he is currently searching the entire Zone for these amulets. He showed me one amulet and figures there are more, based on an ancient book. If I find any he promised to pay well. How these ancient heathen amulets ended up in the Zone, he did not say ...</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, well, interesting, and why are these amulets so valuable?</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_7">
    <text>Each by itself has not much value, but all six together do. They can catalyse the process of the six amulets becoming an Amulet Charm, which doubles their combined protective properties and in addition adds something else, and yet absolutely not radioactive. The five ordinal amulets have different protective properties, while the sixth is just a catalyst that sets in motion the ancient magic. In short, if you collect all six ordinal amulets, you get a unique protection Amulet, hanging it on the belt the owner will get very high protection from damage of various kinds.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, this mystic nonsense is a little hard to believe.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_9">
    <text>Try to find all six and check, I see you're a little doubtful but interested. Especially since the Digger went up to Pripyat, they say, he has recently died under mysterious circumstances, exactly where, I don't know, but they indicate that the last time he was seen, was somewhere in the centre of Pripyat, so there are no more secret areas to scout. See if you can find out what happened to him. The amulet should be on him. People said that one of his team mates had found another amulet, but he too, poor fellow, vanished somewhere in Yantar, in the underground catacombs of the X-16 laboratory. Maybe he was running from a monster or something. Another owner of an amulet is rumoured to have been dishonest. He offered his services to search for rare artifacts. He took an advance payments from Stalkers, and often didn't do the work. He was then set up: ordered to bring something from the bloodsucker's village and was given a specifically damaged AK, with a weak barrel that split after five rounds. That's where he perished, he could not fight off the vampires, the weapon broke into pieces, and they say he was a brave man. So perhaps in the village at the Military Warehouses, and is yet another amulet. The place is uninhabited, so there is a chance finding it. Where to look for the other amulets, I don't know. In short, good luck, Strelok! But I will put the information of all six amulets on your PDA, just in case.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_dialog_10">
    <text>You intrigue me! Thanks for the valuable information. Now I will not rest until I gather all six Amulets.</text>
</string>

<string id="sled_dialog_0">
    <text>Pathfinder?! What are you doing here?</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_1">
    <text>Doctor sent me to protect you. I made my way to Chernobyl NPP from the north through Limansk, there is a Secret Path there.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_2">
    <text>Glad to see you, buddy! What now?</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_3">
    <text>Someone has blocked the entrance to the bunker with an explosion. Now there is no easy way to get in. But there is another option.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_4">
    <text>What, tell me.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, you know about my ability to open Secret Paths. Solomon gave me an Explorer artifact, he found it long ago in the Sarcophagus. The Explorer is quite old, but nevertheless it shows that the transition from the Sarcophagus to the Control Bunker is still running, but the way back is gone. I'll put a marker on your PDA. You've got to hurry up. Go back to the Sarcophagus Strelok, find the entrance to the Control Bunker. I can't go with you because the Secret Path can take only one, so I'll wait here. I hope you will be able to open the inside passage to the Control Bunker. Then together we'll see what's what. Oh, ah, don't forget to talk to Yuri Semetsky, he is in the Sarcophagus room.</text>
</string>
<string id="sled_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood! I'll go to the Sarcophagus and you'll wait here.</text>
</string>

</string_table>

