<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<!-- AMK Dialogs -->
<string_table>
	<!-- Dialogue with the Culinary Specialist -->
	<string id="artem_kulinar_0">
		<text>Welcome! I have a few things to offer, interested? </text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_1">
		  <text>Well lookie here, you have organized a snack Bar. To bad its so damn close to the freak'n radioactive heaps of dust.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_2">
		<text>For some people 'Garbage' is a hard place to reach and I congratulate you on that. It will most likely be forgotten quickly though.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_3">
		<text>Does it make any sense to you? Not far from here is a 'Bar' where stalkers buy and sell possessions. There we have bandits and all sorts of scumbags, and even checkpoints where the bandits will take your money.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_4">
		<text>Over at the Bar the guys are always serious and can easily get angry. So I warn you don't start any trouble there. Garbage is a place where the rookies find out if they can really handle the Zone. Fighting bandits, HA! This is not real combat. They need a few of us old guys to teach them a few things, and the ones that are not going to make it die within a week. They either step into an anomaly or become mutant snacks.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_5">
		<text>All right I heard enough about the rookies. Where are you from?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_6">
		<text>I was brought up in a forest and I traveled around Europe in the Army. When I got out of the Army I was working as a chef on the mainland. I didn't like the city life. Leftover food was given to cats and dogs while the homeless were walking around the streets hungry. I needed some adventure so I came to the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_7">
		<text>Who do I speak with around here concerning weapons, ammo and other supplies?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_8">
		<text>You want to talk to Vityok 'Raven'. He is a very mysterious guy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_9">
		<text>Tell me more about this mysterious guy.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_10">
		<text>Want to know what is really mysterious here in the Zone? Ravens! If they have one talent among them its that they know where death is most likely to happen and they will fly above waiting for fresh corpses. That is how Vityok got the nickname 'Raven'. He is attracted to the dead rookies in Garbage and profits from their possessions. He has some good weapons available for trade though. You will find him outside the hanger.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="artem_kulinar_11">
		<text>Thank you for telling me what you know of Raven.</text>
	</string>
	
	<!-- dialogue with Vitko the Raven -->
	<string id="vitek_voron_0">
		<text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_1">
		<text>Im looking for some better weapons and I also need some ammo.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_2">
		<text>I have a unique selection, but I only deal with skilled stalkers.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_3">
		<text>You only deal with skilled stalkers? What's that supposes to mean?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_4">
		<text>Only a few stalkers have the skill to acquire the goods that I will trade for.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_5">
		<text>I'm no rookie and if I have something you want, we will be doing business.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_6">
		<text>You certainly don't lack confidence. I hope our meeting is profitable for both of us.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="vitek_voron_7">
		<text>Let's drop the small talk and get down to business, what do you have to offer?</text>
	</string>
</string_table>