<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string id="agr_find_ghost_descr">
    <text>Learned that one of the Ghost's group member's name is Arrow. It is a clue anyway. If I find a Ghost, then I can find Arrow.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_journal_cache">
    <text>Well he gave me directions where to search for this hiding place. I found a microstick there which the group member Arrow used as a kind of logbook. Posts there were few, but it was enough to understand that in Arrow's group there where two others: Ghost and Fang. There was mention of another friend, but he was a member of some other group, and had provided substantial assistance to Arrow's group. Furthermore, according to Specter, Fang died when they were ambushed. So far we have the name of one person, Ghost, who knows Arrow. At last something concrete. According to some correspondence I need to look in the northern zone for Arrow.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_journal_krot">
    <text>Well the meeting was productive with Mole. Apparently the hiding place is found in the catacombs of Agricultural Industry down in the dungeons. What's waiting for me there who knows. Hopefully this will be the secret cache of Arrow.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_krot_secret_info">
    <text>Mole states: 'go down the spiral staircase to a room with columns, then to the exit, get into a big room with the pipes on the ceiling. From there down to the second exit, go through the tunnel and turn left. At the end of the hallway it will be on your right. There's a small room across from it, turn right. Looking at the left wall is a hole next to the inscription 'Do not climb, I'll kill you!'. This is the entrance to the Arrow's hiding place.'</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_secret_info_name">
    <text>Arrow's cache</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_military_case">
    <text>\n The report of the investigation group: \n Restricted. \n Project Manager, 'The Truth' \n Security Service Colonel Kruchelnikovu VM \n from the leader of Search Team 2, \n Captain Maksimenko DF \n\n Memorandum. \n Our team of 3 investigators, and special forces branch of the SBU, in the period from 12.05.2012 to 25.05.2012, conducted a survey of the radioactively contaminated soils around the former research institute of agriculture - Agroprom. Most of the equipment and documents have disappeared, but a few that were found, leads to the following conclusion: 'from 2005 to 2008 at the Institute no research was conducted'. All the results of his work, received by the Ministry of Agriculture, were fabricated. At the same time, getting program funding, equipment and supplies, the manager of research institute, Doctor Peter Strizh Danilovich sent in fake invoices relating to experiments at  laboratory X-18 conducted at the farm of the institute. Apparently using the code name taken from a group of people working on a similar case with similar details. Based on an analysis of documents found, we can assume that it was within an hour's drive from the Institute of Agroprom. Most likely it is a highly secret lab, so I propose it is connected to the research department. The information does not explain what this laboratory did.
In the found documents by the infamous Professor Chubko there is mention of another group.  It is my deep conviction that this time we found the end of the thread, and the analytical department will be on your hands. \n\n A suppliment in a zipped file refered to an unprofitable transfer of supplies and equipment that took place some time on a farm near the institute, and an excerpt from a correspondence from Strizh Chubko. \n\n From Captain Maksimenko DF 26.05.2012 to Professor Chubko VM. \n\n Chubko VM Head of Research Agroprom Doctor of Agricultural Sciences Strizh PD Hello, Vadim Mikhailovich, As we agreed, I refer to our experiments at the farm, the next batch of supplies and equipment is very much needed. Financing of the experiments I conducted as full-scale experiments on the interests of our institute is a priority; so that the ministry will not get upset. How are the experiments? I am still under this impression that you described to me the last time. Sincerely yours, PD Swift D. Yes. Mr. Swift PD Much appreciated, Petr Danilovich, all received. My guys are delighted with the laser spectrometer, if not for you, It would have taken much longer to develop this model. And the Ministry of Agriculture, of course, is grateful to get our results ... amuzing the old man. Experiments are on course and what you saw last time, does not compare to what we have achieved. Come often - always glad to see you. Traveling by car to our experimental farm should only take you about an hour. Oh, I forgot, I have news for you - next Monday I will discuss your candidacy with the Group. I think they will support me. Sincerely, Professor Chubko VM \n Head of Research Agroprom, Doctor of Agricultural Sciences, Strizh PD Vadim Mikhailovich, thank you for your trust. I am thankful and will try to justify it. Participating in such an experiment, I think every scientist dreams of, and if they accept me in the group, I'll be very happy.  \n\n  Sincerely yours, PD Swift \n\n P.S. I managed to get from the Ministry two of the newest Japanese broadband oscilloscopes and will transfer them to you at the first convenient opportunity.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_military_case_name">
    <text>The report of the investigation group.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nii_security_plan">
    <text>The diagram marking patrols, guard posts and towers. On the third floor of the Institute headquarters building are documents. In the daytime the whole area is patrolled. At night there are less patrols. After eleven at night there is a change that there will not be a guard. If you want to get into the base then don't go through the gate, the best way is through the catacombs.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nii_security_plan_name">
    <text>A diagram map of the Research Institute Agroprom.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_rats_n_soldiers_text">
    <text>Military bugged by rats that crawl out of the sewers. Delinquent military members are sent into the sewers.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_task_case">
    <text>Trader: 'As soon as the case from the Institute at Agroprom is found take it to the barkeep. He runs the affairs of the bar at '100 X-rays' in the former factory in Rostok'.</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos">
    <text>SOS, the military killed a brother stalker. Guys, all who hear me please help me!</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos_name">
    <text>Meeting with Mole.</text>
</string>

<string id="article_agr_krot_sos1">
    <text>Mole: 'Help, they will kill me!'</text>
</string>

<string id="st_operation_agroprom">
    <text>Operation 'Agroprom'.</text>
</string>

<string id="storyline_gunslinger_flash_info">
    <text>Obtained from Ghost: Shooter I have bad news ... Fang died. We waited in a village near the warehouses, and we waited a long time too. Fang then somehow thought that there where three common neutrals involved. You know the feeling from him that it was necessary. Two guys we had stopped, apparently just punks, but the third was smarter, he sat with Vintorez about 100 meters away. Now there is no more Fang. So the next time will go together. So what now ... these two were our description. I'll never know exactly who gave the order. Although in general, many people have a grudge against us. I missed the third guy. I got one. In my opinion, one of the mercenaries had a big scar on his face and big eyes. I will try to find him. Such are the cases. Be on the alert, good luck. Goodbye Ghost my buddy. I leave you. Let's stay in touch. Stay alert. Dude, I went to the North ... to where we were ... I'll try to get there alone. I'm sorry but there is no time to wait for you. I'll explain later. And the bastard who killed Fang, well we will get him.  We will meet again friend. You know how and where.:)  Good Luck Arrow, regards. You should not have to go to the center of the Zone. However it's a great place to do business. Look for Ghost.</text>
</string>
