<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="bar_ecolog_research_corrupted">
    <text>I, Professor Kruglov, delete our research reports. Dangerous knowledge should not fall into the hands of unreliable elements which could use them for criminal purposes. Anyone who reads this record, let them know that our group was attacked in Wild territory by mercenaries led by the well known thug Wolf. And know that, most likely, we are no longer alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_research_normal">
    <text>... As it turns out, the radiation primarily affects the higher regions of thought. Experiments have shown that only people and animals with a highly organized way of thinking such as dogs,  and horses, are sensitive to this radiation. Of these, only one is totally exposed to the effect of immersion in a trance. In experimentals with animal the effect remained in the range of intense fear. Based on these assumptions we can conclude that the impact on the human brain is severe. Extensive experiments on human volunteers showed that the effects of trance can be removed with medication. Also, we have developed experimental devices that protect the human brain from the effects of radiation doses. According to our calculations the radiation source is located in the heart of Lake Yantar and is likely the source of artificial nature. And it is possible to disable it. There is also a risk that unreliable elements can gain access to the radiation source and try to take it under their control.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents_name">
    <text>Military documents</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents_name">
    <text>Laboratory X-18</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents_name">
    <text>'Brain Scorcher', man made?</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents_name">
    <text>Barkeep</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_radar_task_name">
    <text>After talking with the crazy stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="rostok_tunel_gordon_diary">
    <text>01/12/2012 \n\n To hell with this boss. Do not give the old man any rest. First, the 'Black Mass' and then a strange city in Russia. \n\n Now here again: 'Go-ka are you, old man, in the endless step of Ukraine. Keep your crowbar and a good pastime.' \n\n 20/03/2012 snuck into the Zone. Are there bears here? And who will fight me then? Basically to learn the hard way. For canned meat had to give up the crowbar. \n\n 04/26/2012 Began emissions. The Barkeep told me to quickly hide his ass. Thrown out of an abandoned tunnel, a few rats. I hope to wait out this bad weather.</text>
</string>
