<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- DR 
do not run this file through any of the stalkerdialoghelper
programs because of multiple text lines within a string id.
-->
 
<string id="aes_Monolit_master_bio">
	<text>Sentinel of the faction 'Monolith'. It is best to stay away from him.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Monolit_rpg_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Monolit_sniper_bio">
	<text>Militant from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Monolit_sniper_gauss_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Monolit_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Specnaz from faction 'Monolith'. Well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_commander_bio">
	<text>Commander of the military assault.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_military_bio">
	<text>Military stalker. He is well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_sniper_bio">
	<text>Just a tipical sniper.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_aes_bio">
	<text>Army Spetsnaz. He is well equipped and tough.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_aes_name">
	<text>Vasil Luckless</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Army Spetsnaz. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_x_zombi_bio">
	<text>Army common soldier. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_krot_name">
	<text>Mole</text>
</string>
<string id="agr_krot_bio">
	<text>Former Digger who raids the desolate labs and bunkers that he and his associates come across.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_arena_stalker">
	<text>One of the participants of the deadly fights in the Arena.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_arny_name">
	<text>Arnie</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arny_bio">
    <text>Experienced smuggler.</text>
	<text>Earned his fame by smuggling several hundred stuffed mutants out of the restricted area within a short period of time.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_bar_guard_bio">
	<text>Bouncer at the Bar and Barkeep's bodyguard. His past is unknown.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_bar_guard2_name">
	<text>Zhorik</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_guard2_bio">
	<text>Zhorik is a loner, and a bouncer at the Rostok Bar. Garik is his twin brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_bar_guard_garik_name">
	<text>Garik</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_guard_garik_bio">
	<text>Garik is a loner, and a bouncer at the Rostok Bar. Zhorik is his twin brother.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_barmen_name">
	<text>Barkeep</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_barmen_bio">
    <text>Set up the Bar. Well respected amount the stalkers.</text>
	<text>Neither saint nor scoundrel. Barkeep knows his worth and is respected by all stalkers. Rumor has it that he is hiding in the Zone from some dark events in his past. After an encounter with the anomaly, he started limping slightly and decided to change jobs. He set up a bar by the Duty faction, and the place gradually turned into the meeting point for all the Zone's veterans. The Barkeep has numerous connections both in the Zone and in the outside world.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_drunk_name">
	<text>Alkie</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_drunk_bio">
    <text>Member of the Duty faction. More often off the wagon than on it.</text>
	<text>Duty gave him his last chance for redemption by carrying out a mission. However he was too drunk to get himself together and pull it off.</text>
</string>
 
<!-- DR guy in the bar that lost family gun -->
<string id="bar_hunter_bio">
    <text>Merry fellow and good-natured. Can't shoot worth a damn.</text>
	<text>His problem is that he can only shoot a hunting rifle. Other weapons are not worth trying. Recently he ran into unexpected monsters in Wild Territory and lost his family gun. Now he is at the bar in the hopes that someone will find his family gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_hunter_name">
    <text>Hunter</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_slouching_bio">
	<text>Leader of the 'Hunters'. Suffers from back problems.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_informer_bio">
	<text>A mysterious stalker who knows a lot and sells information.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_informer_name">
	<text>Snitch</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_ivancov_bio">
	<text>Commander of all punitive raids and expeditions against any horde of mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_kicenko_bio">
    <text>He and his Duty squad guard the southern entrance to the Bar.</text>
	<text>He can provide the coordinates of the Bar, the Arena, and Duty's main headquarters. He can also supply background information on Rostok.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_lelik_name">
	<text>Liolik</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_lelik_bio">
    <text>He is a guard at the Arena. His past is known only to be troubled.</text>
	<text>A very tough character. He hates his older brother for beating him when he was little.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_petrenko_name">
	<text>Colonel Petrenko</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_petrenko_bio">
    <text>One of the 'Duty' founders and their leading idea monger at the same time.</text>
	<text>Responsible for the faction's sacred code. He recruited basically all of Duty's key members.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_plichko_name">
	<text>Sergeant Plichko</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_plichko_bio">
    <text>Sergeant Plichko is a member of 'Duty and' is chief of security.</text>
	<text>He and his Duty squad guard the entrance to the Duty base.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_ryaboy_name">
	<text>Pocky</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ryaboy_bio">
    <text>Unknown to most stalkers. His brain fell under the influence of the 'Scorcher'.</text>
	<text>He now says that in his prevous life he was a three-legged rat.
    Nicknamed Pocky because he has marks on his face due to having the Chicken Pox.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_voronin_name">
	<text>General Voronin</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_voronin_bio">
    <text>Gen. Voronin is the leader of the 'Duty' faction, replacing Gen. Krylov who was killed.</text>
	<text>General Voronin is a veteran Dutyer and one of the faction's original founders
    who came into power after his predecessor General Krylov who was killed during 
    the faction wars. He recruited most of the faction's key members and is 
    responsible for upholding the sacred code of the faction.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_bandit_drunk_bio">
	<text>A tipical drunkard.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_bandit_general_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. Reputation leaves a lot to be desired.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_bandit_veteran_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. Unsavory reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_bandits_leader_bio">
	<text>One of the bandit gang leaders. He is well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_name">
	<text>Swamp Doctor</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_doctor_bio">
    <text>One of Strelok's past companions and one of the oldest stalkers in the Zone.</text>
	<text>The Doctor is said to be one of the original stalkers to enter the Zone. It is also said that he reached the center of the Zone and even made it to the 'Wish Granter'. He lives in the Swamps. It is likely that only Strelok's group personally knew him. When Doctor does travel he is often accompanied by the Pseudodog he tamed, and he named it Mongrel.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_pekar_bio">
	<text>A trader that loves to cook. Usually has jobs to offer.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_killer_exo_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary that is well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>

<string id="usb_unknown_stalker_bio">
	<text>Unknown stalker with dubious reputation.</text>
</string>

<string id="usb_unknown_stalker_jokes_bio">
	<text>Unknown stalker with a dubious reputation. But tells great jokes.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_killer_general_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Perhaps well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_killers_leader_bio">
	<text>A leader of a Mercenaries gang. Well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker. A goog map reader.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="dar_corpse_bio">
	<text>Went to Heaven. No information available.</text>
</string>

<string id="dar_explorer_name">
	<text>Zheka Doublet</text>
</string>
<string id="dar_explorer_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker. Keeps your eyes open for him. A real nomad.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="ds_sergant_regular_bio">
	<text>Sergeant in the Ukrainian Armed Forces and in active service.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="ds_soldier_regular_bio">
	<text>Private contractor Armed Forces of the Ukraine.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_bandit_novice_bio">
	<text>An unknown bandit stalker. The dubious reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_captain_bio">
	<text>Rank Captain, with a long service in the Armed Forces of the Ukraine.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_fanat_name">
	<text>Fanatic</text>
</string> 
<string id="esc_fanat_bio">
    <text>An intense man full of purpose. Secondary leader of the rookies.</text>
	<text>His aggressive behavior has earned him well deserved authority over the rookies. After Wolf left Cordon for the heart of the Zone Fanatic took over leadership of the Rookie village.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_fox_bio">
	<text>Fox is an older experienced loner toughened by the Zone, and is the brother of Seriy who is also a stalker.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_killer_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Perhaps well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_petruha_name">
	<text>Petruha</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_petruha_bio">
	<text>A smart rookie that likes to explore. Wolf likes him and often sends him on important missions.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_provodnik_bio">
    <text>He is credited with being the very first stalker.</text>
	<text>Some folks say it is nearly impossible to find him while others even deny his existence. He is alleged to know every location of the Zone and can slip past the most dangerous of anomalies, and sneak past the largest groups of enemies and mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_provodnik_name">
	<text>Guide</text>
</string>


<string id="esc_sledopyt_pathfinder_name">
	<text>Pathfinder</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_sledopyt_pathfinder_bio">
    <text>An old friend of the Swamp Doctor. He is the best guide in the Zone.</text>
	<text>Knows many secret trails. Sometimes he hangs out at the Bar.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_sergant_regular_bio">
	<text>Sergeant member Ukrainian Armed Forces in active service.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_shustryi_name">
	<text>Nimble</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_shustryi_bio">
    <text>A very resourceful and lucky person. He is a survivor and always seems to live to fight another day.</text>
	<text>Thus far he has survived the destruction of the Clear Sky faction, being captured by bandits, and still managed to estabilish a profitable gun running business. Part of that is thanks to his two talents: staying unseen and remaining useful. Nimble is well connected to the underground market thanks to his time spent with Sidorovich. He has also worked for other traders estabilishing a reputation as an indispensable agent who can be trusted with truly sensitive missions.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_soldier_commander_name">
	<text>Major Kuznetsov</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_soldier_commander_bio">
    <text>A corrupt and pompous soldier. Leader of a squad of Ukrainian soldiers.</text>
	<text>Kuznetsov is stationed at the embankment below the bridge in Cordon with a squad of Ukrainian soldiers to prevent stalkers from passing through. However he routinely accepts bribes, such as vodka, from stalkers in exchange for letting them pass through the checkpoint unmolested.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_soldier_regular_bio">
	<text>Regular private in the Ukrainian Army.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_potapov_name">
	<text>Mechanic Potapov</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_potapov_bio">
	<text>Mechanic working out of the Bar. Offers some provisions.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_lazarev_name">
	<text>Lazarev</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_lazarev_bio">
	<text>Laboratory assistant technician from the mobile science lab in Yantar.</text>
</string>

<!-- DR guy near the entrance to the arena -->
<string id="esc_graf_name">
	<text>Earl</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_graf_bio">
	<text>Trader that works out of the Bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_antikvar_name">
	<text>Antiques</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_antikvar_bio">
	<text>A neutral trader. Is usually somewhere in the vicinity of the Bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_semecky_name">
	<text>Yuri Semetsky</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_semecky_bio">
	<text>A ledgendary stalker that seems know a lot about other stalkers. Sometimes he has rare artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_mervin_name">
	<text>Mervin</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_mervin_bio">
	<text>Vile thief and warlock. A real SOB. Recruiter for the 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Army Special Forces. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_specnaz_killer_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_stalker_novice_bio">
	<text>Recent beginner in the Zone.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_tolik_name">
	<text>Tolik</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tolik_bio">
	<text>A rookie loner that was found wounded near the Rookie village. Was in Nimble's group.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_wolf_name">
	<text>Wolf</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_bio">
    <text>Wolf takes care of newbie stalkers at the rookie village in Cordon.</text>
	<text>He plans to get out of the Zone one day. But still there, and as he puts it, the rookies need him. He has several right-hand men, including Zhorik. Wolf has a brother named Wolfhound.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="escape_trader_name">
	<text>Sidorovich</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_trader_bio">
    <text>Hunted and traded from an early age. In kindergarten he was selling pencils and paper.</text>
	<text>In school he sold chewing gum. At the Institute he sold drugs. With the advent of the Zone he realized that this can be good money. Famous for the fact that he is able to establish good trade relations with the most disperate clients.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_bandit_leader_name">
	<text>Vasya Boar</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_bandit_leader_bio">
	<text>Enjoys a certain prestige among the bandits in the Zone. He is Borov's accomplice.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_dolg_blokpost_leader_bio">
	<text>An officer in faction 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_dram_novice_bio">
	<text>A rookie loner usually searching for artifacts in Garbage.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_newbie_bio">
	<text>Rookie. Recently in the zone.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_seriy_bio">
    <text>Seriy is an experienced Stalker and is affiliated with the Loners.</text>
	<text>Although it is unclear how highly ranked he really is, he seems to hold some position of relative rank among the Loners in Garbage.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_stalker_regular_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Militant from faction 'Duty'. Generally well equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_cherep_name">
	<text>Colonel Skull</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_cherep_bio">
	<text>Commander of special forces in 'Duty'. Generally well equipped. Has disobeyed Voronin's orders.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Dolg_specnaz_silence_bio">
	<text>Fighter from faction 'Duty'. Generally well equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Killer_informator_name">
	<text>Ara</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Killer_informator_bio">
    <text>Known throughout the Zone as a stool pigeon and SOB.</text>
	<text>He is an expert mercenary, buying information about 'Freedom' faction's movements from a snitch named Pavlik.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_killer_master_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Well armed and very dangerous. But not to smart.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_killer_sniper_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Apparently in the Zone recently.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Killer_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Perhaps well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Monolit_master_bio">
	<text>A Sentinel of the faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Monolit_regular_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Stalker_master_bio">
    <text>A veteran of the Zone. Knows the area like the back of his hand. Well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Stalker_veteran_bio">
	<text>Stalker veteran. Perhaps well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_blockpost_leader_name">
	<text>Cap</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_blockpost_leader_bio">
    <text>He is the commander of a group of 'Freedom' members at the 'Barrier'.</text>
	<text>Located northeast of the Army Depots, an area often referred to as the 'Barrier' or 'Border'.</text>
</string>

<string id="sar2_svoboda_bodyguard_name">
	<text>Kapets</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_bodyguard3_name">
	<text>Angle</text>
</string>
<string id="svoboda_bodyguard1_zombi_name">
	<text>Kapets</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_bodyguard_bio">
	<text>The security guard of 'Lukash' who the leader of the faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Svoboda_cook_name">
	<text>Chef</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_cook_bio">
    <text>A boozer and a brawler, but an excellent cook. Makes a mean pancake.</text>
	<text>The guard in front of Freedom's base mentions that if he weren't such a great cook they'd throw him out.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_engineer_bio">
    <text>A talented mechanic, he is, allegedly, able to make a tank out of a farm tractor.</text>
	<text>Regardless of the veracity of the claim, he is a very talented fellow, in charge of repairing various vehicles used by Freedom. His workshop is located on the military base's helipad.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_leader_bio">
	<text>A competent and charismatic man that leads the anarchistic faction 'Freedom' in Army Depots.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_bio">
	<text>Commander of the 'Freedom' faction.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Max_name">
	<text>Max</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Max_bio">
	<text>Has achieved a level of notoriety in the Zone as he is referred to as a guardian of Freedom.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Ugrumiy_name">
	<text>Surly</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Ugrumiy_bio">
	<text>Guardian of the faction 'Freedom'. Very loyal. Well equipped and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_regular_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_sniper_bio">
	<text>Sniper faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Fighter from faction 'Freedom'. Generally well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_stukach_bio">
    <text>Pavlik was a member of the faction 'Freedom'. Now known a a traitor.</text>
	<text>And now considered a traitor because he is selling information to Mercenaries.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Svoboda_trader_name">
	<text>Skinflint</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_trader_bio">
	<text>The 'Freedom' trader known for his greed and intransigence. However they say he can get anything.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_swamp_trader_name">
	<text>Miser</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_swamp_trader_bio">
	<text>The trader in the swamp, over the bridge, and a member of the 'Wanderers'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="antreg_skit_trader_name">
	<text>Mozart</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_skit_trader_bio">
	<text>Quartermaster of the 'Wanderers'. Loves music.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_Svoboda_zombi_stalker_name">
	<text>Crazy stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_Svoboda_zombi_stalker_bio">
	<text>A crazy stalker from faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_zoneguard_bio">
	<text>Militant from faction 'Freedom'. Typically well-equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="pri_followers_bomber_bio">
	<text>A veteran of the Zone. Knows the area like the back of his hands. Generally well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_followers_common_bio">
	<text>Stalker veteran. Perhaps well-equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_monolith_common_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_monolith_exo_bio">
	<text>Elite Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_monolith_leader_bio">
	<text>A leader of the faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_monolith_regular_bio">
	<text>Private Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_monolith_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Stalker faction 'Monolith'. Was a member of Spetsnaz.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_zombied_soldier_bio">
	<text>Ordinary soldier.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_zombied_soldier_name">
	<text>Zombified soldier</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_zombied_stalker_bio">
	<text>One of the stalkers who ran out of luck.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="pri_zombied_stalker_name">
	<text>Zombified soldier</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_dolg_master_bio">
	<text>Commander of the 'Duty' faction. Very well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_ecolog_bio">
	<text>Apprentice scientist.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_ecolog_guard_bio">
	<text>Scientists' security.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_monolith_general_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_monolith_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Fighter from faction 'Monolith'. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Army Special Forces. Well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_stalker_master_bio">
	<text>One of the veterans of the Zone. Knows the area quite well. Very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_stalker_veteran_bio">
	<text>Stalker veteran. Perhaps well-equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_svoboda_master_bio">
	<text>Commander of the faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="rad_zombied_general_bio">
	<text>One of the stalkers who were unlucky.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="ros_ecolog_guard_bio">
	<text>A researcher from the mobile science lab.</text>
</string>

<string id="ros_freeman_name">
	<text>Gordon Freeman</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_freeman_bio">
    <text>Freeman was a theoretical physicist and an expert on anomalous phenomena.</text>
	<text>He worked in North America on top secret projects in a former secret laboratory known as "Black Mesa" before going missing. He arrived in the Zone sometime around 12/31/2012. During his trips he remarked that he had to sell his crowbar for a can of meat. He also grumbles about the Zone's lack of action. As an experienced fighter and scientist Gordon Freeman is very much a capable fighter despite his scientistic background. He enjoys killing mutants. However he wants his crowbar back to he can beat the damn mutants with it.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="dar_stalker_explorer_bio">
	<text>Experienced stalker. Keeps your eyes open for him, he's usually wandering around somewhere.</text>
</string>

<string id="ros_happy_name">
	<text>Lucky</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_happy_bio">
    <text>Untrustworthy, looter and murderer. Usually in over his head.</text>
	<text>Once had a good relationship with Duty to help them fight off anything in the current territory. Now he lives in Wild Territory with his gang robbing lone stalkers.</text>
</string>

<string id="ros_kruglov_name">
	<text>Professor Kruglov</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_kruglov_bio">
    <text>Has a Ph.D. in biology, the professor's main area of interest are new species of mutants.</text>
	<text>He finds and studies them, their behaviour and physiology. His study results are sent to researchers outside the Zone. However some are shared with the Barkeep exclusively. He is very enthusiastic about the Zone, and considers it the greatest chance of increasing humanity's scientific knowledge and revolutionizing technology.</text>
</string>

<string id="ros_tiran_name">
	<text>Tyran</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_tiran_bio">
	<text>A hero of the mercenaries. Has been riddled with bullets over time. A crazy sadistic bastard.</text>
</string>

<string id="ros_volkodav_name">
	<text>Wolfhound</text>
</string>
<string id="ros_volkodav_bio">
    <text>A field commander of a 'Mercenaries' group called 'Dogs'. He is Wolf's brother.</text>
	<text>The Commander of some rebels who call themselves 'Dogs'. An anarchist who despises any laws except the laws of force. He is Wolf's brother.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar_monolith_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar_monolith_cristall_bio">
	<text>Monolith stalker Special Forces group called 'Crystal'. Responsible for 'Monolith' safety.</text>
</string>
  
<string id="sar2_bio">
	<text>Psychomaterial form created by the 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_crazy_svoboda_name">
	<text>Crazy stalker</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_dolg_guard_commander_name">
	<text>Security Chief</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_dolg_skull_name">
	<text>Colonel Skull</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_dolg_zastava_commander_name">
	<text>Commander of the Outpost</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_explorer_name">
	<text>Zheka Doublet</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_fanat_name">
	<text>Fanantic</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sar2_gordon_name">
	<text>Gordon</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_bandit_general_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. With dubious reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_bandit_master_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. Has a dubious reputation.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_bandit_master_fraer_name">
	<text>Friar</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_bandit_master_fraer_bio">
    <text>Came to the Zone looking for adventure. Imitates characters from popular comics of the 60's.</text>
	<text>Uses different names: Badman, Macho, the Black Coat, Banderos. Even though he has survived in the Zone for two whole years, no one really takes him seriously and it constantly drives him mad.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_bandit_master_kocherga_name">
	<text>Poker</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_bandit_master_kocherga_bio">
    <text>Fierce, angry, rude, selfish, cruel, unfeeling, and cold. A really evil bandit.</text>
	<text>Poker is probably the most evil bandit to ever roam the Zone. While other crooks might have redeeming qualities, Poker has none. He is a complete psychopath totally indifferent towards the plight of others and their suffering. Everyone fears him and he has absolutely no friends. His condition possibly stems from the fact that he caught a rare disease while on one of his forays deep into the Zone. It has caused total memory loss, both long term and short term. Poker can forget that the person he just met is friendly and kill him thinking that he's an enemy.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_bandit_novice_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. Unsavory reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_bandit_veteran_bio">
	<text>An unknown stalker. Bad reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_dolg_master_bio">
	<text>Guard from the faction 'Duty'. If you're not their friend, then you better avoid them.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_dolg_regular_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_dolg_sniper_bio">
	<text>Militant from faction 'Duty'. Typically well-equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_barin_name">
	<text>Barin</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_barin_bio">
    <text>A ham, bootlicker, hypocrite and coward. Extremely ambitious and touchy.</text>
	<text>Barin’s motto could well be, "After us, the Deluge". Takes advantage of any situation. He came to the Zone, unsurprisingy, for money. For two years now he's been procuring material assets by all possible means.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_bio">
	<text>Militant from faction 'Duty'. Typically well-equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_prapor_name">
	<text>Prapor</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_dolg_veteran_prapor_bio">
    <text>He was once an official recruiter for the Ukrainian Security Service.</text>
	<text>A frequent visitor of the Bar. Everyone knows who he is, as well as the fact that he is the man to turn to when you fall on hard times. However, once you cross a line with him there is no way back into the ranks of the honest stalkers.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_fresh_Zombied_bio">
	<text>One of the stalkers with not much luck.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_killer_general_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Perhaps well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_killer_master_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Is well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_killer_sniper_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Most likely well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_killer_veteran_bio">
	<text>Unknown mercenary. Should be well-armed.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_monolith_master_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_monolith_regular_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_monolith_sniper_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_monolith_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_soldier_commander_bio">
	<text>Detailed information is not available.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_Soldier_master_bio">
	<text>Military stalker. He is well armed and very dangerous.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_soldier_regular_bio">
	<text>Private soldier.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_soldier_sniper_bio">
	<text>Detailed information is available.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_soldier_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Army Special Forces. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_general_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="new_Varangian_name">
	<text>Varangian</text>
</string>
<string id="new_Varangian_bio">
	<text>Another bookie who likes to play dangerous games with stalker's lives.</text>
</string>

<string id="new_claw_name">
	<text>Claw</text>
</string>
<string id="new_claw_bio">
	<text>Borov's personal courier.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_bookmaker_name">
	<text>Bookmaker</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_bookmaker_bio">
	<text>Member of the faction 'Duty'. If you're not his friend, then you better avoid him.</text>
</string>

<!-- DR guy in Chernobyl-1 at the railroad tracks, was Lector -->
<string id="esc_lektor_name">
	<text>Clerk</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_lektor_bio">
    <text>Former bandit. Now a member of the 'Monolith'.</text>
	<text>After helping with clashes against the 'Monolith' he was recruited by Solomon and now faithfully serves the 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>

<!-- DR guy in Rostok with the Railwaymen in Crysis suit -->
<string id="esc_zveroboy_zombi_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker from the faction 'Railwaymen'. Buys, sells and repairs items.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_zveroboy_zombi_name">
	<text>Tutsan</text>
</string>

<!-- DR guy in Rostok with the Railwaymen -->
<string id="esc_lecturer_bio">
	<text>Experienced stalker from the faction 'Railwaymen'. Buys, sells and repairs items. Uses an M-82.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_lecturer_name">
	<text>Lecturer</text>
</string>

 
<string id="sim_stalker_general_upir_bio">
    <text>Stalker born under a lucky star. But his luck doesn't help anyone else.</text>
	<text>Many times the teams he was with would end up in tight spots and every time he was the only survivor. Most stalkers stay away from him on account of the bad luck he is said to bring. Has been roaming the Zone on his own for quite some time now.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_master_bio">
	<text>A veteran of the Zone. Knows his way around quite well. Very dangerous.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_master_chuchelo_name">
	<text>Scarecrow</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_master_chuchelo_bio">
    <text>Experienced smuggler. For a long time he traded in Africa and South America.</text>
	<text>The news of the Chernobyl disaster brought him to the Ukraine.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_master_diador_bio">
    <text>Diodorus is a preacher and is a veteran of the war in Afghanistan.</text>
	<text>After surviving a 'Mujahideen' ambush he converted from Atheism to Christianity, and following the end of his tour of duty he emigrated to Poland and joined a seminary. After graduation he served as a priest in a Catholic church in Lviv. Following the Chernobyl disaster he volunteered to help the victims of the catastrophe. When the Zone emerged he came to it to continue his career as a preacher.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_master_master_name">
	<text>Master</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_master_master_bio">
    <text>Formerly a mechanic at the 'KholodMach' plant. A simple stern man, and a bit rough at times.</text>
	<text>After his wife left him he wanted to take his own life. However being deeply religious he chose the Zone as an unconventional suicide method. Contrary to his expectations he survives. He has gained invaluable experience and has won the respect of other stalkers thanks to his professional skills. Master is probably the most qualified mechanic in the Zone, and repairs equipment and vehicles. Installing security systems in bunkers is what he does best. He is welcome everywhere he goes.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_master_polkan_name">
	<text>Polkan</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_master_polkan_bio">
    <text>Former a military stalker, a lieutenant colonel from mainland troops.</text>
	<text>After one of the operations in the depths of the Zone he was one of a detachment, but they found evidence that they are simply all framed and sent to slaughter. Then decided not to come back, rigged his own death and went to stalkers to deal with problem areas illegally. Silent, cynical, single-minded.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_novice_bio">
	<text>Rookie. Came recently to the zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_novice_neumeha_name">
	<text>Clumsy</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_novice_neumeha_bio">
    <text>He is 20 years old. He lost everything and everyone in the 'Mainland' before coming to the Zone.</text>
	<text>He barely makes a living in the Zone, and he simply has no other place to go. Owes money to many stalkers. Frequents the Zone, but never goes there alone. Always trying to hang on to a group of experienced stalkers. Not a popular companion as more often than not he's plain useless. Hardly makes any money. Mostly lives on handouts from other stalkers and is deep in debt.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_sniper_bio">
	<text>Stalker veteran. Perhaps well-equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_bio">
	<text>Stalker very experienced. Perhaps well-equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_umnik_name">
	<text>Smartass</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_umnik_bio">
    <text>A student from a Physics Department, retired with a fifth degree in the Zone of earnings.</text>
	<text>Amateur show off about scientific knowledge and abstract philosophical topics. During travels he irritates his stalker buddies. But overall a good guy. Still believes in high ideals.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_vorobey_name">
	<text>Sparrow</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_vorobey_bio">
    <text>Sparrow is 27 years old. Seriously far-sighted. At times he can be quite vile.</text>
	<text>In general he leaves an ambiguous impression about yourself. He is thin and pale. He came to the Zone came out of curiosity, and made a promise to himself to leave after two months. But has decided to stay. In his first outing in the Zone he had managed to travel without using any devices while not knowing about all the anomolies. One anomoly almost killed him. Since then he notes that day (October 9) as his second birthday.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_Svoboda_master_bio">
	<text>Master from the faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_Svoboda_regular_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_Svoboda_sniper_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Fighter from faction 'Freedom'. Typically well-equipped.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_leshii_name">
	<text>Leshiy</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_Svoboda_specnaz_leshii_bio">
	<text>Leshiy came to the Zone as a young idealist. His career began as a member of a Mercenary squad.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_svoboda_specnaz_prut_name">
	<text>Twig</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_svoboda_specnaz_prut_bio">
    <text>As a member of Freedom, he is one of the guards at the Freedom base in the Army Depots.</text>
	<text>Twig usually carries a sniper rifle. A really thin guy.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_zombied_master_bio">
	<text>One of the unlucky stalkers.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_zombied_novice_bio">
	<text>Another one bites the dust.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_zombied_veteran_bio">
	<text>One of the stalkers who ran out of luck.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_bandit_bodyguard_bio">
	<text>Bandit guard. Has a dubious reputation.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_bandit_general_bio">
	<text>Private bandit. Don't trust this guy.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_bandit_novice_bio">
	<text>Bandit rookie. Untrustworthy.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_bandit_veteran_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_borov_name">
	<text>Borov</text>
</string>
<string id="val_borov_bio">
    <text>Started out as a barman for the Bandits, he later took Yoga's position as head bandit in the Zone.</text>
	<text>Fellow bandits call Borov an 'aristocrat wannabe' and Borov himself says that he was a natural born leader, saying that even when he was a kid he knew he was destined to be a leader. aka: Hog and Piggy.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_dolg_common_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_monolith_common_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Monolith'.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_prisoner_name">
	<text>Shaggy Sergei</text>
</string>
<string id="val_prisoner_bio">
	<text>Shaggy (aka: Serega) was a member of the 'Duty' faction.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_pulia_bio">
	<text>Stalker from faction 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_soldier_regular_bio">
	<text>Ordinary soldier.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_soldier_specnaz_bio">
	<text>Army Special Forces. He is well equipped.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_stalker_general_bio">
	<text>A very experienced stalker.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_stalker_novice_bio">
	<text>Rookie. Recently in the zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_leila_name">
	<text>Leila</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_leila_bio">
    <text>An experienced stalker. Leader of the 'Wanderers' in Dead City. Karina's twin sister.</text>
	<text>She is really good looking. Has a twin sister named Karina.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_karina_name">
	<text>Karina</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_karina_bio">
	<text>A very experienced stalker. She is a nurse. Is really good looking. Leila's twin sister.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_forester_name">
	<text>Forester</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_forester_bio">
	<text>Very experienced stalker. An ol' timer. Rough looking old hermit living in the Forest.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_zahar_name">
	<text>Zahar</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_zahar_bio">
	<text>Experienced stalker. Old hunter engaged in exchanging artifacts for drugs and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="new_fang_name">
	<text>Fang</text>
</string>
<string id="new_fang_bio">
    <text>Has a slight stutter and talks to himself making other stalkers a bit nervous.</text>
	<text>But overall he was considered to be a level-headed guy. Additionally he was a technical genius.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_sobolev_name">
	<text>Captain Sobolev</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_sobolev_bio">
	<text>Fighter from faction 'Duty'. Generally well equipped. Likes to explore.</text>
</string>

<string id="tankist_tanker_name">
	<text>Tanker</text>
</string>
<string id="tankist_tanker_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker. Leader of a small group of stalkers that usually hang out in Garbage.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_prince_name">
	<text>Prince</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_prince_bio">
	<text>The ringleader of a bandit gang at the Bar. Has a tendency to loose things.</text>
</string>

<string id="garbage_knyaz_name">
	<text>Duke</text>
</string>
<string id="garbage_knyaz_bio">
	<text>Experienced bandit with bad scruples. Claims to be of royal blood. Hangs around the Bar. Smokes 'grass'.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_judah_name">
	<text>Judah</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_judah_bio">
	<text>Experienced stalker with a bad reputation. A member of the 'Monolith' faction. A serious gambler.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="dimos_brown_bio">
	<text>A squad commander for the 'Peacekeepers' faction.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="dimos_smith_bio">
	<text>Commander of the 'Peacekeepers' faction. Loves to drink brandy.</text>
</string>

<string id="dimos_foster_bio">
	<text>Army Special Forces experience.</text>
</string>

<string id="dimos_captain_bio">
	<text>Another experienced stalker. Mean looking guy. Do not piss him off. He will eat your head.</text>
</string>


<string id="dimos_grieg_name">
	<text>Grieg</text>
</string>
<string id="dimos_grieg_bio">
	<text>Another very experienced stalker. Knows a little about transitions.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="antreg_sorcerer_name">
	<text>Sorcerer</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_sorcerer_bio">
	<text>Another very experienced stalker. Supposedly can bring stalkers back from the dead. Weird guy.</text>
</string>

<string id="antreg_mahomet_name">
	<text>Mahomet</text>
</string>
<string id="antreg_mahomet_bio">
	<text>Another very experienced stalker. He is looking for his brother Arrow. Has a weight problem.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="yan_ghost_name">
	<text>Ghost</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_ghost_bio">
    <text>Having mastered the art of sneaking around, Ghost lives up to his nickname.</text>
	<text>He's friendly and loyal to his friends and co-workers. A friend to Strelok. Some stalkers call him 'Phantom'.</text>
</string>

<string id="yan_saharov_name">
	<text>Professor Sakharov</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_saharov_bio">
    <text>He is a professor of genetics, leader of some ecologists, and dabbles in many scientific fields.</text>
	<text>Professor Sakharov has been studying the Zone ever since the first research laboratories were set up on its perimeter in 2007. His politeness and professionalism, along with a tendency to offer stalkers lucrative contracts for artifacts and mutant body parts, make him a very popular employer. He leads a small group of ecologists in Yantar along with his Assistant Professors Kruglov and Semenov.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="yan_semenov_bio">
	<text>Semenov is another scientist in the Yantar bunker and the assistant of Professor Sakharov.</text>
</string>

<string id="yan_vasilyev_name">
	<text>Vasiliev</text>
</string>
<string id="yan_vasilyev_bio">
    <text>He was working as a scientist alongside Sakharov in the Yantar bunker.</text>
	<text>Specializes in field research. His last operation was related to the nearby Lab X-16.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="zombie_name">
	<text>Zombie</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_ecolog_zob_name">
	<text>Scalpel</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_ecolog_zob_bio">
    <text>In everyday life a phlegmatic who keeps his emotions to himself and always stays cool.</text>
	<text>However, when under stress, he gets peppery and aggressive. Highly intellectual. A materialist regretting he had come to the Zone in the first place. After graduating from the medical university he was sent into the Zone where the scientist's needed a neurosurgeon assistant. Dissects mutant brains and researches their psychokinetic properties. Looking forward to his retirement when he can move back to the capital, as far as possible from this rotten place.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_general_upir_name">
	<text>Vampire</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_general_upir_bio">
    <text>Incredibly lucky stalker. For some time now walks alone.</text>
	<text>Many times his team happened to be on the verge of death, and always he was the only one who managed to escape. Considered by stalkers to be an unlucky mascot.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_master_chuchelo_bio">
    <text>The smuggler with experience. For a long time hunted in Africa and South America.</text>
	<text>Stories of Chernobyl mutants led him to the Ukraine. In a short span of time managed to take out of the Zone several hundred mutants, and has been dubbed the 'Scarecrow'. In between jobs in the Zone he is a successful trader. He loves Armani suits and Versace ties, but prefers the uniforms of the Soviets.</text>
</string>

<string id="sim_stalker_master_diador_name">
	<text>Father Diodorus</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_master_diador_bio">
    <text>Formerly from Afghanistan. During one of the ambushes in Mujahideen he found religion.</text>
	<text>After Afghan he immigrated to Poland where he entered the seminary. After graduating from the seminary, for some time, he preached in the Catholic Church in Lviv. After the explosion at the Chernobyl nuclear power plant he became a volunteer to help the injured. The last few years he has been preaching in the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="new_bes_name">
	<text>Bes</text>
</string>
<string id="new_bes_bio">
    <text>Bes hides in the Zone from the law. He had killed his friend's attackers.</text>
	<text>Bes hides in the Zone from the law. Before entering the Zone he was wanted for two counts of murder and inflicting grievous bodily harm, after attacking a group of people who beat up his friend severely.</text>
</string>

<string id="gar_hellcar_name">
	<text>Demon</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_hellcar_bio">
    <text>Demon came into the Zone to hide from law enforcement agencies.</text>
	<text>Alone trying to maintain order in the Zone, as he himself represents it. A fighter with outrage. Tough, but fair. A member of the Wanderers and usually hangs out in Dead City.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_gusarov_name">
	<text>Oleg 'Fiend' Gusarov</text>
</string>
<string id="sim_stalker_veteran_gusarov_bio">
    <text>A former 'Spetsnaz Black Beret'. He is a lone wolf.</text>
	<text>He served in the Russian Special Purpose Police Unit of the Bielocerkowskoj Brigade. Rank, Master Sergeant. His specialty is sniping and demolition.</text>
</string>

<string id="dimos_bio">
	<text>Very experienced. Has been in the Zone for a couple of years.</text>
</string>

<string id="dimos_granny_name">
	<text>Granny</text>
</string>
<string id="dimos_granny_bio">
	<text>Ulgy old witch bitch hooker skank.</text>
</string>

<string id="stalker_general_default_bio">
	<text>Experienced stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nii_commander_zombi_bio">
	<text>Experienced squad commander.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_soldier_sniper_default1_zombi_bio">
	<text>Very reliable sniper.</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_name">
	<text>Captain Ivantsov</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_dolg_ivancov_bio">
	<text>Head of counter insurgency operations and clearing operations for large clusters of mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="generic_no_info_bio">
	<text>No information is available.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_bandit_general_default_bio">
	<text>Ordinary bandit with a dubious reputation.</text>
</string>

<string id="val_bandit_general_default2_bio">
	<text>Experienced bandit with a dubious reputation.</text>
</string>

<!-- DR guy against wall in room with Sviblov in Radar -->
<string id="esc_strannik_name">
	<text>Nomad</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_strannik_bio">
	<text>Experienced 'Clear Sky' stalker. Hangs out in Radar. Knows about medallions and their properties.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_kuvalda_name">
	<text>Sledgehammer</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kuvalda_bio">
	<text>He is one of the best artifact hunters in the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="skit_kent_name">
	<text>Kent</text>
</string>
 
<string id="oso_mono_name">
	<text>Deliberate</text>
</string>
 
<string id="vano_new_name">
	<text>Vano</text>
</string>
 
<string id="maroder_boss_name">
	<text>Razuvaev</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_boss_bio">
	<text>Leader of many marauders. The most wanted dead-or-alive stalker in the Zone.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="maroder_gena_name">
	<text>Gene</text>
</string>
 
<string id="maroder_yang_name">
	<text>Minor</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_yang_bio">
	<text>Leader of a few young marauders. They are more talk than action.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_tsezar_name">
	<text>Caesar</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_gromov_name">
	<text>Professor Gromov</text>
</string>
 
<string id="contra_var_name">
	<text>Nemesis</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_pekar_name">
	<text>Baker</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_saha_name">
	<text>Sahat</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_koha_name">
	<text>Koch</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_cherv_name">
	<text>Grub</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_dan_nebo_name">
	<text>Dan</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="esc_krest_bratok_name">
	<text>Cross</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="esc_shilo_band_name">
	<text>Awl</text>
</string>  
 
<string id="garbage_stalker_wound_name">
	<text>Jeka</text>
</string>  
 
<string id="garbage_levsha_name">
	<text>Lefty</text>
</string> 

<string id="monolit_right_hand_name">
	<text>Righty</text>
</string> 

<string id="clear_scy_leader_name">
	<text>Sviblov</text>
</string>
<string id="clear_scy_leader_bio">
	<text>Leader of the Clear Sky squad in Radar.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_killer_def_kalym_name">
	<text>Dowry</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_nebo_chromov_name">
	<text>Khromov</text>
</string>

<string id="bar_neznakomec_name">
	<text>Grin</text>
</string>

<string id="dark_komandir_belchuk_name">
	<text>Belchuk</text>
</string>
<string id="dark_komandir_belchuk_bio">
	<text>Military squad commander.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_new_wound_name">
	<text>Vova</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_bratok_prisoner_name">
	<text>Jack</text>
</string>
 
<string id="yan_wound_ucen_name">
	<text>Associate Professor Dorodina</text>
</string> 

<string id="stalker_xutor_name">
	<text>Cat</text>
</string>

<string id="prip_old_digger_name">
	<text>Feldsher</text>
</string>
<string id="prip_old_digger_bio">
	<text>Medical assistant. Friend of the Doctor. Usually has lots of supplies. Hangs out in Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="agr_und_zombi_name">
	<text>Crazy Professor</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_commander_krevoshaev_name">
	<text>Major Yarofeev</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_commander_krevoshaev_bio">
	<text>Major Yarofeev is the troop commander in Cordon at the blockpost on the way to Peacekeeping.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_name">
	<text>Chameleon</text>
</string>

<string id="shram_name">
	<text>Scar</text>
</string>

<string id="val_nebo_ambush1_name">
	<text>Perun</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_name">
	<text>Noodles</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_komendant_name">
	<text>Commandant</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_name">
	<text>Monk</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_name">
	<text>Charon</text>
</string>

<string id="pri_followers_bomber_name">
	<text>Sasha Bely</text>
</string>

<string id="trade_mono_name">
	<text>Mahon</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_name">
	<text>Solomon</text>
</string>

<string id="spy_aes_name">
	<text>Earring</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_lucash_name">
	<text>Lukash</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_stukach_name">
	<text>Pavlik</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_engineer_name">
	<text>Screw</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_Svoboda_master_Ugrumiy_name">
	<text>Murk</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mil_komandir_sidorchuk_name">
	<text>Sidorchuk</text>
</string>
 
<string id="fedya_razboinik_name">
	<text>Fyodor Robber</text>
</string>

<string id="val_gila_name">
	<text>Vein</text>
</string>
 
<string id="dark_plen_name">
	<text>Brick</text>
</string>
 
<string id="amk_artem_kulinar_name">
	<text>Artem Culinar</text>
</string>
 
<string id="amk_vitek_voron_name">
	<text>Vitek Raven</text>
</string>
 
<string id="val_escort_nap1_name">
	<text>Bullet</text>
</string> 
 
<string id="dar_corpse_kalugin1_name">
	<text>Piotr Ilyitch Kalugin P.I.</text>
</string> 
<string id="dar_corpse_kalugin1_bio">
    <text>Head of the X-18 laboratory and a member of a group called 'The Group'.</text>
	<text>As the head of the X-18 laboratory, Kalugin was fully aware of what was going on in the most secret areas of the facility and was a member of 'The Group'. He was responsible for granting access to the more secret parts of the facility to lower ranking researchers. For one reason or another, Kalugin, along with the entire staff of X-18, was killed when the mutant specimens contained inside X-18 escaped and killed everyone.</text>
</string> 

<string id="cit_killer_leader_name">
	<text>Dushman</text>
</string> 

<string id="cit_bandit_leader_name">
	<text>Borziy</text>
</string> 

<string id="cit_vp_name">
	<text>Vasily Petrovich</text>
</string>

<string id="brown_name">
	<text>Colonel Brown</text>
</string>

<string id="smith_name">
	<text>General Smith</text>
</string>

<string id="nato_shlem_name">
	<text>Corporal Foster</text>
</string>

<string id="sutuly_name">
	<text>Slouch</text>
</string>
 
<string id="mazay_name">
	<text>Mazai</text>
</string>
 
<string id="grek_name">
	<text>Greek</text>
</string>
 
<string id="drug_name">
	<text>Fima</text>
</string>
 
<string id="nevidimka_name">
	<text>Crystal Mind</text>
</string>
 
<string id="kapitan_name">
	<text>Captain</text>
</string>
 
<string id="esc_fox_name">
	<text>Fox</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_zastava_commander_1_name">
	<text>Sergeant Kitsenko</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_bar_lisiy_name">
	<text>Baldy</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_bar_lisiy_bio">
	<text>Baldy is an experienced loner stalker. Do not tease him about having no hair.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="bar_arena_savage_name">
	<text>Beast</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_seryi_bio">
    <text>Seriy is an experienced Stalker, and is affiliated with the Loner faction.</text>
    <text>Although it is unclear how highly ranked he really is, he seems to hold some position of relative rank among the Loners in Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_seryi_name">
    <text>Seriy</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_dram_novice_name">
    <text>Yurik</text>
</string>
 
<string id="gar_stalker_flame_quest_name">
	<text>Lech Tambov</text>
</string>
<string id="gar_stalker_flame_quest_bio">
	<text>An experienced stalker.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="svoboda_bodyguard2_name">
    <text>Manovar</text>
</string>
 
<string id="aes_Soldier_specnaz_aes_zombi_name">
    <text>Vasil Luckless</text>
</string>
 
<string id="stalker_osoznanie_bio">
    <text>Representative of the project 'C-Consciousness'.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_osoznanie_name">
    <text>Osoznanie</text>
</string>
 
<string id="monolit_leader_zombi_name">
    <text>Putin</text>
</string>
 
<string id="monolit_leader_zombi_name">
    <text>Putin</text>
</string>
 
<string id="svoboda_zoneguard_name">
    <text>Stalin</text>
</string>
 
<string id="actor_name">
    <text>Strelok</text>
</string>
<string id="actor_bio">
    <text>'The Marked One' - Strelok in Russian literally translates to 'Shooter' or 'Gunslinger'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="stalker_esc_bariga_name">
    <text>Huckster</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_esc_bariga_bio">
    <text>A real tricky dicky con artist.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="soldier_commander1_zombi_name">
    <text>Commander</text>
</string>
<string id="soldier_commander1_zombi_bio">
    <text>Spent 10 years with Specnaz.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="soldier_regular_default1_name">
    <text>Ranker</text>
</string>
<string id="soldier_regular_default1_bio">
    <text>Common soldier.</text>
</string>
