<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- DR missing file -->
<string_table>
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_0">
	<text>I need answers to some questions.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1">
	<text>Ask away, I'll try to answer.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_11">
	<text>Where is my stuff?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_111">
	<text>All the confiscated stuff usually goes to the leader. His room is on the upper floor. Your stuff is most likely there.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1111">
	<text>Thank you!</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_12">
	<text>How does one get out of here?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_121">
	<text>While I fought, I noticed a manhole under the stairs on the first floor. If the camera failed to open lattice, then this move would be to hit the road from here. A is better to go to the West, where the tunnel you can get to freedom.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1211">
	<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14">
	<text>Who did we capture?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141">
	<text>We got a mercenary. Who he is is not known to anyone around here, but there are rumors that he is cooperating with foreign intelligence services. The location of his base is the big secret... no one knows how to get into a Dead City. This is a secret many people are interested in, and especially 'Freedom' and 'Duty'.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1411">
	<text>Go on!</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_14111">
	<text>If we could get a map to Dead City, then we could attack them. They are either mercenaries or a bandits. You could try to find them.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_141111">
	<text>Thanks for the information.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_15">
	<text>What do you know about this place?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_151">
	<text>The city is divided into two parts. Form where we are the territory of mercenaries is south of the territory of the bandits. Their base is in the school building in the southwest part of town. Between the bases there is the ruins of a five-story building. Next to that a five-story building, relatively in good shape. So you could stay there. It's around the garage and a couple of small homestead cabins. About half  the bandits, a couple of dozen or so, are in a five-story building with garages. On the other side of the square is the building of the former City Council.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1511">
	<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_16">
	<text>Who leads them?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_161">
	<text>A most pleasant guy named Dushmanov. I noticed a couple of times he held a folder with documents. I think they could be quite interesting.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_1611">
	<text>Thanks for the info.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_escape_dialog_17">
	<text>Nope, nothing.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_11">
	<text>Strelok! Where have you been?! You were not with the guys in the latest attacks! I really started to worry.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_hello_dialog_21">
	<text>Well I think my head is back to normal?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_0">
	<text>Strelok?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_1">
	<text>Well, you're Strelok, but who is it? Doctor. I, you do not know me? Hey, buddy, what's wrong with you, you're not yourself. We are with you in the Zone 2 years go. Do not you remember?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_11">
	<text>I do not remember.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_2">
	<text>Do not you remember? Strelok what are you doing? You're not kidding, an old friend, no? Hmm ... and guys, our guys do you remember? Fanatic, Ghost?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_21">
	<text>Fang can not remember, but Ghost is dead, his body I found in Yantar.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_3">
	<text>Ghost!? Dead?! Damn, how could this happen? Yes, they are also ... but they also have some of the best. Damn, what's wrong with you there then?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_31">
	<text>I do not know what happened, I do not remember.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_4">
	<text>Wait, let me at least a come after the news. I have only one thought - it all has to do with your last outing to the Zone center. When we met last time you left me the key from the cache on the Pripyat and the scheme, how to find it. I was able to save them, mercenaries have found. That hold, just hide well. Perhaps there is something you find. And you always said that with the Monolith a catch. But I understand you and he did not understand what I mean.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_41">
	<text>Chance of Rain. And where are we? I do not remember how I got here.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_5">
	<text>We are in Dead City! In the camp of mercenaries.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_doctor_main_dialog_6">
	<text>We are in Dead City! ... In the camp of mercenaries ...</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_0">
	<text>By the way, I have information about the mercenaries. Are you interested?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1">
	<text>It depends on what kind of information.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_11">
	<text>There is a map showing the location of the base. As well as finding the place and a lot of other useful information.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_111">
	<text>I agree that this information is of value, amounting to three thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1111">
	<text>Good enough. Here you go.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_11111">
	<text>Excellent. And here is your reward. Stalkers soon will long argue whether there was a group of mercenaries as a legend or is it the next Zone.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1112">
	<text>No, it's too little.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_11121">
	<text>Well as you like, but more I still cannot give.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_12">
	<text>There are documents about the mercenaries. I took them from the sniper.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_121">
	<text>This information is valuable in the amount of 3,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1211">
	<text>It's a deal. Here!</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_12111">
	<text>Excellent, and here is your reward.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1212">
	<text>No, it's too little.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_12121">
	<text>Well, as you like, but I cannot give more.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_13">
	<text>No, sorry, they are nothing worthwhile. Just common gossip.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_131">
	<text>If you have something specific, I'll pay.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_14">
	<text>There PDA leader of mercenaries.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_141">
	<text>PDA is of value, amounting to 2,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1411">
	<text>It's a deal. Here.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_14111">
	<text>Excellent. And here is your reward.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_1412">
	<text>No, it's not enough.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="quest_cit_reward_14121">
	<text>So be it, but I can't give any more.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_hunter_killer_start_dialog_0">
	<text>Hello, stalker! For you I have bad news. This is our territory and you will go with us.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_hunter_killer_start_dialog_1">
	<text>Well, all right. Lead away.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_hunter_killer_start_dialog_2">
	<text>You are still not mature enough nor tough enough to threaten me.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_start_dialog_11">
	<text>Ah it's you, Shooter! Cool. Long time since I have seen you.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_start_dialog_21">
	<text>Hey!</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_start_dialog_22">
	<text>What this time?</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_pda_dialog_0">
	<text>Take this, it seems to be your PDA.</text>
</string>
 
<string id="cit_vp_pda_dialog_1">
	<text>Yes, thanks. Hand it over.</text>
</string>
 
</string_table>
