<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="gar_seryi_info">
    <text>Mole and his companions unearthed an Arrow cache in Agricultural Industry close to an abandoned factory. Why don't you go and find out what's going on there. After all, he invited us to join the search.</text>
</string>
<string id="memuars">
    <text>Personal Notes</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_beginning">
    <text>Who am I?</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_beginning_text">
    <text>Damn it, it's all a haze now... I do remember a car. They drove me somewhere for a long time and my whole body hurt. It was darkness. What happened before that I've no idea. I am so confused. Now this fat guy calls me the 'Strelok', probably because of the strange tattoo on my arm, and there's this weird mission to kill some guy called Strelok on my PDA. Is it even my PDA? Looking at Strelok's photo I'm not even sure if I knew him. Damm! It's all like a bad dream that you can't wake up from! What to do? Where to go? And worst of all, who the hell am I? Ok Ok, calm down, control yourself. The first thing I'll have to do is do some tasks for this Sidorovich guy. He claims to have saved my life after all. That shouldn't be too bad. I'll take a walk to calm down myself and perhaps my head will clear up a bit.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_first_deep_raid">
    <text>The first deep raid into the Zone</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_first_deep_raid_text">
    <text>So I am going on my first deep raid into the Zone, and the target is the Agroprom Research Institute. I need to recover some documents belonging to a military expedition. Apart from the mission the trader gave me some information about an area to the north on the way to the Zone's center where brains boil. Probably more of a legend than a fact, but since there's clearly something wrong with my head I probably should check it out and talk to some stalkers. You never know, maybe I've been there before. Also the trader told me that Strelok discovered a way to get through the area and the traders want to know it. Their reasons are clear that they want access to untouched artifact fields. Well I'm going to help them, I guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_first_opinions">
    <text>First impressions</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_first_opinions_text">
    <text>Well well I got some fresh air and saw the local wildlife. Interestingly I seem to remember some of it already, but it's all in a haze. Had a chance to try the local amusements called anomalies. Judging by the fact that I survived I've probably come across them before, but my brain stubbornly refuses to remember. Sidorovich is one clever bastard. He knows he can use me almost for free and that's exactly what he wants to do. Still, maybe he'll help me find this bloody Strelok fella. He seems to be my only connection with my past.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_fox_meet">
    <text>Meeting with Fox.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_fox_meet_text">
    <text>Met with Fox. There are two news items - one is bad: Arrow, he knows little - the other is good, I was informed that his brother, they call Gray knows more. Seryi I understand is about two kilometers to the north somewhere around the radioactive waste dump near the hangar. So the task is clear, to meet with him before he moves to another location.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_monolith_off">
    <text>Disabling the Monolith</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_monolith_off_text">
    <text>I am only a step away from the people who created this damn network of Psi-units throughout the Zone. The Monolith is just another zombifier it seems, with the exception that someone took the care to install a hologram in the shape of a huge crystal inside the Sarcophagus. When the unlucky ones approach it, it messes up their brains. Maybe it even makes them believe that their wishes have come true, who knows? Have I been affected by this shit before? I'm not sure, but whoever is behind this will soon be answering my questions. They even invited me. Well here I come you assholes!</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_provodnik">
    <text>Superconductor</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_provodnik_text">
    <text>The explorer said Doctor thinks he's being followed and will stay at Strelok's old hideout. Well I guess I'll have to pay him a visit.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_seryi_meet">
    <text>Meeting with Seryi</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_seryi_meet_text">
    <text>My hopes of learning something about Strelok must be put on hold for a while longer. Seryi sent me to meet a stalker named Mole who apparently knows the location of Strelok's secret stash. Doubt it, but if he's right at least I would know something. Who knows maybe I'll learn something useful there.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_usefull_info">
    <text>Useful information from the trader</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_usefull_info_text">
    <text>Hmm ... the dealer didn't disappoint me. I thank him for giving me a hand in the search for Arrow. Namely the tip-off to a stalker called Fox. He then lit up next, asking for help. Sidorovich thinks he knows Arrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend">
    <text>Legend of the Wishmaster</text>
</string>
<string id="sl_wishmaster_legend_text">
    <text>A bit of the local folklore I picked up: Legend has it there is a wish-granting machine deep inside the Zone. The exact location is unknown, but it's somewhere in the center. Apparently all you need to do is get to it and all of a sudden your life becomes much, much easier. Hmm... how about finding it and saying 'I want to remember everything about my past!' Then again I wouldn't want to waste a wish. What if I remembered everything and it turned out that I am a complete bastard? Wouldn't that be a bummer! I wonder how many wishes it grants. I wonder if I can wish for wishes!</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_seriy_flash_info">
    <text>Bugay writes Gray: 'Mole and the company unearthed a cache arrow on the agricultural industry, go, know that there is, and how. Buga Gray responds:' All the same, they will go after the bar, I'm better than them at the Garbage wait on the road. '</text>
</string>
