<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<!-- DR and GH -->
<string_table>

<string id="vas1_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Vasiliev!</text>
</string>
 <string id="vas1_dialog_1">
    <text>Who are you and how do you know me?</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_2">
    <text>Forester sent me to help you bring what he needs. He has a bad heart and couldn't come himself.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_3">
    <text>I see, but we have a problem. Forester probably told you that I was bringing him medicine and food, in exchange for cooked roots and artifacts, but an emission was beginning and I was forced to run for shelter. As I ran through the woods I was chased by mutants and dropped my backpack which contained the medicine and my PDA with the forest map. So I stayed here not knowing what to do.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_4">
    <text>So, what do we do? Forester needs the medication.</text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_5">
    <text>We must return to our base at Yantar. There, Professor Sakharov has more medicine that you can take to Forester. Having you with me, I'm not scared to walk through the Forest. Do you have your PDA? On it I will show you how to get to Yantar. I see that you only have a shotgun. Here take my pistol, a couple of boxes of ammo, a scientific med kit and some bandages. Well, let's go? </text>
</string>
<string id="vas1_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, let's go.</text>
</string> 

<string id="mandra_start_dialog_0">
    <text>How I can help?</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to find a rare forest root for the environmentalists, I have promised them. In the past few days I have fallen ill. Problems with my heart so I can't go.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_start_dialog_2">
    <text>I am happy to help you. Tell me what the root is and where to find it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_3">
    <text>First, it is the root of a plant called Mandrake. Second, when pulled out of the ground, the Mandrake emits a 'wild cry', which can lead to insanity or even death to those who try to do it. I will outline the approximate location on the map where you can find the Mandrake. Although it's a quiet place, be careful. Just do not forget to plug your ears before extracting the root.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_start_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand, but can you give me a shotgun and some buckshot just in case? It's kind of scary to walk through the forest with just a knife.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Certainly, here take my old BM16 shotgun and two boxes of buckshot. Also take this leather jacket, a couple of med kits and bandages just in case and...the simple detector artifact. I'll wait here, have a cup of tea and something to eat.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_start_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I will find the Mandrake root</text>
</string>

<string id="mandra_est_dialog_0">
    <text>I found the Mandrake root.</text>
</string>
<string id="mandra_est_dialog_1">
    <text>You make a fine assistant.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_est_dialog_2">
    <text>You said it was a calm place ... it wasn't. There was a herd of insidious monsters, similar to pigs, grazing nearby, and when I took the Mandrake from the ground, they charged. I shot them but they still tore my jacket.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_est_dialog_3">
    <text>Strange, that has always been quiet. Well you've done a fine job and I see you're not afraid of mutants! Here, have some food, fortify yourself a little. Keep the gun, you can't wander around the Zone without one. Here, take a couple of anti-radiation drugs - they will greatly help if you get radiation sickness.</text>
</string>
 <string id="mandra_est_dialog_4">
    <text>Thank you! Happy to help.</text>
</string>

<string id="perehod_dialog1_0">
    <text>Is this the place?</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog1_1">
    <text>Almost. We must go to the swamp. But be careful out there, just follow me, in my tracks. You see, over there in the middle of the marshes, chemical anomalies? Among them should be the entrance to an underwater cave. We'll have to dive. All right, let's go, do not fall behind.</text>
</string>
 <string id="perehod_dialog1_2">
    <text>All clear, let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="perehod_dialog2_0">
    <text>Well, where to next?</text>
</string>
<string id="perehod_dialog2_1">
    <text>This is the place, the entrance to the underwater cave. It's the transition point to Yantar, you need to dive into the hole. You dive in first and I'll follow you, Be careful out there and be on the alert, it is not known at what part of Yantar we'll land, the place is hazardous. </text>
</string>
 <string id="perehod_dialog2_2">
    <text>Well, I'll go first.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
