<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<!--********************************-->
<!-- Sidorovich miniquest dialog start -->
<!--********************************-->
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_0">
		<text>Hey, you said someone left a little loot for me, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_1">
		<text>Oh... yeah, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_2">
		<text>Perfect. I'm taking it now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_3">
		<text>Hey, wait a second... no no, I'm not trying to steal it from you, off course it's yours. I kept it safe and you can have it now. By the way, I didn't know it maybe there was something harmful inside, and I'm not a very healthy man these days, not like in the old days... So, One hundred rubles for keeping it for you. I think it's a fair deal. OK?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_5">
		<text>Damn, your greed is like a curse! Here, take this for keeping it safe, huh...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_6">
		<text>That's fine. Take your loot.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_7">
		<text>Have you lost your mind? You'll give it here now or I'll squeal about your undercover deals!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_4">
		<text>Damn, I'm out of money right now. I'll get it later some time.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_8">
		<text>Here, take your precious bundle.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_9">
		<text>Ha ha, oh scared huh! Who are you kidding?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_10">
		<text>Newbies in  the rookies camp. You can be sure they will buy nothing from you.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_11">
		<text>The Military! Guess what they will do with an illegal trader caught in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_12">
		<text>My word is not enough! My fist will speak up! Do you want it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_13">
		<text>I got some friends here. Very powerful people, you know.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_14">
		<text>They will buy nothing and others will buy more. This is the Zone. They can not leave the Zone. The soldiers blocked all paths, and for going deeper into the Zone they will need ammo and weapons. Where can you get those except from me? So I don't give a shit what you say to them, got it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_15">
		<text>Ha! Ha-ha! You are really funny guy! I can't laugh enough. Where do you think I get all this equipment, all of the weapons and ammo? And who do you think is transfering artifacts from the Zone? The Military needs my business more than anyone. But you can go there, that's gonna be interesting. I wonder if they will shoot you before you say something, or maybe afterwards.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_16">
		<text>Man, if you are more greedy than me then just say it. I do not like guys who's fists are ahead of their words.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_17">
		<text>Remember, friendship ends where big money begins. And I don't care about your friends. Now they are powerful, tomorrow they will be weak. It's the Zone, understand?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_18">
		<text>Okay. One hundred rubles and you can have your stuff.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_19">
		<text>Thank you!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="escape_trader_miniquest_20">
		<text>Got it!</text>
	</string>

<!--****************************-->
<!-- Barist Repair dialog start -->
<!--****************************-->
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_0">
		<text>You have something for me, a guy left it, right?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_1">
		<text>Yes, a small package. It is here. I almost forgot about it. Do you need it now?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_2">
		<text>Yes, I'm taking it now.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_3">
		<text>No problem, here it is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="bar_trader_miniquest_4">
		<text>Thank you very much.</text>
	</string>
<!--********************-->
<!-- miniquest dialogs end -->
<!--********************-->

</string_table>
