<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="about_enciclopedia">
    <text>This section - Encyclopedia. During this experience information about the world will be recorded here and sorted by topic.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_pda">
    <text>About the Encyclopedia</text>
</string>
<string id="Bandit's flash">
    <text>PDA from the bandit in the factory</text>
</string>
<string id="blokpost_case_text">
    <text>Dealer: Go to the checkpoint and steal the briefcase with the report of a military expedition from the Northern Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="Dead novice's flash">
    <text>PDA from a dead rookie.</text>
</string>
<string id="defend_lager_text">
    <text>Fanatic: Help fend off mercenaries who came in and demanded the expulsion of rookies from their camp. All be careful not get caught. Sneak into the camp and then attack on command.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_meet">
    <text>Guide's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_meet_2">
    <text>Meeting with Doctor</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_meet_quest_text">
    <text>Doctor: 'I'm waiting for a guy from Arrow's group coming to the hiding place. If this is the right guy he will find this place.'</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_meet_text">
    <text>Well, I will meet Ghost's aquaintance. I'll wait for him in Arrow's secret place. If he's one of our own, he will know where to find me. Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_flash_task_descr">
    <text>Trader: '... my guys were on their way back from a mission and disappeared. One of them, called Nimble, was carrying some information for me. They must have vanished nearby because they had passed the bridge. I do not know what to think. We decided to send someone else. Guess who? So you find the USB flash drive that Nimble has and bring it to me. Nimble was one of Wolf's guys, and he was here, in the camp. Ask him: what he knows. He could possibly help you with arms and ammunition.'</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_fox_info">
    <text>Seriy to Fox: A friend asked to meet a group of stalkers that found Arrow's cache. I'm going with some guys to the hanger in the Garbage. You can find me there.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_kolyan_lost">
    <text>One brother went yesterday to explore an abandoned mill and he is still missing. We ought to go and check on him.</text>
</string>
<string id="factory_dynamit_text">
    <text>Wolf: get the dynamite stolen by bandits at the factory. To help out see my guys near the bridge and say the password: 'Greetings from Hell', or you will be shot, lol. Then lead them in the attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="factory_trader_text">
    <text>Wolf: kill off the bandits at the factory with the help of my scouts near the bridge, then return and report to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="Flash dead stalker">
    <text>PDA from the dead stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="gunslinger_clan_cache">
    <text>I woke up in a hut with some ugly guy. I remember nothing. I have a PDA with a picture of a guy. The PDA has only one entry, 'Kill the Arrow'.</text>
</string>
<string id="help_to_fox">
    <text>Trader: Fox returned from a raid, asking for help. Perhaps he has knowledge of Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="meet_seryi_text">
    <text>Fox: Seriy is in a hangar in Garbage. He knows a lot.</text>
</string>
<string id="military_case_text">
    <text>Trader: Go to the Institute in Agroprom Industry and get the military expedition documents and take them to the Bar at '100 Roentgen' and give them to the Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="Seryi flash">
    <text>Fox's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_fox_flash_info">
    <text>A merchant sent us to monitor the military at the Institute of Agroprom. For the hell of it we killed everybody. We found some interesting stuff. I found a cipher, *abracadabra, type, code*.</text>
</string>
<string id="storyline_seryi_info">
    <text>Seriy to Fox: A friend of mine asked to meet a group of stalkers who unearthed Arrow's cache. I'll be in Garbage. Stop by if you want.</text>
</string>
<string id="Tolik flash">
    <text>Tolik's PDA</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_artefact_find">
    <text>Trader: here nearby is a 'Whirligig'. Artifact at its center. Get it!</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_moving_anomaly_text">
    <text>There is a very strange anomaly nearby. It seems to be moving around. I will try to calculate its trajectory and travel time. I can give this data to the soldiers near the bridge to pay for passage since I have no money.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_secret_place">
    <text>I left on an abandoned farm a small stash. There's a bit of food and ammo. I am to sick to get it. Not sure if I can get to the camp.</text>
</string>
