<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table> 

<string id="sar_first_dialog_0">
    <text>I greet you brother! Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="sar_first_dialog_1">
    <text>And to you regards! Is there any work for me?</text>
</string>

<string id="sar_first_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother our Director is waiting for you. He will tell you about our rules and commandments. Listen to him and take everything in. Here, take these specially prepared items: weapons and equipment. God and the power of the Monolith are with you!</text>
</string>

<string id="sar_first_dialog_3">
    <text>Thanks brother I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_0">
    <text>Teacher I need something repaired.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_1">
    <text>Yes our enemies are not asleep, let's have a look.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the first gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the second gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_4">
    <text>Repair the armour.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_5">
    <text>Teacher I don't have enough money.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_6">
    <text>Here is your weapon brother, let our enemies tremble.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_7">
    <text>Armour repaired. Glory to Monolith! Down with our evil enemies, one additional brother is ready to defend our truth.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_8">
    <text>I thank you, Teacher.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_9">
    <text>I am again ready to bear faith and truth to the un-believers. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_10">
    <text>Teacher there's more.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_repair_11">
    <text>Oh that's cool, let's take a look.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_trade_speak_0">
    <text>How do you do Teacher?</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_trade_speak_1">
    <text>I salute you brother! I'm glad you have joined us recently, therefore I wish to give to you several manuals.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_trade_speak_2">
    <text>You have my full attention, Teacher.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_trade_speak_3">
    <text>As anyone who has embarked on the true path, you must work. The killing of infidels - is the responsibility of all our members. But nevertheless, the community must survive. We need, food, water, med kits, ammo and so on. To get all of this, we require artifacts. The outside World, alas, is not with us, there is only chaos and disbelief. They're ready to sell anything to anyone, but what they mostly require, is what the Zone produces - artifacts.  Each member of community is obligated to yield any artifacts, which he finds. For them, he will receive rations, consisting of rounds of ammunition, food and med kits. The better the artefact, the better the rations.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_0">
    <text>I greet you Teacher.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_1">
    <text>Go on brother I'm listening.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_trade_speak_4">
    <text>I understand Teacher I will try.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_2">
    <text>Teacher, I brought something here, look.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_3">
    <text>Artifacts?</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_31">
    <text>I have a Stone Flower.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_32">
    <text>I have a Stone Blood.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_33">
    <text>I have a Night Star.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_34">
    <text>I have a Soul.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_35">
    <text>I have a Spring.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_36">
    <text>I have a Crystal.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_37">
    <text>I have a Goldfish.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_38">
    <text>I have a Meat Chunk.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_39">
    <text>I have a Gravi.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_390">
    <text>Oh excuse me Teacher I was wrong.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_311">
    <text>Not much ... Well, here's three packs of ammo for the AK, a med kit and one antirad.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_321">
    <text>Slim pickings, well okay, take two regular med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_331">
    <text>Oh-oh-oh, A Night Star! Let me look at it ... ya don't see them around here very often. Good for you, here's somne ammo: 5 packs of armour piercing rounds for the ThunderStorm, two scientific med kits and two antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_341">
    <text>Rare artefact, you deserve a reward! Here, NATO cartridges, 5 packs, plus 3 scientific med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_351">
    <text>It has been a long time since anyone has brought me a Spring. Here, for your SVU, are 5 packs of armour-piercing bullets and 2 antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_361">
    <text>You have brought the Crystal? I'm pleased! Take 5 packs of standard cartridges for the Val, and two army med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_371">
    <text>For the Goldfish take this: Five packs of armour-piercing cartridges for the AK, two army med kits and five cans of food.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_381">
    <text>For the Meat Chunk, I will give you 3 boxes of ammo for the AK, a standard med kit and 4 pieces of sausage.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_change_391">
    <text>For the Gravi here are 3 packs of normal NATO rounds, 2 standard med kits and 4 pieces of sausage.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_0">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_1">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith! I greet our new brother! As you already know, we recently gained control over the territory of the Sarcophagus. After the accident here, besides us, there was not a single person, only monsters. Too many of them are spread through-out. Here's the first task: beneath us, in the Sarcophagus, we have got a family of 5-6 Burers around. We don't want them here. Therefore, soldier, listen to the order: Go there and clear out the area. These creatures have stolen a device - a decoder, which we really need. It is necessary that we annihilate these dwarfs, and recover the decoder. Dig up all their holes, but find the instrument.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_2">
    <text>I am happy to fulfil this mission Director. I will not fail you.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_est_0">
    <text>I greet you Director!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_est_1">
    <text>Oh our new brother have you fulfilled my task?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_first_speak_est_2">
    <text>Yes I did as you requested. The Dwarfs are annihilated and here is your instrument.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_0">
    <text>Brother!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_1">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_2">
    <text>Do you have anything to drink?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_3">
    <text>Brother are you mad? They can hear us.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_4">
    <text>I must have some, It's been more than three months since I've had a drink ... I can't take it any longer. Get me five bottles of Vodka my friend, and I'll give you a brand new gun, a TT-33.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_5">
    <text>I'm sorry brother but I have no vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_vodka_6">
    <text>Here take it, but make sure Mahon does not see you...</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_0">
    <text>Brother do you have any excess food?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_1">
    <text>Need anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_2">
    <text>I need five cans of preserved food to eat whilst hunting, but Mahon won't give me any.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_3">
    <text>Okay if I find some I'll bring it to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_0">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_1">
    <text>And hello to you, here, I have found exactly 5 cans.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_2">
    <text>Brother I thank you, but I have nothing to give. Listen, I have here a recipe for transmutations. I'll download it to your PDA. It will be useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_conserva_est_3">
    <text>Thanks for the recipe. Good luck, brother. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_0">
    <text>Brother, do you have batteries for a PDA?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_1">
    <text>Of course not, where would I get them?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_2">
    <text>Well there is no shop around here, of course, but there is a way. Bring me 5 PDA's. All I really want are the batteries.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_need_pda_3">
    <text>It is agreeable brother, if I find 5 PDA's then I will bring them to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_0">
    <text>Hey brother did you get them?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_1">
    <text>Yes, here take them!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_ohr_est_pda_2">
    <text>Thank you! Wait, I can't thank you enough. I've got a Koster grenade launcher, quite new, and some ammo for the AK, here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_0">
    <text>Did you summon me, Charon?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_1">
    <text>Yes, brother, I have a task for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_2">
    <text>I'm listening, Director.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_3">
    <text>Solomon's group have spotted a few stalkers in Chernobyl-2. It turns out that our enemy has infiltrated our rear. These 'infidels' not only do not wish to embark on the true course, they defile the 'Holy Places' with their presence.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_4">
    <text>Give me permission; I'll erase them into powder. These infidels will receive their just deserts!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_5">
    <text>Do not hurry, and do not go alone. Solomon's Group is waiting for you, find them. Remember, I need Solomon alive. You are responsible for his head! Here's a little ammo and a couple of med kits. Transition on CNPP-2 you will find in the room of the Monolith, you will pass over the hall with large windows, and then go along the wall with the windows all the way and to the left of the room.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_need_6">
    <text>Thank you, Director, for your confidence. I will not fail you. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_aes_need_0">
    <text>I greet you, brother!</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_aes_need_1">
    <text>You're on time, brother, we are ready, we were waiting for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_aes_need_2">
    <text>What are your plans?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_aes_need_3">
    <text>We'll advance slowly, going as a group, with you in the lead. All right, let's go!</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_aes_need_4">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith! God be with us with his strength and power!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_est_0">
    <text>Director, you will again teach me ... okay ... I hear and obey. Director, I have brought good news.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_aes_est_1">
    <text>That's good that you are patient and obedient. They have already reported to me about your feats. You are a fine person! Glory to the Monolith! He does not abandon his children but helps them in difficult times.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_0">
    <text>Well infidel should I shoot you like a dog?</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_1">
    <text>I beg you do not kill me.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_2">
    <text>You and your people have defiled the 'Holy Places'; there is no mercy for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_3">
    <text>Brother ... Brother, do not kill me ... I ... I sincerely want to believe, I am ready to join with you. I beg you, give me a med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_4">
    <text>Okay here's a med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_5">
    <text>I don't have a med kit, die trying infidel!</text>
</string>

<string id="chaes_mamai_master_6">
    <text>Thank you brother! Listen I have a formula for transmutations. I'll record it onto your PDA. It surely will come in handy.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_dialog_0">
    <text>I'm listening brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_dialog_1">
    <text>Brother you have proved you have a good side. I see that you are intelligent. I have a special mission for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_dialog_2">
    <text>Speak Solomon, I am glad that you trust me, especially, a skilled soldier such as yourself.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_dialog_3">
    <text>Brother, when we came here, the place was not deserted. What we found here was a detachment of military stalkers. But, glory to the Monolith, we succeeded in vanquishing them but lost many brothers in the process. From one of our brothers, who incidentally, was a former Special Forces soldier, and had participated in the raid, we learnt that they were looking for documents that a scientist, from before the Big Bang (Dorodina was his name), had carefully collected and stored into three fireproof cases. We were not able to find them ... But we were able to track the location of the 2 of the cases, while the third seems to have vanished into thin air. I'll put their coordinates on your PDA. Well, soldier, here are your orders: dig up entire western unit Of Chernobyl-2 and find the three cases. One more thing, we've located a weak signal that could be the third case, it's coming from outside the upper levels of the Sarcophagus. The only way to get there is to pass through the teleport anomalies. My men are too afraid to use them.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_dialog_4">
    <text>Solomon I have the might and will of the Monolith, everything I need and more. My faith will help me, I am ready!</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_est_0">
    <text>Glory to the Monolith, I have not failed you, Solomon.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_est_1">
    <text>You found them?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_est_2">
    <text>Yes Solomon, here are they - all three.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_case_est_3">
    <text>Your services to the flock are great! You are an example of a good brother. Your humility and hard work will not go unnoticed. The Monolith sees and hears all. You have prepared for a great honour. In the meantime, let me reward you. Here, take 5 F-1 grenades, let our enemies fear you more!</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_0">
    <text>Brother, a matter exists.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_1">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_2">
    <text>Brother help me. Solomon gave my mate and I the job of clearing mutants from the CNPP-2 territory, but we were drunk and trouble occurred. My partner was carried off by snorks ... OMG ... they gorged on him. The Monolith were angered at what happened. But they gave me a second chance. So I have two days left and I'm afraid to go. But what do I say to Solomon? I need to present the evidence he needs, but where can I get it if I don't go. Please, can you help me by getting eight snork feet? In return I will give you six boxes of buckshot. But be careful, Snorks jump off the roofs like crazy grasshoppers! They live not far from here, just west of our camp. But again, be careful! Look up at the roofs and entice them down.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_3">
    <text>I'll get your snork feet. Just do not drink any more, brother. We have embarked on the path of 'Truth'. It's a sin to booze.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_0">
    <text>Well, brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_1">
    <text>I brought the Snorks feet.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_ohr_change_est_2">
    <text>Eight pieces? Thanks brother, you really saved me! Here, take the buckshot as I promised.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_0">
    <text>I greet you Charon! Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_1">
    <text>Soldier, above us is the Monolith Control Bunker. We wish, in the course of time, to create a Control Centre there to coordinate and manage our resources, but there ... ah ... in the darkness, are many mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_2">
    <text>Director, what should I do?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_dialog_3">
    <text>The task is a simple one, clean up the Monolith Control Bunker of all mutants. And who knows how many are there, so be careful. The passage through Chernobyl-2 is currently blocked. So go through the Sarcophagus room to Chernobyl-1. The entrance to the Control Bunker is around there, look on your PDA I've marked its location. Oh and here for you are a couple of med kits, and cartridges for the AK just in case. I will also give you my Winchester shotgun, which often helped me at difficult times. Take care of it and it will faithfully serve you. Let this be your reward from me for your skill and dedication.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_0">
    <text>I was in the bunker.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_1">
    <text>Well what did you find there?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_2">
    <text>A freak'n bizillion bloodsuckers, zombies and burers. So I eliminated everything that moved.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_contr_mono_est_3">
    <text>Good as always. I was not mistaken when I chose you for the job.</text>
</string>


<string id="about_mervin_dialog_0">
    <text>Director, is there any serious work?</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_1">
    <text>Are you ready for some serious work?</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_2">
    <text>I believe so. I want to earn your more of your trust.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_3">
    <text>You're a young soldier, full of promise, so you now have to go through additional training. Go to your saviour Mervin, he will give you a few more lessons.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_4">
    <text>Where will I find him?</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_5">
    <text>Mervin is the keeper of Monolith. You'll find him there, in the Sarcophagus room, next to our 'Treasure'.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_6">
    <text>Good, I will go and find Mervin.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_0">
    <text>Greetings Mervin. Charon sent me.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_1">
    <text>Yes, Charon told me you were coming. He indicates that as a whole he is satisfied with you, and sees for you great prospects, but you have arrogance and have a lot of dissent. In connection with all that it is required to teach you the power of the spirit, courage, as well as humility and tolerance. Just do not perceive it as punishment. This is the special training that each new soldier has to pass, in order to earn the confidence of the Director.</text>
</string>

<string id="about_mervin_dialog_est_2">
    <text>I see.</text>
</string>


<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Charon. Mervin said that you had an urgent matter.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes soldier, there is an urgent matter: there is a doctor - his name is Swamp Doctor. He lives in the Swamps, far from Pripyat, well, it does not matter. He makes drugs for us that are hard to get, in return for rare and valuable artifacts which can only be found here, in the CNPP territory. Now we have many patients, especially here at CNPP-2. So: there's an urgent need to go to Pripyat, meet with the Doctor or his messenger, and bring back some medication. The doctor himself rarely comes, usually sends his apprentice - they call him Feldsher, a small annoying ... But okay, closer to the point: I have no one but you to send, so get ready for the road.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_2">
    <text>Where is the meeting place in Pripyat?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_dialog_3">
    <text>Look in the stadium, the Doctor and his pupil Feldsher normally go there when they come to Pripyat. I'll mark the spot on your PDA. I'll give you the coordinates for the transition point from the Sarcophagus to Chernobyl, from there I hope you will find how to get to Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_est_0">
    <text>Director, here are the drugs.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_est_1">
    <text>Let me see, well ... seems, like that's all that's needed. What did you think of the Doctor?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_est_2">
    <text>There was no doctor, just his pupil, Feldsher. A normal guy. It's a pity he's not one of us. However he asked me for artifacts, says that we owed him, I had to find some.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_est_3">
    <text>I see! About those medical guys, I do not like them and they don't like me. We would have shot them a long time ago, but the Swamp Doctor ...  well, he was the only doctor in the area so we had to endure them. The last time we bought medicine from the Doctor he shot my messenger. He said that the messenger spoke to him rudely. I will not forgive him for this ... all in good time.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_doctor_est_4">
    <text>Okay Charon I understand.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello are you Clerk?</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes that's me. Brother, one cannot go further. We noticed a detachment of military, clearly not noobs, killed two of my scouts, which had no time to utter a word.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Brother I'm in a hurry. I have an urgent request from Charon. By the way, you have a gangster's mug. Are you a bandit?</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_start_dialog_3">
    <text>It's a common face, I did not choose it! Yes I was a bandit. In one skirmish in Pripyat with a detachment of Monolith I was wounded. Solomon found me, and did not kill me. He cured me instead and then enlightened me and sent me on the right path. So now I'm in his debt. Now I faithfully serve the Monolith! All right, enough philosophy, I am restless. Help me out brother! I have to personally answer to Charon! He told me he would blow off my head because there are enemies in the territory. There is a gun I have, a PP Bison with a removable scope. If you help us it's yours.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_start_dialog_4">
    <text>It is agreeable brother I'll help you. Then I have one more question. But first, let's do it. We advance.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>You ok Clerk?</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>Son of a bitch! Many of our brothers are dead. Yes I'm in one piece. Glory to the Monolith. Although I think, I took a hit. Damn!</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>Well take care of yourself.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>Yup! Here as promised, the gun, a little ammunition and a scope. God be with you and the strength and spirit of the Monolith!</text>
</string>


<string id="dyak_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Clerk I'm performing a task for Solomon and only you can help me.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_1">
    <text>You bailed me out and I am already indebted to Solomon. So how can I help you? </text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Solomon asked me to bring him something, namely canned food from Pripyat and a container of medical supplies, which, he says Mahon hid somewhere in the Chernobyl area and he said you know where it is. Solomon, you can trust for sure.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_3">
    <text>So that's it ... Well, the exact place I'll can't tell you because I don't know. I didn't see Mahon hide the container, but out of the corner of my eye I saw in which direction he went.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, I do not know what to look for or where as I'm a stranger in these parts. Just tell me the approximate direction.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_5">
    <text>About two months ago Mahon came here to Chernobyl NPP, he was very reserved and taciturn. He only asked to send a patrol to the eastern part of the Chernobyl NPP and clear the area of mutants. My guys did what was asked of them, and then came back and reported. He then went to one and asked him not to escort him. I saw that he had a metal container probably full of drugs. He returned later without it. I saw that he went through the eastern gate, not far from where we are now. He then walked around the locomotive and up towards the old freight train cars. That's where you should look, you may find it somewhere around there.</text>
</string>

<string id="dyak_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Understood! I will try to find the container in the eastern part of Chernobyl.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Greetings, Charon sent me.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>What he does wish?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Medicines, as always.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>So, tell him that he will not give any. Several times he was given credit, but this time we have lost patience. He needs to pay up first.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Hmmm ... Feldsher, I cannot go without medicine, we have a lot of patients.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Do you wish to obtain the medicines? Well then you pay! How does he not understand that I need artifacts and mutant parts to produce medicines? If there are no artifacts then there are no drugs.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Feldsher what you need? I'll try to get them.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Two Night Star artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Here Feldsher I have two. I found them on the way here.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I don't have a Night Star. Can I bring something else?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Then bring to me 10 blind dog tails.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_5">
    <text>I have them. Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_6">
    <text>I don't have that many tails, I will go find some more.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_7">
    <text>You're a fine person, I look at you and don't understand why you are with them, do you realise they are fanatics?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_8">
    <text>We are not fanatics we believe in the truth. Although, quite frankly I actually was confused.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_9">
    <text>You yourself do not believe in what you say ... I've heard your predecessors say similar words. I used to watch their eyes. All those who came before you, their eyes were empty, and yours ... Yours burn! It's not my business, of course, but think, why and for what reason you believe in this ... burden. Carrying this burden is not easy, it's mysterious and incomprehensible, but whatever you say, but it's still just a burden.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Feldsher, I advise you not to utter such words in my presence.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, I will not detain you any longer, just listen to your heart, trust it, and it will give you the right advice as given by a Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_second_dialog_12">
    <text>That was done quickly. I look at you and don't understand your situtation. Have you forgotten that you are among fanatics?</text>
</string>


<string id="digger_repair_0">
    <text>Feldsher, do you do repairs?</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_1">
    <text>I do a little repairs.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the first gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the second gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_4">
    <text>Repair my armour.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_5">
    <text>Yeah right you crook, at those prices, you must be crazy. I'll wait.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_6">
    <text>Well, lookie here, as good as new.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_7">
    <text>Yeah, something had to be done to bring this suit into good repair. All the plates were changed.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_8">
    <text>Well, thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_9">
    <text>Listen, in my opinion, now it's even better than when it was new.</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_10">
    <text>There is something else, will you look?</text>
</string>

<string id="digger_repair_11">
    <text>Yes, what do we have here?</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Master.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_1">
    <text>Come, my brother, I'm listening.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_2">
    <text>Master, I brought something, take a look.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_3">
    <text>Artifacts?</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_31">
    <text>I have a Stone Flower.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_32">
    <text>I have a Stone Blood.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_33">
    <text>I have a Night Star.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_34">
    <text>I have a Soul.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_35">
    <text>I have a Spring.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_36">
    <text>I have a Crystal.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_37">
    <text>I have a Goldfish.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_38">
    <text>I have a Meat Chunk.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_39">
    <text>I have a Gravi.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_390">
    <text>Oh, forgive me teacher, I was mistaken.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_311">
    <text>Not much ... Well, here's three packs of ammo for the AK, a med kit and one antirad.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_321">
    <text>Slim pickings, well, okay, take two regular med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_331">
    <text>Oh-oh-oh, A Night Star! Let me look at it ... Don't see them very often around here. Good for you, here's ammo: 5 packs of armour piercing rounds for the Storm, two scientific med kits and two antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_341">
    <text>Rare artefact, you deserve a decoration! Here, NATO cartridges, 5 packs, plus 3 scientific med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_351">
    <text>It has been a long time since anyone has brought me a Spring. Here, for your SVU, are 5 packs of armour-piercing bullets and 2 antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_361">
    <text>You have brought the Crystal? I'm pleased! Take 5 packs of standard cartridges for the Val, and two army med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_371">
    <text>For the Goldfish take this: Five packs of armour-piercing cartridges for the AK, two army med kits and five cans of food.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_381">
    <text>For the Meat Chunk, I will give you 3 boxes of ammo for the AK, a standard med kit and 4 pieces of sausage.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_change_391">
    <text>For the Gravi, here are 3 packs of normal NATO rounds, 2 standard med kits and 4 pieces of sausage.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_0">
    <text>Master, I need something repaired.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_1">
    <text>Yes our enemies are not asleep, let's take a look.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_2">
    <text>Repair the first gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_3">
    <text>Repair the second gun.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_4">
    <text>Repair the armour.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_5">
    <text>Master, I don't have enough money.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_6">
    <text>Here is your weapon, brother, let our enemies tremble.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_7">
    <text>Armour repaired. Glory to the Monolith! To spite our enemies, one additional brother is ready to protect our truth.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_8">
    <text>I thank you, Master.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_9">
    <text>I am again ready to bear truth to the unbelievers. Glory to the Monolith!!!</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_10">
    <text>Master, there is still something.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_repair_11">
    <text>Okay, give me a look:</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Director, have I overheard that Mercenaries have captured our base in Pripyat?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes there is this matter, we must drive them from Pripyat, and persecute them, bit by bit.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, is it time for us to show them who is the owner of Pripyat?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>I think so. Listen, soldier, Mahon is already there with his men. Get prepared and go. Talk to him, he will explain all to you. But consider this: Mahon - is my right hand man, I will hold you personally responsible if he dies during the assault. On your return, you will continue your special training with Mervin.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_est_0">
    <text>Greetings to you, Director, Victory! Mahon is alive and well.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_est_1">
    <text>Mahon has already reported. You have done well! Glory to the Monolith, it leaves us in an easier position. I don't think they will attack us again for a long time. But we can't be complacent, is not worth it. We have many enemies, much...</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_baza_est_2">
    <text>I serve the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Teacher, I am here to help out.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>What took you so long?! You see these guys with me, they are the best of the best! Maybe someday you'll be one of them. The 'Inner Circle'. Grasp that? In short, our motto: 'no fear, no mercy, no pain, no compassion'. But plenty of vodka!</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>Just a few mutants, sir. I hope I'll someday be one of the best too. Well Mahon shall we move on?</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>Let's go brother. We've sat here for too long a time already.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_0">
    <text>Teacher you called me?</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait... give me time to recover my breath.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_2">
    <text>Mahon don't hurry, all is sweet. It's over.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_3">
    <text>It's not all over yet. It is still necessary to cleanse the central area. Take the guys and go in the direction of the Lenin Monument.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_dialog_4">
    <text>I'm on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_est_0">
    <text>Fuuuf ... I'm exhausted, what a day.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_est_1">
    <text>Yes it was hard work. But the results were positive. We freed our base and the City centre. Now the Mercenaries only hold the outskirts. Do not worry, we will get there.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_est_2">
    <text>Okay Mahon I need to go, I have to report to Charon.</text>
</string>

<string id="mathon_lenin_est_3">
    <text>Brother take this anomaly detector. It's not the best, but it can save your life that's for sure.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_about_change_0">
    <text>Feldsher do you have something to sell?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_about_change_1">
    <text>For sale yes, but I also offer an exchange service: you bring me mutant parts, but bear in mind: I only take parts in bulk, 10 pieces at a time. These I will exchange for med kits and ammo.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_about_change_2">
    <text>That's good, what I find I'll bring.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_0">
    <text>Here I have something.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_1">
    <text>What have you got?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_2">
    <text>I have 10 Flesh's eyes</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_3">
    <text>I have 10 Boar hooves.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_4">
    <text>I have 10 Blind dog tails.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_5">
    <text>I have 10 Pseudo-dog tails.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_6">
    <text>I have 10 Bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_7">
    <text>I have 10 Burer hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_8">
    <text>I have 10 Zombie hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_9">
    <text>I have 10 Snork's feet.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_10">
    <text>I have 10 Tushkano heads.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_11">
    <text>I have 10 Controller hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_12">
    <text>I have 10 Pseudogiant paws.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_13">
    <text>I have 10 Chimera claws.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_14">
    <text>Unfortunately today I have zip.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_21">
    <text>Give them to me, good medicines are obtained from them! In return you get 4 scientific med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_31">
    <text>For 10 Boar hooves - 4 army med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_41">
    <text>But how did you get them? Fine person! Here are 4 boxes of buckshot.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_51">
    <text>Pseudo-dogs are very risky; I did not think that you were capable. Here are 4 F1 grenades.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_61">
    <text>10 Bloodsucker tentacles! You are a dangerous man! Here are 4 boxes of armour-piercing cartridges for the Vintorez.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_71">
    <text>10 Burer hands! Where did you find them? Well it's agreeable - here are four boxes of NATO armour-piercing cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_81">
    <text>For the civilian Zombies hands, I'll give you ... I will give you 5 boxes of buckshot.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_91">
    <text>Snorks, brrr ... I don't like them, I've had a nasty encounter with them. Here are four med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_101">
    <text>Tushkanos, you have to be agile to kill them. Here are 5 boxes of 9x18 armour-piercing cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_111">
    <text>Controllers, oh mother, well you ... okay, here's 5 antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_121">
    <text>Pseudogiant? Pseudogiant, oh yeah, tough creatures. Here, for you 7 boxes of standard NATO cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_131">
    <text>Chimera - risky monster, here for you, 5 boxes of armour-piercing cartridges for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_change_141">
    <text>When you have something, return.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_need_0">
    <text>What do you want, brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_need_1">
    <text>Brother, I need your help. Here, at the arse end of the world, there are no shops, but we're all human and need food and meds to survive this hell. Charon usually solves this, but so far has done little. While we wait for him, we swell from hunger and rot from cholera.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_need_2">
    <text>How I can you help?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_need_3">
    <text>Sooner or later Charon will send you to Pripyat. Where there is a shop, it is certainly not a clothing shop, it's a former grocery store. But I'm almost 100% sure there are products there. I do not know, like maybe canned food ... may be something else. Brother help us, if you find something, bring it back. But that's not all, only one doctor prepares and supplies our brotherhood with medicine, and Mahon rations them for my guys with whom we protect the inner CNPP territory. This is all due to the fact that we had an argument with him on the subject of our faith, so he takes revenge slowly. But I know that Mahon's caches are filled with medications in the CNPP territory. One of our brothers, a former bandit called Clerk, told me. From the Sarcophagus going to Pripyat is possible only through the external CNPP territory, and there you will find Clerk, a senior guard. Be sure to talk to him, tell him about my request, and find what I am asking you to bring. He will help, because he owes me a debt.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_need_4">
    <text>Yes brother I'll help you. While I'm in Pripyat I will search all the grocery stores for food, and with Clerk's help I will also search the CNPP territory for the medications. </text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_0">
    <text>Well brother I've brought good news.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_1">
    <text>What's the news?</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_2">
    <text>I was in Pripyat, I found this grocery store and it was empty. It seemed to me that someone had been there before, apparently. But still searching I found one box of canned food. I was also able to find Mahon's drug cache in the CNPP territory. It was not easy I tell you, it was very hard.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_3">
    <text>Canned food is good, it has less radiation. Well give me what you brought. Also I wish to reward you. Here, choose something:</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_31">
    <text>Optics for NATO weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_32">
    <text>Optics for Russian weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_33">
    <text>Submachine gun HK MP5K-N modified, chambered for 9x18.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_311">
    <text>I'll take the optics for the Sig-550.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_321">
    <text>I'll take the optics for the AK-74.</text>
</string>

<string id="solomon_food_est_331">
    <text>I'll take the 'HK MP5K-N' modified.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_0">
    <text>My training is completed, Director. How else can I help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_1">
    <text>Soldier there is a mission for you. Clerk's men have caught a stalker. He is now in the CNPP-2 territory. Your task is to interrogate him and find out everything he knows. Spies like him need to be eliminated. Only don't you do it. Clerk will do everything himself. He knows how to solve such problems. Report back to me when you're finished.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_0">
    <text>Well, tell me who are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_1">
    <text>Friend, don't kill me, I will tell all.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_2">
    <text>Stop whining, you knew what you were doing. Only a confession may save you now.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_3">
    <text>Brother, brother, I will tell you everything, if you just don't kill me.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_4">
    <text>For the last time, who are you and what are you looking for?</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_5">
    <text>Earring ... my name is Earring. I ... I was sent by Ghost ... I mean three of us were, but two were killed. He sent us here to find a way into the Control Bunker.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_6">
    <text>Why did you need to get into the bunker? And who is this 'Ghost'?</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_7">
    <text>Doc ... ah ... some important documents. A map of the underground passages between Pripyat and the Sarcophagus. I think, but I'm not sure. Brother have pity. That's all I can tell you.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_8">
    <text>Who is this 'Ghost'?</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_9">
    <text>He seems to be former Military, maybe KGB. He ... He ... I ... We recently worked together. He was looking for a way into the Sarcophagus, bypassing the posts. Why? I do not know, Ghost never told me anything in detail.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_10">
    <text>Where do I find him?</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_11">
    <text>I don't know precisely, but he will be either in Pripyat or at the Radar where his base is. I'm not positive.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_12">
    <text>The interrogation is finished.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_13">
    <text>No brother! Brother don't kill me. No need to ... I beg you, tell Clerk to let me go. I told you all I know.</text>
</string>

<string id="shpion_dopross_14">
    <text>I said the interrogation is finished.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_est_0">
    <text>Greetings Director. Glory to the Monolith!</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_est_1">
    <text>What news did you bring soldier?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_est_2">
    <text>I questioned the spy. Earring was his name, he sought with two other stalkers some documents, a map of the Pripyat underground. He could be lying, though unlikely, Clerk is a true beast. Yet the spy mentioned a stalker named Ghost.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_dopross_est_3">
    <text>Ghost ... Ghost, the name is familiar. I'm sure it has something to do with the Swamp Doctor and his assistant Feldsher. Okay soldier rest for now. I will call you when I need you again.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_net_work_0">
    <text>Director, is there any work? If I sit for too long, I get nervous...</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_net_work_1">
    <text>You're a good soldier! I will soon present you with a serious reward. But, at the moment there is no work. I'll call you when you're needed. So for now, relax, pray and fortify your faith!</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Feldsher, you requested me to visit.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, yes, your help is necessary.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_2">
    <text>What has happened?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_3">
    <text>I do not know if you have heard anything about a man called Ghost, but if you have, it's probably bad, but I need your help.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Of course, I heard about him recently. I would like to have a word with Ghost.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_5">
    <text>So you will have a talk, but there is a small problem.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_6">
    <text>This is getting interesting.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_7">
    <text>In order to talk to him, you must first free him. He was captured by Mercenaries. He's being held in Pripyat, I'll load the coordinates into your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_8">
    <text>It is strange that they did not shoot him.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_9">
    <text>Nothing strange about it. They are not fanatics such as your brothers, who find it easier to kill than to gain information. I suspect that the real reason they didn't was so they could get to me and the Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_10">
    <text>Why do you think that?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_11">
    <text>They came to us several times, but the Doctor and I refused to treat them. So now they harbour a grudge against us.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_12">
    <text>You have strange scruples ... As I understand it, you and the Doctor are not exactly thrilled with us, but you still deliver healing, and by your standards, are we really any better than them?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_13">
    <text>You are fanatics. At least half of you or maybe more, are controlled. I don't know how you manage with that, but I hope to find out. And you ... yes ... even you have you not noticed that you're not your own master. So, I'm sorry for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_14">
    <text>An interesting theory. Worst of all, unfortunately, is that I don't remember a thing, who or what I was before I got here. I can't remember my name or why I was in the Zone. I cannot remember anything before Pripyat. My memories start from when Mervin pulled me out of an anomaly ... Okay, give me Ghost's coordinates, I'll go and do what I do best - kill!</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_dialog_15">
    <text>Give me your PDA ... Yes, I've marked the place. If all goes well, come back here, I have something for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you Ghost?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_1">
    <text>A minute ago I was, but now I'm not sure. This is the first time the Monolith has helped me. Usually all they want to give me is a bullet in the head.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_2">
    <text>This is no joke, Feldsher sent me. Let's go. Follow me.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_3">
    <text>Ah Feldsher, I underestimated him! I thought he just blindly carried out assignments from the Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_plen_dialog_4">
    <text>Come on let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_0">
    <text>Well you're free now.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_1">
    <text>My freedom seems conditional. You saved me from the Mercenaries so that you can control me.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_2">
    <text>Clever, but I'm growing tired of this. First Feldsher, now you. This Theory of a device or something out there, controlling us. Let's talk about facts. What documents were you looking for at the CNPP?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_3">
    <text>What are you talking about? Ahh ... I understand. So, they got caught? I did not have anyone else available, and the documents were needed. All that was required of them was to conduct, so to speak, a reconnaissance of the CNPP to see where and how your brothers were positioned.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_4">
    <text>What kind of documents?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_5">
    <text>Documents ... After all, don't you believe there is a device that controls you? The Doctor and I do. That is what we seek. Its location is somewhere in the Sarcophagus. But where, is unknown to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_free_dialog_6">
    <text>What's happened to me, half a day ago, I wanted to shoot you, but now I do not know. But bear in mind that if you get caught again, I won't be sorry.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_est_0">
    <text>Feldsher, Ghost is free.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_est_1">
    <text>Thank you, now I'm more convinced that I was right about you. You'll have to meet with the Doctor and talk to him; he can explain everything better than I. He's certainly able to help you.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_est_2">
    <text>I appreciate your concern, but I don't need your help. Let me follow my path to true 'C-Consciousness'. Also, warn Ghost that if our paths cross again, I won't save him.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_help_est_3">
    <text>You are stubborn, but oh well. Here, I have a recipe for transmutation, keep it, you may need it.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>Director, you called me?  </text>
</string>

<string id="haron_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes I did. We found Ghost. He's in Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>What now?</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>I learned some things about him. He needs to be liquidated, while he's still alive our work can't continue. I can think of no one better than you. So you get the honour of killing this young reptile.</text>
</string>

<string id="haron_finish_dialog_4">
    <text>I will not let you down, Charon!</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_0">
    <text>Feldsher, what happened?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_1">
    <text>Have you been given the task to kill Ghost?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_2">
    <text>Once again I'm amazed at your knowledge. I think you know more about me than I do.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_3">
    <text>I am the assistant of the Doctor who lives in the Swamp, and don't forget it. Some patients, so to speak, out of a sense of gratitude for the Doctor, help ... well, I hope you understand.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_4">
    <text>Okay Feldsher get to the point.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_5">
    <text>You must not kill Ghost.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_6">
    <text>I have my orders! Even though it displeases me, I must, Ghost is a shady character.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_7">
    <text>Mmmm ... I do not want to, but ... probably will have to ...</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_set_actor_8">
    <text>What are you talking about? Hey...</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_0">
    <text>Oh what happened to me? I feel sick. I feel like shit.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_1">
    <text>Nothing, be a little patient. Relax! I injected you with a potent sedative. That, let's just say, is the after-effects from it.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_2">
    <text>My head, something's wrong, I can't remember anything.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_3">
    <text>Don't worry your memory will return, but gradually. I hope this will help you remember who you really are and how you ended up in Pripyat. I do not know what to call you; you're out there in his Brotherhood almost without a name, brothers, in one word, yes. I'll give you a helmet to use. Don't lose or sell it, it will protect you against psionic radiation. If you take it off, then the Monolith will control you again.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_4">
    <text>Man give me time to recover ... I ... my name is Strelok, I remember! I remembered why I came to Pripyat. I'm looking for my brother! You ... do you by chance know anything about a stalker nicknamed 'Captain', and the raid by Stalkers on the Sarcophagus more than two years ago?</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_5">
    <text>Well hello Strelok! I congratulate you on your return to yourself. I don't know of a Stalker called 'Captain', nor have I heard of a raid on the Sarcophagus two years ago, as I only recently arrived in the Zone ... Yes, and still, I just want to remind you: do not forget, your previous friends - now are no longer your friends. So, don't go back to Chernobyl it's unlikely they'll be happy to see you. I advise you to get away from Pripyat. You have to get to the Swamp Doctor - He can answer your many questions, maybe he knows something about your brother. Ghost can help you get to the Swamp. Speaking of Ghost, he is in danger; I know that Charon always insures against failure, he would have sent others in case you didn't succeed. You need Ghost alive, so do not let him die.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_6">
    <text>Feldsher or whoever you are, I don't remember Ghost, Charon, or the others. Why can't you take me to the doctor?</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_7">
    <text>You'll see, your memory will return gradually. We're stuck here in Pripyat. The old route to the Swamps through the Radar is now inaccessible, and yet another ... But as I said, Ghost can help you find the path to the Swamps, and I still have some business here in Pripyat. I'll download Ghosts position to your PDA. You shouldn't have any trouble finding it. It's possible Charon's people are already there. I hope you haven't forgotten how to use weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_neytral_8">
    <text>I think it's innate ... Okay, I'll find Ghost.</text>
</string>


<string id="prizrak_doc_need_0">
    <text>Are you Ghost? I think we've met before.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_need_1">
    <text>Something like that.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_need_2">
    <text>No No, I do not remember.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_need_3">
    <text>Recently ... well you still don't remember. Listen to me, Feldsher asked me take you away from Pripyat to the Swamps to the Doctor, but there is a problem. The passage down to the Radar is being monitored by Mercenaries. And even if you get through, further down there has recently formed a sufficiently strong Psy-emission where no gun will help you, and you will die rapidly and painfully. When it moves around is unknown, but you have no time to wait. There is one additional Secret Path to the Swamps from Pripyat. But where is it? There is information somewhere in Chernobyl's Control Bunker. There should be secret documents there. If you find them bring them to me and I'll try to decipher them. They should show the transition point. Be careful in there. Do you remember your way back to the bunker?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_need_4">
    <text>Yes I remember. I will try to get the documents.</text>
</string>


<string id="prizrak_doc_est_0">
    <text>Ghost here are the documents from the Control Bunker.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_est_1">
    <text>Got them? Good for you! I'll have a look at them. Yeah ... so ... all figured out. Now you go to Fang, he will escort you to the  transition place. I'll load the coordinates of the transition to your PDA, and he'll show you the way, it's not far from here, and it's safer if you both go.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_est_2">
    <text>Copy that! I'm already going. Yes, I think I remember everything now. I recall for example that I recently rescued you from captivity by the Mercenaries.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_est_3">
    <text>I see your memory is coming back quickly. Okay go. There's no time to waste. Good luck and thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_doc_est_4">
    <text>Stay healthy, Ghost, I hope to see you again.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Are you the tooth fairy er ... I mean Fang?</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Wise ass! Yes, Ghost told me you were coming. Are you ready to go?</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes I'm ready! I'm all finished here.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_start_dialog_3">
    <text>We'll go slowly. We want to avoid any Monolith patrols. Let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Are we there?</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, here look, the transition to the Swamps is just behind me. I've marked it on your PDA. All right brother so long. Good luck, I'll be seeing you. Give the Doctor my regards.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>And to you too. I'm sure we'll meet again.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Wait, wait a minute ... there is something Ghost wants from us. Yeah, that's ... he sent a message. In short, he asks us to return.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Shit! We've almost crossed from Pripyat to the Swamps and now he wants us to return.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>Don't worry it'll be quick. Ghost said that he had forgotten something very important to convey to the Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="kliyk_perehod_dialog_6">
    <text>Ah okay then let's go back to Ghost.</text>
</string>


<string id="suvenir_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello again. Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="suvenir_dialog_1">
    <text>I forgot, Feldsher has a gift for you, three army med kits and something unique, a Gravity Gun. With this weapon you can pull things to you like weapons, artifacts, corpses, anything that can move. You can use it to make anomalies from artifacts. Pick them with second fire mode and when you shoot the artefact, it's transformed into the anomaly that created it. It's a terrible weapon, okay? Be careful where you create them, Burner or Springboard anomalies can lead to dire consequences, especially in the Swamps. Here, take this, as they say, good luck, brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="suvenir_dialog_2">
    <text>And good luck to you. Please thank Feldsher for me. Do you know if something terrible awaits me there?</text>
</string>

<string id="suvenir_dialog_3">
    <text>Stick to your guns! You are a clever man so everything will be fine! If anything you know where to find us. Now go, the Doctor is waiting. Oh and my advice to you, do not try to touch the Doctors patients. He would not like that, get it?</text>
</string>

<string id="suvenir_dialog_4">
    <text>I understand. I'll go to the Doctor in the Swamps, till we meet again.</text>
</string>


<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_0">
    <text>You are who?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_1">
    <text>You don't know, you bastard?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_2">
    <text>You don't believe me? I really don't know. Feldsher in Pripyat thoroughly cleansed my mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_3">
    <text>You know Feldsher?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_4">
    <text>Do I know Feldsher? Yes he told me he cleared my head. I'm as pure as an infant. Like being reborn.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_5">
    <text>Feldsher is the assistant to the Swamp Doctor, but the Doctor told me nothing about you ... hmmm.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_6">
    <text>Believe me I'm not lying I simply don't know. I have not yet met the Swamp Doctor, but I've heard a lot about him from Feldsher.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_7">
    <text>What is your name?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_8">
    <text>My name is Strelok! You stole all my weapons, gear, loot and money. Give it all back you jack ass.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_9">
    <text>Don't yell at me! I did not take your things or your money. I don't do such things. I found you here lying unconscious as they say, in your shorts. Apparently those who robbed you had decided that you had already paid your dues, otherwise they would not have left you alive. Consider yourself lucky.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_10">
    <text>If not you, then who mugged and robbed me?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_11">
    <text>I don't know. I can only assume that it was one of your old friends from the Sarcophagus. Now listen here Strelok, do not move, I'll slowly ... very slowly give you a shotgun and some ammunition and some army med kits. Understand?</text>
</string>  

<string id="aes_solomon_dialog_12">
    <text>I may have been reborn, but I'm not stupid.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Listen, why do you help me?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>It's because of the Doctor. Thank him if you see him. He together with Feldsher once saved me. They cleansed my mind as they did yours. I now find myself obligated to him for the rest of my life.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>But why have you not left?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>Where to? And why? I am in good standing with Charon. He gave me command of CNPP-2. Here I am practically my own master. Yes sometimes it is necessary to carry out his dirty work. But then you do not know how long I would survive on the side of their enemies. Yes, I am old now.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>Listen I'm going through to the other side. Do you have a request?</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>Hmmm ... Yes perhaps there is one thing. I'd like to send a parcel to the 'Mainland'. I have a daughter that I haven't seen for about ten years.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Wow that's a long time. I'm unlikely to find her.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_7">
    <text>There is a person at the Cordon, a merchant they call Barkeep, he will help you. When I was a loner I was amazed at what kind of contacts we had. If you do it, I'll give you a recipe for transmutation.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_8">
    <text>It's not necessary, I'll take the parcel to Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="aes_solomon_pismo_9">
    <text>It is necessary brother, I am thankful, such are the times. Well then since you've agreed I'll send the Barkeep a note. Perhaps he still remembers me. I'll download the recipe onto your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Barkeep, I've brought a parcel from Solomon who is in the CNPP.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>What am I to do with it?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>It needs be sent to The Grand Theatre, to Solomon's daughter.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>Moscow Arts Theatre! Are you crazy? Most come here from the CNPP to the Cordon to take a rest for a week or two, to drink litres of Vodka, but you, you utter such nonsense. Are you hunting for a woman? Do not bother me about this kind of stuff.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>Barkeep I'm not here to drink Vodka or hunt for a woman. I just need a parcel delivered. What do you want in return?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>Do you think it's that easy? There too are people who need to be paid off.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Okay Barkeep what do you need in return?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_7">
    <text>Two Crystal artifacts, Got any?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_8">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_9">
    <text>I don't have any.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_10">
    <text>Then two Pellicle artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_11">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_12">
    <text>I don't have any.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_13">
    <text>When you have something then come back.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_14">
    <text>Give me the Crystals, do not worry, I have reliable channels, everything is tiptop.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_solomon_pismo_15">
    <text>Give me the Pellicles, do not worry, I have reliable channels, everything is tiptop.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_0">
    <text>Hello Barkeep! How about the shipment?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_1">
    <text>Have you got them?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_2">
    <text>Yes I have two Crystal artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_3">
    <text>Yes I have two Pellicle artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_4">
    <text>No, Okay I'll go look for them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_5">
    <text>Give me the Crystals, do not worry, I have reliable channels, everything is tiptop.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_two_solomon_pismo_6">
    <text>Give me the Pellicles, do not worry, I have reliable channels, everything is tiptop.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_0">
    <text>Well, friend, lucky I got here in time.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_1">
    <text>I thank you Stalker. I'm still in one piece.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_2">
    <text> Apart from that, who are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_3">
    <text>I'm called Zahar.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_4">
    <text>What are you doing here, can't you see it's a dangerous place?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_5">
    <text>I live here alone, I don't bother the mutants, and they leave me alone, so we live in peace,  but these ... they've strayed from Pripyat. It's crazy, it's the first time I've seen them.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_6">
    <text>Zahar why don't you choose another place? Not only is it not safe here, but lonely.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_7">
    <text>Previously, I worked at the CNPP, I lived in Pripyat, with my family and friends. And then the disaster ... my wife died, the children too ... And I ... I was the only one of my family to survive, only because of the work I was doing at the time. I was an electrician installing a cable underground. Where do I go now? Here is my family, my home.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_8">
    <text>I'm sorry for your pain and loss. I did not know.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_help_est_9">
    <text>Thank you, but time heals all wounds.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_0">
    <text>Zahar, what's the matter?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_1">
    <text>I need to find Cyril.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_2">
    <text>Who is he?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_3">
    <text>He is a bloodsucker, a friend of mine. A boar almost ripped him to death, but I was able to heal him. And since we live together, in honour of my dead son, I named him Cyril.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah, one word - Z.O.N.A.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_5">
    <text>Help me, brother, find him! I am afraid that it you don't, he will be ripped to pieces. He does not touch locals, he prefers boars, and these stray ... it can be.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_6">
    <text>But, what if ... Won't he attack? He does not know me?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_7">
    <text>Since I cured him, he has not killed one person, although I must say, he has not seen any for a long time. There were several bandits, who survived when they emptied their cache, and then departed, to the warehouses. If you help me, I will be in your debt, and I will even reveal to you the transition point from the 'Military Warehouses' back to here to the "ATP". This way will come in handy.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, I will look for the beast. But, if it attacks me, don't blame me if I don't let it have me for dinner.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_est_0">
    <text>Regards, Zahar.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_est_1">
    <text>Hello, but I do not know what to call you.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_est_2">
    <text>My name is Strelok. I found Cyril - he was almost eaten by wild boars, apparently, not only he loves them.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_kirill_est_3">
    <text>Thank you, twice you've helped me. Here's a recipe for transmutations, I found it on a dead Dutier in Pripyat, take it, is useful. And, as promised, the reverse transition from the 'Military Warehouses' to the "ATP".</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Zahar, it's time for me to go, thank you for your hospitality.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>What's an old man to do now? Well, good luck.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>Do you need anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, actually, I do have a request. A man exists, by the name of Dan, we previously were neighbours, I remember him as a child.  He lived with his mother, his father had died.  Well, some might say, I replaced his father. Now that my family has perished, he is the closest to having relative I have. But where is he? I know that he's in the Zone, but what is his destiny?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_4">
    <text>Is there is a network of Stalkers, you can search through? Do you have a PDA?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_5">
    <text>No, Strelok, I don't. I do not know how to use one. A letter is personal, I do not want anyone to read it. In general, a request from me to you: If you find Dan, give him this.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay Zahar, if I find Dan, I'll give it to him.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_pismo_dialog_7">
    <text>You go now, I enjoyed our conversations, they were never boring. It's not the same talking to Cyril.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_0">
    <text>Hi Zahar, it's been a long time.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_1">
    <text>Yeah, a long time ... While you were away, something happened.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_2">
    <text>What happened?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_3">
    <text>Bandits came, they told me to clear out. They gave me two days. But I've become accustomed to this place. Where will I go? They are about to arrive any minute, I await them...</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, we'll see about that. Zahar, do not worry, help has arrived.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_5">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, there's so many of them, I fear they will overpower you.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, Zahar, I come well prepared, so do not worry!</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_est_0">
    <text>Well, old man, I told you there was nothing to worry about!</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_est_1">
    <text>Well, you outsmarted them. It was not easy, my son ... Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_est_2">
    <text>Okay, old man you're alive and well.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_band_est_3">
    <text>Here, take something, in gratitude.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_0">
    <text>Zahar, have you things to trade?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_1">
    <text>I can offer buckshot, med kits or standard cartridges for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_2">
    <text>I'll take the Buckshot.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_3">
    <text>I'll take the med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_4">
    <text>I'll take the cartridges for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_21">
    <text>I can exchange five packs of buckshot for either 8 Blind dog tails, 6 Boar hooves, 6 Chimera claws or 2 Wrenched artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_211">
    <text>Zahar, I have eight Blind Dogs tails.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_212">
    <text>Zahar, I have six Boars hooves.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_213">
    <text>Zahar, I have six Chimera claws.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_214">
    <text>Zahar, I have the Wrenched artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_215">
    <text>I have nothing today.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_31">
    <text>I exchange three med kits for either 8 Pseudo-dog tails, or a Slug, or a Stone Flower, or a Gravi artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_311">
    <text>Zahar, I have eight Pseudo-dog tails.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_312">
    <text>Zahar, I have a Slug.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_313">
    <text>Zahar, I have a Stone Flower.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_314">
    <text>Zahar, I have a Gravi.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_41">
    <text>I'll exchange five packs of standard cartridges for the AK for either six Bloodsucker tentacles, a Meat Chunk, or two Slime, or two Jellyfish artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_411">
    <text>Zahar, I have six Bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_412">
    <text>Zahar, I have a Meat Chunk.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_413">
    <text>Zahar, I have two Slime.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_zahar_change_414">
    <text>Zahar, I have two Jellyfish.</text>
</string>


<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_0">
    <text>Oh, I've almost forgotten ... It seems that I have something for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_1">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_2">
    <text>News from your friend ... From Zahar. You do know him?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_3">
    <text>Zahar? I haven't heard from him for a very long time. I thought that maybe he died. Where did meet you meet him? How is my old friend doing?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_4">
    <text>Zahar's all right, he has long been a hunter in the forests, wandering through the fields. He asked me to deliver a letter to you. He says he wants to make peace.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_5">
    <text>Does he, the "old fogy"! I never got angry at him nor do I hold a grudge. Foolishly, we had a falling-out. Anyway, that is - it is ... Good news you have brought me, man.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_pismo_zahar_dialog_6">
    <text>Here, keep the letter.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey guys, who are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_1">
    <text>We are Freedom members, and who are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_2">
    <text>I'm called Strelok.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_3">
    <text>Strelok, are you interested in some work? If you help us, we will be in your debt.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_4">
    <text>What sort of work?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_5">
    <text>Look, you see the base nearby? Well there are soldiers there. Belchuk, their Commander is a rare breed. They caught three of our guys last night near the wall. That bitch, wait till I get my hands on him.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_6">
    <text>Yeah I see, what's next?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_7">
    <text>This base is necessary to us. If we don't keep the soldiers out, for Stalkers, the passage into the centre of the Zone is closed. So we look for free Stalkers who are not afraid to come with us. As you see, we are only a small group. Another extra gun wouldn't hurt. Will you come with us? Do not worry, I'll pay well.  Brother, you think about it, the Zone is our home, yours and mine, and no soldier should dictate where and why we go. With them here, every day is a risk. The other day we lost a friend ...This Belchuk is a putz. They fall greedily to power and our brothers who get caught - are shot on the spot.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, okay brother, you persuaded me, well when do we do this?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_9">
    <text>Right now.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_vstrecha_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, let's go.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, Lukash, the base is our! Belchuk is dead.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, the job is half done.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you mean, half done? You said that it was only necessary to capture the base.. well it's done.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_3">
    <text>We have more soldiers to dislodge at the Barrier, and then the route to the centre will be relatively free. </text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_4">
    <text>Yeah right, but why didn't you tell me before?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_5">
    <text>If I did you may not have agreed to help. Now's the time to seize the Barrier, don't worry you will be paid. Come on brother, hurry while the soldiers are off guard. </text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_6">
    <text>Am I the only one to go?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_7">
    <text>No, certainly not, Cap and the boys will go with you. Stick with Cap, but he must survive!</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_baza_dialog_8">
    <text>Happily I agree!</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_0">
    <text>All is good, Lukash, the job is done.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, it worked well! You are indeed a master, you know.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, what's the situation?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_3">
    <text>Well of course, as I promised. Incidentally Strelok, I see that you are not like the rest of the vagrants around here, who are just searching for profit. I see fire in your eyes. What are you doing here in the Zone, if it's not a secret?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_4">
    <text>You're right, I don't seek profit - I'm looking for my brother, he was lost under very obscure and unexplained circumstances. I'm trying to find a trace of my brother, and maybe with luck - he himself. Have you heard of a man called 'Captain'? More than two years ago he, with a group of other Stalkers, went to the Sarcophagus?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_5">
    <text>No, I've not heard of a Stalker by that name. About the sortie into the heart of the Zone, I heard from others. Anything else I do not know. Anyhow take this reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_after_dialog_6">
    <text>Nevertheless thank you Lukash. Ok, give me my reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_0">
    <text>Halt!</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_1">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_2">
    <text>Listen peasant, this territory is ours and cannot be travelled free of charge.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_3">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_4">
    <text>2,000 rubles for a one-time pass through our territory.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_5">
    <text>Buggers, I left my Travellers checks at home.</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_6">
    <text>Cash then!</text>
</string>

<string id="esc_koha_prohod_7">
    <text>Well, I see you're a business man. When returning you will see us, so do not forget to approach me! Here Duke is the main dude, he always was and always will be our leader. Remember, no cash, no passage!</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_0">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_1">
    <text>Good day, I have a business proposal for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_2">
    <text>What's the proposal?</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_3">
    <text>I purchase PDA's of dead stalkers.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_4">
    <text>Why do you need them?</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_5">
    <text>Well, I should inform you as much as possible as the profession requires. Listen, for 10 PDA's I'll give you a few small things, and that would be: ammunition, medical supplies, and parts of the monsters. If you bring 20 PDA's, then I'll give you information about caches. True, you could be lucky and find these stashes yourself, but then again you might not.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_buy_pda_6">
    <text>Agreed, if I find any PDA's I will bring them to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_0">
    <text>Hi, how's life, heard any rumours?</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_1">
    <text>No, no rumours, get to the point, what have you had brought?</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_2">
    <text>Here, I've brought you 10 PDA's.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_3">
    <text>I've had a rich day. Here's 20 PDA's.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_4">
    <text>As a matter of fact I don't have any PDA's, I'll bring them in due course.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_5">
    <text>For the 10 PDA's, then take this, as promised.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_6">
    <text>20 PDA's - they have much information! Give me your PDA and I will mark the position of the hidden cache.</text>
</string>

<string id="informator_beret_pda_7">
    <text>Well then, until next time.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_0">
    <text>Borov, I want to buy something.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_2">
    <text>I have cartridges and weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_3">
    <text>Cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_4">
    <text>Weapon.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5">
    <text>What kind of ammo?</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6">
    <text>I have a Saiga and an AK-47.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5111">
    <text>Standard for the AK-47.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_51">
    <text>7.62x39mm, 3 packs for five cans of preserves.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5211">
    <text>Armour-piercing for the AK-47.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_52">
    <text>7.62x39mm armour-piercing, three packs for four bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5311">
    <text>For the AK, standard.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_53">
    <text>5.45x39mm, 3 packs, for five loaves of bread.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5411">
    <text>For the AK, improved.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_54">
    <text>5.45x39mm BP, 3 packs for four bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5511">
    <text>For LR -300, standard.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_55">
    <text>5.56x45mm SS109, three packs for five knobs of sausage.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5611">
    <text>For LR -300, improved.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_56">
    <text>5.56x45mm AP, three packs for four bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5711">
    <text>For the SVD, standard.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_57">
    <text>7.62x54R of 7N1, three packs for a Stone Flower artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_5811">
    <text>For Vintorez, Shaft, and ThunderStorm, standard.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_58">
    <text>9x39 PUB-9, three packs for a Slime artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6111">
    <text>Ak-47.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_61">
    <text>Ak-47 for two Mica artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_6211">
    <text>Saiga.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_62">
    <text>Saiga for two Meat Chunk artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_611">
    <text>AK-47 - my favourite weapon, come here.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_612">
    <text>It is somewhat expensive.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_621">
    <text>Saiga? All right, Snorks, beware! Here, take 2 Meat Chunks.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_622">
    <text>No, not today, I'm empty.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_511">
    <text>Come on, ya gotta have the usual.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_512">
    <text>I ate the canned food, I was hungry.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_521">
    <text>Do you have armour-piercing for the AK-47? Give.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_522">
    <text>Nope!</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_531">
    <text>I need standard cartridges for the AK, I'm running out.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_532">
    <text>Nope, all gone.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_541">
    <text>Armour piercing? Come on.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_542">
    <text>Nope, we took a bit of a walk in the village yesterday.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_551">
    <text>I need cartridges for the LR -300.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_552">
    <text>All gone.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_561">
    <text>Armour-piercing NATO rounds? Come on.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_562">
    <text>I don't have any Vodka left - I drank it all with the guys.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_571">
    <text>Give it to me, I have a Stone Flower.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_572">
    <text>I don't have any Vodka left - I drank it all.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_581">
    <text>Ok, give me the ThunderStorm.</text>
</string>

<string id="trader_bratok_dialog_582">
    <text>Do not have any today.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_0">
    <text>Good morning!</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_1">
    <text>What has brought you to me, Stalker?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_2">
    <text>Lukash told me that you can show me how to get from the territory of the Military Warehouses to the Bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes I can show you the path to the Bar, but only if you me help. You arrived at an opportune time. There is an urgent matter here: after the Military warriors were repulsed they left some documents behind. Where they are now, who knows; but they're at the base that's for sure. If you could find them before Freedom ... I would like to see these documents before Lukash's people find them. Let's just say, for ethical reasons.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_4">
    <text>Do I understand you correctly? You want me to find some documents at the Freedom base.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_5">
    <text>Precisely! If you find documents for me, I will show you the way to the Bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_6">
    <text>How do you suggest I find these documents? There are so many of them and I might not live long enough to find them all. And I must continue on my journey.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_7">
    <text>Hold on, brother, don't get excited. This folder is special, I assure you. It's hidden, but not among other documents, (whispers in a very depressing voice), on the envelope should be written: Agents and Case Number. This folder is in a protective waterproof and fireproof transparent cover. So that it can lie anywhere, even outdoors. OK? I am very ... very willing to pay for them, Stalker. So apart from the transition to the Bar I will give you a recipe for transmutating artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_dialog_8">
    <text>Well it's in good hands. I'll find you the documents at the Freedom base, as it is necessary for me to get to the Military Warehouses.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_0">
    <text>Hello, I was at the base.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_1">
    <text>Well? Did you find anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I found them. Entertaining reading, I caught a glimpse of something very important to me in those documents ... I didn't just come here by accident - I am looking for my brother, for whom I've been searching for a long time. He's called 'Captain'. In the secret folder, I found mention of him. These notes are relatively new according the dates. You know anything about my brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_3">
    <text>You shouldn't have poked you nose in them. Oh well! And about your 'Captain': I think you've already found out - he recently joined the group Duty, as their guide, he is a seasoned Stalker now. The entire area, inside and out has benefited because of him. I hope you find him soon. I hope I've been of help.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_4">
    <text>This is the best news I've had since I entered the Zone! Thank you for the information about my brother. But where do I find this group called Duty?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_5">
    <text>As far as I know, Duty is now based in the Dark Valley. You have to go through the Bar to get there. It is true that you will have to go through the Garbage, but that is just a minor detail. I will note on your PDA the transition to the Bar as promised, and I will give you a recipe of transmutations, it is useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_6">
    <text>Thanks, hand it over.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_7">
    <text>Well, I'll give you some free valuable information. There lives in the Zone, in a tunnel at the Agroprom, a person called Sorcerer. He is engaged in black magic. The most interesting thing is that he can resurrect the dead. So if you need to bring back someone to life, then look for him at the Agroprom.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_est_8">
    <text>Well, thanks for the info! I hope I do not have to use the services of the Sorcerer's 'black magic'.</text>
</string>  

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_0">
    <text>Can I do something else for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_1">
    <text>Yes you can, there's an emergency. Some guys, Diggers, got into trouble at the Radar. Someone robbed their cache, they are now without food or medicine.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_2">
    <text>What is required?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_3">
    <text>Well, in general, this is easy. What I gathered for them should be sufficient. Your task is to deliver the parcel. Here are their coordinates. At the same time I will show you the transition from the Military Warehouses to the Radar. It will come in handy later.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_osvedomitel_second_4">
    <text>Ok give me the coordinates as I need to hurry. I'll go to the Radar and help out the guys on the way. I can search for artifacts. And I need to find Prince anyway. They say there are a lot of artifacts out there, such as the 'Klondike'. Oh, and then I'll to the Bar for a drink and relax a bit. Hopefully I can get acquainted with Duty and track down my brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_0">
    <text>Who are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_1">
    <text>It's better not to ask. All I saw was this damn Bloodsucker, a powerful one. Shot it with my revolver and didn't hurt it. Good that it was well fed. It didn't try to kill us, so no one was harmed. We could have been infected. The Zone takes what it wants. Ok Stalker, what you doing here?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_2">
    <text>Oh yeah, I nearly forgot, I'm here on behalf of Snitch, he has collected some things for you, he said the other day you were robbed. Well, here are a few items for you: food, med kits and Vodka. As for me, I'm searching the Zone for my brother, we were separated a long time ago, he's called 'Captain'. Have you heard anything about him or his team?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_3">
    <text>No, I'm sorry, I have not heard anything. But thank you, you saved us. How can we reward you? Wait there is something! We found weapons and cartridges in someone's cache. What would you prefer? NATO or ours?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_4">
    <text>I'll take NATO.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_help_5">
    <text>I'll take ours.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, I've wandered into another wilderness. Do you have a job for me?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_1">
    <text>How about hunting?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_2">
    <text>What, the marked bloodsucker, the one almost tore you to shreds?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_3">
    <text>It has a birthmark! Or are you chicken? I wish to make an effigy in memory of it.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I'm not afraid, where do I find it?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_dialog_5">
    <text>Here, it is close to us. I'll put a marker on your PDA. Kill the creature and drag the carcass to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_0">
    <text>Shit, that damn beast was hard to kill.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_1">
    <text>How did you handle it? I still do not understand.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_2">
    <text>Yeah, had to fuck with it. Okay, here is the carcass, take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_krovosos_est_3">
    <text>Damn creature stinks of infection. Well as agreed, here is a med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_0">
    <text>What's next?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_1">
    <text>I think we need to catch that bastard who stole our things from the cache.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_2">
    <text>How do we do that?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_3">
    <text>It's very simple. Look, I'll put a little swag in one of our caches, and you hide in the bushes close by. I'm sure the thief is one of us, so I will gather the men and tell them about the swag. The 'rat' among us, will probably go and steal again, and there ...  I hope, it's up to you brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_4">
    <text>Sviblov, I will not fail you.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_dialog_5">
    <text>Only this, don't act prematurely. Wait until he comes to the stash, but then you never know, it could be just someone walking by. Don't be seen, the matter is delicate, and make sure you're not heard.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_0">
    <text>Greetings, Sviblov.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_1">
    <text>Oh, our saviour! By the way, what is your name?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_2">
    <text>I'm called Strelok.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_3">
    <text>So Strelok, so how's our deal?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_4">
    <text>Finished, everything is quiet now. However, Fyodor was the thief.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_5">
    <text>Oh, the devil, I also suspected him, but there was no evidence. Okay, thank you for your service. Yes, here is your reward, a silenced sniper rifle. The boys dug it up somewhere. I'll give you some ammo for it as well.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_6">
    <text>Thanks for the rifle! Oh, I took this off the neck of that thief Fyodor, it's some sort of ancient amulet, a very strange thing indeed. Here, look ... Do you have any idea what this thing is?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_7">
    <text>Yes a curious thing indeed... slightly radioactive, and obviously has some protective properties. You know what, show this Amulet to the stalker who is over there standing against the wall. He's recently returned from a raid. He should know what this thing is.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_predatel_est_8">
    <text>Okay, give the amulet to me and then I'll show it to him.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Sviblov if there's no more work I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_1">
    <text>Wait, there is something. I do have another job. I need you need to go down into the bunker and haul some stuff out from there. Just bring everything you can find in there.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_2">
    <text>Hmmm, it sounds a little vague. You need to be more specific.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_3">
    <text>We need a computer, and there may be some documents there as well. So bring them too.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood I'm on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_0">
    <text>Well Sviblov I found the place! The monsters were like cockroaches.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_1">
    <text>They were very important documents. Did you find them?</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_2">
    <text>Yes, here is the computer and documents.</text>
</string>

<string id="rad_sveeblov_lab_est_3">
    <text>You're good. I will give you a transmutation recipe. My guys removed this recipe from a Mercenary's PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_0">
    <text>Lukash do you have any more work?</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_1">
    <text>Work? No I don't have any as yet, but I do have a request.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_2">
    <text>What request?</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_3">
    <text>I need you to find someone.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_4">
    <text>To kill or what?</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_5">
    <text>You don't understand, there is a man - Lefty, a master of all trades. We recaptured the base, but there are still a lot of things to do - there are repairs to make, well, as you know. But he is not happy working for Duty.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_6">
    <text>Duty? Who are they?</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_7">
    <text>Military types, with crazy ideas - 'to clear the zone'. Well, we don't agree with them. Find Lefty and persuade him to join us ... We need him.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_8">
    <text>Well, if I can find Lefty, I'll try and talk him into it.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_9">
    <text>Don't keep us waiting. You see, we are desperate. Oh, and here at the Military Warehouses, in the village near the abandoned checkpoint there's a person called Snitch. He's a murky type, you need to see him, but be careful. To exit from this territory, you need to know where the transition is. As far as I know you can get only from the Military Warehouses to the Bar, but only Snitch knows the way. So go see him.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_need_levsha_dialog_10">
    <text>Okay, I'll go have a talk with Snitch.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Lefty?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I am.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_2">
    <text>They say you're a jack of all trades.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I can do much. What do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_4">
    <text>I've been sent by someone who wants you to come to his base, to do sundry repairs. Well, generally, fix everything that you can.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_5">
    <text>No, I'm no longer at Voronin's beck and call. Subordination, discipline, brrr, well, I'd rather live on charity.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_6">
    <text>No, not by Voronin, by Lukash.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_7">
    <text>Ah, to be part of Freedom, but how can I go to them? Look at me all I have are castoffs, my weapon is worn, and it's a long way to go. I'll tell you what, get me a new weapon, a Groza, and a new suit, something better than a Seva, maybe a Scientific Mercenary Outfit. And then I'll consider it, agreed?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_dialog_8">
    <text>Oh damn it, how did I get into this? Well agreed, I will find you a new Scientific Mercenary Outfit and Groza.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_0">
    <text>Well, Lefty, regards.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_1">
    <text>And to you regards. Well, did you find the new acquisitions for me?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I found everything. Here take them, as you requested the Scientific Mercenary Outfit and the Groza. All in excellent condition.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_3">
    <text>Oh, man, thank you! If you need something repaired at once you can contact me.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_about_lukash_est_4">
    <text>Okay, agreed. Good luck!</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_est_levsha_0">
    <text>Regards, Lukash.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_est_levsha_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, come in, what's new?</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_est_levsha_2">
    <text>I found Lefty. He, of course, was a little stubborn, but eventually agreed. So he awaits his guests.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_est_levsha_3">
    <text>As always, you didn't disappoint me, thank you. I owe you one. Oh, by the way, I need you to visit Skinflint as he has a serious problem.</text>
</string>

<string id="lukash_est_levsha_4">
    <text>Okay, I will go see Skinflint.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_0">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_1">
    <text>Brother, I need help.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_2">
    <text>Ok please explain. What is the problem?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_3">
    <text>Some friends of mine were captured by Bandits, and were put in a local prison.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_4">
    <text>Where is this prison?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, like yeah, they just converted an old bunker into a jail and all those captured, are held there.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, how can I help? Can you pay me or give me something?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_7">
    <text>The local big shot Duke won't speak to me since he captured my guys, and he is a big dude. But he might talk to you. Persuade Duke to release my guys. And I ... and I'll give a recipe for a transmutation.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_need_dialog_8">
    <text>Agreed, I will have a talk with Duke, but I promise nothing.</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, friend.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, Stalker. Where are you from? What do you want here?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_2">
    <text>I've came here to do business with you, so I have no time to waste.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_3">
    <text>Ok stalker what business do you have?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_4">
    <text>I've heard that you're holding a couple of Stalkers in jail because they owe a debt.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_5">
    <text>Soooo, Sahat has sent you, shit! He drives me crazy, he should be thrown out of the Zone, everyone is pissed with him.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, so what about the boys?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_7">
    <text>Yeah the shameful bitches, they stole my unique Winchester 12 shotgun, the one Lefty gave me for my birthday. I killed a pseudogiant with it ... but these rats. What happened was before I had a shower in the Bar, I placed the weapon in the rack because I knew that no one would touch it there. Then I went to the recreation room. I had a few hours sleep, and went back to the bar, there were only a couple of guys there, and Borov. I looked at the rack, and my weapon was gone. Well naturally I assumed this and that, but with a solid punch, Borov interfered. It turned out eventually that these two bastards had shortly left the bar. Well my training had paid off, I took off in pursuit and caught them. All they saw was one ugly looking gangster who ran out of the bar like a bullet and knocked them down. These guys wouldn't admit to the crime: "Who us? No, never Duke! We respect you and we value our lives too much.", and all that usual bullshit. Well, I had them placed in the slammer. I told them that if they didn't confess, and return the weapon plus a penalty, they could rot in there forever.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_8">
    <text>If I find the weapon will you let the guys go?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_9">
    <text>The weapon and a penalty, let's say 15,000 rubles.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_10">
    <text>Ten thousand and the gun, that's all I can afford.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, I agree friend. I hope you keep your word. Yes, you have to impress Sahat. He basically is sly, clearly not all that you claim.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, do you want me to help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Of course, why would I ask you then?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well then, cut out all the bullshit and tell me what happened.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I understand someone swiped Duke's Winchester and Cat was in the bar at approximately the same time. Well now everyone is thinking it was him. Moreover everyone knows that Cat is an avid gambler and always loses constantly. Admit it, with such a reputation is not difficult to point the finger? But it wasn't him.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_4">
    <text>Then who?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_5">
    <text>The boys, when they came into the bar, bumped into a guy and nearly knocked him over. They think it was him.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Well where should I look for this guy they bumped into?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_7">
    <text>Here's what I can tell you: when Cat was in the Bar prison with two others, I overheard him talking to a guy from the Bandit gang, his nickname was Walnut. He and two others, inexperienced Stalkers, went to get a very rare and valuable artefact. It was somewhere in a secluded area, a strange phenomenon had happened and all the known anomalies were in one place for three days, and formed a monstrous raging haze. During this time they spotted about a dozen of the rarest artifacts. They were all located in this same mess. Exactly where this place is, I didn't hear. But it is somewhere in the Dark Valley. The artifacts that were formed there disappeared into the ground. You would have to be lucky to find them. So these three decided to hit the jackpot and went there. But the place had so many monsters - Mama Mia! Well, the two inexperienced Stalkers pissed their pants and ran away. Walnut saw an artefact, so he jumped off the roof to get one, but the wind blew strongly and chimeras appeared. Well, he also then ran like hell. He ran for a long time but still could not get away ... he was wounded severely.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_8">
    <text>Why did you keep silent?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_9">
    <text>I didn't keep silent, no one here wanted to listen to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_10">
    <text>So, okay, it's clear. You better tell me, where I can look for Duke's shotgun?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_second_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, don't get pissed! I think that the Winchester is near Walnut's body. Where he was killed by a chimera. After all, beasts don't need guns ... The Bandits said this all took place in the Dark Valley. The two that ran away were near a small two-story building, which is at the gas station next to the unfinished factory. In it, Walnut tried to shelter, but no luck, you see ... There, in the house at a gas station, I'd look for it.</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_0">
    <text>Well, Duke, I found your Winchester.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_1">
    <text>And money, did you bring any?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I have the money.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_3">
    <text>No, there is no money.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_weapon_est_4">
    <text>Well done, but this is not what I expected, shit! You greased me, brother! All right, I'll tell my guys to release these two freaks.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Well are you satisfied? I found Duke's shotgun.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Thank you, that helped. And the guys, are they released?</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, Duke has already released them.</text>
</string>

<string id="saha_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>Well, I... Well, I'll... Write down the recipe, thanks to you again.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_dialog_0">
    <text>Anything I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_dialog_1">
    <text>Man, we need your help. Our brother, Lefty, was captured by Mercenaries. The guys are concerned because there are only a few of us left, each weapon is important. Help us out, brother, come with us. Please don't resent our comrade.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, Lefty! Yes, I need him.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_dialog_3">
    <text>Follow us.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_dialog_4">
    <text>Understood.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_est_0">
    <text>Bes do you have any cartridges??</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_est_1">
    <text>I can give you some for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_help_est_2">
    <text>Well give them up. Then I can kick butt.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_0">
    <text>What's going on here?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_1">
    <text>Bandits, they are looters and scum. We have declared a war on them here, almost cleaned them all out of the Dark Valley, but it did not last long, well now they are in revenge and decided to attack us all at once. Okay, we'll show them who's boss.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_2">
    <text>I see. You haven't really chosen a good place for the base.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_3">
    <text>Well, our clan is relatively young. Our forces have gathered and are waiting for us at the Bar. It's time to expel the Bandits again.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_4">
    <text>It'll be rather difficult for you have. Painfully, they are well entrenched.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_voronin_help_est_5">
    <text>Give us time and we'll get there. I, General Voronin, make this promise to you. By the way, thanks for the help. Here, take this from me, it'll come in handy.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_0">
    <text>Hello, Comrade Colonel.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_1">
    <text>Hello, Stalker, Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_2">
    <text>Well, I need to buy something.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_3">
    <text>I have cartridges, med kits and weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4">
    <text>Cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5">
    <text>Weapon.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_6">
    <text>Med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41">
    <text>What cartridges?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51">
    <text>What weapon?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_61">
    <text>Military.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_411">
    <text>Cartridges, armour-piercing, 5.45x39mm BP.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4111">
    <text>3 packs for a jellyfish artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41111">
    <text>I have a Jellyfish, take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41112">
    <text>Agreed.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_412">
    <text>Cartridges, sniper, 7.62x54R for 7N1.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4121">
    <text>3 packs - for a Meat Chunk artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41211">
    <text>Give me that sniper rifle you have in your rucksack.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41212">
    <text>No, I don't have any.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_413">
    <text>Cartridges, armour-piercing, 7.62x54R for 7N14.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4131">
    <text>3 packs - for a Flash artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41311">
    <text>Give me armour-piercing - this for that.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41312">
    <text>No I don't have a Flash.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_414">
    <text>Cartridges, sniper, 9x39 CP-5.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4141">
    <text>3 packs - for a Gravi artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41411">
    <text>Come then, for the Thunderstorm.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41412">
    <text>Will you take a Gravi?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_415">
    <text>Cartridges, 9x39 CP-6, armour-piercing.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_4151">
    <text>3 packs - for 2 Sparkler artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41511">
    <text>Yes, I have 2 Sparkler artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_41512">
    <text>No thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_511">
    <text>An-94 Abakan Sniper.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5111">
    <text>An-94 Abakan Sniper - for 2 Gravi artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51111">
    <text>Okay, I have 2 Gravi artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51112">
    <text>No thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_512">
    <text>Assault rifle, Abakan.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5121">
    <text>Assault rifle, Abakan - for 2 Sea Urchin artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51211">
    <text>Okay, I have 2 Sea Urchin"artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51212">
    <text>Prices!!! Prices!!! I think I'll stick with the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_513">
    <text>Noiseless modified sniper rifle SVU.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5131">
    <text>Noiseless modified sniper rifle SVU - for 2 Ruby Spring artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51311">
    <text>Ok, I have two Ruby Spring artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51312">
    <text>Never mind, I don't need it.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_514">
    <text>VSS Vintorez.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5141">
    <text>VSS Vintorez - for 2 Ruby Spring artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51411">
    <text>Give, I have a couple of Ruby Spring artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51412">
    <text>No, I don't need one...</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_515">
    <text>RPG-7V.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_5151">
    <text>RPG-7V - for two Stone Flower artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51511">
    <text>Give, I have a couple of Stone Flowe artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_51512">
    <text>It is somewhat expensive.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_611">
    <text>Army or what?</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_6111">
    <text>Army med kit - for one Slug artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_61111">
    <text>Give, I have one Slug artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_changhe_61112">
    <text>It is somewhat expensive.</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke yes -->

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_0">
    <text>Is there work, Duke?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_1">
    <text>Well friend aren't you afraid to work with us? You understand, we work on special tasks.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_2">
    <text>I understand, come out with it.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_3">
    <text>Here's your task, it's simple, there is a loser they call Jeka, he owes me money, just shameful. He's hanging out in the Garbage.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_4">
    <text>What should I do?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_5">
    <text>Two options: either to get the dough from this son of a bitch, or, ah, you know...</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_need_dolg_6">
    <text>Okay, I will have a talk with him.</text>
</string>


<string id="djeka_first_speak_0">
    <text>Are you Jeka?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_1">
    <text>Yes, how can I help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_2">
    <text>Duke sent me. Guess what we are going to talk about?!</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_3">
    <text>He's spoken to me before. I asked to him wait a bit, as things have been slow around here, but hopefully, they are about to get better. The Garbage is practically empty of artifacts, so basically we sit around with nothing to do.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_4">
    <text>This response will not satisfy Duke.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_5">
    <text>What do you want to do, kill me?! I have no money. Listen, there is another option.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_6">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_7">
    <text>I can suggest one thing ... it is a map, if it's analysed, you can find the location of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_8">
    <text>That is bullshit. Are you offering me this piece of paper?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_9">
    <text>No, I know what I'm saying. An old Digger gave it to me while we sheltered from an emission, I don't remember his name, I survived but he ... he told me that he and Semetsky had met earlier near the Sarcophagus, and they had formed a group of eight, plus Semetsky, who then went to them. He told them he was going on a journey and may not return, lastly he took out a map where his cache was marked. He divided this map into eight parts and gave one to each of the guys. Why, I do not know.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_10">
    <text>And what you do propose?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_11">
    <text>Well, I'll give you this map fragment if you have my debt cleared.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_12">
    <text>Surely you're lying. Ah ok, give me the piece of the map.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_first_speak_13">
    <text>No, brother, I know better!</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_0">
    <text>Regards, Duke.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_1">
    <text>Are you healthy and happy?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_2">
    <text>Yes I am. This Jeka, I tried to reason with him. It was necessary to shoot him. He won't put himself in any more debt now.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_gadnyi_durak_3">
    <text>Oh, I figured that guy wouldn't make it. People were getting fed up with him. Anyway, here take this</text>
</string>


<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_0">
    <text>Regards Duke.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_1">
    <text>Well did you have any success with Jeka?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_2">
    <text>Yes, he paid after I threatened him.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_3">
    <text>Well then give me the money.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_4">
    <text>Here take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_5">
    <text>Damn I lost my wallet in Garbage. I searched all over the place.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_igrok_normal_6">
    <text>Well done friend! Good work! And here's a little gift for your troubles.</text>
</string>

<!-- this is Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_trava_need_0">
    <text>Any work Duke? By the way I'm Strelok. You remember.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_need_1">
    <text>There is one thing Strelok, this task should be easy, then again it maybe not. We were to receive a delivery of a bag of 'grass', you know, the puff the magic dragon kind. The problem was an emission. The damn Zone was not being hospitable. The helicopter nearly crashed because the turbulence was so bad the pilots lost control of the heli and jettisoned the bag somewhere in the vacinity a small water tower	before they crashed. I sent a colleague to search the area, but he found jack shit. So consider that tower somewhat of a reference point.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_need_2">
    <text>You have a weak reference point, so how many kilometres do I have to crawl on my belly?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_need_3">
    <text>Yes I see your dilemma. Listen you go back to the nerds in Yantar. I'm sure they can help you. Just ask those egg-heads to put a label on your PDA where you can find this bag of 'grass'.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_need_4">
    <text>Okay, let's see... I gotta find it. So I need to go to the scientists in Yantar.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_0">
    <text>Greetings sir!</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_1">
    <text>Hello, Stalker. Are you hiding from mutants or are you here on business?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_2">
    <text>Basically on business.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_3">
    <text>Well, out with it.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_4">
    <text>Yes, I need a PDA marker for something.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_5">
    <text>What kind of thing? Speak clearly.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_6">
    <text>A bag of grass, marijuana probably. Maybe it's Columbian.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_7">
    <text>Wow, a valuable commodity!! We don't often get requests for such stuff. We can find it, no problem. But you understand there is a price.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_8">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_9">
    <text>Two Fireball artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_10">
    <text>Expensive of course, but oh well.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_help_metka_11">
    <text>The price is too steep, I'll find it myself.</text>
</string>

<!-- what should be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_trava_est_0">
    <text>Hello Duke!</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_est_1">
    <text>Cough it up, friend.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_est_2">
    <text>Here keep it! The bag is heavy and it's slightly water-logged. How it get wet I don't know.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trava_est_3">
    <text>Let it dry, no big deal! You work efficiently. I need to learn from you. Anyway, I have a proposition for you if you're interested.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_0">
    <text>Any way I can help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_1">
    <text>I see you are a hard working guy. Do you do not want make some money?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_2">
    <text>Hell yeah. What do you propose?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_3">
    <text>Well there is a way to make good money, but it's risky.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_4">
    <text>What exactly do you mean? What kind of work? Not macabre, is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_5">
    <text>Well there's this guy named Varangian, you can find him in the underground in the Agroprom. He has a game that pays well, but there is a catch.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_6">
    <text>What's the 'but' mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_7">
    <text>The problem is that no one has ever won, not once. Losing is death.</text>
</string>

<string id="djeka_predlagaet_work_8">
    <text>Sounds like fun. Well, I'll think about it. Maybe I'll check it out.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Varangian, right?</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, that's me. Have you decided to test yourself by going through the mutant gauntlet?</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well sort of.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Do you know the rules? No? I'll tell you. It is necessary to run four laps. Each lap will be increasingly more difficult and the mutants more insidious. If you finish all four consecutive laps you'll receive a reward: a recipe for transmutation, and a weapon - an M16 rifle. Remember! Until you complete all four laps it is not possible to leave the basements of the Agroprom, and you must surrender your weapons before you start. Only a knife is permitted, so you can't take anything else. You have to run to the end. When you get there you'll find a med kit and/or bandages. I hope you make it. After you get there I will give a signal when to return.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_0">
    <text>Understood!</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_1">
    <text>Well are you ready?</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_2">
    <text>Yep, I'm one badass stalker.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_3">
    <text>Give me your stuff. Remember you have to run all the way to the end. There will be med kits and bandages there for you. When you come back and I will have more med kits and bandages. And for each lap you will get less.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_first_krug_4">
    <text>Ok take everything.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_0">
    <text>Yes, like man, the truth is, these Zombies are bitches, very tenacious.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_1">
    <text>You're wounded, here take a med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_2">
    <text>Thanks.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_3">
    <text>Well, the first round is over.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_4">
    <text>Yes I know, I'm here ain't I.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_5">
    <text>Well it's time for the second round.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_second_krug_6">
    <text>Wish me luck.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_0">
    <text>The laps are more difficult now.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_1">
    <text>Take this med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_2">
    <text>Thanks again.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_3">
    <text>Well, are you ready?</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_tri_krug_4">
    <text>Ah, let me catch my breath ... ok I am ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_0">
    <text>Those damn bloodsuckers. I hate those creatures! I was almost torn into pieces.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_1">
    <text>Yeah it's best to avoid them, especially without a good weapon.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_2">
    <text>Anyway it's the last round.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_3">
    <text>Yes, you are right. Here take a med kit.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_four_krug_4">
    <text>All right, I'm leaving.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_0">
    <text>Hurray I made it!!</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_1">
    <text>You sure did, I didn't expect you to make it through. Well done! You are the only stalker that survived.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_2">
    <text>Okay, give back my things. I should eat something too.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_3">
    <text>Ok, here is your shit dude. And here is your prize and another recipe for a transmutation.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_finish_dialog_4">
    <text>Thanks, and for the recipe especially. I taught those Burers some humility.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_fail_0">
    <text>Damn Varangian, I did not succeed.</text>
</string>

<string id="agro_varayg_fail_1">
    <text>Here's your stuff, get out of here you meathead.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_need_0">
    <text>What do you want, brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_need_1">
    <text>Listen brother, I have two unique Mercenary weapons - M16's with an integrated optical sight. It is difficult to find cartridges for them. Perhaps some Duty guys would be interested. Take these guns, and in return I ask for cartridges, but only for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_need_2">
    <text>Well, I'm not really going that way...</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_need_3">
    <text>Come on brother, help me, I will be indebted to you. I also throw in some odds and ends.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_need_4">
    <text>Ok, I'm persuaded, give them here.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_0">
    <text>Hello Colonel.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok? What brings you here?</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_2">
    <text>Here I brought to you something.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_3">
    <text>Oh, M16's modified as sniper rifles? Where did you get them?</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_4">
    <text>Bes got them from two Mercenaries that where killed. He requests cartridges for the AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_patron_need_5">
    <text>The rifles are intriguing and worth money. Okay I will not detain you, here take the ammo. Say hi to Bes for me. A good man, sorry that he is no longer with us.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_est_0">
    <text>Hello Bes. Petrenko sends his regards and wishes you were still with them.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_est_1">
    <text>Well Strelok, I cannot go back to them. They have their ethics and I have mine, theirs is not to my liking.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_est_2">
    <text>Agreed brother, here are the cartridges, as promised.</text>
</string>

<string id="bes_patron_est_3">
    <text>Thank you, and I have something for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_0">
    <text>Hello Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_1">
    <text>Welcome young man, what do you need of me?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_2">
    <text>Yes, I came to purchase something. I will work for food.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_3">
    <text>Hmmm ... Okay, but can you handle tough tasks?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_4">
    <text>I'll try, Professor, I'm capable.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_5">
    <text>Well, here's your assignment: we found several species of monsters that have surprised us with their abilities, namely, they regenerate very fast. We are very interested in why and how this mutation occurs, and need to observe them. To do this, they need to be tagged.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_6">
    <text>You're joking, right?! Where are they now and how would I tag them? It's not likely they'd cooperate.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_need_7">
    <text>A Pseudogiant was last seen in Rostok near where a helicopter has crashed. A Bald Chimera can be found in the Dark Valley, you know near the abandoned factory where the Bandits occasionally hang out, behind it is a small swamp, right by the fence, where the sewers discharge, Understand?! A bloodsucker lives in the Cordon at the abandoned pig farms near the destroyed trestle bridge. Now on how to hang the tags, I'll give you a special Protecta weapon, it's been converted by one of our craftsmen. It fires a special-cartridge, which when contacting the body of a target will apply a tag without causing any harm. Thus you will be able to hang a tag on all three mutants. And don't forget to return this shotgun, you can't kill anything with it, and we still need it. If everything goes to plan I will mark on your PDA some useful information about the transition from Yantar to Radar and back. Obviously these experiments with mutants must be done while they are alive.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_est_0">
    <text>Professor, I've returned.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_est_1">
    <text>You managed the mission well, Strelok, I did not expect it, to be honest.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_est_2">
    <text>I told you, Doc. that I was capable. Although, I had to run my arse off.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_first_work_est_3">
    <text>Well give me the shotgun and I will mark the transition from Yantar to the Radar on your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_0">
    <text>Well Doctor do you have any more work?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_1">
    <text>There is one very delicate matter. One of our researchers, Associate Professor Dorodina, betrayed us by stealing a very rare artefact. He sold it to a corrupt customer on the 'Mainland'. It earned him a lot of money, which he then deposited to a bank account. Then he arranged with three soldiers to him get out of the Zone. Along with him went another scientist, his assistant, who has very valuable data which could earn him a considerable amount of money on the 'Mainland'. His memory is phenomenal, all the information is in his head, without that brain power neither Dorodina nor anyone else would associate with him.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_2">
    <text>So, what do you need me to do?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_3">
    <text>For his treachery he should be punished severely! Eliminate Dorodina, period. With his assistant, do what you consider necessary, so that he is no longer a threat to us, but he should be punished as well.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_4">
    <text>The Military and I have crossed paths before, and they won't be happy to see me.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_need_5">
    <text>I'll give you the mission to eliminate Dorodina and Dan has all the details. It seems everything is already planned out. After all he is our head of Security.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_second_work_need_0">
    <text>Hi Dan. The Professor said that you know what is going on and will explain everything to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_second_work_need_1">
    <text>Regards, Strelok! I see Sakharov briefly told you about the treachery Of Dorodina and his assistant. We tracked their movements and these two are still in the Zone. They are in the Dark Valley under the protection of three corrupt soldiers. They are waiting for a helicopter to take them out of the Zone. You should find them and eliminate them. Dorodina must be terminated - it's your primary objective. The second guy, the traitor, should also be shot. That's just the way it is.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_second_work_need_2">
    <text>Understood. So, how am I to do this?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_second_work_need_3">
    <text>You're familiar with Lab X-18 in the Dark Valley aren't you? On the right is a hilly field with a lot of anomalies and mutants. There is a fence near the edge of it. I will put a marker on your PDA. Anyway, these three soldiers who guard the traitors are clearly specialists. You really don't have to deal with them, just the traitors. Get on the roof of the X-18 complex, there is a great sniping spot there. You will have to move quietly and quickly to get on the roof. And remember your main goal - the elimination of Dorodina. He should be terminated quietly and most importantly, don't let the soldiers see you, otherwise the mission might fail. The two scientists are wearing the same green Research Suits, that will help you indentify them - once in position, bring them both down with a bullet. Once you kill both of these traitors, the soldiers should be peaceful. I'll be in touch. Read the messages from me...</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_0">
    <text>Dan, do you have a sniper's rifle?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_1">
    <text>I can give you an American M14 sniper rifle and 30 sniper cartridges for it.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_2">
    <text>How much?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_3">
    <text>Not much, just 4 Fireball artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_4">
    <text>Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_trade_5">
    <text>I don't have any.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_est_0">
    <text>Professor, good day.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_est_1">
    <text>Come in, Strelok, you have completed the job. I am pleased with your cooperation.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_est_2">
    <text>Nice to hear. Hopefully this will be reflected somehow in my reputation. Right?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_est_3">
    <text>You know, I've been thinking that you still have time to earn some weapons and ammo. I will give you more valuable information and a couple of recipes for transmuting artifacts. Give me your PDA and I will load the information about the transition from the Agroprom to Yantar and vice versa. Oh, and again your help is needed. We have a person missing. Kruglov has the information, talk to him please.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_second_work_est_4">
    <text>Ok I will go talk with Kruglov.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_0">
    <text>Professor do you have anything for sale?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_1">
    <text>Cartridges, med kits, weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_2">
    <text>How much for the cartridges?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_3">
    <text>How much for weapons?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_4">
    <text>How much for med kits?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_21">
    <text>For the ammo I've got: \n
 1) "7.62x51 mm NATO" - 2 packs of three Droplets artifacts,  \n
 2) "7.62x51 mm NATO PSU" - 2 packs for 2 Fireball artifacts,  \n
 3) "12.7x99 mm" for the WA-2000 sniper rifle - 2 packs for one Pellicle artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_31">
    <text>These are the NATO sniper rifles:  \n
 1) GALATZ - for - one Soul artefact, \n
 2) The SR-25 rifle - for a Crystal artefact,  \n
 3) HK 417 Automatic Rifle  - for a Moonlight artefact, \n
 4) Occasional WA-2000 sniper rifle - for 10 Poltergeist Eyes.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_41">
    <text>Scientific med kits - 3 for 10 Cat Tails, or antirads - 2 for 10 Burer Hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_211">
    <text>Give me 7.62x51mm NATO I have 3 Droplets artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_212">
    <text>Give me 7.62x51mm NATO PSU, I love armour-piercing cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_213">
    <text>Give me 12.7x99mm for the WA-2000 sniper rifle.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_214">
    <text>No, professor, nothing today.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_311">
    <text>Give me the Galatz, if you have cartridges for it.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_312">
    <text>Give me the automatic SR-25, I'll test that beast.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_313">
    <text>Automatic rifle HK 417? Well, I'll try it out.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_314">
    <text>WA-2000 Sniper rifle - my dream, I take without looking.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_411">
    <text>Scientific med kits are necessary, I'll take some.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_trade_412">
    <text>I'll take the antirads, otherwise my missions might fail. My nuts already itch.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_0">
    <text>I met with 'Captain'. He is not my brother ... my mistake.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_1">
    <text>It's a shame, I sympathize with you.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_2">
    <text>General, Captain Sobolev said that you can show me the path to the Cordon from the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_3">
    <text>Well we might know after a while. I sent a Scout to the factory where the Bandits are entrenched. There, he can obtain information about where they store their data about transitions from the Dark Valley. In the meantime you can help us.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_4">
    <text>It is agreeable, General, I will wait. How I can you help?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_5">
    <text>I can see that you can handle weapons, so I think there is a job for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_6">
    <text>What should I do?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_7">
    <text>Recently a lot of different mutants have bred near the X-18 Laboratory. This area around X-18 must be cleared of all mutants. The Scientists have long asked for this, but somehow we never got around to doing it.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_need_8">
    <text>Roger that General. I am on my way.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_est_0">
    <text>General, may I report?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_est_1">
    <text>Greetings to you, Strelok. Are you kidding? Okay, what's with the mission?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_est_2">
    <text>Task completed, the area is clear, the way into the lab is safe.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_snork_est_3">
    <text>Good for you, and here is the reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_0">
    <text>Well how about the transition to the Cordon, General?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_1">
    <text>Listen Strelok, according to our data, somewhere in the abandoned factory in the Dark Valley there is a bandit stash. If you find it, take everything. We suffered quite a serious blow from a local gang of bandits. In this stash, there are many weapons and there's a flash drive or disk with information about the transition to the Cordon.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_2">
    <text>General, that's a big plant, looking there for a bandit stash without exact coordinates is like looking for a needle in a haystack.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_3">
    <text>I understand, but if everything was so simple, we would have found it ourselves. I can tell you there is a man, a Bandit called Vein, find him, and he can help you to find the stash.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_4">
    <text>Isn't it strange, a Bandit will help me to rob their own?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_5">
    <text>He has some kind of deal with the bandit leaders apparently, so I think that if you talk to him nicely he would help. By the way, he once gave useful information to one of my scouts.</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_6">
    <text>Where do I find this Vein?</text>
</string>

<string id="vorornin_nychka_need_7">
    <text>It is necessary to search somewhere near the factory, exactly where I cannot say. He hides from everyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_0">
    <text>Hello, are you the bandit called Vein?</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_1">
    <text>Well I suppose I am, what you want?</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_2">
    <text>Well if you are Vein, then I must speak with you.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_3">
    <text>What do you need to speak to me about friend?</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_4">
    <text>You possess certain information which I need. Do you know where the Bandit stash is?</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_5">
    <text>Ah, so that's it? Why the fuck should I tell you?</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_6">
    <text>To put it bluntly: I can affect you health, others you do not have to worry about. And here I can be your saviour. Will you help me? I will put in a good word for you to Voronin that we have a deal on the basis of trust.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_7">
    <text>Ok friend, let's do a deal: first you negotiate with General Voronin and then I will tell you about the stash. You may hold the most of trump cards, but I still have one. If I tell you about the stash now, then I will no longer be useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_nychka_need_8">
    <text>Fine, wait for me, I will return soon.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_0">
    <text>General!</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_1">
    <text>What's up, Strelok?</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_2">
    <text>I found the Bandit, he agrees to reveal the location of the stash. But he ... He wants your protection and to be allowed back onto the base.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_3">
    <text>Why would I want any Bandit rabble here? The guy's stuff would begin to vanish. I know these criminals, only the grave will stop them.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_4">
    <text>General Voronin, he's not a thief, he's a former Paratrooper, he was just unlucky. He went to prison, and there he learnt about the Zone. After his release he had now where else to go. Because your group doesn't accept ex-cons, you rejected him and only the Bandits would take him in. He's a good guy, I can vouch for him.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_after_jila_nychka_need_5">
    <text>Well, if you vouch for him then give him this warning. Steal, and he is up against the wall.</text>
</string>


<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_0">
    <text>Regards, Vein.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_1">
    <text>Hello.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_2">
    <text>All right, Voronin agreed, you can move to the base. I fulfilled my part of the contract so now it's your turn.</text>
</string>

<string id="jila_give_info_nychka_3">
    <text>Listen up me. The stash is on the roof of the main part of the former factory. You will need to climb to the roof. You'll be going over some wooden plants toward a window. I'll mark your PDA. It will help you find it quickly.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_0">
    <text>Here, General, take - all that I've found.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_1">
    <text>Good stuff, weapons and many rounds of ammunition. You can equip a small army.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_2">
    <text>There's still that flash drive you spoke about.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_3">
    <text>That's fine! Well, the Bandits won't 'be happy' when they discover that their stash is empty. Here, take it, you earned it. So, let's see what's on a flash drive. Wait a minute...</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_4">
    <text>Well, what is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_5">
    <text>There is data about the transition. I'll mark your PDA with the transition from the Dark Valley to the Cordon and back.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_nychka_est_6">
    <text>Well, that's good. Now I can go to the Cordon.</text>
</string>


<string id="dan_racia_zahar_0">
    <text>Is there something you wish to say?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_racia_zahar_1">
    <text>I want to ask you about something. By the way, what's your name?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_racia_zahar_2">
    <text>I'm Strelok. What do you want to ask?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_racia_zahar_3">
    <text>I have a portable radio, take it to Zahar. I want him to have constant communication. The instructions are inside. I think he will understand them. Tell him I am no longer mad at him.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_racia_zahar_4">
    <text>It's far away, but yes, I have the time - I will deliver it.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_racia_give_0">
    <text>Zahar, hello.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_racia_give_1">
    <text>Hello, Strelok! Did you decide to visit again? Did you find your brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_racia_give_2">
    <text>No, I haven't found my brother yet, but I found your friend Captain Sobolev, he works with Duty now. He asked me to tell you he doesn't hold any grudges. Here, he has sent you this portable radio unit for keeping in contact with him. Instructions are inside.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_racia_give_3">
    <text>Thank you, Strelok! You brought an old man good news. Take this - here a little buckshot, as a thank you from me.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_racia_give_4">
    <text>Don't mention it, Zahar. Today I helped you - tomorrow you me. Since we live in this damn Zone, so it...</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_0">
    <text>Can I help with something else?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_1">
    <text>Um, well there is one little matter in which you can help.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_2">
    <text>So, fill me in.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_3">
    <text>Yes, the last time I used the transition to the Military Warehouses and back to our camp was to collect a few artifacts. As I passed near a small swamp, in the northern part of the Forest, I ran into a pack of pseudo-dogs. They chased me into the swamp, I barely escaped these creatures. But the thing is, I dropped the container with the collected artifacts, somewhere in the swamp. I did not have time to search for it and had to run quickly back to camp as it was getting dark. Thank God I managed to get back before nightfall. My feet still hurt.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_4">
    <text>I understand that you want me to go to the swamp and find your container with the artifacts?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_5">
    <text>Yes, it would be good if you could help me. I would be indebted to you. I'll have to mark the spot on your PDA. However, you will have to search in the water...</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_6">
    <text>Well, Zahar, point out the place to search and I will try to help you.</text>
</string> 


<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_0">
    <text>Zahar, I found your container in the swamp.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_1">
    <text>Well, thank you, Strelok</text>
</string> 

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_2">
    <text>The swamp was heavy with creatures, they were almost the death of me, but I managed.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_3">
    <text>Yes Strelok, the mutants in the Forest have multiplied. I haven't had time to shoot them yet. Well, give me the container, and here's something I've prepared for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_vodyanoy_est_4">
    <text>Here, take your container and don't lose it!</text>
</string>  
  

<string id="dan_zombi_need_0">
    <text>Regards, Dan.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_need_1">
    <text>Long time no see. But we have a Zombie problem, you understand, every day more and more of our comrades fall. Listen up; this is what I think...</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_need_2">
    <text>What?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_need_3">
    <text>At the plant at Yantar, there are many monsters and zombies ... Ufff ... And this scum is out every night, howls, moans, screams and growls, for a whole week I couldn't sleep. This is what I propose: it is necessary to clean out the territory. Are you interested?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_need_4">
    <text>That task is not easy. Does it pay well?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_need_5">
    <text>To be honest it doesn't pay much. But I do have a grenade launcher and charges for it, here take them and make good use of them.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_est_0">
    <text>Hello, Dan. Well I killed off all the mutants.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_est_1">
    <text>Yeah, heard weapons firing and screaming ... Finally I can get some sleep.</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_est_2">
    <text>Do you want the grenade launcher back?</text>
</string>

<string id="dan_zombi_est_3">
    <text>No, keep it as a reward, and I'll throw in some more cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="petruha_about_tolik_0">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="petruha_about_tolik_1">
    <text>My friend, help me out, Tolik has sent an SOS, but I cannot leave my post, Wolf has put me here. Lately we've have a problem with the Bandits. Well, get to the camp and then Wolf will explain everything. But don't go into the village because there are Bandits there. Without someone as experienced as Wolf, who would protect the camp? The Rookies, they've scattered, it's understandable. Anyway I have been talking too much and Tolik needs your help.</text>
</string>

<string id="petruha_about_tolik_2">
    <text>And where do I find him?</text>
</string>

<string id="petruha_about_tolik_3">
    <text>Tolik is somewhere near the transition to the Garbage. So go there and find him. Hurry brother and watch out for mutants. God forbid if something happens to him!</text>
</string>

<string id="petruha_about_tolik_4">
    <text>Okay I'll go find Tolik.</text>
</string>

<string id="tolik_need_help_0">
    <text>Hey, are you Tolik?</text>
</string>

<string id="tolik_need_help_1">
    <text>Oh brother, I'm fucked.</text>
</string>

<string id="tolik_need_help_2">
    <text>Well, you don't look so bad. The main thing is you are still alive.</text>
</string>

<string id="tolik_need_help_3">
    <text>Brother, help, help me get to the camp. Wolf will thank you. I'm afraid I'll not get there because I have double vision right now. Wow, I was fighting a bloodsucker. Then a couple of wild boars appeared and it went after them. I was sure lucky.</text>
</string>

<string id="tolik_need_help_4">
    <text>Well brother come on, let's go before it comes back</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_0">
    <text>Are you in charge?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_1">
    <text>Yes I am. They call me Wolf. Thanks for helping Tolik get here.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_2">
    <text>No problem, I don't mind helping Stalkers. Most wouldn't.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_thanks_tolik_3">
    <text>True, brother, not everyone would rush to help others. Some would only help for weapons or artifacts. I have some something for, accept a little gift, and dont be offended.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_0">
    <text>Petruha told me about the Bandits.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_1">
    <text>Oh, yeah ... Shit happens: Barkeep sent me to the Agroprom, and I took the more experienced guys with me. All that was left in the village was Fanatic and some Rookies. Well, the Bandits took advantage of this and came, they shot half, and the other half - scattered. Fanatic was always drunk - he needs to drink less. When he dozed off, even the sound of gunfire couldn't wake him.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_2">
    <text>Why haven't you tried to recapture it?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_3">
    <text>We are outnumbered by 2 or 3 to 1, and our guys are Rookies.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_4">
    <text>Well, can I help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_5">
    <text>Well, it is evident that you are an experienced Stalker! Of course you can help. Our chances are better with your help to expel these Bandits. We could still use some more experienced Stalkers though. Listen up, you could go help a small group of Stalkers, they have been delayed on the road, they said they fear the mutants, and they do not want to move. They are camped not far from here. If you help them they can get here faster, then in no time we could clear the village of all Bandits.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_6">
    <text>Yes I'll go help them, are you coming?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_7">
    <text>Haven't you heard?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_8">
    <text>No, about what?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_9">
    <text>These mutants have multiplied. It is now too dangerous. No brother I will not go with you, it is too risky.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_10">
    <text>Okay, I'll go alone, tell me where?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_11">
    <text>Well, if you're not afraid, then listen, I can put a label on your PDA. When you find there Stalkers persuade them to join us. If they agree, lead them here. Then we can try to recapture the village.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_about_tainik_12">
    <text>Understood. I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="podmoga_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Stalker! Are you looking for Wolf?</text>
</string>

<string id="podmoga_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, we are. Only, we fear to go any further ... There were five of us, but mutants tore apart two, so it was necessary to harbour here.</text>
</string>

<string id="podmoga_dialog_2">
    <text>Got it. I'm here to escort you to Wolf. Don't be afraid, you can move quickly with me. If anything, I'll cover you. Deal?</text>
</string>

<string id="podmoga_dialog_3">
    <text>It's a deal. Great. To be honest, we are very tired and afraid all the time now. Finally, we're pissed off. Come, lead us.</text>
</string>

<string id="podmoga_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, let's get going. No one lags behind.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_give_pda_0">
    <text>Wolf, here's your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_give_pda_1">
    <text>Well thank you! All right, now give the guys some weapons.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_give_pda_2">
    <text>Okay, I'll do it straight away.</text>
</string>


<string id="novice_talk1_0">
    <text>Shalom!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk1_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk1_2">
    <text>Thank you, now I can kick some Bandit's butt!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk2_0">
    <text>Bonjour!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk2_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk2_2">
    <text>Thanks, this is better than my PM.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk3_0">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk3_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk3_2">
    <text>Thank you.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk4_0">
    <text>Hi!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk4_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk4_2">
    <text>Well, all the Bandits will have to answer to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk5_0">
    <text>Hey!</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk5_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk5_2">
    <text>Give them to me, they will be very useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk6_0">
    <text>Regards.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk6_1">
    <text>Here, take this weapon and ammunition.</text>
</string>

<string id="novice_talk6_2">
    <text>Nice, I was getting tired of running all the time.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_0">
    <text>Well, Wolf, I've brought you the guys.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_1">
    <text>I see, well done; now we can act. Oh, the Bandits will be overwhelmed. I want you to lead, as I'm not very experienced, so the main task will rest on your shoulders. Don't get to far ahead, stay with me until reach the village, and then act on the situation.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_2">
    <text>Got it, it's not the first time. How do we advance?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_3">
    <text>Stay close to me, so we can cover the Rookies, so that they won't flee.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_0">
    <text>Well Wolf, we can rejoice, the village is ours.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_1">
    <text>Yes brother, thanks to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_2">
    <text>Hey, why didn't the Bandits attack Barkeep?</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_3">
    <text>Barkeep? Well I'll tell you, that sly old fox seems to wiggle out of trouble, and who will touch him with his connections? Bandits too, need to eat and drink and buy weapons. Many of them pass through here.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_4">
    <text>Well Wolf, come on, I need to see Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="volk_talk_vilage_est_5">
    <text>I have a transmutation recipe for you that will come in handy.</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_0">
    <text>Hello Duke! Got any work?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_1">
    <text>Oh, some people! There is here one thing Strelok. Some of my guys are going to meet with some 'Chekhovians'.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_2">
    <text>And who are these 'Chekhovians'?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_3">
    <text>Just riff-raff, lawless morons basically. They work for Stone Blood artifacts. They are brainless piss-ants. Blah ... they are useless. It is necessary to consider them freaks.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_4">
    <text>Well, so what is the problem?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_5">
    <text>The problem is that I don't believe their bullshit. We agreed that the meeting will be held without weapons. Yeah right! In any event, there will be an old pal of mine there named Cross. I fear for his life. It is necessary to protect him, just in case the situation gets out of control.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_6">
    <text>Where will the meeting take place?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_need_7">
    <text>At the Garbage near the transition to the Dark Valley. Do not let them see you. 'Chekhovians' are nervous, yet they have amassed many enemies. If they get spooked they will start shooting immediately. There is a ruined building nearby. That's where you can climb up to and oversee what transpires. If everything is okay they will disperse peacefully with weapons holstered, but if all hell breaks loose don't leave these cretins alive, and remember Cross must survive. Wait for my signal before you start shooting and don't be seen. Sit still and wait. I know what you're like with a gun in your hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_0">
    <text>Hello Duke.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_1">
    <text>Well, if it isn't Strelok. I hear you handled the situation skillfully.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_2">
    <text>Yes, I almost fell asleep thinking that everything in the world was at peace. And then your message.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_krest_razborka_est_3">
    <text>Okay in respect for Cross here take this for clearing out a small mob of 'Chekhovians'.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_1">
    <text>And hello to you Strelok. Do not want to earn some money?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you need done?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_3">
    <text>We have discovered a new artifact, until now it was unknown to. It's called the Heart of the Controller. We need you procure one for us.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_4">
    <text>Where can I find this artifact? This is the first time I have heard of it.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_5">
    <text>There is only one place and that is in the Agroprom. There in a small swamp with a trailer in the middle of it. Someone said it was there. But beware this artifact has a strange property. It emits telepathic waves which greatly suppresses brain activity. Furthermore, to discover it is only possible by using a special instrument which needs to be worn on your belt.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_6">
    <text>What kind of device? Where can I get it?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll give you the device, it's unique, if you hang it on your belt, and you will be able to find the Heart of the Controller artifact. Without it, you won't succeed.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_need_dialog_8">
    <text>Okay, give me the instrument and I will hang it on my belt. I will try to find this artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Regards Professor, well, about that job you gave me.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Hard was it?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_2">
    <text>There was a Controller, I had to get tough.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_3">
    <text>This artifact attracts Controllers, why - is not yet known, but there is something that draws them to it. Anyway, here's what I suggest, you give me back my instrument and I'll pay a reward for the Heart of the Controller artefact, or you can keep this device as a reward and with it you can seek out more artifacts and return them to me. I'll pay you for each artefact you find. Without this device you will not find them, that's for sure. Yes, I will pay for rare artifacts, but not broken ones! Think about it.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_4">
    <text>No brother, pay me now for work and you take back your instrument.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_art_est_dialog_5">
    <text>Okay, I'll take the instrument, it will prove useful.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_0">
    <text>Hi, Kruglov, I've changed my mind.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_1">
    <text>What are you talking about?</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_2">
    <text>I want to take your device, because you say you will not pay for a bad Heart of the Controller artifact, and without it I can't find any.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_3">
    <text>I can give you one, but not for free.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_4">
    <text>What you do want for it?</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_5">
    <text>Necklaces Ladies Burer.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_6">
    <text>Yikes, expensive, but oh well, keep it.</text>
</string>

<string id="actor_need_detector_7">
    <text>I don't have one ... I'll bring one later.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_0">
    <text>I have a standard anomaly detector. Do you have a better one, by any chance?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_1">
    <text>Yes, I can exchange one for artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_2">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_3">
    <text>One artefact, Heart of the Controller. I'll exchange it for an Elite Detector.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_4">
    <text>I'll take the detector.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_elite_detector_5">
    <text>I'm going to look for one.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_0">
    <text>Hello Kruglov.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_1">
    <text>And to you, Strelok, hello! What did you bring?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_2">
    <text>I brought the artefact, Heart of the Controller.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_change_3">
    <text>You've done well ... A rare artefact indeed. Here is your reward.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, I need to talk to you.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_1">
    <text>About what?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_2">
    <text>Do you deal in information?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_3">
    <text>I do, if it's any good.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_4">
    <text>I have some map fragments; if I had all the pieces I could put all them together to show the location of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_5">
    <text>Well?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_6">
    <text>Well, I searched the entire area, but some parts cannot be found. Can you help determine the coordinates of his cache?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_7">
    <text>There is one person, but you understand....</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_8">
    <text>What is required?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_9">
    <text>An artefact, a Bengal Crystal Soul.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_10">
    <text>Wow, costly! Well I guess I will go look for one.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_dialog_11">
    <text>You search for it, and I will come up with something, I need to think.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_0">
    <text>Hello Snitch, I've not come back empty-handed!</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_1">
    <text>What did you bring?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_2">
    <text>Here, take this artifact, Bengal Crystal Soul.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_3">
    <text>Good, give it here.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_0">
    <text>Well, what happened to our deal?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_1">
    <text>Had to work it out. The information that you provided, was not enough, but still...</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_2">
    <text>What do you mean? Youre being vague.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_semeckii_est_post_3">
    <text>Oh, don't get flushed! Don't worry everything is fine. Let me put the coordinates of the cache on your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_0">
    <text>Okay.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_1">
    <text>I have information about the transition from the Radar to the Dark Valley and back.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you want for it?</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_3">
    <text>Two artifacts, Tears of the Chimera.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_4">
    <text>Here take them, I cooked two this morning.</text>
</string>

<string id="osvedom_trade_perehod_dialog_5">
    <text>So, we need 2 Droplets, based on them we obtain 2 Tears of Fire, and then ... Remember to cook them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, hello, Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok, I've been waiting for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Oh, you know me?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_3">
    <text>I remember stuff. I know many, if not all Stalkers. Well, okay, let's get to the point. I know you are looking for your brother. He came to me - he was good. I don't know where he is right now. Maybe sometime later I can help you.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Yes you really are the centre of information. No wonder Stalkers speak about you knowing everything.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Strelok, skip the compliments; you've must find Mahomet, right? Yes, that's right, I know. Mahomet is an experienced Digger-Loner, an X-Jihadist, and he irritates the hell out of Sidorovich who is a trader and who holds an important position in the Peacekeepers Corps. So you have to see Sidorovich. He will tell you where to find Mahomet. I too need to talk to him, but I cannot contact him now because after the last emission the Zone has expanded into large parts of the Peacekeeper's area, and there is something strange going on with communications. I also have news to send to Sidorovich, understand? So we have a common interest.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_6">
    <text>And what do you propose?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_7">
    <text>I'll have to think about it, I will consult with some Stalkers in the Peacekeeping Corps territory; until I solve this, go help some good people.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_8">
    <text>But who are these 'good people', and how do I help them?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_9">
    <text>You know them - Fang, Ghost, Feldsher... Should I continue?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_10">
    <text>Yeah, they're all familiar to me ... What do they need from me?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_11">
    <text>You understand, many do not believe in the extraterrestrial origin of the Zone. The common theory is that could not have happened without the intervention of man. You do realize that there are several laboratories in the territory of the Zone?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_12">
    <text>I know, I even visited some of them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_13">
    <text>Well, what are they? What experiments were carried out? It is unclear ... Military frequented some of them, and found documents.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_14">
    <text>Continue.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_15">
    <text>We need to find these documents. Or something that can shed some light on this whole situation.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_16">
    <text>Where can I find the documents? I'm more than sure the Military has removed them from the Zone.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_17">
    <text>You're right, of course. But, you must understand in order to reach the laboratory, it's necessary to know the Zone really well. Surely someone led the Military there. You know what I mean? They must have had a guide. He was either a Stalker or former Stalker who joined the Military.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_18">
    <text>How do I find him?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_19">
    <text>I'll help you. I know who the guide was, a Stalker named Varangian. I can even tell you where to find him, at the Agroprom. I can't be more precise than that, find him and try to talk to him. He's a serious guy, so be careful with him. Go, while I work out how to get you a 'pass' for the Peacekeeping Corps, so you can get past the Military checkpoint. Find Varangian, learn what he knows, then report back to me at once. By that time I will figure something out.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_start_dialog_20">
    <text>I love businessmen. Okay, all clear, I am going to Varangian.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_zanat_0">
    <text>Are you Varangian?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_zanat_1">
    <text>Well I am, what can I do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_zanat_2">
    <text>I have a couple of questions for you, I was sent by Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_zanat_3">
    <text>I have no desire to talk to you. All the more, to answer your questions, your Barkeep can drop dead. Piss off! Don't disturb me.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_0">
    <text>Varangian, regards!</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_1">
    <text>Oh, hi Strelok, what brings you back here?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_2">
    <text>Listen, Varangian, this concerns you, Barkeep has sent me. Remember, when you were assigned to a Military lab? Well, we're looking for some documents.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_3">
    <text>Why do you and Barkeep want these documents?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_4">
    <text>Believe me Varangian, it is necessary, very necessary to find them.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_5">
    <text>Anyone else - would be shot, but you're the first who was able to win my ... Okay, listen: it was about a year ago, I was a Digger with a vengeance, and I came here and investigated the area inside and out. I was particularly interested in the various dungeons and laboratories. However, here I found a place where there were lots of artifacts, I grabbed them all. I hit the jack-pot, so to speak.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_6">
    <text>Please continue.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_7">
    <text>Oh and note, with regular trips back to the Cordon, I always took the direct path to Barkeep. I was in a good mood and I muttered under my breath about the artifacts in my backpack being fairly good, and out of nowhere, the Special Forces appear. I was overpowered and taken to the checkpoint. And there ... Major Yarofeev, the bastard! He threatened me - either I lead the Military group to the laboratory or get shot here and now, since officially in this area, everything and anything that moves, is subject to automatic destruction. Well, what to do? I agreed with this 'mother fucker'. So, I took his soldiers to the laboratory, and out of ten people, only half survived. He told me after all, I was just a piece of meat to them who knew the way. Also, we had seen a fancy Burer in Laboratory X-18. Anyway, they found the box of documents and we all went back to the Cordon. There I struck them down since I was more than sure I could shoot Yarofeev. Damn, why did I let him live as a witness?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_8">
    <text>Listen, those documents, do you know where they are now? Approximately anyway?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_9">
    <text>Come on! Like I have nothing else to do but read some documents. I wished to survive and for me this was the main thing. I think you should find Major Yarofeev, he is bound to know something.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_10">
    <text>Where can I find him?</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_11">
    <text>Where, where, at the checkpoint, where else? Though he is cunning, he is always drunk, so most likely he will always remain at the checkpoint. He'll get plastered and sleep for two days, so wake the prick. In short, ask Barkeep as to Major Yarofeev's whereabouts.</text>
</string>

<string id="varyag_about_lab_12">
    <text>Well, thanks Varangian, I will go to Barkeep in the Cordon, I think he will be able to tell me how to find Major Yarofeev.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_0">
    <text>Hello, Barkeep. I've seen Varangian - he's a serious man.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_1">
    <text>Well, did you learn anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_2">
    <text>Yes, I did find out something. There is a Major at the checkpoint named Yarofeev. He is precisely who we're looking for. He should be the key to getting the information we need. Do you know if he is at the checkpoint right now?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_3">
    <text>Yes, I know this louse. I have an idea, picture this: let's have a little war with the Military, it's time. You won't be alone, I have three brave men, and they are close to the checkpoint, just to the left, in the valley where the mine field is. I'll tell them to advance to the checkpoint. While they distract them, you try to get through, well, then - you can act on the situation. Go with God, Strelok. The guys will clear the road to the Peacekeeping Corps. After you extract the information from Yarofeev fill me in, tell me what and how, and then I'll give you a pass to the Peacekeeping Corps and a letter for Sidorovich. That's the plan.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_yarofeev_talk_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll be back.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_0">
    <text>Well, Yarofeev, we need to talk.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_1">
    <text>Who the hell are you?</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_2">
    <text>You better drink some water and then listen attentively, your response will determine whether you live or die.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_3">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_4">
    <text>Remember Varangian? A year or so ago, he led a group of Military to the Laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_5">
    <text>Wait... well yes it was, like... It was - I remember! But what do you want from me?</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_6">
    <text>I need to know what was in those documents that were removed from the Laboratory.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_7">
    <text>But how could I know? That was a top secret operation, what can I tell you?</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_8">
    <text>Well, if you do not know then I don't need you.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_9">
    <text>Wait ... wait, I really don't know what was in those documents, but I remember that one of our leaders, a Colonel I think, spilled the beans on the subject. We drank a lot, yes, I remember it now, and the booze loosened his tongue. He spoke about the fact that in this laboratory, experiments were conducted on prisoners, some of which impacted on the brain. To what extent, I really don't know. I also remember that the Colonel said that it would be necessary to go to X-16, another Laboratory. There must be some more important documents there. Just how do you get there? Two groups have already disappeared, and there is virtually no place for a helicopter to land. All the pilots say as soon as you start to fly into the territory of the laboratory the helicopter does not handle correctly. The place has some kind of devilry.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_10">
    <text>Is that all?</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_11">
    <text>I swear, that's all, I know nothing more.</text>
</string>

<string id="yarotheev_about_lab_12">
    <text>I need to deal with you ... Well, Okay - you can live, but if you're lying - don't blame me, you will be shot.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_0">
    <text>Regards, Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, what happened with Yarofeev?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_2">
    <text>I learnt from Major Yarofeev that in Laboratory X-18, mind experiments were conducted on prisoners, and that there is another Laboratory called X-16. He indicated that there are some more important documents or other things still there. But to get there is not easy and there is some evil there too.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_3">
    <text>I've heard about this lab - indeed, it's a dangerous place. Well, I need to consult with someone, and decide what to do. In the meantime, you should go to the Peacekeeping Corps and find Sidorovich in the village in the northeast and give him this encrypted message from me. But at the same time you should also learn about Mahomet. Here, take this letter and the pass for the Peacekeepers - show it to the sentry at the gate, they should let you pass - they are not warriors, they first think, then shoot. But nevertheless, be careful with them. Tell them, that you work as a guide for the Military at the Cordon. About the pass, don't worry - it's, well, almost real, no one should challenge it.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_dialog_4">
    <text>It is clear, give me the letter and pass, and I'll move on.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_0">
    <text>Hey, Barkeep.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_1">
    <text>Well what's new?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_2">
    <text>I delivered your letter to Sidorovich. He in turn sends you a response. Here take it. I learned from him where I can find Mahomet. For this I need to see the scientists at Yantar. So, going to the Peacekeeping Corps has been very useful. However it was necessary to shoot and run a little, but I'm used to it. Okay, what's next?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_3">
    <text>Wait, now, lets see what Sidorovich says ... Well, well, an interesting proposal. Well, I will have to think...</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_4">
    <text>What is the importance there?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_5">
    <text>Yes, I have very important things to plan. But, until you reveal some secrets I cannot. I'll have to think things through carefully and consult with someone before making a final decision. Now down to urgent matters about Laboratory X-16 about which Yarofeev spoke: you have to go into the lab at Yantar and find anything: documents, computer, laptop. In short, anything that will help us to understand what was happening there. All the more, as I understand it, this will help in finding your brother. To get to the X-16 lab will not be easy. They say that in the laboratory there is something that burns the brains of all living things. You need to ask the scientists at Yantar, maybe they can help get you into the laboratory. Talk with Sakharov. Yantar by road is through Rostok. Ask Earl how to get there, he has asked for you to do an important job for him anyway. I think you know where to find him, especially since it's on your way. While you are working on this issue I need to think about Sodorovich's proposal. Your help will be needed later. Remember to take what you find to Fang, he'll be waiting for you at a farmstead near the Freedom base at the Military Warehouses.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_about_lab_6">
    <text>Understood, I'm going.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Hi, Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, your here, I'm always glad to see you. How are you? Did you find your brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_2">
    <text>No, unfortunately I haven't. I'm here on a somewhat different matter. I need your help to get into lab X-16.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_3">
    <text>They say that there is a kind of Psi-working machine there which destroys the brain of any living creature. I don't know how to help you.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_4">
    <text>Professor look I have a helmet, maybe it is possible to do something with it?</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_5">
    <text>Give me a look. It's well made. Your helmet should shield the radiation coming from the unit, but apparently all the protection from your helmet will not be enough. You know, I thought of this: if your helmet can be reconfigured then perhaps you will be able to pass into the lab.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_6">
    <text>Professor, can you do it?</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_7">
    <text>But alas, I cannot.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_8">
    <text>But who can?</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_9">
    <text>There is one person, that we had once worked with. Then something strange happened to him. He began to shout at night, then suddenly he would became silent and would just sit and stare at something all day, then he got even worse and he began to throw things at people. We ... I had to part with him. Apparently he experienced a wave of radiation from the laboratory. It was decided to eliminate him, so Dan and his guys went to the Radar to kill this crazy Professor. They spoke to Sviblov who said the crazy Professor had fled. So you need to find him. He once, a long ago, had been occupied with studying the effects of Psi emissions on the brain of humans and kept a journal. In this journal there are valuable notes. And if we procure this journal then I could retune your helmet.</text>
</string>

<string id="saharov_about_lab_10">
    <text>Got it, I'll talk to Sviblov.</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Sviblov, hello.</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_1">
    <text>Hi Strelok, what has brought here?</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_2">
    <text>Sakharov has sent me to you. I'm looking for the crazy Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_3">
    <text>This loony escaped at night by using his teeth to gnaw through the rope and fled even though he hurt his neck in the process. He, like lightning, was fucking impossible to stop. As far as I am concerned he should have been shot a long time ago.</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_4">
    <text>And where can I find him now?</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_5">
    <text>Well, most likely in the laboratory. But why do you seek him? He is unpredictable. You need to tranquilize him or he will attack you. You need to procure a tranquilizer pistol.</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_6">
    <text>So where can I get one?</text>
</string>

<string id="sveeblov_about_lab_7">
    <text>Well, go to Kruglov, he will give you the tranquilizers and a special pistol for firing them.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_0">
    <text>Hello Kruglov, I have a request.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_1">
    <text>What kind of request?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_2">
    <text>They say you have a gun that shoots tranquilizers. I need to borrow it for a couple of days.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_3">
    <text>I can loan it, but not free, you understand.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_4">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_5">
    <text> I have some valuable information about monsters for Duty, and I have no one to deliver it.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_6">
    <text>It's hard to walk away.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_7">
    <text>Take this. I'll give you a gun, and even a recipe for transmutations that is very rare. And another request - go through Rostok, there is a gang of thugs there that we need to deal with.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_about_lab_8">
    <text>Okay, I'll go. I will deal with these scumbags.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_lab_0">
    <text>Greetings, General!</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_lab_1">
    <text>Oh, Strelok, what's brought you here?</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_lab_2">
    <text>Here, Kruglov has sent this case.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_lab_3">
    <text>At last, I was beginning to worry. Now we're going to know about the situation with the mutants and I hope it will help us. Oh well, go to Petrenko, he was looking for you for some reason.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_0">
    <text>Hello Colonel! You wanted to see me?</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_1">
    <text>Yes, there is one little matter. According to rumours, Freedom has altered an RG-6 to use NATO M-209 rounds.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_2">
    <text>So, why am I needed?</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_3">
    <text>Very simply, we need you procure one for us.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_need_weapons_4">
    <text>Well, Colonel, I'll try.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_0">
    <text>Halt!</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_1">
    <text>Soldier, I'm here on business.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_2">
    <text>I was ordered to not allow anyone to pass.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_3">
    <text>What do you need to let me in?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_4">
    <text>I do not take bribes.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_5">
    <text>Ok, vodka maybe?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_6">
    <text>Fuck your vodka, we have it in bulk.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_7">
    <text>Maybe some weapons or med kits?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_8">
    <text>I have enough ... ah maybe ... something good to smoke. If you know what I mean! Can you get me some?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_9">
    <text>I think I can help you. Okay?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_need_vzatka_10">
    <text>Okay, bring me some 'grass' and we'll talk.</text>
</string>

<!-- what would be Duke -->

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_0">
    <text>Hello, Duke. I need something from you.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_1">
    <text>Greetings to you too! What do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_2">
    <text>I need some 'grass', you know, not parsley.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_3">
    <text>Uh-uh brother, sorry but nope, that was sold. But maybe there will be some more in about a week.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_4">
    <text>C'mon Duke, surely you have a little bit for me?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_5">
    <text>Well there is little, but you can understand that it's not easy to come by.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_6">
    <text>What do you want for it?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_7">
    <text>Well Strelok it's my sidekick's birthday soon. I want to give him a decent weapon. An Abakan with an integrated grenade launcher. He had always wanted one. Now I remember, it's called an Assault Akaban!</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_8">
    <text>Okay I will get this gun just for you, but don't sell the 'grass' to anyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_0">
    <text>Regards Duke, here, take it, I found the Assault Akaban.</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_1">
    <text>Well done! Shit, I'm happy! The lad will be delighted. He's wanted one for so long. Well thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_2">
    <text>Well, did you get the 'grass'?</text>
</string>

<string id="knyaz_trade_trava_est_3">
    <text>Yes! Here's your grass. I put it in a box so it does not get wet. And here is a present from me, a modified SPAS-12. Take it, Duke doesn't lie!</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_0">
    <text>Good.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_1">
    <text>Hello, I've got the 'grass', here take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_est_vzatka_2">
    <text>Well done. I'll go away and pretend to see nothing. Come on, you have three minutes to take what you need.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_0">
    <text>Regards Colonel.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_1">
    <text>So, did you bring anything?</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_2">
    <text>As promised I've brought you the modified RG-6.</text>
</string>

<string id="petrenko_est_weapons_3">
    <text>Well done, and here is your reward - a formula for transmutations and more: personally from me, an AK-47 with a specially modified magazine.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_0">
    <text>Well, I fulfilled your request.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_1">
    <text>Thanks, you've saved us.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_2">
    <text>Okay, Kruglov, I'm in a hurry, give me what you promised and I will go, there are things I have to do.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_3">
    <text>Here is a special Colt and a clip with tranquilizers. Is this for the mad Professor?</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_4">
    <text>I'll give him a new birthmark.</text>
</string>

<string id="kruglov_give_weapons_5">
    <text>Well, here's a tip: when you see him, just shoot him, they say he's crazy. If you delay he will begin firing at you. This gun won't harm him but you will be able to get him under control and talk to him - he will calm down for a while. I think you'll have enough time to talk. And another thing: you can only do it once, otherwise he will be even more out of control and you won't be able to calm him - that's a feature of the sedative.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_0">
    <text>Professor... Professor, wake up!</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_1">
    <text>I'm listening ... I'm listening, I hear them. Do you hear them?</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_2">
    <text>Whom?</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_3">
    <text>Voices, they... They are calling me.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_4">
    <text>No, I hear nothing.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_5">
    <text>Bu bu bu bu bu.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_6">
    <text>Professor, I need your journal.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_7">
    <text>Listen ... they ... they sing ... so beautifully...</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_8">
    <text>Yes, yes, very nice, but listen, listen to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_9">
    <text>Journal?</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_10">
    <text>Yes, yes, the voices requested that you give me your journal.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_11">
    <text>Voices ... hurt ... and ... beautiful.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_12">
    <text>They requested that you give me the journal and then all will be beautiful without pain.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_13">
    <text>It won't hurt, I do not want ... My head ... Very, very painful...</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_14">
    <text>Trust me, everything will be fine, give me the journal, do you have it?</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_15">
    <text>Well ... Okay, here. It hurts not to be ... they call ... I'll be happy ... bu bu bu bu bu.</text>
</string>

<string id="mad_professor_dialog_16">
    <text>God forbid this happening to me.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Well Professor, I finally found you.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_1">
    <text>You did get the journal?</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, here is it, take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_3">
    <text>So let's take a look ... yeah ... clear, get your helmet ... so ... in all, now I think it will protect you from the Psi-emission.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_4">
    <text>I hope so, God forbid, suffering the same fate as the Professor.</text>
</string>

<string id="sahar_dnevnik_est_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, Strelok, I hope you succeed. God bless you or whoever you believe in.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, we meet again.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Thanks to you those Mercenaries, those bastards, are screwed.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes, today I help you, tomorrow you help me.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_3">
    <text>You did bring the documents from laboratory X -16?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_4">
    <text>There were no documents, just a laptop computer.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_5">
    <text>Let's take a look. Yeah ... so ... You know what, it turns out that they conducted experiments on humans in Laboratory X 18, and then using data they obtained there, they put it to use in Lab X-16, and adjusted their Psi-installation.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_0">
    <text>Well, what do we do now?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_1">
    <text>We still don't know who is behind it all. But we've learnt that there is a group of people that have conducted terrible experiments on prisoners, and that there is some installation in lab X-16, by the way, I don't think that it is the only one, surely there are more. We should pay a visit to laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_2">
    <text>Why? The Military have already been there and I doubt they left anything.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_3">
    <text>The laptop has relatively recent entries. There is even an entry a month back, you know what that means? Someone has been there not long ago.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_start_dialog_post_4">
    <text>Okay, I'll go, I'll see if I can find something interesting.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, Fang.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, have you been inside the laboratory?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes! However it was strange that they were waiting for me.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_3">
    <text>Who?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_4">
    <text>The Monolith.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_5">
    <text>For some reason I think that they are somehow involved. Strelok, the situation is heating up! I have a feeling that the Monolith has something planned. Passing Diggers have said that they spotted a group of Monolith at the Radar, and then running into them in the lab ...There is something very serious brewing with these mercenaries. Well, Strelok, Ghost is waiting for you. We need to understand all this before it is too late.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_6">
    <text>Back to Pripyat? No, I'm not going.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_7">
    <text>But why?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_8">
    <text>I barely got out of there alive. No to Pripyat and Chernobyl combined! I'll pass!</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_9">
    <text>Damn, I never expected that from you Strelok. Oh well! Can you do a small job for me? An easy one!</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_10">
    <text>What do you need me to do?</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_11">
    <text>It's not safe here. Take this flash drive and the laptop from lab X-16 to Barkeep. You need to lie low for a while. That's all I'm asking, go. Barkeep still has some work for you. In the meantime, I'll try to solve your issues. When you return, we will decide how to solve this puzzle.</text>
</string>

<string id="mil_klyak_second_dialog_12">
    <text>Okay, Fang, I will give Barkeep the laptop computer and flash drive.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_0">
    <text>Regards Barkeep, I have some stuff for you from Fang.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_1">
    <text>What has he sent?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_2">
    <text>A flash drive and a laptop from Laboratory X-16.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_3">
    <text>Oh, mother of ... well ... all right then. Anything else?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_last_work_dialog_4">
    <text>Fang directed me to Lab X-18 for a PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_0">
    <text>What is needed?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_1">
    <text>There is easy work, escort a tourist around 'Cordon'.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_2">
    <text>Well these tourists will go anywhere. What do they think, that this is a "Theme Park"?!</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_3">
    <text>Come on the work is easy and it pays well. You don't have to go far. Take him to the bridge, well, maybe a little farther, and then bring him back. At first he said he wanted to go to the 'Garbage', but I immediately told him that is was too dangerous. He was happy with that.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_4">
    <text>Where is this tourist?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_5">
    <text>He waits for you in the village.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, I will work this tour. Hopefully he's not a complete idiot.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello, are you looking for a guide?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes, I ... I want to see mutants like a Bloodsucker and a Chimera.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Bloodsucker, Chimera ... Hmm ... we'll have to look around. Well, let's go I suppose.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_start_dialog_3">
    <text>Yes I'm ready.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_second_dialog_0">
    <text>What's wrong?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_second_dialog_1">
    <text>Travelling is difficult. Let me catch my breath. Where are the bloodsuckers? I want see a live bloodsucker.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Well you're annoying, we'll go past the bridge. There I think you will see a bloodsucker.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, did you see what you came to see?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_1">
    <text>Not really, can we go to the 'Garbage'?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_2">
    <text>You can go by yourself. I won't take you there. It is too dangerous there, especially for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_3">
    <text>It's a pity, okay then let's go back to camp.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_tri_dialog_4">
    <text>It is high time.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_0">
    <text>Well Sidorovich it's done.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_1">
    <text>I relied on you, you did not fail me.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_2">
    <text>Okay, pay me and let me go.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_freeman_est_3">
    <text>Here take this.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_0">
    <text>What else has happened?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_1">
    <text>The Doctor and his friends have a problem.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_2">
    <text>What's the problem?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_3">
    <text>The Monolith are hunting them, and the Mercenaries are after them too. In short, they need help.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_4">
    <text>Here we go again. I thought they could handle their own affairs.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_5">
    <text>It turns out that they need your help. Besides, this problem must be resolved. It won't go away because the Monolith has something really big planned. I am afraid that for all of us help might not come in time. So you need to go to Pripyat to find Feldsher and Ghost and seek someone's help.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_6">
    <text>Well it's time to hit the road. I need to go to Chernobyl NPP. I've discovered something about my brother. I must find someone to ... hell, how do I get to Pripyat? Through the Radar? That place is full of Mercenaries.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_7">
    <text>Talk with the Doctor he will help you. Oh, and Fang asked for you. He has something important for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_about_doctor_8">
    <text>Okay I'll go. I'll hit the road and find Fang. See you!</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_0">
    <text>Hello Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_1">
    <text>It's good that you've come, Strelok.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_2">
    <text>Your friends are in danger. To help them, I have to go to Pripyat. The sooner I go the better things will be. I'm on my way to Chernobyl. I think I found a clue that might clarify what happened to my brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_3">
    <text>Yes, these are serious affairs now. I will show you how to get to Pripyat, but it is difficult. So you must help me first. For you it's a snap. While I find out where the path to Pripyat from the Swamps starts you can do something for me.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_4">
    <text>What you do need?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_5">
    <text>I feel somewhat under the weather and I need to cook up some medicine, so I need several ingredients.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_6">
    <text>What are they?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_7">
    <text>I need 3 poltergeist eyes, 3 burer hands, 3 cat tails and a Ruby Battery artifact.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_8">
    <text>No problem, it's a lay-up! I will go look for them.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_est_0">
    <text>Hi, Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_est_1">
    <text>Well did you find what I requested?</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_est_2">
    <text>Yes here is everything that was on the list.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_give_perehod_est_3">
    <text>You've saved me, so thanks! Come here and I'll mark your PDA with the transition to Pripyat from the Swamps.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_0">
    <text>How do you do Feldsher? I haven't seen you for a while.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_1">
    <text>Yes destiny does not deceive.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_2">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_3">
    <text>No matter how hard you try to run away from what you are destined to do, you just can't get away. You must fulfil your mission.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_4">
    <text>What mission, what are you talking about?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_5">
    <text>Strelok, you need to go to the Control Bunker again. Apparently in such a short time there is something that is going happen that is seriously bad for us all. You should find some time to prevent the threat. Specific information about what the mad scientists are plotting is in the bunker. So we will have to act accordingly.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_6">
    <text>Okay, but what are my chances?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_7">
    <text>I won't lie to you, you have little chance of doing this. But you're the only one who can cope with this task. Most likely you will face in the Bunker some new kind of psycho-therapy. According to the specificity of experiments that the scientists are conducting there. Therefore it is necessary for you to protect yourself from possible danger. There is a very strong drug called Adulin. This is a powerful biochemical tool for the long time protecting of the human psyche from a variety of Psy-effects and psychological attacks. The protection that this drug gives is much higher than that of a Psi-helmet.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_8">
    <text>So where do I get this drug?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_9">
    <text>Not far from here, in the heart of Pripyat, somewhere near Lenin Square, there is a cache, a backpack with Adulin injectors, in a special refrigerated container. Solomon told me about this Monolith cache. Bring me the backpack and I'll give you the injection, which will protect your mind from the effects of Psi, or any other interference to your mind while you're in the Bunker.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_final_dialog_10">
    <text>Well, I'll go look for this hidden backpack with Adulin.</text>
</string>

<string id="rukzak_dialog_0">
    <text>Here, Feldsher, I found the backpack with the Adulin.</text>
</string>

<string id="rukzak_dialog_1">
    <text>Good, give it here.</text>
</string>

<string id="rukzak_dialog_2">
    <text>Here take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_0">
    <text>So what's next?</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_1">
    <text>I'll give you an injection of Adulin.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_2">
    <text>I hope this doesn't hurt.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_3">
    <text>No Strelok it won't hurt, but after the injection you will be a little hazy, but this will soon pass.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_4">
    <text>Ah, I wish I didn't have to do this... I'm beginning to hate needles.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_5">
    <text>I understand, but such is fate. It's your destiny. Also since you're going away the Doctor prepared a gift for you, a one-time Teleporter. It can be very useful when you have no other choice. Just remember: when activated teleportation will occur from the point where the person is standing to the Doctor in the Swamps. Teleportation is possible only once for one person. But be careful the Mercenaries have raided Pripyat. I had to change locations. I moved here from the stadium. Surely they are hanging out somewhere near here. Look out for them! I think I said everything I wanted. Now prepare for the injection.</text>
</string>

<string id="adulin_dialog_6">
    <text>Take my arm, it's faster. And thanks for the teleporter, it certainly will come in handy. Well goodbye, just in case.</text>
</string>

<string id="oso_final_dialog_0">
    <text>I have a choice?</text>
</string>

<string id="oso_final_dialog_1">
    <text>No. We need you. Besides, you know too much.</text>
</string>

<string id="oso_final_dialog_2">
    <text>And what are you going to do to me?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_0">
    <text>Do you have something for sale?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_1">
    <text>I have weapons, cartridges and med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_2">
    <text>What kind of weapons?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_3">
    <text>What cartridges?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_4">
    <text>How much for a med kit?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_21">
    <text>I have a type MR-7a3 submachine gun for 40 blind dog tails, a smooth bore SPAS-12 shotgun for 30 pseudo-dog tails, and a Bison submachine gun for 25 Bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_31">
    <text>I have common AK cartridges - 3 packs for 6 Chimera claws, or buckshot - 3 packs for 6 Wild Boar hooves.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_41">
    <text>I have two med kits - for 6 Flesh Eyes.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_211">
    <text>Give me the MR-7a3, I like it.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_214">
    <text>Yes, Barkeep, greed can be good, but in moderation.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_212">
    <text>Where is the SPAS-12? My favourite weapon, I take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_213">
    <text>Bison - this is cool, I take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_311">
    <text>Cartridges for the AK? I'll take some, I have many Bloodsucker tentacles.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_312">
    <text>Buckshot? I need some, I'll take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_313">
    <text>At those prices! I might just as well shoot myself.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_change_411">
    <text>Well, give me some med kits, and then I can go back to the Zone. You can never have too many.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_0">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_1">
    <text>I'm here to do some business.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_2">
    <text>What kind of business?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_3">
    <text>I exchange for parts of mutants, but not all of them.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_4">
    <text>Which ones?</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_5">
    <text>For 10 Tushkano heads - 3 packs of NATO rounds, \n
 For 10 Zombie hands - 3 packs of NATO armour piercing rounds, \n
 For 5 Pseudogiant paws - 3 packs of cartridges for SVD sniper rifle  \n
 For 5 Controller hands - 5 Army med kits, plus five antirads..</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_predlag_6">
    <text>Okay, I'll get some.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_0">
    <text>Hello, Mazai. I've brought something.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_1">
    <text>What do you have? remember, we agreed on a fixed fee: \n
 For 10 Tushkano heads - 3 packs of NATO rounds, \n
 For 10 Zombie hands - 3 packs of NATO armour piercing rounds, \n
 For 5 Pseudogiant paws - 3 packs of cartridges for SVD sniper rifle \n
 For 5 Controller hands - 5 Army med kits, plus five antirads.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_2">
    <text>I have 10 Tushkano heads.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_3">
    <text>I have 10 Zombie hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_4">
    <text>I have 5 Pseudogiant paws.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_5">
    <text>I have 5 Controller hands.</text>
</string>

<string id="freeman_change_6">
    <text>Forgive me, I was mistaken.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_0">
    <text>What's on sale here?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_1">
    <text>Weapon, cartridges and Army med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_2">
    <text>What weapons?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_3">
    <text>What cartridges?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_4">
    <text>How much for the Army med kits?</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_21">
    <text>This is what I've got: 
 1) SIG SG552 Commando for a Cobblestone artefact. 
 2) SIG SG551 for a Tears of Fire artefact. 
 3) M16A1 rifle for a Simbion artefact. 
 4) Colt M4A1 for a Ruby Spring artefact. 
 5) FA MAS prototype 3 for a Gold Slice artefact. 
 6) SIG 550 sniper rifle for a Soul Drops artefact.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_211">
    <text>I'll take the SIG SG552 Commando.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_212">
    <text>I'll take the SIG SG551.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_213">
    <text>I'll take the M16A1 rifle.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_214">
    <text>I'll take the Colt M4A1.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_215">
    <text>I'll take the FA MAS prototype 3.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_216">
    <text>I'll take the SIG 550 sniper rifle.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_217">
    <text>Not at those prices, well, I'll just stick with my AK.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_31">
    <text>This is what I have: 
 1) "5.56x45mm AP" - three packs for two Droplets artifacts, 
 2) "5.56x45mm SS109" - three packs for two Blood Stone artifacts, 
 3) "F-1 Grenade" - three pieces for two Bengal Fire artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_311">
    <text>Give me the armour-piercing cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_312">
    <text>Give me the common cartridges.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_313">
    <text>Give me the grenades.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_41">
    <text>Army med kits, 2 pieces - for 3 Slime artifacts.</text>
</string>

<string id="svoboda_change_411">
    <text>Give me the Army med kits.</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_0">
    <text>Is there something I can do for you?</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_1">
    <text>Dude! I have some work, do you want to earn something?</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_2">
    <text>What kind of work?</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_3">
    <text>In short, man, listen here ... Ick ... My sidekick, Jack, as always, shit, he went on a trip. You know, dragging all sorts of odds and ends to the 'Mainland'. He was high man, you know from smoking joints, and took time off even though he was not sick, damn him. He didn't tell us. And now jack has literally screwed us ... Ick ... Without him we cannot go to the 'Mainland' and come back. There is a lot of danger there. The entire perimeter is guarded by helicopters. Fuck, complete asshole, tries ... Ick...</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_4">
    <text>Are you drunk? God, you look disgusting! How does Duke tolerate such freaks? Well ... well, how I can to help you?</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_5">
    <text>Do not worry, I'm ok! Duke said that you are a good guy, not like most of those shitty Stalkers. They just sit around the campfire telling tales and gorge themselves with Vodka, they are too afraid to help you. Help me out, brother, it is necessary to bring Jack back, he is now near the border of the Zone, he's hiding around the checkpoint. Or maybe he has already been seized by the Military ... Find my sidekick, bring him to the checkpoint, then I will thank you properly ... Be like Spock - save the shmuck! ... Ick ... Well, while I'll still drink, I don't want to break the habit, ha ha.</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_about_valet_6">
    <text>Gladly, I will try.</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_0">
    <text>Hello, are you Jack?</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_1">
    <text>Well, I, and who are you, my mother? You got any "cones"? Vodka?</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_2">
    <text>No "cones". Vodka yes, but not for you. Cross sent me to cover your backside.</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_3">
    <text>Shut up, it's already covered. It's very dangerous here, not only are there "gun -ships", but Special Forces as well. They are like an elephants in a china shop. In short, we're dead meat, pal.</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_4">
    <text>Watch your language. I've come to help out, but if you don't need me, I'll go.</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_5">
    <text>Well so what asshole. But thanks anyway for your offer. Look, I've been under a lot of stress. For two days I've been on edge, hungry and tired, trying to soothe my nerves. So calm down brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="valet_about_valet_6">
    <text>Okay, let's finish this argument and get out of here quietly.</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_work_est_0">
    <text>All's good.</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_work_est_1">
    <text>Ahh, Strelok, you mother fucker! Well, like, hello and all that ... Well, did you find Jack?</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_work_est_2">
    <text>Well fuck Cross! The man does not like me. I brought Jack to the checkpoint, and then I don't know where he went or what happened to him. He's crass, just like you.</text>
</string>

<string id="krest_work_est_3">
    <text>What, not again! Well done, brother! Duke was not mistaken, you really know your business. Well, as I promised, here take this as a sort of a present for your help!</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_detector_0">
    <text>Hello Lefty.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_detector_1">
    <text>Well you seem healthy. Long time no see.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_detector_2">
    <text>I had to see you. I have an anomaly detector, an unusual one. I found it on a Monolith, look, can it be repaired?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_detector_3">
    <text>Come on; let's take a look at it. Oooh, this is a very good detector, if it's set correctly, then it will map practically all anomalies. So... so, in principle, it can be done, but it must be reconfigured with artifacts from anomalies that we want to show. To do this we need 6 artifacts, 1) Mica, 2) Crystal, 3) Goldfish, 4) Soul, 5) Ruby Spring and 6) Flash.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_detector_4">
    <text>Damn! Where am I going to find all these artifacts? Well, ok, I will go look for them.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_0">
    <text>Hello Lefty.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_1">
    <text>Hey, brother! Did you find the artifacts?</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_2">
    <text>Got everything. Here, take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="levsha_remont_art_est_3">
    <text>Okay, wait a bit, now a little bit more ... so ... that's it, it is as good as new. You should now recognize anomalies, well almost all, at least the most dangerous ones, that's for sure.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_start_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello Fanatic! Jeez, you don't look so good?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_start_dialog_1">
    <text>Ahhhhh, my head hurts! Do you have anything for it? Three bottles of vodka will do nicely.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_start_dialog_2">
    <text>Well, I do have 3 bottles of vodka.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_start_dialog_3">
    <text>I can't wait, please give one to me now.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_start_dialog_4">
    <text>Sure, here take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_0">
    <text>So how are you feeling now?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_1">
    <text>A little better. Can I have another one?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_2">
    <text>Sure, here's another.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll give you a transmutation recipe, it's very valuable.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_4">
    <text>What's the recipe for?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_5">
    <text>Well, it's time for another one. Please join me.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_6">
    <text>I never turn down vodka. Sure, here. Well what's the recipe for?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_7">
    <text>A recipe to transmutate a Stone Porcupine. The artifact is rare, I can tell you! I have one of these ... ah...</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_8">
    <text>What do you want for it?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_9">
    <text>You know I've recently had health problems. My liver has gone to hell. Knowledgeable people say that two Golden Slice artifacts would cure me and I don't have any.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_second_dialog_10">
    <text>Well brother if I find some I'll bring them to you, just don't forget about the recipe. And stop boozing, it will be end of you!</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_0">
    <text>Hi, I'm here to save you.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_1">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_2">
    <text>Well old man have you forgotten already, about the formula that is?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_3">
    <text>E-my, my memory has become full of holes. Well did you get the artifacts?</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_4">
    <text>Yes, here take them.</text>
</string>

<string id="fanat_art_est_5">
    <text>Well you've saved me, thank you! I will be cured now! I will put the recipe for the transmutation on your PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey, bro!</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello again. Got anything for me to do?</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_2">
    <text>I have some work, it's not hard either.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_3">
    <text>What kind of work?</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_4">
    <text>Briefly, there's this person, his name is Noodles, he used to be my sidekick, but the bastard betrayed me. Hell if I know where he is. I would like to get my hands on that young reptile.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_5">
    <text>What do you expect me to do?</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_6">
    <text>Just find this louse and you can decide what to do with him. For doing that I will give a recipe for transmutations, Giants Little Brother. In any case I was told recently by someone that he saw this four-eyed dog Noodles in the Garbage near the transition to the Dark Valley. Try to look for him there. Just hurry up otherwise he may disappear.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_dialog_7">
    <text>Okay, I will try to find Noodles.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_0">
    <text>What have you done Noodles?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_1">
    <text>What do you mean?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_2">
    <text>Haven't you guessed? I assume you know that you are being sought after.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_3">
    <text>Who? For what?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_4">
    <text>Well, it's better for you to explain your situation.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_5">
    <text>Well ... I was out with this guy, with who I was somewhat friendly, searching for artifacts but we found nothing. On our way back he found the corpse of a stalker. Well you know, we searched the body and found a recipe for transmutation and several good artifacts. It was getting dark so we camped for the night. My partner was on guard duty and I was asleep by the campfire. I woke up with someone strangling me. What a bitch! I couldn't make any noise, you know, because monsters were around. I had a large hunting knife, well, I somehow reached out and stabbed him to death. Now his pals will probably try to avenge his death.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_6">
    <text>Are you sure they will persecute you?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_7">
    <text>Believe me they sure will! Listen brother, what did the bandit promise you for your help?</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_8">
    <text>Formula of transmutations, Giants Little Brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_9">
    <text>I wonder how that bastard learned about it. Well yes, agreed. I'll give you the formula for transmutations for Giants Little Brother, and on top of that one more little thing, a rare Ruger revolver. This gun is very rare and valuable and very powerful too. Finding cartridges for it will be difficult, so I'll give you one spare mag of cartridges. You can get more cartridges from Antiques. He deals in rare weapon ammo. I got this Ruger from him ... expensively! Moreover these cartridges I'll give you are the common type. Antiques should have the armour-piercing type. Go to the Bar to seek him out. He goes there often. Ask Borov he will knows where to find Antiques.</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_10">
    <text>Fuck you!</text>
</string>

<string id="atp_barman_dialog_11">
    <text>Okay, you've persuaded me. Give me the recipe and the Ruger. I'll find Antiques. I love rare things.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_est_0">
    <text>Well? What happened?</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_est_1">
    <text>Yeah yeah, your Noodles, I put him down.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_est_2">
    <text>You said you would, you did well, I respect you for that.</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_est_3">
    <text>So where's the recipe?</text>
</string>

<string id="band_kill_est_4">
    <text>Give me your PDA, I'll download the recipe, joking with you is dangerous, pal!</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Borov, have you any work?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Strelok, there is this matter, my courier Claw was to arrive here with important information.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_2">
    <text>Well, and?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_3">
    <text>That's the problem! It's been two days and he has not shown up.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_4">
    <text>Well have you heard anything at all?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_5">
    <text>Nope, nothing really. The only clue is the fact that the last message he sent was from the Dark Valley. Perhaps it was Bandits or Marauders that got involved, they often hang around there. You know what, go down to Voronin, he polices the Dark Valley, maybe he knows something. Only one thing don't tell him who sent you. You understand I have some ideological differences with Duty. If you find the cache be careful it might be rigged to explode.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_kogot_6">
    <text>Okay, I will carefully try to find out what is going on.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Greetings General.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok what has brought you here?</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_kogot_2">
    <text>I was sent by someone who said that his courier has vanished, somewhere in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_about_kogot_3">
    <text>About this courier I know nothing, nor do we control the entire Valley. At the factory all hell is breaking loose and we don't know what's going on. Although recently a gang of Bandits has arrived. I sent some guys to check it out and have not heard from them since. You go and find out what happened.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_0">
    <text>Regards, are you the one Borov is looking for?</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_1">
    <text>Yeah I am. Thank you brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_2">
    <text>What happened then?</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_3">
    <text>I was captured looking for a shorter route to the Bar from the Radar, by going through the Dark Valley. Damn it ... I've sat here for a couple two days now.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_4">
    <text>Why didn't they kill you?</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_5">
    <text>I told them that Borov would pay a ransom for me. I knew he wouldn't pay, but I was stalling for time.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_6">
    <text>Okay let's get down to business, the information that you carried for Borov, where is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_7">
    <text>They took everything so I don't have it.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_8">
    <text>Shit where am I going to find it?</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_9">
    <text>Don't worry, I overheard a small conversation between the Bandits, they intended to kill me anyway. They have a cache somewhere in Lab X-18. In the laboratory and somewhere high over a work bench.</text>
</string>

<string id="kogot_about_kogot_10">
    <text>Well, thank you for this. I'll go look for the PDA.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_0">
    <text>Well Borov the trip was waste of time. The PDA is gone, the cache was blown to hell. Boobytrapped! I almost lost my walnuts.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_1">
    <text>Now you have to go back to Pripyat to Ghost. He's got the information that was carried by the courier, and I've already paid him in advance. Just ask Ghost if he would give you a copy of the information, of course, thats if he has a copy.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_2">
    <text>But there is one thing!</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_3">
    <text>What's with the 'but'?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_4">
    <text>There is no path to Pripyat. How do I get there?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_5">
    <text>Oh hell ... you know what Strelok, there is a way out.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_6">
    <text>How?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_7">
    <text>Rumour has it that Freedom wanted to go to Pripyat through the Radar. And they say that they have just found the passage to Pripyat. So, why don't you talk to Lukash?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_about_pda_8">
    <text>Okay, I'll try to talk to Lukash.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_0">
    <text>Greetings!</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok, haven't seen you for a while.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_2">
    <text>Yes, it's been a while. Listen up, I am on business.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_3">
    <text>What's up?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_4">
    <text>I've heard that you've found a path to Pripyat, right?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_5">
    <text>Who told you?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_6">
    <text>Come on, does it matter, I desperately need to Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_7">
    <text>Well there is such a path, your information, though not 100% correct is fairly accurate. While we were at the Radar we accidentally discovered it.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_8">
    <text>Well, will you help me?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_9">
    <text>Look, get this: 'Quid Pro Quo'.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_10">
    <text>Man I hate lawyer talk. What do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_11">
    <text>At the Radar, in the forest, a helicopter has recently crashed. The scientists had something in a metal container. I sent some guys there, but they found nothing. Find me the container and I'll help you.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_12">
    <text>Roger, you need the metal container which should be near the crashed helicopter. No problem.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_need_box_13">
    <text>Oh, I forgot to warn you that the container is radioactive, so do not forget to get more antirads, and if you have any artifacts that absorb radiation then hang them on your belt.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_0">
    <text>Hello!</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_1">
    <text>Well did you find the container?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_2">
    <text>Ahuh, here is it, take it quickly, I'm already in pain from its radiation.</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_3">
    <text>Well done! My guys just want to drink Vodka, tell stories and sit around the campfire. They are idiots!</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_4">
    <text>Okay, Lucash what about my request?</text>
</string>

<string id="lucash_est_box_5">
    <text>Ah yes, you helped me. Give me your PDA and I will mark the way to Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_0">
    <text>Regards, we meet again.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_1">
    <text>Hello Strelok, come in. How's things?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_2">
    <text>Good and bad. Did you send Borov some information via a courier?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_3">
    <text>Well I did, why? You're probably wondering why I got in touch with the Marauders? Borov's a rare bastard, but he pays well. I desperately need the money so I got involved in a scam with Fang. We extracted the required information and sent it to Borov by a courier.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_4">
    <text>I see. But here is the thing, there was a problem, Marauders captured the courier. He's alive, but the PDA was destroyed.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_5">
    <text>Damn! The information was the sole copy ... although, wait, I think I remember that Fang made a copy. I wonder, does he still have it?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_6">
    <text>Are you assuming that Fang has a copy?</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_7">
    <text>Yes, most likely, he is a meticulous guy, loves to have insurance. So, now you must help Fang.</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_about_pda_8">
    <text>Well, there's one thing left to do, go to Fang. Well goodbye see you later.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_0">
    <text>Hello tooth fairy, er, I mean Fang.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_1">
    <text>Hi Strelok. I see you have a good sense of humor.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_2">
    <text>Well I hope you could possibly help me out.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_3">
    <text>I'll try, but what do you need?</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_4">
    <text>Listen this could take a long time to explain, but the PDA which Ghost gave the courier to deliver has been lost. Ghost said that perhaps you may have a copy of the data.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_5">
    <text>Well you're lucky! Yes I do have a copy.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_6">
    <text>Thank God, so where is it?</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_7">
    <text>The PDA is close, it's in the bloodsuckers village. There is a house with a cellar. The entrance to the cellar is covered by an oil barrel. It stops the beasts from accidently falling through, but it doesn't stop people. However some of the errie sounds do. lol There is a problem though.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_8">
    <text>What is the problem?</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_9">
    <text>Recently in this house an anomaly has formed, or something like that, so I cannot get near the cache. It throws me back.</text>
</string>

<string id="klyak_about_pda_dialog_10">
    <text>Well all sorts of wonders exist. Hopefully I'll sort it out.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_0">
    <text>Hey!</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_1">
    <text>Hello, let's sit by the fire and chat.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_2">
    <text>I wanted to ask you, do you know what kind anomaly is in that house. I try going in, but it pushes me back.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_3">
    <text>Are there unpleasant sounds? Come back at night and I will explain everything.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_4">
    <text>But why at night?</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_5">
    <text>Just come, I will explain it all and bring me some sweets. I love candies.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_6">
    <text>What kind of candy?</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_day_dialog_7">
    <text>Have you any chocolate? No, then bring a tin of 'Montpensier'.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_0">
    <text>Well, I've brought a tin of 'Montpensier' candy for you.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_1">
    <text>Well, thank you!</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_2">
    <text>Come on, tell me now.</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_3">
    <text>This is what I can tell you, recently a family of poltergeists settled in the village. At night time they come out, so to speak, and during the day they sleep inside the house. I don't know how they do it, but during the day they protect themselves with a force field, so you can't enter. Well, now do understand why you can only enter at night?</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_4">
    <text>I see. During the day, while they are in the house, I can't get in?</text>
</string>

<string id="monach_night_dialog_5">
    <text>That's right, unless you kill them all, you cannot get inside the house in the daytime.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_0">
    <text>Yeah, well, about the job you assigned. Poltergeists gave me a run around while searching for the PDA, here's a present for you!</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_1">
    <text>Did you find it?</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_2">
    <text>Yes I found it, here take it.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pda_est_dialog_3">
    <text>This is very valuable information, well done! Here take this you deserve it.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
