<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="descr_bar_crazy_veterans_quest">
    <text>Barkeep: 'Duty' values its reputation. So they want to do everything quietly. You enough to destroy the boss named Lucky and bring it to the CPC as evidence.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_community_quest">
    <text>In order to join the 'Duty' you must get the approval of one of the most respected fighters group. And also to prove the leader of the 'Duty' that you deserve to be one of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_ambush_quest">
    <text>Barkeep: 'Your task - the destruction of Tyran, the leader of a group of mercenaries. Detachment of mercenaries burst in wild territory, and sat down at a construction site. Be careful, some of the militants sitting in ambush at the approaches to the construction site. As soon as you bring me a PDA Tyran, your reward.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_svoboda_leader_kill_quest">
    <text>General Voronin: 'The war with' Freedom 'is coming to an end, Strelok You contributed to the cause, and now I want to put an end to this war. I want you to destroy the leader of' Freedom '.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_dolg_test_quest">
    <text>Captain Ivantsov, '... before drawing conclusions, pass a little test. You've got to get the archive folder from an abandoned building across the street. Specifying easy, simply enter inside, take the folder and bring it to me. What could be simpler, right? When a folder I will, then decide you godishsya for 'Duty' or not.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_hunter_rifle">
    <text>Hunter: 'Bring a gun. I lost it near the home of bloodsuckers, now you throw off the coordinates of the place. And the more careful out there, these creatures are very angry.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_kill_professor">
    <text>Wolfhound: 'We've got a little hunting. Clamped scientists, there is a helicopter. My guys secretly shot at them, not to escape. Let's you connect to, are going to finish. If you help, we will give you the space suit research, from the downed helicopter pulled out. Your goal - Professor Kruglov, kill him, otherwise he will escape during the battle, I know their breed. If you kill him, your suit, no - it means not destiny. '</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_radar_deactivate">
    <text>Barkeep: 'Security prototype you have to from the' Burner 'to hide behind, the coordinates of the bunker, I know. Do not forget that the prototype will not be able indefinitely to protect you from radiation, so you should as soon as possible to get into the bunker under the antennas and turn off the' Burner ' . All we need is to get to the antenna and turn them off. '</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_resque_information">
    <text>Kruglov, 'Stalker, help! We were attacked Mercenaries, half of what we lost. Help us, we will not stay in debt ...' \n \n '... are you more careful, about fifteen of them, though we do not know.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_resque_information_2">
    <text>Kruglov, 'We came back with Amber, when we knocked Mercenaries. It is said that the information they need, but I do know - they will shoot us. Lead me to Amber and I will share with you what I know about the 'Brain Burner'. The Barkeep will pay well for it. I am not a soldier, so you'll have to cover me on the way.'</text>
</string>
<string id="descr_bar_x16_documents">
    <text>Barkeep: 'You have to get to the scientists and find out where the lab X-16 to get the missing part of the documents.'</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_after_agroprom_documents">
    <text>Scanned documents, which were military in the former research institute. The conclusion is: this institution in recent years before the disaster was the cover of the independent laboratory X-18, which seems to have carried out a mysterious experiment. Where is the laboratory, the documents do not provide an answer. Military lab about this, too, seems to know nothing. Hmm ... Riddles are multiplying ... But perhaps this is a thread that needs to merchants. Well, now to be on my way north to the merchant named Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_bar_darklab_documents">
    <text>Hmm ... Unhappy this place - laboratory X-18 ... and its present inhabitants ... Do not even think that such evil can exist in the world. Found some documents ... Of these, little is understood - it is some technical specifications on some blocks to radiators Kaymanov. But interestingly, these units were intended for another laboratory with X-16 code and, apparently, is also classified.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_bar_x16_documents">
    <text>Hmm ... Marketers really dug a lot of these laboratories. For Barkeep was not unexpected information about radiators and about X-16. And now he is convinced that this 'brain-Burner' rukotvoren. He thinks that this laboratory X-16 is located near the camp at Lake Yantar scientists. They just learn it radiation, which is similar to the effect 'Burner.' So now my path is to the academic fraternity Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_darklab_documents">
    <text>Met with the Barkeep. After overlooking the documents of the Institute he suggested that X-18 is in the so-called Dark Valley, and offers me to come back there for finding information and documents. He says that is sent on a mission to infiltrate Dolgovtsev in this dungeon. But they were gone. The Barkeep suggested that they were captured by bandits near the base. If so, then all that will be dug Dolgovtsev the leader of the bandits, the Borov. The Barkeep calls for caution and ... and obviously something about it keep back underground. Anyway, for the work: first, to communicate with Borov, and if the conversation succeeds, then climb into the ground.</text>
</string>
<string id="journal_before_radar_task">
    <text>Well, I'm ready to go to the 'Burner.' I learned from Psycho while reducing the radiation power and a safe place where I can wait this time. At other times, my Psy-protection still does not help. I'll have to find the entrance to an underground bunker to laboratory X-19, and inside - the path to the antenna control 'Brain Scorcher'.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_gordon_diary">
    <text>Gordon's PDA</text>
</string>
