<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- ;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;
;	 ,,,,,      ,,,,,,,    ,,,,,,_  ,,,,,,,,  ,,,,,,   
;       MMMMM1     M0MMMM&    MMMMM@'  MMMMMM0"  MMMM0!   
;       4MMMM#      ^MMMMMr   MMMMMf    #MMMM&    B0'     
;      &]MMMMMc      #MMMM# ] MMMMMf    #MMMM&   j#       
;      M 0MMMM&       MMMMML# MMMMMf    #MMMM&  pM&       
;     pY 4MMMMM     ] #MMMMM# MMMMMf    #MMMM& pMMMt      
;     M   MMMMMc    ]& MMMMMf MMMMMf    #MMMM&]MMMM0      
;    ]#   0MMMM&    ]M #MMMM  MMMMMf    #MMMM& MMMMM&     
;    QfjMMMMMMMM    ]M  MMMf  MMMMMf    #MMMM& 4MMMMM     
;   _M    "MMMMMf   ]M  BMM   MMMMMf    #MMMM&  MMMMM&    
;  _Q#     MMMMM&   jMg  M8  _MMMMMf    BMMMM&  jMMMMM,   
; 4MMMM   #MMMMMM# 0MMM& B  ]MMMMMMM&  0MMMMMM&]MMMMMMMt  
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;; -->

  <string id="af_buliz">
		<text>'Cobblestone'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_buliz">
		<text>The artifact, which as a result of energy collapse lost all its properties. However, in spite of the absence of explicit positive properties, 'Cobblestones' remain interesting to scientists.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_spirit_1">
		<text>'Soul Drops'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_1">
		<text>This modification possesses an outstanding increase in human health, and speeds up radiation reduction. but on the other hand it decreases.</text>
	</string> 

  <string id="af_spirit_2">
		<text>'Fiery Soul'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_2">
		<text>This modification has properties similar to 'Soul Drops', but radiation reduction increased.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_spirit_3">
		<text>'Crystal Soul'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_3">
		<text>Affects the owner the same way as the 'Fiery Soul', but radiation reduction raised to a higher level.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_spirit_4">
		<text>'Fervent Crystal'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_spirit_4">
		<text>This modification has, probably, the highest health increasing/radiation protection effects.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_cry_1">
		<text>'Tears of Electra'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_1">
		<text>This modification speeds up radiation conclusion and slightly decrease owner's fatigue.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_cry_2">
		<text>'Tears of Fire'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_2">
		<text>This modification highly speeds up radiation conclusion.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_cry_3">
		<text>'Tears of Chimera'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_cry_3">
		<text>This modification possesses the outstanding radiation conclusion effect and block half of psy-emissions. But on the other side it decreases owner's endurance and decrease wound healing speed.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_babka_1">
		<text>'Old Glassbeads'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_1">
		<text>This modification increases endurance of owner and generates the field of gravitational kind, somewhat retarding bullets entering it, increasing the protection from the firearms. But, it's little radioactive and increases electrical damage.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_babka_2">
		<text>'Ancient Glassbeads'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_2">
		<text>Ancient 'Glassbeads' has weaker gunfire defence than 'Old Glassbeads', but it increase health and wound healing speed. Also, it's little radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_babka_3">
		<text>'Elder Glassbeads'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_babka_3">
		<text>'Elder Glassbeads' create field with so high power large power that its owner can survive after being shot from SVD. Instantly stops wound bleeding, increases health. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_pudd_1">
		<text>'Fire Dummy'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_1">
		<text>This modification decreases the action of high temperatures and increases endurance, but on the other hand also increaces electrical damage.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_pudd_2">
		<text>'Shining Dummy'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_2">
		<text>Same as the 'Fire Dummy', this modification perfectly defends from high temperatures, and, also, increase endurance, but with higher effectiveness. Side effect - increased electrical damage.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_pudd_3">
		<text>'Moonshine Dummy'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_3">
		<text>This modification inherited all properties from 'Shining Dummy', but it acts on the owner more intensively.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_pudd_4">
		<text>'Pudding'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_pudd_4">
		<text>This modification perfectly defend from electroshock and high temperatures. Also, it slightly increases endurance.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_dik_1">
		<text>'Porcupine'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_1">
		<text>This modification considerably accelerates conclusion of the radiation, but slightly decrease endurance.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_dik_2">
		<text>'Electro Porcupine'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_2">
		<text>This modification has very good level of radiation conclusion effect and slightly increase endurance, but on the other hand it also decrease electroshock resistance.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_dik_3">
		<text>'Acidic Porcupine'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_3">
		<text>This modification has the unique level of radiation conclusion effect, increase endurance and speeds up bleeding healing. Flows with acid stinky substance.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_dik_4">
		<text>'Stone Porcupine'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_dik_4">
		<text>'Stone Porcupine' has unique radiation conclusion effectiveness, and, also, increase endurance, speeds up bleeding healing and increase electroshock resistance.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_kol_1">
		<text>'Steel Kolobok'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_1">
		<text>This modification generates the field of a gravitational kind, somewhat retarding bullets entering it, increasing the protection from the firearms. Besides this, it decreases the sensitivity of the skin to the break. Unfortunately - it's radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_kol_2">
		<text>'Titan Kolobok'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_2">
		<text>'Titan Kolobok' increase the sensitivity of the skin to the break and decreases the damage by fire, and, also, brings down from the trajectory a certain percentage of bullets with the generated field of gravitational kind. Unfortunately it's radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_kol_3">
		<text>'Diamond Kolobok'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_3">
		<text>This modification increaces resistance to break, decreases the action of fire and chemically aggressive substances, and, also, brings down from the trajectory a certain percentage of bullets with the generated field of gravitational kind. Unfortunately it's radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_kol_4">
		<text>'Sphere'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_kol_4">
		<text>'Sphere' inherited the properties of its predecessor, 'Diamond Kolobok', but also, gets rid of the radioactivity and it makes possible for owner to feel good without food for a longer time.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_armor_1">
		<text>'Skin'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_1">
		<text>This modification decreases the receptivity to the action of any chemically aggressive substances, a little improves resistance to bullet injuries. Radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_armor_2">
		<text>'Scale'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_2">
		<text>'Scale' improves it decreases the action of chemically aggressive substances, improves health and specially it acts on human skin, making with its less sensitive to the bullet injuries. Radioactive, strengthens bleeding.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_armor_3">
		<text>'Steel Scale'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_3">
		<text>'Steel Scale' inherited the properties of its predecessor, 'Scale', but it gets rid of the bleeding strengthen effect. Still radioactive.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_armor_4">
		<text>'Controller Scalp'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_armor_4">
		<text>'Controller Scalp' decreases the action of chemically aggressive substances, increaces psy-emissions resistance, lowers need for the food and improves health. Strangely acts on human skin, making with its less sensitive to the bullet injuries.</text>
	</string>

  <string id="af_simbion">
		<text>'Simbion'</text>
	</string>
  <string id="enc_zone_artifact_simbion">
		<text>'Simbion' is the unique hybrid modificate, obtained by merging four artifacts and transmutating them. It perfectly blocks psy-emission, but, on the other hand, it strengthens wound bleeding, lowers endurance and raises break damage.</text>
	</string>

<!-- 19:06 17.06.2007 -->
<!-- Modified by Aero 13:22 25.04.2008 -->