<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="binoc_tutorial">
    <text>In order to use the binoculars, select ($$ACTION_wpn_5$$) and press 'fire' for the approximation.</text>
</string>
<string id="binocular">
    <text>Binoculars</text>
</string>
<string id="crouch">
    <text>Crouch</text>
</string>
<string id="crouch_down_tutorial">
    <text>In order to crouch lower use ($$ACTION_crouch$$) + (Shift).</text>
</string>
<string id="crouch_tutorial">
    <text>To crouch press ($$ACTION_crouch$$). To crouch lower use ($$ACTION_crouch$$) ($$ACTION_accel$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="hide_weapon">
    <text>Choice of weapons.</text>
</string>
<string id="hide_weapon_tutorial">
    <text>Some stalkers will not talk to you when you have your weapon in their face. So put away your weapon. Select the bolt ($$ACTION_wpn_6$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="jump">
    <text>Jumping</text>
</string>
<string id="jump_tutorial">
    <text>Jumping will help you climb on low obsticles. To jump press ($$ACTION_jump$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="move_tutorial">
    <text>Modes of transportation.</text>
</string>
<string id="overload">
    <text>Overloaded</text>
</string>
<string id="overload_tutorial">
    <text>You are not a truck and cannot carry a ton of stuff. The more you carry the more quickly you'll lose strength. To much and you won't be able to move at all.</text>
</string>
<string id="radiation">
    <text>Radiation</text>
</string>
<string id="radiation_tutorial">
    <text>When a character is in an area with high background radiation or a radioactive Zone near an artifact, he shows signs of radiation damage. In this case the character begins to diminish health. To remove the effect of radiation damage one can use antirads or vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="relation">
    <text>Relations</text>
</string>
<string id="relation_tutorial">
    <text>When a player helps someone it improves the reputation and character in general. If you have a good reputation then the dealers will sell you the goods at a discount. If you have a bad reputation then get ready for higher prices.</text>
</string>
<string id="sleep_tutorial">
    <text>This is a special place to sleep. You can sleep, wait till night, or just wait for the appointed hour. To sleep you need to open the sleeping bag and set the time on the clock face in which you want to sleep, and click the 'rest.' After the specified time the character wakes up. Sometimes he can dream.</text>
</string>
<string id="sprint">
    <text>Sprinting</text>
</string>
<string id="sprint_tutorial">
    <text>In some cases sprinting can save your life. To sprint press ($$ACTION_sprint_toggle$$). During sprinting you can still jump, but you will get tired quicker, and you cannot fire a weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="starvation_tutorial">
    <text>When a character does not eat for a long time he has a feeling of hunger. When the hunger becomes strong, then he begins to slowly loose  health. To prevent this decline, we must eat. You can satisfy your hunger by eating a loaf of bread, canned food or a piece of sausage.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial">
    <text>Training</text>
</string>
<string id="weakness">
    <text>Fatigue</text>
</string>
<string id="weakness_tutorial">
    <text>If you run or are carrying a lot of heavy stuff, you'll start to get tired. If you're too tired, you will not be able to run or walk for a while. Fortunately strength is quickly restored when not moving for a while.</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon">
    <text>Weapon</text>
</string>
<string id="weapon_tutorial">
    <text>Any weapon can show affects of wear and tear. The more wear and tear, the more it jams. In order to fix a jam you have to reload (press reload $$ACTION_wpn_reload$$). The weapon reliability is gradually reduced, and will at some time need repair.</text>
</string>
<string id="wound">
    <text>Wound</text>
</string>
<string id="wound_tutorial">
    <text>If you hit a character it is likely that he will start bleeding. Bleeding - a permanent loss of health. The more serious bleeding (green icon - slight bleeding, red - strong), the more the character will lose health. Over time bleeding will go away, but with a bandage can be stopped quicker.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_diary_tutorial">
    <text>In the PDA of a dead stalker you'll find him observing anomalies in the tunnel. It turns out that he had discovered regularity in their appearance. You can read it in your PDA in the 'Diary'.</text>
</string>
</string_table>
