<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
#include "text\eng\string_table_amk_matras.xml"
#include "text\eng\string_table_amk_metka.xml"

<string id="enc_bioradar">
    <text>This amazing device allows you to detect at a distance of 50 meters many life forms, either warm-blooded or cold-blooded. The principles of its operation are described in detail in the published works of Professor Bolshakov, 'Practical applications of the unique properties of artifact ZX-232 - 'Crystal Ball' as known in the field. And also in the thesis by assistant Semenov - 'Biological organisms as natural radio transceivers'. A brief explanation of the operation of this device can be as so: the majority of living organisms emit, while moving, electromagnetic waves that are trackable, and measure their frequency, intensity and determine their position in space. When working muscles but also the nerve fiber to muscle bundle receives electrical impulses, and the living tissue, as well as the tissue in which the conduction current are stored microtransmitter. Quite a long time it was thought that due to the extreme weakness of the signals to pinpoint their position was only possible only under laboratory conditions, using bulky amplifying equipment - according to this principle the so-called 'auroskopy', devices that hold around a living body to an 'aura', which is on essentially electromagnetic radiation a certain range. During the study the various artifacts Zone scientists came upon a very interesting effect of one of the subjects - an artifact called 'Crystal Ball'. With a small handheld radio assistant Semenova unexpectedly began to receive a signal of a private radio station, located in one of the provincial areas of Argentina. Having studied the unusual phenomenon, the collective scientific camps came to the only plausible explanation - an artifact of the 'Crystal Ball' amplifies and filters the noise from the radio ordered. Obviously, the microscopic part of the Argentine radio receiving a signal present at the location of the camp, but was so small that no powerful receivers have not been able to fix it. However, it was worth only bring a console connection to a stationary camp 'Crystal Ball', as the noise from the air began to be heard hundreds of voices in the further setting up successfully filtered out and caught almost all the signals available on a range of remote communication transmitters, the most distant of which was at a distance of 14 thousands of miles! To develop the project 'Crystal interception immediately imposed a stamp 'top secret', but until that time, some devices made with such amazing properties, yet the public domain. The device 'bioradar Peleng radiation of living tissues of organisms measures their frequency and distance. As a result, conventional liquid crystal display you can see the marks that indicate living organisms. Since the unit was created primarily for exploration in the Zone, an assistant Semenov uploaded to the database device information about the frequencies most often emitted by members of the local fauna. Unfortunately, the organisms in the Zone quickly mutate, in a few weeks a list of frequencies had to be updated. However, the resourceful stalkers among the first users of the device, invented a simple, though barbaric way, to get a bearing on the mutants - if the product is installed, the best on the belt, put a sample of biological tissue of the monster types you want to pinpoint - the device will automatically reset, and mutants of the desired type will be displayed on the small screen. It is true that recently there have been some new varieties of mutants that can not detect with this instrument. The disadvantage of the device is its high cost.</text>
</string>
<string id="bioradar">
    <text>'Bioradar'</text>
</string>
<string id="Antirad">
    <text>'Antiradiation drugs'</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-heavy">
    <text>'Heavy stalker gear'</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-light">
    <text>'Light stalker gear'</text>
</string>
<string id="Arm-medium">
    <text>'Medium stalker gear'</text>
</string>
<string id="bandage">
    <text>'Bandages'</text>
</string>
<string id="Binocul">
    <text>'Binoculars'</text>
</string>
<string id="Bread">
    <text>'Bread'</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_desc">
    <text>A detailed map of 'Dead City' including Merc positions</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_deadcity_maps_name">
    <text>Map of the 'Dead City'</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_doctors_key_desc">
    <text>Doctor's key to a secret stash in 'Pripyat'</text>
</string>
<string id="cit_doctors_key_short_desc">
    <text>'Doctor's key'</text>
</string>
<string id="Conserva">
    <text>Tourist's Delight</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect1">
    <text>Anomaly detector (DA-2)</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect2">
    <text>'Dosimeter'</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect3">
    <text>'Anomaly detector'</text>
</string>
<string id="Detect4">
    <text>'Elite anomaly detector'</text>
</string>
<string id="Devic">
    <text>'Instruments and devices'</text>
</string>
<string id="device-PDA">
    <text>'PDA'</text>
</string>
<string id="device-torch">
    <text>'Flashlight'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-heavy">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight: 18kg. Details: Protects the body from Jellyfish, Burnt Fuzz, most anomalies and physical damage. The torso and back are protected by built-in bio-metallic plates. The suit is equipped with an airtight, reinforced plastic helmet and two oxygen bottles. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-light">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight: 8 kg. Details: Protects the body from weak anomalies and physical damage. Equipped with an oxygen mask. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_arm-medium">
    <text>Protective suit. Weight: 12 kg. Details: Protects the user from Jellyfish, Burnt Fuzz, many anomalies and physical damage. Equipped with an airtight helmet and an oxygen bottle. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_armors_sci2">
    <text>A red S.C.A.P.E suit with an airtight helmet. Weight: 11kg. Description: Protects the body from fire, acid, toxic gas, various anomalies, Burnt Fuzz and physical damage. Equipped with two oxygen bottles. Note: During extended periods of use the suit tears through and gradually deteriorates beyond use.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_binocul1">
    <text>Army handheld binoculars.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect1">
    <text>Dosimeter - a device that measures the dose or radiated power. For it to work it must be placed on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect2">
    <text>Device indicating the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances and report them to beep. For it to work it must be placed on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_detect3">
    <text>Elite anomaly detector, invented by scientists in the Zone. Determines not only the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances, but also shows a map of their location, and reports such an audible signal. For the work must be activated by placing the device on his belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-PDA1">
    <text>Personal Digital Assistant (PDA) - an indispensable device in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1">
    <text>A powerful flashlight. Quite useful in areas with insufficient lighting.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_devic_device-torch1_m1">
    <text>A powerful flashlight. Battery recharge time has been reduced thanks to a modernized transformer.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_energydrink">
    <text>This is an excellent energy drink consisting of caffeine, taurine and a mixture of rejuvenating vitamins. Just the ticket when you're too tired to push forward!</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_energydrinka">
    <text>Unknown object. The label says that the beer.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_bread1">
    <text>Hard to say who manages to bake these loaves in the Zone, but the bread isn't contaminated and is perfectly edible. Well, at least none of the stalkers have complained about it.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_conserva1">
    <text>Canned food from an army warehouse raided by stalkers. The best-before period hasn't expired yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_kolbasa1">
    <text>Made from a mix of chicken guts and soya. This 'diet' sausage is often, for lack of other options, a stalker's breakfast, lunch and dinner in one.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_food_vodka1">
    <text>Vodka made by the GSC company. Goes down easily and significantly reduces the effects of radiation, but for obvious reasons should be enjoyed in moderation.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_antirad1">
    <text>Reduces the effects of radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_bandage1">
    <text>Bandages. Help stop bleeding.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit1">
    <text>An all-purpose medkit. Used to treat injuries of various types and severities - wounds, burns, poisonings, etc.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit2">
    <text>A specialized medical kit to fight against physical damage and blood loss. In it is included a component for blood coagulation, antibiotics, immunal stimulators, and painkillers.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_equipment_medi_medkit3">
    <text>Medical kit, designed especially for work in the Zone. The kit includes means of healing wounds as well as means of eliminating radionucleodes from the body. Prevents the development of radiowave sickness and lowers the dose of accumulated radiation.</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name">
    <text>Energy Drink 'S.T.A.L.K.E.R.'</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name_dbeer">
    <text>Beer of unknown origin</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_name_dbeer_short">
    <text>Beer from somewhere</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_name">
    <text>Canister with colloidal gas</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_name_short">
    <text>Canister of colloidal gas</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_ballon_opisalovo">
    <text>Colloidal gas is supplied to laboratories for experimentation in research, which is - now is not known. It is only known that the contents of containers are extremely active chemical, explosive and poisonous.</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_name">
    <text>Canister with gasoline</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_name_short">
    <text>'Jerrycan'</text>
</string>
<string id="amk_kanistra_opisalovo">
    <text>Canister of gasoline</text>
</string>
<string id="energy_drink_short_name">
    <text>'Energy drink'</text>
</string>
<string id="Equipment">
    <text>'Equipment'</text>
</string>
<string id="Food">
    <text>'Food'</text>
</string>
<string id="Kolbasa">
    <text>'Sausage'</text>
</string>
<string id="Medi">
    <text>'Medicines'</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit">
    <text>'Medkit'</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit_army">
    <text>Army first aid kit</text>
</string>
<string id="Medkit_scientific">
    <text>Scientific first aid kit</text>
</string>
<string id="Sci2">
    <text>Scientific EXP-4</text>
</string>
<string id="Vodka">
    <text>'Cossacks vodka'</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector">
    <text>'Dosimeter'</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector2">
    <text>'Anomaly detector'</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector3">
    <text>'Elite anomaly detector'</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_descr1">
    <text>Dosimeter - a device that measures the dose or radiated power. For it to work it must be placed on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_descr2">
    <text>Device indicating the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances and report them to beep. For it to work it must be placed on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_detector_descr3">
    <text>Elite anomaly detector invented by scientists in the Zone. Determines not only the presence of anomalous fields and disturbances, but also shows a map of their location, and reports such an audible signal. For it to work it must be places on the belt.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
    <text>'Smoke grenade'</text>
</string>
<string id="zamok">
    <text>'Psy-Lock'</text>
</string>
<string id="zamok_desc">
    <text>Device to protect personal caches. When activated it remembers the frequency of the personal PDA owner, and the approach of man, holds a reconciliation of frequencies. For non-compliance or the absence of an active PDA signal that includes the local IFP radiation, will lead to the temporary effect of panic, fear, dizziness and headache. Effects grow as we approach the hiding place, and nullified at a distance of more than 7 meters.</text>
</string>
<string id="st_repair_suit">
		<text>Outfit repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_suit_descr">
		<text>A set of very strong threads, needles and patches made of high-durability materials. Will help you keep your suit in a good condition at all times.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_weapon">
		<text>Weapon repair kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_repair_weapon_descr">
		<text>Manner of use: firearm you intend to repair should be placed in an appropriate slot, bearing in mind that the second slot must be empty.\nContains tools that will allow you to repair your weapon to some extent.</text>
        </string>
        <string id="det_art_indy">
		<text>Echo artifact detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_indy_info">
		<text>This dated anomalous activity detector produces an alarm signal when anomalous particles enter a special chamber as you approach an anomaly. It can also register the presence of artifacts and measure the distance to the nearest one. The distance is indicated by the frequency of the sound the detector emits. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Due to its simple design, Echo can only be used to locate the most common artifacts. To use it, put it on the belt and choose the bolt (6).\n\nRange of initial detection: 15m 
\nEffective range: 2m</text>
	</string>
        <string id="det_art_pro">
		<text>Detector "Bear"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_pro_info">
		<text>This last generation anomalous activity detector transfers the data of location of anomalous formations directly to the PDA. To switch to artifact search mode, open the device's front cover. Unfortunately, the device is programmed with a somewhat outdated list of detectable artifacts. To use it, put it on the belt and choose the bolt (6).\n\nRange of initial detection: 30m 
\nEffective range: 5m</text>
	</string>
         <string id="det_art_super">
		<text>Veles detector</text>
	</string>
	<string id="det_art_super_info">
		<text>A next generation scientific detection scanner. Thanks to three modernized detection chambers, the position of artifacts is shown on a special display screen and transferred to the PDA. When closed, the device registers only radiation and anomalies. To switch to artifact search mode, open the front LED display. When in search mode, the detector is capable of locating all artifacts known to science. To use it, put it on the belt and choose the bolt (6).\n\nRange of initial detection: 45m 
\nEffective range: 9m</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
