<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- #include "text\eng\string_table_amk_ammo_desc.xml" -->

<string id="wpn-ak47">
    <text>AK-47</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak47">
    <text>The Kalashnikov automatic rifle model 1947 using the cartridge 7.62x39mm. A simple and reliable weapon, although the cheapness before the production somewhat had effect on convenience in utilisation and precision of combat. In the Zone this sufficiently rare weapon because of its absence in arsenal of army. \n the ammunition: \n common 7.62x39mm, \n armour-piercing 7.62x39mm AP.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x39-ap">
    <text>Armour-piercing cartridge for the automatic machines AK47 and AK104T. Improved armour-piercing ability of bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
    <text>Standard cartridge for the automatic machines AK47 and AK104T. Simple core, tunicary bullet.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
    <text>Round 7.62x39mm</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj_s">
    <text>7.62x39mm</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x39mm</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap_s">
    <text>7.62x39mm</text>
</string>
<string id="Ammo">
    <text>Ammunition</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
    <text>Rounds 45 ACP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
    <text>.45 ACP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
    <text>.45 ACP Hydra-Shock</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
    <text>.45 ACP HS</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
    <text>Rounds 12x70 Buckshot</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
    <text>12x70 Buckshot</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x76-dart">
    <text>Rounds 12x76 Dart</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x76-dart_s">
    <text>12x76 Dart</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
    <text>Rounds 12x76 Zhekan</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
    <text>12x76 Zhekan</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
    <text>Rounds 5.45x39mm AP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
    <text>5.45 AP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
    <text>Rounds 5.45x39mm</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
    <text>5.45x39</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
    <text>Rounds 5.56x45mm AP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
    <text>5.56 AP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
    <text>5.56x45mm SS109</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
    <text>5.56x45 SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x54mm 7N1</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
    <text>7.62 7N1</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h13">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x54R 7N13</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h13_s">
    <text>of 7.62x54R 7N13</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x54R 7N14</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
    <text>7.62x54R 7N14</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
    <text>Rounds 9x18mm</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
    <text>9x18</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
    <text>Rounds 9x18mm PBM</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
    <text>9x18 PBM</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
    <text>Rounds 9x19 FMJ</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
    <text>9x19 FMJ</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
    <text>Rounds 9x19 PBP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
    <text>9x19 PBP</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
    <text>Rounds 9x39 SP-6</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-6</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
    <text>Rounds 9x39 PAB-9</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
    <text>9x39 PAB-9</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5">
    <text>Rounds 9x39 SP-5</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-9x39-sp5_s">
    <text>9x39 SP-5</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-gauss">
    <text>Gauss-cartridge</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-gauss_s">
    <text>Gauss</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-m209">
    <text>Round M-209</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-m209_s">
    <text>M-209</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-og-7b">
    <text>Round OG-7V</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
    <text>OG-7V</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-vog-25">
    <text>Round VOG-25</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
    <text>VOG-25</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-vog-25p">
    <text>Round VOG-25R</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
    <text>VOG-25R</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
    <text>Basic cartridge for pistols Desert Eagle, Colt 1911, SIG 220, USP. A simple core shell bullet.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
    <text>Hydra-Shock - cartridge with improved characteristics for handguns Desert Eagle, Colt 1911, SIG 220, USP. Expansionary bullet which has good stopping power.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-buck">
    <text>A standard 12 calibre round filled with 6 mm shot. It has an enormous killing power at a close range. It is designed for the BM 17, the Chaser 13 and the SPSA14 shotguns. It is most effective at ranges under 30 meters.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-dart">
    <text>A finned bullet. It can stabilize in flight, which increases its accuracy. It is designed for the TOS 34, the BM 17, Chaser 13 and the SPSA14 shotguns. It has an armor-piercing effect and an increased range. It is effective at a range of up to 150 meters.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-zhekan">
    <text>A round with a heavy naked bullet. It is usually used for big game hunting, but can be used for other purposes. Its heavy bullet does not pierce but actually forces itself through bulletproof vests. It is designed for the TOS 34, the BM 17, the Chaser 13 and the SPSA14 shotguns. It is effective at a range of up to 100 meters.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-ap">
    <text>An armor-piercing round for the Akm 74/2, the Akm 74/2U and the ON-94 assault rifles. It has an improved armor-piercing effect, but a decreased stopping effect.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
    <text>A standard round for the Akm 74/2, the Akm 74/2U and the Obokan assault rifles. It has a standard core and a full-jacketed bullet.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ap">
    <text>A round with an armor-piercing bullet for the IL 86, the TRs 301, the SGI 5k, the GP 37 and the FT 200M assault rifles.</text>

</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
    <text>A standard NATO round widely-known under its Belgian SS109 index. It is used with the IL 86, the TRs 301, the SGI 5k, the GP 37 and the FT 200M assault rifles.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h13">
    <text>Gross up-to-date 7.62mm rifle cartridge for the sniper rifles of SVD and SVU-ACE. \n Pulya of 7N13, in spite of similar down the sniper ammunition ballistic data, has sufficiently great (on the sniper requirements) dispersion even on the average distances; however, it possesses the increased penetration effect due to the introduction beside the construction of the bullet of armour-piercing core through the hardened tool steel.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
    <text>A sniper round for the SVDm 2 and the SVUmk2 sniper rifles. It has an improved accuracy and range.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
    <text>7N1 (TsP) - authorised sniper cartridge for the rifles of SVD, THE SVU-ACE also of machine gun PKM. \n Nesmotrya down the fact that 7N1 is accepted for the armament in 1967, it 2-3 times exceeds up-to-date gross 7N13 about the indicators of dispersion. But because of the application of the blunt-ended stamped core through steel 10, bullet TsP does not possess high breakdown properties.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-fmj">
    <text>A standard round for the PMm, PB1s, Fort-12Mk2 pistols. It has a standard core and a full-jacketed bullet. It has a weak armor-piercing effect.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pmm">
    <text>Cartridge with the improved ballistic data for the pistols PM, PB, Fort 12. Due to the higher initial velocity of bullet it is considerably more effective than the common cartridge. More expressed armour-piercing effect.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-fmj">
    <text>Base cartridge for the pistol type walther type P99 and submachine gun HK MP5K-N. Tunicary bullet. Weak armour-piercing activity.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-pbp">
    <text>Cartridge with the improved characteristicss for the pistol type walther type P99 and submachine gun HK MP5K- N. Powerful cartridge with the expansive bullet and the armour-piercing core.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-ap">
    <text>Armour-piercing cartridge for the automatic machines 'Thunderstorm', 'Shaft', and VSS 'thread cutter'. Due to the armour-piercing bullet of special construction will punch through any bulletproof vest even at the maximum distance. However, it has greater dispersion than sniper 9x39 CP -5.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-pab9">
    <text>Cartridge for the automatic machinegun 'Thunderstorm'. The cheaper before the manufacture modification of the cartridge of 9x39, fits also ACE 'shaft' and VSS 'thread cutter', but rapidly it drives in them.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-sp5">
    <text>Specially developed sniper cartridge for the automatic machineguns 'Thunderstorm', 'Shaft' and VSS 'thread cutter'. Excellent characteristics.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
    <text>Energy capacities with finished lethal 9mm by elements for the rifle of Gauss (10 pieces in the magazine). The energy source is the encapsulated fragment of artifact "Flash".</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m209">
    <text>Shot for the under-barrel grenade launcher M-203 (LR300, SIG 550, HK G36) and for the integrated grenade launcher FN type F2000.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-og-7b">
    <text>HE fragmentation shot for RPG-7V. It is equally effective both against the personnel and against legkobronirovanoy equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25">
    <text>Shot for the under-barrel grenade launcher OF GP-25 'Bonfire', integrated grenade launcher 'Thunderstorm' and revolver grenade launcher RG-6.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25p">
    <text>Shot for the under-barrel grenade launcher OF GP-25 'Bonfire', integrated grenade launcher 'Thunderstorm' and revolver grenade launcher RG-6. Before the burst the shot jumps down the height about the metre, which increases its damage effect.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-f1">
    <text>Hand defensive grenade with the great effective casualty radius by fragments. Thrown it should be only from cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-gd05">
    <text>Hand smoke grenade. It is intended for the installation of smoke cover. Time of action - 10 seconds.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgd5">
    <text>Offensive hand grenade with the small effective casualty radius by fragments.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n Avtomat type Nikonov 'Abakan' (An-94) model 1994 on the base of the system of Kalashnikov. It was came out as the replacement of obsolete AK-74. Before 'Abakan' are mobile not only internal mechanisms, but also entire receiver group together with the gun, which makes it possible to decrease output, thus having considerably raised the precision of combat.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n AN-94 'Abakan', provided by 3x-multiple optical sight for conducting the sniper fire. Built-in beside the corps optics possesses greater multiplicity than standard sights.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-abakan_m2">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n ammunition for integrated GP-25 'Bonfire': \n • shot VOG-25 \n • the shot VOG-25R \n AN-94 'Abakan' GP-25 of supplied by the integrated rifle grenade launcher, which makes this model even for the sake of more universal weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • shot VOG-25 \n • shot VOG-25P \n integrated grenade launcher 'Bonfire' of 25mm (GP-25 'Bonfire') for the automatic machines, utilised in the countries of the Warsaw Pact.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • shot M -209 \n integrated grenade launcher for the rifles, produced in the NATO alliance countries.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope">
    <text>Widely distributed PSO-1 (sight sniper optical) of Soviet production. For the installation down the weapon is used fastening of the type dovetail standard in the countries of the Warsaw Pact.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-scope-susat">
    <text>Sight sniper 4x-multiple 'Susat L9A1', produced in the NATO alliance countries. For the installation down the weapon is used the standard NATO fastening, named the plank type Picatinny.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-silencer">
    <text>PBS - silencer, assembled in the Zone by some skillful individuals. With it before the set of attending the framing of perexodinikov under the weapon of any calibre.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n Avtomat of Kalashnikov folding (AKS-74) of model 1974 under the cartridge of 5.45x39mm is simple and reliable weapon, although the cheapness before the production somewhat had effect on convenience in utilisation and precision of combat. In the Zone this basic weapon of military stalkers and many lone persons.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n AKS-74M has the modified breech mechanism, which increases the velocity of firing.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.45x39 - basic \n • 5.45x39 AP - armour-piercing \n Avtomat of the Kalashnikov of collapsible shortened (AKS-74U) of model 1974. Before its dimensions and mass AKS-74U it is close down the submachine guns; however, the operating principle of the mechanism of this weapon and the cartridge used before it make for the sake of its representative of the class of automatic machines. The advantages include low dimensions, which is extremely useful with conducting of combat due to the urban conditions, and sufficiently high punching ability of cartridge. Central failures - low sighting range and tendency down to the rapid superheating with the fire in bursts.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u_m1">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 5.45x39mm - basic \n • 5.45x39mm AP - armour-piercing \n Modification of base version. It is said this automatic machine was found before the heap of rusty iron beyond Garbage, moreover against that place itself, where three months 'strand' gravity anomaly. It is however strange, ACE proved to be before the excellent condition, and the stay before the anomaly had effect on it by the surprising mode: bullets released of this weapon possess considerably greater energy. It is furnished for the sake of tight silencer.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 9x19mm type parabellum - basic \n • 9x19mm PBP - improved \n Sostoit in arsenal of the Vooruzhennyx forces and police of the USA, many militarised and law-enforcement formings in the entire world. It is so popular in the representatives of criminal peace because of the powerful cartridge and the great capacity of magazine.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta_m1">
    <text>Newest modification type M9 - American version of this weapon. is characterised by gun manufactured with the help of most up-to-date technologies, as a result of which considerably they were improved precision and lethal activity of weapon. \n the ammunition: \n of the basis of 9x19mm IEC, \n improved 9x19mm PBP.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 12x70 buckshot \n • 12x76 type Jacques \n • 12x76 the dart \n of nObrez of hunting gun BM-16. It is considerably more compact and easier than the full-valued double-gun, but it is effective only for close combat. One of the most promissing types of weapons for novices.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .45 ACP - basic \n • .45 ACP type hydra-Shok - improved \n Favorite of hired killers. Old good reliable Colt, provided by the Captive 'silencer'.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt1911">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .45 ACP - basic \n • .45 ACP type hydra-Shok - improved \n Klassichesky automatic Colt, with the honour which passed all the armed conflicts of the 20th century and which confidently entered the new century. Low magazine capacity down the specific degree is compensated by the utilisation of a powerful cartridge.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-desert-eagle">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .45 ACP - basic \n • .45 ACP type hydra-Shok - improved \n 'Desert type Eagle' ('Desert Orel') - present gun for the real heroes. Great heavy and extremely lethal. Because of the price and the dimensions it does not enjoy particular popularity in the zone, nevertheless not each day you hunt the elephant.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-eagle_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x39 PUB -9 - basic \n • 9x39 CP -6 - armour-piercing \n • 9x39 CP-5 sniper \n "Desert type Eagle" of 9x39 - modification even without that of powerful pistol under the special cartridge of the calibre of 9x39mm truly killing piece for the close combat.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n ammunition for that integrated M-203: \n • the shot M -209 \n FN type herstal type f2000 - automatic-grenade-throwing complex with the computerised sight-module of control of fire and 40mm by grenade launcher.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x18 - basic \n • 9x18 "P" - improved \n Pistol the police designation of Ukrainian production, that took the place PM. It possesses best in comparison with "Makarov" the precision of combat, ergonomics and more spacious magazine; however, is less reliable.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x18 - basic \n • 9x18 'P' - the improved \n Eksperimentalny prototype of the pistol type Fort.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 5.56x45mm SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45mm AR - armour-piercing \n Heckler and Koch type G36 - assault rifle of German production, which is a sufficiently good model with up-to-date features and it is ergonomic.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g37">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 5.56x45mm SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45mm AR - armour-piercing \n Heckler and Koch type g36 - assault rifle of German production, which is the sufficiently good model of up-to-date weapon - lung and ergonomic. This model lay long time before the anomaly 'Jelly' and gained unique properties - seriously was increased destructive power and firing distance. In addition to this, the model is equipped for the sake of the integrated NATO rifle grenade launcher under the shot M-203.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36_m1">
    <text>Modification of base version. Even series G36 is one of the best assault rifles in the Zone. But also so high combat characteristicss it was possible to considerably improve. Someone from the grouping 'Monolith' was conjectured to grind an artifact 'Gravi', and the obtained powder to rub beside the external and internal surfaces of gun. The considerable increase of lethal force and precision became result. \n ammunition: \n common 5.56x45mm SS109, \n armour-piercing 5.56x45mm AR.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • the charges type m72 'Gauss' - basic \n M72-M the rifle of Gauss - cverxtochnoe weapon, which they gathered and modernized in the mobile laboratory of scientists. It works almost noiselessly, since energy of artifacts,, but not powder gases is used for the firing. In spite of the colossal power of shot, output in the rifle of Gauss is very small. Any classical small arms exceeds on the precision and the lethal force. Complete ignoring of put on bronizhileta.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x39 PUB -9 - basic \n • 9x39 CP -6 - armour-piercing \n • 9x39 CP-5 sniper \n ammunition for integrated GP-25 'Bonfire': \n • shot VOG- 25 \n • shot VOG-25R \n Avtomatno-grenade-throwing complex OC-14 'Thunderstorm' - the very successful due to Zone conditions version of assault rifle for the close combat: compact, reliable and at the same time universal and powerful.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza_m1">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 5.45x39mm - basic \n • 5.45x39mm AP - armour-piercing \n OC 'Thunderstorm' of 5.45mm - modification of one of the stalker- skillful individuals, at the point of which it was possible to alter rifle under the more propagated cartridge of 5.45mm. Furthermore, this model has the integrated the 3rd multiple optical sight and the increased magazine (45 cartridges).</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza_m2">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 7.62x39mm - basic \n • 7.62x39mm AP - armour-piercing \n ammunition for the integrated grenade launcher - \n • Shot VOG-25 \n This weapon was presented to General Voronin by one of the armourers beside the commendation at the point of the rescue of life. Version 'Thunderstorm-1' for the army Special Force under the widespread cartridge of 7x62 x39. Automatic machine as far as 70 percent is standardised with AKM, and are used standard AKMovskie magazines.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hpsa">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x19 FMJ - basic \n • 9x19 OF PBP - improved \n to n 'Browning' is deservedly considered one of the best pistols of the 20th century. Reliable and powerful. It possesses grow prettier by an accuracy of firing. Magazine capacity composes 13 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife">
    <text>Hunting knife</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-l85">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Enfield type l85 A2. After this rifle was replaced as far as the UK Army down German HK type g36, it before the large numbers floated up on the Black Market, and then in the Zone. The main advantage type enfield type l85 A2 are the authorised 4x- multiple optical sight "Of susat L9A1" and the high precision of the first shot. The precision of combat sharply falls with the fire in bursts, and the reliability of the basic mechanisms of rifle is insufficiently high.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-l85_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Aid of several modifications was possible to decrease the effect of recoil of gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-l85_m2">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Oruzhie is furnished for the sake of the integrated 'silencer'. Many details are replaced down the lighter analogs, which substantially decreases the weight of weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-lr300">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n The new step before the development of the family of famous M16. Name literally indicates 'light rifle with the effective fire range to 300 metres'. Because of the exceptionally even descent, high ergonomics and low weight this weapon is characterised by the high precision of combat, although the high sensitivity to the contamination is made its not always suitable for the utilisation before the complex field conditions.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-lr300_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Modification of the civilian version LR300 SR without the regime of automatic fire, fitted by 3x-optics. It was assumed that it will be used as the cheap analogue of sniper rifle.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x19 FMJ - basic \n • 9x19 PBP - improved \n Heckler and Koch MP5N-K, one of the best before the class submachine guns weapon. During the recent decades of the 20th century it was accepted for the armament of the special units of army and police before many countries of world. Since the beginning of its gradual replacement as far as more up-to-date models it began to frequently appear against the Black Market, from where mass it fell also beside the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x19 FMJ - basic \n • 9x19 PBP - improved \n Heckler and Koch MP5K-N - light, compact, and now still and altered under the common calibre, this submachine gun is present find for the beginning stalkers .</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5_m2">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x19 FMJ - basic \n • 9x19 PBP - improved \n Heckler and Koch MP5K-N. Modification of base model. Is added the Captive 'silencer'.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pb">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x18 - basic \n • 9x18 'P' - improved \n Pistol noiseless (PB) with the integrated 'silencer', there is no time used as far as the Soviet Special Force. It became obsolete, but before the skillful hands as before it is sufficiently effective.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pm">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x18 - basic \n • 9x18 'P' - improved \n Pistol Makarov (PM), the most common in the Zone pistol - legacy of Soviet epoch. Sufficiently reliable and cheap, is characterised by low magazine capacity with the undercapacity and the unsatisfactory grouping of cartridge. Basic weapon of stalker-novice.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg-6">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • shot VOG-25 \n • shot VOG-25P \n Hand help grenade launcher (RG) of the revolving drum type. Sometimes it is simply irreplaceable, in particular with removal of mutants from great areas, attack beyond the protected stationary objects, in combat with the particularly tenacious creatures.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg6_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • shot M -209 \n Hand help a grenade launcher (RG) of the revolving drum type. It is modified for the delivery of fire by the shots of western model M-209.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpg7">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • shot PG-7V \n Hand help the antitank grenade launcher (RPG-7V) of model 1960X, before the huge amount which was remained on the army depots, from where it fell beside the Zone. Rare for the stalker weapon: imposing dimensions and great weight make for the sake of its not too popular, although it is simply irreplaceable for some missions.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Oruzhie was created for conducting battles due to the conditions of city. In order to lighten weight, some components were retracted or replaced. As a result down the weapon greater it is not possible to hang either sight, or barrel-attached grenade launcher. Then weight was reduced almost doubly.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig_m2">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Modification for conducting the sniper fire. Weapon is furnished for the sake of the Captive optical sight of the increased multiplicity.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig220">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .45 ACP - basic \n • .45 ACP type hydra-Shok - improved Model \n came out still in 1975, but, until now, popular in the entire world. Magazine insufficiently large-capacity, then mechanism is reliable as Swiss hours; second plus is the utilisation of a powerful koltovskogo cartridge.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig550">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 5.56x45 SS109 - basic \n • 5.56x45 AR - armour-piercing \n Odna from the relatively new Swiss assault rifles under the cartridge of 5.56x45 SS109. Precision, soft output and high reliability of this weapon rapidly earned to it the widest popularity.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 12x70 buckshot \n • 12x76 type Jacques \n • 12x76 dart \n Modification gun SPAS 12 was came out at the end as far as 1970 - X as the universal combat weapon for the police and the assault subunits of army. High reliability and flexibility of application differ this weapon; based on the other side, it is sufficiently massive, it is complicated before the device and it is dear. Perhaps, the best gun for the close combat before the Zone not to find.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 12x76 type Jacques \n • 12x76 dart \n Modification down the decrease of dispersion this SPAS 12 badly is suitable for the firing buckshot, then it is ideal for the firing the cartridges type Jacques or dart.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 7.62 x54 of 7N1 - basic \n • 7.62 x54 type h13 - armour-piercing \n • 7x62 x54 of 7N14 - sniper \n the nSnayperskaya rifle type Dragunov (SVD). Widely it was used before all combat operations, which were being conducted by Soviet and Russian armies with 1960 - X of years. It recommended itself as exceptionally reliable before the address weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 7.62 x54 of 7N1 - basic \n • 7.62 x54 type h13 - armour-piercing \n • 7x62 x54 of 7N14 - sniper \n Modification of SVD, equipped by special gun. Optics of 6X. The balance of weapon is improved, output is as a result reduced.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 7.62x54R of 7N13 - basic, armour-piercing \n • 7.62x54R of 7N1 - sniper \n • 7.62x54R of 7N14 - sniper, armour-piercing \n sniper rifle shortened automatic folding (SVU-ACE). The modern indoor compact version SVD, carried out according to the scheme 'of bull-pup' (scheme before which magazine and mechanisms are located behind the control handle besides fire). The advantage of this scheme consists before the fact that with the relatively greater length of gun the weapon remains compact. \n it is very good before the remote journeys through the zone, however, in comparison with SVD, it nevertheless suffers an increase in the average dispersion, which limits effective fire range to the average distances.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu_m1">
    <text>Modification of base version. If we believe to stalker stories, SVU once belonged to experimental stalker on the nickname little-one (this person was actually small growth and in no way Herculean build). It itself altered its SVU, having considerably lightened it and after equipping for the sake of the compensator of output. \n the ammunition: \n common 7.62 x54mm of 7N1, \n armour-piercing 7.62 x54mm AP, \n sniper 7.62 x54mm of 7N14.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 12x70 buckshot \n • 12x76 type Jacques \n • 12x76 dart \n Shiroko widespread and by nothing particular, besides the power of combat, not remarkable hunting rifle TOZ-34 'Of vertikalka.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-usp">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .45 ACP - basic \n • .45 ACP type hydra-Shok - improved \n Solidny gun. German quality and reliability. Compact short-range weapon. It enjoys particular popularity among the veterans of Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val">
    <text>This weapon is based on the VSS Vintorez sniper rifle.  However, it has a folding stock, can fire in bursts, and has a larger magazine. Originally designed for special forces units operating in conditions demanding silenced and supressed fire.\n Ammunition:\n Standard 9x39mm PAB-9\n Armor-Piercing 9x39mm SP-6\n Sniper 9x39mm SP-5</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x39 CP -6 - armour-piercing \n • 9x39 CP -5 - sniper \n AC 'Shaft' with integrated triple optics.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 9x39mm CP -6 - armour-piercing \n • 9x39mm CP -5 - sniper \n Version sniper special 'thread cutter' (VSS 'thread cutter'), is intended for the noiseless and flameless sniper firing and is furnished for the sake of the integrated 'silencer'. For the self defence is envisaged the regime of automatic fire; however, sufficiently it is rapidly driven in by carbon deposit. In spite of this, at the point of compactness, precision, high efficiency and possibility to conduct direct fire 'shed' greatly is valued by the stalker of any level.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_m1">
    <text>Modification of base version with larger-capacity magazine and unique optics. 'Thread cutter' with the grant label from nobody Sergey Tixy's stalker. No one in the Zone remembers nothing about the origin of this weapon - apparently, its real owner has long ago been dead. The surprising property of this rifle - its bullet they fly with the greater velocity across the more straight direct trajectory. \n the ammunition: \n common 9x39mm PUB -9, \n armour-piercing 9x39mm CP -6, \n sniper 9x39mm CP -5.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-walther">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 9x19mm type parabellum - basic \n • 9x19mm PBP - improved \n Otlichny pistol of German production, which is characterised by high reliability, large-capacity magazine grow prettier by the precision of combat, especially before this version - under the 9 - millimeter cartridge type parabellum.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-walther_m1">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x18 - basic \n • 9x18 'P' - improved \n Modification of pistol for the delivery of fire by ammunition of the calibre of 9x18 millimeters</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1300">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 12x70mm buckshot \n • 12x76mm of Dart \n • 12x76mm dart \n Modification pump-action the gun of American production, created for the application due to the quite neblagopritnyx conditions and characterising by high reliability. All details are furnished for the sake of anticorrosive coating.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1100">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 12x70mm buckshot \n • 12x76mm of Dart \n • 12x76mm dart \n Modification pump-action the gun of American production. All details are furnished for the sake of anticorrosive coating. This model underwent the lasting effect of radiation, after lying half a year in the anomalous Zone down Chernobyl, and it gained unique properties before the plan of the increased wear resistance, rate of fire, destructive power and precision of firing.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-fn2000_old">
    <text>Unique FN2000</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000_old">
    <text>The unique creation of stalker nicknamed Screw. At the point of five boxes of vodka he altered this gun to use cartridge 5.45. Unfortunately, barrel-attached grenade launcher proved to be damaged.</text>
</string>
<string id="grenade-f1">
    <text>F1 Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="grenade-gd05">
    <text>GD-05 Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="grenade-rgd5">
    <text>RGD-5 Grenade</text>
</string>
<string id="Weapons1">
    <text>Weapon</text>
</string>
<string id="wp_desert_eagle">
    <text>Desert Eagle</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_hpsa">
    <text>HPSS-1m</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_korth">
    <text>UDP Compact</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-abakan">
    <text>Abakan</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-abakan_m1">
    <text>AN-94 Abakan 'Sniper'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-abakan_m2">
    <text>AN-94 Abakan 'Assault'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
    <text>GP-25 Kostyer</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
    <text>M203</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-addon-scope">
    <text>PSO-1 Scope</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-addon-scope-susat">
    <text>SUSAT Scope</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-addon-silencer">
    <text>Silencer</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-ak74">
    <text>AKS-74</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-ak74_m1">
    <text>AKS-74M</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-ak74u">
    <text>AKS-74U</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-ak74u_m1">
    <text>AKS-74U 'Modified'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-beretta">
    <text>Beretta 92FS</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-beretta_m1">
    <text>Beretta M9A1</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-bm16">
    <text>BM-16</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-colt_m1">
    <text>Colt Silenced</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-colt1911">
    <text>Colt 1911</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-eagle_m1">
    <text>Desert Eagle 9x39</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-fn2000">
    <text>FN2000</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-fort">
    <text>Fort 12</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-fort_m">
    <text>Fort 15</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-g36">
    <text>HK G36</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-g37">
    <text>HK G36 modified</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-g36_m1">
    <text>G36 Crystal</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-gauss">
    <text>Gauss weapon</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-groza">
    <text>OC-14 Groza</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-groza_m1">
    <text>OC Groza standard calibre</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-groza_m2">
    <text>General Voronin's 5.45mm 'Groza'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-l85">
    <text>Enfield L85-A2</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-l85_m1">
    <text>Enfield L85-A2 Balanced</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-l85_m2">
    <text>Enfield L85-A2 Lightened</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-lr300">
    <text>LR300</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-lr300_m1">
    <text>LR300 SR</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-mp5">
    <text>HK MP5N-K</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-mp5_m1">
    <text>HK MP5N-K 9x18</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-mp5_m2">
    <text>HK MP5 Silenced</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-pb">
    <text>PB</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-pm">
    <text>PM</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-rg-6">
    <text>RG-6</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-rg6_m1">
    <text>RG-6 M-209</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-rpg7">
    <text>RPG-7V</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-sig_m1">
    <text>SIG 550 Lightened</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-sig_m2">
    <text>SIG 550 Sniper</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-sig220">
    <text>SIG 220</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-sig550">
    <text>SIG 550</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-spas12">
    <text>SPAS 12</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-spas12_m1">
    <text>SPAS 12 Modified</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-svd">
    <text>SVD</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-svd_m1">
    <text>SVD Modified</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-svu">
    <text>SVU 'ACE'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-svu_m1">
    <text>SVU 'Little-One'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-toz34">
    <text>TOZ-34 'Vertical'</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-val">
    <text>AS VAL</text> <!-- VS Val -->
</string>
<string id="wpn-val_m1">
    <text>Scoped AS VAL</text> <!-- VS Val 'M1' -->
</string>
<string id="wpn-vintorez">
    <text>VSS Vintorez</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-vintorez_m1">
    <text>VSS Vintorez Modified</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-walther">
    <text>Walther P99</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-walther_m1">
    <text>Walter P99-M 9x18</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-wincheaster1300">
    <text>Winchester 1300</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-wincheaster1100">
    <text>Winchester 1300 Modified</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_dark_gauss">
    <text>Gauss Dark because of the fact that for long lay before an anomaly of jellied meat and has furious rate of fire in comparison with other gauss.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_dark_gauss">
    <text>Gauss Illusion</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta_m1">
    <text>The newest modification type M9 - American version of this weapon. is characterised by gun manufactured with the help of most up-to-date technologies, as a result of which considerably they were improved precision and lethal activity of weapon. \n the ammunition: \n of the basis of 9x19mm IEC, \n improved 9x19mm PBP.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-beretta_m1">
    <text>Beretta M9A1</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-flame_readme">
    <text>The homemade flamethrower by the construction of Svobodov for Screw. It is charged for the sake of two-component mixture from the colloidal gas 'F' and the petroleum products. Mixture self-ignites in air; therefore construction is maximally simple. However, the details, manufactured based on highly technological anticorrosive materials, received due to the particular laboratory conditions, are applied because of the high chemical activity of mixture before the construction. Moreover only screw, masters the listening post of the production of mixture. At the point of these reasons the flamethrower did not become mass article, in spite of the very serious advantages over the common firearms with the rendezvous with some inhabitants of Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-flame_name">
    <text>Flamethrower</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-flame_name_s">
    <text>Flamethrower</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo_flame_name">
    <text>Combustible Mixture</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-p90">
    <text>PDW of which type belgian FN of company of developed. I do the of novel of design of which of before of based on of ergonomics of does of not of have. Because FN type p90 (project 90) is of firearms of a of new of form to of use of ammunition of for of exclusive of use of a of thing of of shape of such as of the of rifle of bullet of that of was of miniaturised of without of using an of existing of handgun of bullet of for of unlike of the of submachine of gun; at of first of 'PDW' (Personal Defence Weapon). It of was of announced in a of category of called of personal of defence of weapon). For of operative of thought of FN of company, I did of not of engage in of control of duties of such as a of panzer of unit or of the of backward of military of unit, and the of power of was of suggested as of handy, strong of firearms to of carry of with Me so of that of the of member of who of did of not of need of the of carrying of such as of the of automatics of which I had a of long it, and was of heavy of of the of thing of which of there of was by of all of means of either of coped of with of subversive of activity at of the of time of of the of rear of penetration by of the of enemy of corps, and it was of developed at of the of end of of 1980 ' s. \n type ammunition: \n of 5.7 x 28mm SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-p90_name">
    <text>FN P90</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.7x28">
    <text>5.7x28mm SS190 of full of metal of jacket of bullet is of the of accomplishment of bullet of which is of made to of penetrate of body type armour. An iron of warhead is of covered a of bullet of core of made by of aluminium of with.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.7x28_name">
    <text>5.7x28 SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.7x28_s">
    <text>5.7x28 SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pkm">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 7.62x54mm (tape on 250 cartridges) \n for the sake of a similar weapon are usually equipped the heavily armed detachments of military stalkers. In the Zone it is encountered extremely rarely, in view of great dimensions and weight, which requires the carrying of the exoskeleton for the firing based on the hands \n the machine guns of a series PK / OF RMB are characterised by high reliability and enjoy the deserved popularity before the troops, disregarding besides a somewhat pereuslozhnennuyu two-stage feed system of cartridges besides the tape beside the gun. Barrel quick-change, has a carrying handle, also utilised for replacing the hot gun. Feed by cartridges - from the nerassypnoy metallic tape with the closed team. The authorised capacity of belts is 100 (before the manual version) cartridges. The direction of belt feed - from right to left, ports for supply and emergence of tape are equipped for the sake of dust caps as port for the blowout of the spent cases. The supply of cartridges from the tape two-stage - first special capture with the recoil of zavtornoy frame extracts cartridge from the tape ago, after which cartridge descends down the line of ramming and with the counterrecoil of breechblock is rammed home beside the gun. Firing is conducted based on the discovered breechblock, only by automatic fire. Standard controls before the infantry version include pistol handle, trigger, manual safety device and frame butt.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-pkm_name">
    <text>PKM</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54r">
    <text>Authorised sniper cartridge for the rifles of SVD, THE SVU-ACE also of machine gun PKM. Breech casing with a belt 250 cartridges for the manual version of machine gun PKM. \n despite the fact that of 7N1 is accepted for the armament in 1967, it 2-3 times exceeds up-to-date gross 7N13 about the indicators of dispersion. However, because of the application of the blunt-ended stamped core through steel 10, bullet TsP does not possess high breakdown properties.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54r_s">
    <text>7.62x54mm, 250 belt</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-p90">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 5.7x28 SS190 \n the Belgian submachine gun, came out before 1980 - X years by the firm FN type herstal. In spite of unusual exterior view, is sufficiently effective. For FN type p90 was came out the special cartridge of 5.7x28mm SS190, which possesses greater breakdown power than other pistol cartridges. This bullet develops muzzle velocity to 715 metres per second and is capable of clearing the majority of bulletproof vests. It is convenient before the application, it has extremely weak output. Magazine is located on top, capacity - 50 cartridges.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-p90_name">
    <text>FN P90</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.7x28">
    <text>The 5.7x28mm cartridge is a small caliber, high velocity cartridge created by FN Herstal in Belgium in conjunction with the FN P90 personal defense weapon (PDW) and FN Five-Seven pistol. Developed in response to NATO requests for a replacement for 9x19mm Parabellum, the 5.7x28mm is a bottlenecked centerfire cartridge that is somewhat similar to the .22 Hornet or .22 K-Hornet. The SS190 FMJ, a refinement of the SS90, was introduced in 1993. It offered superior performance over the prototype projectile as well as slightly reduced length. This bullet develops a muzzle velocity of 715 metres per second and is capable of penetrating bulletproof vests.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.7x28_name">
    <text>5.7x28 SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-5.7x28_s">
    <text>5.7x28 SS190</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-tt33">
    <text>TT-33</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-tt33">
    <text>Tokarev pistol, model 1933 (TT-33) under the cartridge of 7.62x25mm \n the ammunition: \n common 7.62x25mm TT, \n 7.62x39mm with the steel bullet PS.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x25mm PS</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_s">
    <text>7.62x25 PS</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p">
    <text>Rounds 7.62x39mm TT</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_s">
    <text>7.62x25 TT</text>
</string>

; ------- weapons ZEN ------- ;

<string id="enc_weapons1_kriss_super_v">
    <text>Submachine gun under the cartridge 11.43mm is designed by company TDI in such a way that the gun is located by very low-, practically on one line with the hand. Therefore in spite of the utilisation of this powerful cartridge possesses unique stability and grouping with the firing. To the deficiencies can be attributed the utilisation of a standard magazine from the pistol type Glock 21 down 13 cartridges. \n the ammunition: \n obychny .45 ACP, \n uluchshenny .45 ACP hydro-shock.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-mp7a3">
    <text>The submachine gun of MR-7a3 PDW (personal weapon of self defence), is came out by firm Heckler and Koch for the armament of soldiers, to which the full-valued automatic machine is not assumed on the state. Pp it was developed under the progressive cartridge of 4.6x30mm, but low ubiquitous of this cartridge forced creators to release modification under standard conditions 9x19mm type parabellum, although the majority of its advantages pp lost with this cartridge. \n the ammunition: \n osnovnoy of 9x19mm type parabellum, \n uluchshenny 9x19mm PBP.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bizon">
    <text>Submachine gun PP-19 'bison' was developed for the armament MVD on the basis of wide standardisation with the automatic machine AK-74. On 'the bison' is established the original auger magazine of high capacity down 64 cartridges. Magazine is located sufficiently conveniently, and in parallel is performed the role of shank. \n the ammunition: \n osnovnoy of 9x18 millimeters, \n uluchshenny 9x18mm of P.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_mp7">
    <text>HK MP-7a3</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-bizon">
    <text>PP-19 Bison</text>
</string>
<string id="kriss_super_v">
    <text>Kriss Super V</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-9mm_nato-silencer">
    <text>Army American silencer. It is used in essence for the submachine guns of the western production of the calibre of 9mm.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-9mm_nato-silencer">
    <text>Silencer of 9mm (NATO)</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-m1891_30_scope_name">
    <text>M1891/30-PE</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-m1891_30_scope">
    <text>Ammunition - \n • 7.62x54mm of 7N1 - basic \n • 7.62x54mm AP - armour-piercing \n • 7.62x54mm of 7N14 - sniper \n Version of the system type Mosin is magazine-fed weapon with the manual recharging. Optical sight of model P. The sufficiently typical model of the Russian and Soviet weapons idea, when convenience before the address with the weapon and ergonomics were sacrificed of reliability, to simplicity before the production and the assimilation and the cheapness.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-357sw-jhp">
    <text>Type of the bullet: JHP (semi-jacketed with the expansive cut); Weight of bullet, deg: 8.125; Diameter of bullet, millimeters: 9.02; Muzzle velocity, m \n a: 442; Energy, George: 793</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-357sw-jhp">
    <text>357 Smith and Wesson Magnum (9x32mm)</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-357sw-jfp">
    <text>A type of bullet: Jacketed type flat type point (tunicary with the flat head part) the weight of bullet, deg: 10.27 diameter of bullet, millimeters: 9.02 muzzle velocity, m \n a: 377 energy, George: 898</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-357sw-jfp">
    <text>357 Smith and Wesson Magnum (9x32mm R)</text>
</string>

<string id="wpn-colt_python">
    <text>Colt 'Python'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-colt_python">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .357 magnum \n • sighting range 60 m \n • rate of fire 25 volts per metre \n • the capacity of the mag of 6 cartridges \n Sportivno-hunting revolver Colt 'Python-Elite' with the gun of the long of 153mm (6 inches), possesses high lethal activity and grow prettier by precision. It is at present removed from series production, but, until now he is valued by the lovers of revolvers. The reasons for appearance before the Zone are unknown.</text>
</string>

<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_50BMG">
    <text>Modernization explosive cartridge for the rifles WA-2000 and M82A3.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-50BMG">
    <text>12.7x99mm (.50 BMG)</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapon_wa2000">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .50 BMG - basic \n Snayperskaya rifle WA-2000 was came out by German firm Carl type walther type waffenfabrik before the beginning of 1970x of years as the special-purpose weapon for the police and the protivoterroristicheskix subunits. In the Zone it is modernised under the cartridge .50 BMG, which allowed this rifle, let and with small otstovaniem, to keep against the level M82A3.</text>
</string>
<string id="name_WA-2000">
    <text>Walther WA-2000</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapon_m82a3">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • .50 BMG - basic \n Dovolno the famous sniper rifle type barrett type m82, which stands in arsenal of the US Army, Great Britain, Austria, Chile, Bulgaria, Brazil, Finland, Germany, Israel and many others. The maximum distance of fire - 6 km; however, effective fire can be conducted only on the distance to 2100m. This rifle to be envelopped beside the price of approximately 8,900 US dollars. This modification is M82A1 modernization version, with the universal plank type Picatinny.</text>
</string>
<string id="M82A3">
    <text>Barret M82A3</text>
</string>
<string id="ars-c96">
    <text>Mauser C96 Model 712</text>
</string>
<string id="arsenal_mod-c96">
    <text>Ammunition: \n • 9x19 FMJ - basic \n • 9x19 PBP - improved \n Mauzer C-96 model 712 - the automatic version with the ring down twenty cartridges, came out about 1895. Pistol relates down the most powerful models of the automatic pistols, the activity of automation of which is based beyond the utilisation of recoil energy of gun with its short course. Down the advantages of pistol is worth relating precision and distance of combat, powerful cartridge and good life of weapon in field conditions. To the deficiencies - complexity of the rechargings, greater mass and dimensions.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-ppsh">
    <text>PPSH-41</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ppsh">
    <text>Submachine gun type Shpagina of the model in 1941 - The PPSh operated with simple blowback action, had a box or drum magazine, and fired the 7.62x25mm pistol round. This version is equipped with a curve-slide sight and circular magazine down 71 cartridges. \n the ammunition: \n common 7.62 x25 millimeters, \n armour-piercing 7.62 x25mm AP.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
