<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<!-- ;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;
;	 ,,,,,      ,,,,,,,    ,,,,,,_  ,,,,,,,,  ,,,,,,   
;       MMMMM1     M0MMMM&    MMMMM@'  MMMMMM0"  MMMM0!   
;       4MMMM#      ^MMMMMr   MMMMMf    #MMMM&    B0'     
;      &]MMMMMc      #MMMM# ] MMMMMf    #MMMM&   j#       
;      M 0MMMM&       MMMMML# MMMMMf    #MMMM&  pM&       
;     pY 4MMMMM     ] #MMMMM# MMMMMf    #MMMM& pMMMt      
;     M   MMMMMc    ]& MMMMMf MMMMMf    #MMMM&]MMMM0      
;    ]#   0MMMM&    ]M #MMMM  MMMMMf    #MMMM& MMMMM&     
;    QfjMMMMMMMM    ]M  MMMf  MMMMMf    #MMMM& 4MMMMM     
;   _M    "MMMMMf   ]M  BMM   MMMMMf    #MMMM&  MMMMM&    
;  _Q#     MMMMM&   jMg  M8  _MMMMMf    BMMMM&  jMMMMM,   
; 4MMMM   #MMMMMM# 0MMM& B  ]MMMMMMM&  0MMMMMM&]MMMMMMMt  
;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;;

-->

	<string id="amk_metka">
		<text>GPS-beacon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="amk_metka_s">
		<text>GPS-beacon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_amk_metka">
		<text>GPS-beacon. The Zone appeared not so long ago and GPS-beacon enjoys extreme popularity due to it's usability and acceptable pricing. Initially, the prototype was delivered to the territory of 'Duty' to demonstrate and make a deal to supply large quantities of these beacons. However, the accidental loss of the test version on the eve of the representative's meeting, of both sides, caused a falling-out in their relations with the supplier. The long and mutually beneficial relationship between General Voronin and Sakharov occurred there at an opportune time, and with the help of a local merchant the prototype beacon fell into the hands of field laboratory scientists in Amber. It was modernized and put into mass production for the needs of all. The original version did not survive due to a direct upgrade of the prototype. The upgraded version is different in a positive way because you can put a digital signature on the Beacon (Cyrillic, unfortunately, is not supported) and synchronize it with the owner's PDA. On the base of the research of the system for protection from psy affects the scientists attained that the beacon will not interfere and detection by people is practically impossible. Given the fact that the GPS-beacons are produced in-house at Sakharov's laboratory, the scientist prices are more reasonable than those of Zone dealers.</text>
	</string>

<!-- 20:58 09.07.2007 -->
<-- Modified="" by="" Aero="" 19:22="" 20="">

