<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="bar_arena_actor_afraid">
    <text>The fight is canceled. The challenger chickened out and left the ring. Coward!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_10">
    <text>It took 10 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_20">
    <text>It took 20 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_30">
    <text>It took 30 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_40">
    <text>It took 40 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_50">
    <text>It took 50 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_60">
    <text>A minute passed!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_70">
    <text>A minute passed, and 10 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_80">
    <text>A minute passed, and 20 seconds!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_90">
    <text>It took fifteen minutes!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_begin">
    <text>The battle has begun!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_bloodsucker">
    <text>Attention! Attention! Soon the arena will begin a new battle! In the left corner of the arena bloody and always hungry leech! In the right corner of the arena ... people? Yes, man! Everyone calls him Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_burer">
    <text>Attention! Attention! Soon the arena will begin a new battle! In the left corner of the arena, he knows 'Fou Yuck', he is able to bend spoons in his ass! In the right corner of the arena hero, whose search never ends! Everyone calls him Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_dead">
    <text>So what? The enemy killed the challenger. That's was cool!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_lose">
    <text>So what? The challenger did kill the enemy, but not in the timea alloted and lost!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_pseudodog">
    <text>Attention! Attention! Soon, the arena will begin a new battle! In the left corner of the arena white and fluffy, but incredibly evil, a pseudodog! In the right corner of the arena came out of nowhere, going nowhere. Everyone calls him Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_savage">
    <text>Attention! Attention! Soon, the arena will begin a new battle! In the left corner of the arena, you know it, you love it. And he hates you. This is a beast! In the right corner of the arena is still alive Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_snork">
    <text>Attention! Attention! Soon, the arena will begin a new battle! In the left corner of the arena a 'martial arts' expert in nutrition and Snork! In the right corner of the arena a man without a past. Everyone calls him Strelok.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_timeout">
    <text>Time's up! Challenger lost, but still fighting for his life!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_arena_fight_victory">
    <text>So what? The challenger had killed the enemy in the required time and won!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_attack">
    <text>As you wish.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_attract_actor">
    <text>Stalker my friend! Please do not go away, help us! Anarchists shot down our helicopter and now we will get killed. We have injured, we need your help!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_heli_down">
    <text>He he, that's all. Do not have your helicopter! Now you get the shaft!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_crush_start_heli">
    <text>All right Wolf you dog face. They flew in on a military helicopter. Now they have you as a puppy!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_escape">
    <text>Professor escaped! Urgent, all go in pursuit of Kruglov! He could not have gone far.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_hit">
    <text>Strelok, help me! Killing me!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_1">
    <text>Manage these bastards. This ain't school where we would be putting forth an ultimatum.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_2">
    <text>If you attack I will destroy the information. 'Between the lines dude', not my work.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_3">
    <text>If you do not want me to destroy the research results then stay away.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_ecolog_spam_4">
    <text>Wolf, takes his dogs, while their tails are between their legs!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_attack">
    <text>All conversations are over. Let us start shooting.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_attack_attract_actor">
    <text>Man let's finish them off! The point is, let's kill these guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_attack_spy">
    <text>Strelok. If you support us we will be indebted.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_chase">
    <text>They come for us? Strelok stop them!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_spam_1">
    <text>In short you idiot scientist. You give me the results or you will leave in a body bag.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_spam_2">
    <text>Kruglov I do not know Latin, but I know the language of weapons. Do you want to give up your life or give up the information?</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_spam_3">
    <text>Professor you're a smart person. Give up the information and then get lost.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_freedom_spam_4">
    <text>Kruglov, you still do not understand? We shot down your freak'n helicopter and we need the information that you have. Once you give it to us you are can leave. This is your last chance to get out of here, let's talk and split up.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_psih_come">
    <text>Urgent help needed here! Near Radar my guys caught a wacky stalker and now they are trying to interrogate him.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_dolg_1_hit">
    <text>Strelok are you crazy? Immediately stop shooting! That's an order!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_dolg_2_hit">
    <text>Strelok immediately cease fire! If you disobey the order, you're dead meat!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_dolg_3_hit">
    <text>Strelok, for violation of the 'Duty' Code, your expelled from the group. From now on you're our enemy.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_dolg_kill">
    <text>Strelok, you disobeyed an order! Now you're dead! 'Duty' does not forgive!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_1_hit">
    <text>Cease fire, in the territory of 'Duty'! Shooting is prohibited! Disobey and be punished!</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_2_hit">
    <text>Attention! For violation of the law on the use of weapons in the territory of 'Duty' Strelok is declared a criminal.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_territory_nodolg_kill">
    <text>Attention! Discovered a killer! Order to all individuals in 'Duty'! Urgent to destroy this killer!</text>
</string>
<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_1">
    <text>Stalker, help! We were attacked by mercenaries, half of our guys are lost. Help us, we will be indebted.</text>
</string>
<string id="rostok_kruglov_spam_2">
    <text>Help us to break through the ambush near the plant. I sent you the coordinates. Be careful, Wolf is with his thugs near the helicopter.</text>
</string>
