<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string_table>
<string id="aes_case1_desc">
    <text>Common metallic noncombustible case #1. Evidently, containing valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case1_name">
    <text>Common metallic case.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case2_desc">
    <text>Common metallic noncombustible case #2. Evidently, containing valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case2_name">
    <text>Common metallic case.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case3_desc">
    <text>Common metallic noncombustible case #3. Evidently, containing valuable documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="aes_case3_name">
    <text>Common metallic case.</text>
</string>
<string id="stranger">
    <text>Stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_box_desc">
    <text>Container with the medicines. Convenient container for the transportation of medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_box_name">
    <text>Container with the medicines.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_food_desc">
    <text>Wooden box with preserves inside. Evidently still good meat. It's well preserved, we know how to make good food.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_food_name">
    <text>Wooden box with preserves inside.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_sms">
    <text>Personal statements.</text>
</string>
<string id="sms">
    <text>Statement.</text>
</string>
<string id="sms_haron_text">
    <text>This is Charon I am waiting for you ... there is an urgent matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_desc">
    <text>Communication diagram of Pripyat and Chernobyl. Drawings and graphics. Hard for an inexperienced man to understand them.</text>
</string>
<string id="shceme_document_name">
    <text>Diagram of the communications of Pripyat and Chernobyl.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_box_desc">
    <text>Small metallic container. Solomon's sending.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_box_name">
    <text>Small metallic container.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_pismo_desc">
    <text>Letter for Sobolyev from Zahar covered by strong cardboard packaging.</text>
</string>
<string id="zahar_pismo_name">
    <text>Letter from Zahar.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_doc_desc">
    <text>Millboard with the list of the agents, which one way or another cooperated with the military.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_doc_name">
    <text>Millboard with the list of agents.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-winchester_knyaz">
    <text>Duke's Winchester.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_computer_desc">
    <text>Computer disk from Laboratory X-10 at the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_computer_name">
    <text>Computer unit.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_doc_desc">
    <text>Documents from Laboratory X-10 at the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx10_doc_name">
    <text>Documents from Lab X-10.</text>
</string>
<string id="part1_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part1_name">
    <text>Map fragment #1.</text>
</string>
<string id="part2_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part2_name">
    <text>Map fragment #2.</text>
</string>
<string id="part3_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part3_name">
    <text>Map fragment #3.</text>
</string>
<string id="part4_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part4_name">
    <text>Map fragment #4.</text>
</string>
<string id="part5_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part5_name">
    <text>Map fragment #5.</text>
</string>
<string id="part6_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part6_name">
    <text>Map fragment #6.</text>
</string>
<string id="part7_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part7_name">
    <text>Map fragment #7.</text>
</string>
<string id="part8_desc">
    <text>A fragment of the map, on which is indicated the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="part8_name">
    <text>Map fragment #8.</text>
</string>
<string id="semeckii_treasure_box_descr">
    <text>Semetsky's hiding place. It is said he stores very valuable things here.</text>
</string>
<string id="rad_semeckii_treasure_box_name">
    <text>Hiding place of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="tainik_semeckii">
    <text>Search for the hiding place of Semetsky's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="first">
    <text>First fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="first_part_text">
    <text>You found the first fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="second">
    <text>Second fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="second_part_text">
    <text>You found the second fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri">
    <text>Third fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_part_text">
    <text>You found the third fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="four">
    <text>Fourth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="four_part_text">
    <text>You found the fourth fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="five">
    <text>Fifth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="five_part_text">
    <text>You found the fifth fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="six">
    <text>Sixth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="six_part_text">
    <text>You found the sixth fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="seven">
    <text>Seventh fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="seven_part_text">
    <text>You found the seventh fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="vosem">
    <text>Eighth fragment.</text>
</string>
<string id="vosem_part_text">
    <text>You found the eighth fragment of the map which indicates the location of the hiding place of Semetsky's cache.</text>
</string>
<string id="new_plan_desc">
    <text>Bag with Marijuana for the Duke.</text>
</string>
<string id="new_plan_name">
    <text>Bag with the grass.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn-m1891_30_scope_ucen">
    <text>Modified rifle 'Protecta'.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ucen">
    <text>Sniper cartridge with a marker beacon tag.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-ucen">
    <text>Modified sniper cartridge for a modified 'Protecta' for the needs of the scientists. This cartridge possesses very little power, it does not kill, but suspends a small beacon on the victim. This makes it possible to investigate the flora in the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-m1891_30_scope_ucen">
    <text>The modified rifle 'Protecta' for the needs of scientists, which uses only one type of cartridges. A sniper cartridge with a marker tag. This cartridge is a highly under powered. To kill someone is almost impossible.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_ucen_need_metka">
    <text>To hang labels on the monsters: Pseudogiants was last seen in Rostok where a crashed helicopter lies. Bald Chimera can be found in the Dark Valley. You know there is still an abandoned factory there. The bandits sometimes use it as their hangout, and there is a small swamp next to the fence where the waste pipes are. Well I hope you understand. A bloodsucker in the Cordon near a destroyed railway bridge and abandoned pig farms. Now about how to hang a label: I'll give you a rifle 'Protecta', reworked by one of our handymen. It shoots only a special cartridge which in contact with the body of the target hangs a label while not causing any harm. Thus you need to hang a label on all three mutants. Do not forget to return the rifle. To kill outright it will not work, and it still is useful to us. If all goes well I will put onto your PDA useful information about a transition from yantar to the Radar. And of course you cannot kill any of these mutants, I need them alive.</text>
</string>
<string id="af-caterpillar">
    <text>'Heart of the Controller'.</text>
</string>
<string id="af_caterpillar-desc">
    <text>Rare artifact. To find it is possible, but it is very complicated, and that for this it is necessary to have special equipment. This artifact attracts monsters to itself, especially Controllers. Because of this they call it 'Heart of the Controller'. This artifact protects well from bullet wounds, but if a Controller attacks you this artifact will not help, vice-versa, will increase the effect the Controller has your brain.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_pda_name">
    <text>Wolf's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_pda_desc">
    <text>Personal PDA of Wolf.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_krest_razborka">
    <text>In the Garbage near the transition to the Dark Valley, a meeting will occur between Cross and the Chekhovs. You don't want to be seen!! Chekhov's people are nervous; therefore trigger happy. If they see you they will start shooting immediately. There is a destroyed building near the checkpoint. That's where you go for an excellent view. Zashkersya is there. Sit and stay. If all goes well then they'll disperse peacefully with their weapons put away. But if shooting begins then kill all those nitz, and most importantly look after Cross. In short, before my signal do not shoot and do not be seen, sit still and wait. I know you, just be patient.</text>
</string>
<string id="detector_kruglov">
    <text>Kruglov's Detector.</text>
</string>
<string id="detector_kruglov_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's Detector, use it by hanging it on the belt, it will help you to discover of a very rare artifact called 'Heart of the Controller'.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_zombi_name">
    <text>Journal of the mad professor.</text>
</string>
<string id="book_zombi_desc">
    <text>Diary of an insane professor. Apparently this professor worked in the Yantar lab. What particularly interested him was how Psi settings worked.</text>
</string>
<string id="notebook_x16_name">
    <text>Laptop computer from X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="notebook_x16_desc">
    <text>Laptop computer from X-16. There were research records compiled over the years. Perhaps when the X-16 was a fairly large lab, but then something happened and employees ran away, but most still many roam the plant, not as people anymore, but as wandering zombies.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_colt_ucen">
    <text>Kruglov's Colt.</text>
</string>
<string id="wpn_colt_ucen_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's Colt. Altered by a skillful individual, a Colt with silencer that shoots a special cartridge which does not kill its victims, but only paralyses them for a period of time.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo_9x19_ucen">
    <text>Special cartridge of scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="ammo_9x19_ucen_desc">
    <text>Special cartridge of scientists. This altered cartridge, size 9x19, does not kill the victim, but only temporarily paralyses them.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_case_name">
    <text>Kruglov's case.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_case_desc">
    <text>Kruglov's case, intended for General Voronin.</text>
</string>
<string id="check_name">
    <text>Bag of 'grass'.</text>
</string>
<string id="check_desc">
    <text>Small package with the 'grass', not parsley or dill. It is Marijuana.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx18_flash_name">
    <text>Monolith's flash drive.</text>
</string>
<string id="labx18_flash_desc">
    <text>Monolith's flash drive from the X-18 Laboratory.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_mayor_yarofeev">
    <text>According to a Varangian, Major Yarofeev said that it is possible to go beyond the Cordon, and beyond the checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_sidr_lab">
    <text>Go to the Lab at Yantar and find anything: documents, computer, laptop or any thing that will help us understand what was going on. Whatever you find take to Fang, he'll be waiting in Warehouses on a farm near the base of Freedom. They say that in the Laboratory there is something that burns the brains of all living things. Talk to the scientists, maybe they can help.</text>
</string>
<string id="text_arc_sahar_shlem">
    <text>There was one person I used to work with, but then ... then something began to occur to him, something terrible: he was yelling at night, and then suddenly fell silent would and only sit staring at one spot the whole day. Then even worse he was throwing stuff at people. We ... I had to part with him, apparently he experienced a wave of radiation from a Laboratory. Dan and the guys took him to the Radar to Sviblov, but they say he ran away. So you need to find him. He worked for a long time on the influence of psy-radiation affects on the human brain and kept a diary which contains valuable notes. If you get this log I'd be able to reconfigure your helmet.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_black_name">
    <text>Black box.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_black_desc">
    <text>Black box from the crashed helicopter in Radar. Careful it is radioactive.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_priz_name">
    <text>Ghost's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_priz_desc">
    <text>Ghost's PDA. It has data on artifacts and places of their appearance. Also is mentioned is a faction called 'Last Day' and the murder of their leader. There is a little information about the Monolith as well. Data is encoded.</text>
</string>

-----------------------------------new-----------------------------------------

<string id="svitok_1_name">
    <text>The manuscript #1.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_1_desc">
    <text>The manuscript roll, in which is contained the first unit of the laws of the 'Monolith' brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_2_name">
    <text>The manuscript #2.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_2_desc">
    <text>The manuscript roll, in which is contained the second unit of the laws of the 'Monolith' brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_3_name">
    <text>The manuscript #3.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_3_desc">
    <text>The manuscript roll, in which is contained the third unit of the laws of the 'Monolith' brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_4_name">
    <text>The manuscript #4.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_4_desc">
    <text>The manuscript roll, in which is contained the fourth unit of the laws of the 'Monolith' brotherhood.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_5_name">
    <text>The manuscript #5.</text>
</string>
<string id="svitok_5_desc">
    <text>The manuscript roll, which contains the fifth unit of the laws of the 'Monolith' brotherhood:  \n '... the soldier that betrays the brotherhood will become an outcast, and there will be no rest for him, nor will will there be any salvation for him, and Demons will pursue him eternally, as far as one's will...'</text>
</string>

<string id="box_pekar_desc">
    <text>Wooden box with the spare parts for the stove.</text>
</string>
<string id="box_pekar_name">
    <text>Wooden box of Baker.</text>
</string>

<string id="diplomat_skryaga_desc">
    <text>Leather attache case with very important information inside. Sent from the 'Mainland' for Skinflint.</text>
</string>
<string id="diplomat_skryaga_name">
    <text>Leather attache case.</text>
</string>

<string id="muka_desc">
    <text>Bag with the rye flour, weight 25 kg.</text>
</string>
<string id="muka_name">
    <text>Bag with the rye flour.</text>
</string>

<string id="bread_pekar_desk">
    <text>Fresh rye grain bread, which does not get stale for a month. The loaf is extremely expensive, but the one who tastes it will understand its worth. This miracle-grain can only be baked by one person in the Zone. His nickname is 'Baker'. He faithfully keeps the secret recipe for making this truly wonderful bread.</text>
</string>
<string id="bread_pekar_name">
    <text>Rye grain bread.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc1_name">
    <text>Document #1.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc1_desc">
    <text>The encoded information.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc2_name">
    <text>Document #2.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc2_desc">
    <text>The encoded information.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc3_name">
    <text>Document #3.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc3_desc">
    <text>The encoded information.</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_tsezar_name">
    <text>USB flash drive of Caesar.</text>
</string>
<string id="flash_tsezar_desc">
    <text>USB flash drive, in which are stored the cipher codes of the Mercenaries.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_cod_name">
    <text>PDA with the base codes.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_cod_desc">
    <text>PDA in which Caesar loaded general base codes. He has asked that they be taken to Earl together with the third part of the encoded documents.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_graf_name">
    <text>Earl's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_graf_desc">
    <text>PDA in which Earl loaded the deciphered data about the special operations of the Mercenaries. This PDA must go to Fang.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_solomon_name">
    <text>Solomon's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_solomon_desc">
    <text>Solomon's PDA, where his personal data are stored.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_chelnok_name">
    <text>Shuttle's PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="pda_chelnok_desc">
    <text>Shuttle's PDA, where he stored all the information about his clients and missions. Device is badly damaged. Apparently because of the impact of anomalies, or talons and teeth of monsters.</text>
</string>

</string_table>
