<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252"?>
<string id="esc_direction_fire">
    <text>There will be no shooting unless I give the order. No itchy trigger fingers, understood?</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_fanat_victory">
    <text>Victory!!! Everyone, get over here. Come here Strelok we need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_return_dv">
    <text>Good, Strelok. Glad you're alive and decided to pay us a visit. Come here and we'll have a chat. There's a little something coming up.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tutorial_end">
    <text>Excellent, your task is complete. Safe to say you've learned the basic skills.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_wolf_thanks">
    <text>Strelok the way to the camp is now open to you. Come over and we'll chat.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_fox_quest">
    <text>A word about Strelok, Strelok. A stalker just came back from a long raid. Fox he's called. Looks like he had a pretty rough time and he's asking for help. Some weird beasts followed him all the way back, he says he won't hold out much longer. I reckon the fella will know a bit about Strelok. Here are his coordinates. You might wanna hurry up.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_stalker_death">
    <text>Well that sucked, Strelok. The boys are dead, although that ain't exactly your fault. These things happen in the Zone. Anyway you passed the test so come here and we'll talk business.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_stalker_helped">
    <text>Good job Strelok. Keep it up and you'll make yourself a few friends. Pay me a visit and we'll talk business.</text>
</string>
<string id="escape_stalker_killed">
    <text>That wasn't very smart Strelok. You passed the test but you're gonna have to deal with Wolf and his goons on your own now. Anyway I'm waiting for you. We have more work to discuss.</text>
</string>
<string id="info_esc_give_agroprom_task">
    <text>Strelok the military dug up some interesting stuff at the Agroprom Research Institute. I'd like to get my hands on it and you probably would too. Get the info and take it to the Barman at the stalker's Bar. Now get moving!</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_anomalies">
    <text>Watch out! You're right next to the anomalies. Use your bolts to work out their exact location and shape.</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_about_pda">
    <text>Press Contact ($$ACTION_CONTACTS$$). People within 250 meters of you who have turned their PDA's on will become visible in Contacts and on your visor Minimap. You will also see their attitude towards you, so you can look out for potential enemies. However, bandits and mutants don't usually turn their PDA's on, so be careful!</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_map">
    <text>To activate the map, press ($$ACTION_MAP$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_activate_pda">
    <text>To activate the PDA, press ($$ACTION_ACTIVE_JOBS$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_how_to_talk">
    <text>To talk to someone, aim at them and press ($$ACTION_USE$$).</text>
</string>
<string id="tips_esc_trader_quest_1">
    <text>Find the artifact in the area marked on the map and take it to the trader.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_flash_anomaly_alarm">
    <text>Pay attention Strelok. Next time it could be your butt.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_trader_give_medikit">
    <text>Give this moron a medkit.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_trader_look_vagon">
    <text>Strelok forget the artifact you can drop it off later. Get to the trailer by the road ASAP. My boys need help there. The idiots opened fire at a passing chopper. I've sent you the coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="tutorial_trader_search_corpses">
    <text>Search the corpse there might be something useful.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_1">
    <text>Yes stalker, not your day today. Your plan did not play out. Your gain is zero peanuts.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_2">
    <text>Gain of 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_3">
    <text>Gain of 1,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_4">
    <text>Gain of 5,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_5">
    <text>Gain of 10,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_6">
    <text>Gain of 15,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_7">
    <text>Gain of 20,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_8">
    <text>Gain of 25,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_9">
    <text>Gain of 50,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_10">
    <text>Gain of 100,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_11">
    <text>Gain of 200,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_12">
    <text>Gain of 300,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_13">
    <text>Gain of 400,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_14">
    <text>Gain of 500,000 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_15">
    <text>Jack pot stalker! Your gain is 1 million rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_1">
    <text>Stalker, about the small debt. You need to pay up. You should have checked. You still owe a little.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_2">
    <text>You stalker stop wasting my time and pay up. Let's go!!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_3">
    <text>And what does this mean stalker? You had a certain amount of time to pay. Times up! So as what's his name said, "g'me the fk'n money".</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_4">
    <text>Well well stalker to profit we love, but to pay up we don't. Pay up or you will loose your hands. Understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_5">
    <text>Strelok are you always this insolent?! What part of 'you owe money' do you not understand? The guys came and promised to cut you down like a dog and what's left they will feed to the fleshes. Wake up and face the music.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_6">
    <text>I do not understand why you don't pay up as we agreed. You had three days. There is no excuse. Delay if you wish, but pay up immediately. Otherwise I will be pissed at you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_7">
    <text>Stalker, quickly go to the Bar. Your expected ... with the loot. Otherwise blame yourself. The axe is ground.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_8">
    <text>Well you are a bitch Stalker, and you're my bitch. Be aware that if you don't pay up by this evening then my shop for you will be closed forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_10">
    <text>Last Chinese warning to you, fella: 'time has run out', you did not lift a finger. The clerk will make a note about you if you don't pay up.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_10">
    <text>Well fella you're canned meat. I hired mercenaries. They are already looking for you.</text>
</string>

