<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1252" ?>
<string_table>
<string id="Army">
    <text>'Army'</text>
</string>
<string id="Bandits">
    <text>'Bandits'</text>
</string>
<string id='Duty'>
    <text>Faction 'Duty'</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_military_army">
    <text>The soldiers of regular army units. Guarding the approaches to the closed areas of the Zone, patrolling the perimeter, shooting mutants and catching looters. Army Special Forces an elite division. As a rule they are planted in the Zone for rescue and special operations.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_military_milstalkers">
    <text>Soldiers, stalkers that have special training and are experienced in the Zone, or stalkers contracted with the Army. Usually supplied with a large number of auxiliary equipment and well armed. Mainly used to study the causes and consequences of the disaster, but also map the Zone. They may move alone or in groups of up to five people. Regular stalkers do not mess with these guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-groups">
    <text>Removed</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_scientists_mobile-labs">
    <text>Mobile lab looks like a small metal tank with small tinted windows. Can withstand almost all known human damage of any kind. Can be use in full autonomous mode for a few months, and is equipped with reliable life-support systems. In the Zone delivered by cargo helicopter. Laboratory staff never lets outsiders pass through the airlock, so inside the laboratory have never been regular stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_bandits">
    <text>Representatives of the criminal world who came into the Zone for different reasons: earn from selling artifacts, hide from the law, buy or sell weapons. The Zone has a lot of this type of element, from hoodlums to hardened criminals. For the most part they merge into gangs. Although a single organization of bandits in the Zone do not bother the ordinary stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_duty">
    <text>Obviously a militant group wherein have strict discipline: its members actually live according to the ordinance. Only representatives of 'Duty' not to trade unique items from the Zone with the outside world, according to rumors, all the artifacts found by scientists to give up. Everyone thinks Dutiers primarily to protect the world from the effects of the Zone. Most of the operations group linked to the extermination of monsters, so the raids 'Duty' is often relieve ordinary stalkers from many pressing problems. Have had a long and fierce war with the faction 'Freedom'.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_freedom">
    <text>Anarchists and daredevils who declare themselves as freedom fighters in the Zone, and therefore are in constant conflict with army units, military stalkers and the faction 'Duty.' Svobodovt believes that information about what's happening in the Zone can not hide from humanity, thus challenging the monopoly of government agencies in possession of the people here about the mysteries and wonders.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_killers">
    <text>The most mysterious and secretive faction in the Zone, in the existence of which many do not even believe it. Some people always use the services of mercenaries: professionals in their field, they quickly deal with any stalker, and can even completely eliminate a small group. For their services, seems to take large sums of money or artifacts. The location of the base of this faction still remains a mystery, apparently it is somewhere in the depths of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_loners">
    <text>Stalkers exploring the Zone alone. The majority, as membership in grouping takes valuable time, thus reducing earnings, in addition, some just by nature inclined to solitude and independence.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_monolith">
    <text>This faction, rather reminiscent of a religious sect. Its members believe what rests at the center of the Zone, evolutionary Crystal - Monolith - extra-terrestrial origin. Most stalkers despise the Monolithians, and consider them lunatics. Since its inception the group impedes the progress of stalkers to the Zone center, citing the ill intentions of the latter in respect of the Monolith. According to rumors the Monolithians have a large base somewhere near the center of the Zone, but the exact location of it nobody knows, except the members of the group.</text>
</string>
<string id="enc_social_stalker-clans_zomstalkers">
    <text>Those who suffered extensive impact of radiators in Yantar or some other sectors. Careless stalkers quickly become insane, turning into walking semi-corpses or like zombies. They are plentiful in the Zone, some even reach the perimeter. Anyway, to help them is impossible: the process of personality erasure is irreversible. Although zombie stalkers can still use their weapons, they are rather stupid. At meetings you can hear them murmuring just words or small phrases, which are completely devoid of meaning. In time zombie stalkers completely lose all previous skills and turn into a zombie. As a rul, they are very aggressive and when in masses pose a serious threat.</text>
</string>
<string id='Freedom'>
    <text>Faction 'Freedom'</text>
</string>
<string id="Killers">
    <text>'Mercenaries'</text>
</string>
<string id="Loners">
    <text>'Loners'</text>
</string>
<string id="Military">
    <text>'Paramilitary'</text>
</string>
<string id="Milstalkers">
    <text>'Military Stalkers'</text>
</string>
<string id="Mobile-groups">
    <text>'Research Groups'</text>
</string>
<string id="Mobile-labs">
    <text>Mobile camp of scientists</text>
</string>
<string id="Monolith">
    <text>Faction 'Monolith'</text>
</string>
<string id="Scientists">
    <text>'Scientists'</text>
</string>
<string id="Social">
    <text>Social</text>
</string>
<string id="Stalker-clans">
    <text>'Clans of stalkers'</text>
</string>
<string id="Zomstalkers">
    <text>'Zombied stalkers'</text>
</string>
</string_table>
