<string id="dolg_news_0">
    <text>We're having equipment problems, connection with the base and squads might be glitchy for a couple of days.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_1">
    <text>Don't clog the airwaves, nobody is interested in your exploits killing random guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_2">
    <text>Switch to the private channel, download the security update. If there is an information leak because you were too lazy to patch - I'll strangle you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_3">
    <text>Information regarding raids on mutants and other operations - to the private channel. We don't need a leak on top of everything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_4">
    <text>Stalkers, join "Duty". We will protect the planet from the Zone's infection!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_5">
    <text>Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on Snorks. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_6">
    <text>Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on mutants. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_7">
    <text>Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on mutant spawn. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_8">
    <text>Petrenko, answer me, dammit! What is going on with your private channel?! Is it down again?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_9">
    <text>This is Petrenko. We have temporary interruptions in the private channel operation, if anything happens - PM me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_10">
    <text>Voronin speaking. All squads, report in immediately! General assembly on the channel!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_11">
    <text>Petrenko speaking. I repeat, passage to the base is strictly by pass or my order.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_12">
    <text>This is Petrenko. 3rd Squad, where is the data on the recon raid? Report if there are casualties in the squad! And what the hell is wrong with your comms?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_13">
    <text>This is Zheka Starosta. Squad commanders, report to Gen. Voronin for briefing!!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_14">
    <text>This is Prapor. Attention all! Issuance of equipment and ammunition is at the specified hours! Do I have to sleep here or what?!!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_15">
    <text>This is Petrenko. 5th Squad! Nobody cancelled the raid for Arena monsters! Get out of the bar now! Do you want to go to the anarchists?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_16">
    <text>This is Petrenko. For squads one through four! I repeat, only for squads one through four! Square thirteen, snail nine, map six - is closed until seventeen hundred hours tomorrow. High mutant activity expected.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_0">
    <text>Long live "Freedom"! We'll make the world better with the help of the Zone!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_1">
    <text>Join "Freedom"! Let's stop the Zone's takeover!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_2">
    <text>Experienced stalkers needed for an artifact raid. Treats are on us.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_3">
    <text>Loners! "Freedom" speaking! If you want to live in normal conditions in the Zone and without army obligations like in "Duty" - move to us! Always glad to see new faces.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_4">
    <text>All our guys - urgently log into the private channel, we are updating security. Don't complain later that "Duty" found out about your raid.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_5">
    <text>If you are on a mission, all info goes to the private channel. Not only our guys read this one, don't blow your cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_6">
    <text>Send data on merc movements immediately to my private chat, this is really important.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_7">
    <text>Dudes! Imagine, the grass near the Springboard - hits hard! Ha-ha-ha!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_8">
    <text>Lukash! We've been waiting for the Barrier relief shift for three days! We're sick of this...</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_9">
    <text>This is Skryaga. I got hold of some toilet paper, whoever is tired of burdocks - run here fast, the batch is limited.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_10">
    <text>The Barrier relief shift is late again! What kind of negligence is this! I'm not going to fry my brains here!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_11">
    <text>This is the expeditionary group! We are in heavy combat with superior enemy forces. Equipment partially destroyed. Requesting reinforcements!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_12">
    <text>Max! We're burned! Let's get out of here!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_0">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]A pair of helicopters just passed over me heading north. Coordinates attached. Let's keep our heads down, I don't know what their orders are.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_1">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad:\n%c[default]We are moving by bearing to the helicopter that crashed in the swamps. No one so far.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_2">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad:\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave, coming from the northwest, see attached coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_3">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad:\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave, coming from the northern ravine.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_4">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad:\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave. Coming from the east. Presumably, from the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_5">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Mayday, a pack of dogs is coming straight at us, exact coordinates attached!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_6">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Marauders, bastards... They destroyed all of Pripyat, it's a pity... I grew up there.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_7">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]A pseudodog attacked, barely shot it!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_8">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Saw a group of some random guys, presumably Freedom, heading towards the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_9">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]A group of five people is moving towards the Barrier, presumably Monolith. Take measures.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_10">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unidentified:\n%c[default]Mayday, the military pinned us down at Agroprom in the central complex!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_11">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Lukash, the mercs are shot, we are going home.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_12">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Two-three-seven, coming home, meet us.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_13">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Marauders pinned me down, help!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_14">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Heard military comms, they are planning some operation at Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_15">
    <text>%c[orange]Drunk Programmer:\n%c[default]Need internet access. Is there any in the bar, or do I have to drag myself to Sidorovich?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_16">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich:\n%c[default]It is dangerous to live and be a trader nowadays, need people for security. For me and my savings!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_17">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep:\n%c[default]I want to remind everyone again: whoever finds old music recordings on any media, bring them to me! I don't promise money, but we will play what you bring. If quality allows.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_18">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Need a stalker, specialist in combination locks, with experience raiding the north of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_19">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Vasily! Give back the guitar, you bastard!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_20">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Don't play cards with Bilba - he cheats.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_21">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]who has "tetris" - let me play for a couple of days...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_22">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Was at the Warehouses, found a medal for courage, a whole box, who were they going to award them to?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_23">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]I heard the Americans sent one of their supermen to us. Will be interesting to look at him.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_24">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unidentified:\n%c[default] Don't go into the basements, they are full of creatures! Go around on top!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_25">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Hemul, blow to the bar urgently, I have business!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_26">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]People! Be careful in the village at the warehouses - there's Burnt Fuzz drifted onto the posts!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_27">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Hello, heroes, dammit! Stop trying to kick us out of the ATP! If any scumbag hasn't realized yet - this is our territory and don't fuck with us!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_28">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unidentified:\n%c[default]Damn! Holy cow, it's full of zombies at Yantar again! Be careful there, people!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_29">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Stalkers! Sakharov gives good money for loot! And keeps looking for someone to send to the factory there... I'm not risking it... It's highly radioactive there, plus zombies...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_30">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Attention! If in the village in the Dark Valley they offer you to buy some fancy rifle for 800 rubles - don't believe it, it's a scam!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_31">
    <text>%c[orange]Baldy:\n%c[default]Bandits have appeared in the Dark Valley again. Not good. We will be eradicating them.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_32">
    <text>%c[orange]Baldy:\n%c[default]Sponge Gop, sweatpants. If you see him - shoot him.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_33">
    <text>%c[orange]Mole:\n%c[default]Recruiting people for a raid into the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_34">
    <text>%c[orange]Mole:\n%c[default]Need two stalkers for a raid into the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_35">
    <text>%c[orange]Mole:\n%c[default]Recruiting people for a raid into the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_36">
    <text>%c[orange]Fanatic:\n%c[default]Wolf, respond, need to talk. How many times do I have to repeat? Where did you disappear to?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_37">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep:\n%c[default]So... explaining once and for all - I will not say where the communication center is located.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_38">
    <text>%c[orange]Fanatic:\n%c[default]Wolf, respond, need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_39">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko:\n%c[default]I repeat, passage to the "Duty" base - strictly by pass or my order.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_40">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov:\n%c[default]A personal request from me: if anyone is near my shelter and is not short on ammo, please, kill the Snorks in the swamps - they make my life miserable!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_41">
    <text>%c[orange]Rafyk:\n%c[default]We solve your problems with competitors. Expensive. Ask Ara, yes? We'll be near the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_42">
    <text>%c[orange]Rafyk:\n%c[default]Hey, who was blabbering about me in the Bar? I find out - I stab, yes?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_43">
    <text>%c[orange]Ivan Scikun:\n%c[default]Heard the news: someone wants to break through to the Scorcher again. Scary!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_44">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]They say Sakharov has new detectors!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_45">
    <text>%c[orange]Andriy Patriot:\n%c[default]Wow, damn, so many Muscovites arrived</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_46">
    <text>%c[orange]Yarik Rooster:\n%c[default]Some random loser is wandering in the Dark Valley. But his gun is cool. If anyone loots him - I'll buy that gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_47">
    <text>%c[orange]bacha:\n%c[default]Today, at 2 AM, a Zaporozhets was stolen from the bridges towards the bar (from the garbage side). Color - rust with milk, no doors or trunk lid. Around 1 AM a controller was hanging around the Zaz (wearing only torn pants), complaining for a long time that nobody needs my wreck. If anyone saw this scum - report it. Reward guaranteed.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_48">
    <text>%c[orange]bacha:\n%c[default]At the Warehouses, where the mercenary outpost is, a corpse went missing. Killed four, but there are three bodies. Devices show three too. Did anyone take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_49">
    <text>%c[orange]bacha:\n%c[default]Barkeep, motherfucker, charged 60 grand plus for repairing the suit and didn't finish fixing it, had to pay another 40. That's not according to the code.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_50">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Guys, help out! Dark Valley! Thugs pinned me down! Help, whoever is nearby!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_51">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Doctors! Who has seen the Swamp Doctor? I am in the swamps. I feel bad...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_52">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]What the hell is happening to me? Skin is peeling off... Hair falling out...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_53">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]M-m-m-m-m... KI-I-I-ILL!!!..</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_54">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]K... K... CRU-U-U-USH!!!..</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_55">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Goodbye, my right leg... Goodbye, everyone who knew me... Hello, bloodsucker spawn!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_56">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Hr-r-r... d-d-d-d-d... ooo-o-o-o-o... HEL......P SOMEBO......DY!..</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_57">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]MAYDAY! MAYDAY! A mutant wave is coming right at us! Whoever is close - help! We can't handle it alone!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_58">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]People! Does anyone know when the next Blowout is?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_59">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Who knows - is the next Blowout soon?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_60">
    <text>%c[orange]Zhora Joint:\n%c[default]Guys! A batch of dope has arrived. Whoever needs it - paddle over.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_61">
    <text>%c[orange]Hidden:\n%c[default]Guys! What is this leftist propaganda on the channel? Where is it coming from?</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_62">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Do you still think you are right? Look around! You like this, don't you?! You found yourself here?! So why do you say the Zone is a punishment, a penalty to humanity... Do you suffer when others get pleasure? Feel injustice? Want to change the world for the better? But maybe you have changed yourself? You are so used to pain that you became its messenger in the world...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_63">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Everything has its term. Look back - there is emptiness. Look into the distance - there is horror and death. Why feel and see this? After all, you just need to change yourself, start feeling goodness from the Zone, so that all this stops...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_64">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Are you afraid for your life? The Zone can give advice, help...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_65">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Only the worthy will receive happiness! YOU think Blowouts are death to all living things? We know how to turn it to our advantage! Become worthy! Receive happiness!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_66">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Is the Zone not freedom? Is it not beautiful here? Do you not want to die here? We will help You become a friend of the Zone, learn to benefit from it!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_67">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]The Zone is growing... You don't believe it? Look around! Don't you see? It is already inside you! Why go against yourself? Become its friend, not an enemy!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_68">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Everything is decaying... Are you not glad about this? You live here, which means you only accelerate the decay. Run from the Zone or become its guide to the rest of the lost world! Only the Zone gives truth! You won't get truth from its pathetic semblance...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_69">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]You are drawn to HIM... But you are rude, deceitful, selfish! You are unworthy of HIM! Only humility and obedience will give you what you want!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_70">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]HE knows everything! Infidels will die! HIS voice leads us to victory!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_71">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]What you seek, HE knows. You think you are worthy? Only the faithful will receive happiness...</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_72">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Life for HIS sake is the least I can give! Tremble infidels! For we are coming to cleanse the world!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_73">
    <text>%c[orange]ID not registered in system:\n%c[default]Brothers! We are one! We are HIS sons! Let there be happiness for everyone and let no one be offended!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_74">
    <text>%c[blue]Deathdoor:\n%c[default]Looking for a sensible modeler, with experience in Max or Maya. Those interested - knock in PM, we'll discuss details at the meeting.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_75">
    <text>%c[blue]Dusty79:\n%c[default]Using plugins on the channel is forbidden! Nobody cares what music you are listening to right now and what mood you are in.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_76">
    <text>%c[blue]kamikaZze:\n%c[default]What infection tried to hack the comms server again?! I find you - I'll personally separate your head from your body!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_77">
    <text>%c[blue]Metroid:\n%c[default]Don't be like the idiots screaming in the general channel for any reason. I'll take care of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_78">
    <text>%c[blue]FEAR93:\n%c[default]Attention all exoskeleton owners! A bug found in the right manipulator coprocessor drivers! Come to me in PM for a patch! Bazil Whistler, Vovka Kutsiy and Lekha Angela Davis can smoke calmly on the sidelines – I changed your firmware recently, everything is normal there!</text>
</string>
<string id="noname_teamletes_79">
    <text>%c[blue]kamikaZze:\n%c[default]TO EVERYONE! At the Wild Territory took a PDA off a dead stalker from a bandit. Filled with unsent "Maydays" due to network overload. Sorry for the guy. People, don't clog the airwaves with garbage, you might end up in his place. To the especially dense ones I will block the PDA. Sidor, Barkeep and Four-eyes are also aware - they won't help.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_17">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Stalkers! The number of zombies at Yantar increases every day, we can't cope! Join our ranks - let's protect our native science!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_18">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Stalkers! The number of zombies at Yantar increases every day, we can't cope! Join our ranks - let's protect our native science!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_19">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Alright, Freedomers, dammit! If you stoned idiots think about putting boar manure in our stashes again - we'll hang you by your feet!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_20">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Attention all squads located in square H-23 or nearby! Immediately confirm the presence of particularly dangerous mutants in this region! Information came from an unverified source.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_21">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Squad commanders, from unofficial sources it became known that the so-called Death Truck appeared on the Cordon again. Moreover, it became known that survivors were found in it. Whoever is closer - pay a visit there, check what's what, it's a suspicious matter.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_22">
    <text>%c[orange]Zheka Starosta\n%c[default]Squad commanders must urgently arrive for briefing to General Voronin!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_23">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Who knows where to get old Soviet radio stations and is willing to share this information - approach Colonel Petrenko. Such means of radio communication are needed to link checkpoints with the main base. New models don't work long in the Zone and only at very short distances. But old Soviet tech is just what we need. And remember: "Duty" pays its debts!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_24">
    <text>%c[orange]Skull\n%c[default]Base, come in, Cherepanov speaking. We have casualties, I repeat, we have casualties. Vasily got hit, Mikhalchenko is barely breathing. Transmitting coordinates.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_25">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Serious warning! Snorks spotted at the Wild Territory, not far from the western gate. Why did they leave the swamp... Brothers, arm yourselves better!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_26">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Don't clog the airwaves, nobody is interested in your exploits killing random guys.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_27">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Switch to the private channel, download the security update. If there is an information leak because you were too lazy to patch - I'll strangle you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_28">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Looking for a skilled anti-sniper group to destroy the enemy in the Unexplored Land. Those interested approach Colonel Petrenko. Good reward guaranteed!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_29">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Information on special operations - to the private channel. We don't need a leak on top of everything else.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_30">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Stalkers, join "Duty". We will protect the planet from the Zone's infection!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_31">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Stalker! Life gives you the opportunity to find loyal comrades in the ranks of "Duty"! Only here will you find those who will cover your back and share the last piece of bread!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_32">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]According to our data, in the new open territories - Zaton and the Jupiter surroundings, there is a huge breeding ground for mutants. Appearances of unclassified objects are possible. A massive cleanup will be carried out soon, using heavy weapons, armored vehicles, and helicopters, with military support. It is not recommended to visit these territories before the start and during the cleanup.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_33">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on Snorks. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_34">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on mutants. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_35">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed for a raid on mutant spawn. Payment is appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_36">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Information about the appearance of an unknown group of snipers in the Unexplored Land has been confirmed. They kill everyone they see in the scope. Stalkers, mercenaries, Freedomers, and even Monoliths. Our squad also fell into an ambush and did not return. The snipers are well armed and equipped. It is not recommended to visit the Unexplored Land until we solve this problem. Soon we will clean out these bastards.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_37">
    <text>%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Petrenko, answer me! What is going on with our private channel?! Is it down again?\n%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]Sick of you. I don't handle communications, smartasses. When they fix it - they fix it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_38">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]Bullet, where is the data on the recon raid? Report, are there casualties in the squad?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_39">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]We received several mortars. Checkpoint commanders - come to me urgently, to reinforce your defenses!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_40">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]5th Squad! Nobody cancelled the raid for Arena monsters! Get out of the bar now! Do you want to go to the anarchists?!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_41">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]We received several decommissioned APCs. Fear, Freedom bastards! If you get lucky and wheedle a chopper from the military, our raid last year will seem like a sweet dream to you!\n%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]You scared a cat with a sausage! We have several APCs too! And we also have a tank at the base, stationary, true, but there are shells, and the turret turns. More than enough for your tin cans! And there are plenty of RPGs lying around somewhere.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_42">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]We have temporary interruptions in the private channel operation, if anything happens - PM me.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_43">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]We received a new batch of exoskeletons and weapons. All strike squad commanders - approach me to receive them.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_44">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]I repeat, passage to the base is strictly by pass or my order.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_45">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]For squads one through four! I repeat, only for squads one through four! Square thirteen, snail nine, map six - is closed until seventeen hundred hours tomorrow. High mutant activity expected.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_46">
    <text>%c[orange]Voronin\n%c[default]He who comes to us with a sword, will get hit in the face!</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_47">
    <text>%c[orange]Voronin\n%c[default]All squads report in urgently!\n%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]He-he, Duty screwed up somewhere again...</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_news_48">
    <text>%c[orange]Voronin\n%c[default]All squads, report in immediately! General assembly on the channel!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_13">
    <text>%c[orange]Max%c[default] G4.\n%c[orange]Skryaga%c[default] Miss. A6.\n%c[orange]Max%c[default] Hit!\n%c[orange]Lukash%c[default] Cut the crap! Losses at the Barrier again. Max, get the men up.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_14">
    <text>%c[orange]Belka\n%c[default]Boar, I am Squirrel. Following you.\n%c[orange]Kaban\n%c[default]Squirrel, I am Boar. Why are you following me?\n%c[orange]Belka\n%c[default]Ferret's order.\n%c[orange]Kaban\n%c[default]Squirrel, didn't understand. Who is Ferret?\n%c[orange]Belka\n%c[default]Boar, you are a woodpecker, got it?!\n%c[orange]Kaban\n%c[default]Got it. I am Woodpecker. You are Squirrel. But who is Ferret - didn't understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_15">
    <text>%c[orange]Genka Brave\n%c[default]I heard Cook has interesting magazines with girls...\n%c[orange]Fedka Crumpled\n%c[default]And Skryaga has tapes, they say...\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Listen here, guys: go to your subnet and chat there. Stop polluting the airwaves. By the way... does Cook really have something?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_16">
    <text>%c[orange]Cap\n%c[default]Lukash! We've been waiting for the Barrier relief shift for three days! We're sick of this...</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_17">
    <text>%c[orange]Screw\n%c[default]We fixed the tracks on our tank after all! Now we can chase Dutyers or reinforce the Barrier! Wait, what do you mean there's no engine?! Drank it away?! Who?! Me?!!! To whom? What do you mean you don't know?! Damn! Cap, sorry, we'll have to manage on our own for now...</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_18">
    <text>%c[orange]Screw\n%c[default]The best flame mixture is only at my place! For lovers of barbecue and fried bloodsuckers! Your money - our mix! Come to the Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_19">
    <text>%c[orange]Cap\n%c[default]A mutant wave is coming from the north, requesting help, we can't handle it alone! Everyone who can provide fire support - hurry to the Barrier! If we survive - we'll settle up.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_20">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Cool and buzzed peppers! Only in "Freedom" will you be appreciated and accepted as family! No obligations and ideological garbage, no morning reveilles and minimal prohibition! If you are a real stalker and love the free life among people like yourself - join our ranks! Joining time - anytime. We accept without breaks and weekends, daily and nightly!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_21">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Veterans and rookies! If you value your freedom and want to be among friends - join our ranks! "Freedom" welcomes everyone led to us by the roads of the Zone!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_22">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]The Zone is stalkers. Stalkers are freedom. Be free to the end! Join "Freedom"!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_23">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]We are having equipment problems. Connection with the base and squads might be glitchy for a couple of days.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_24">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Do you wish to meet new interesting people every day, wander in unexplored lands, feel the taste of true romance of life, spend nights under the starry sky? Go on a binge with us!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_25">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Long live Freedom! Let's make the world better with the help of the Zone!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_26">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Join Freedom! Let's stop the Zone's takeover!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_27">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Only here! Boar on a spit, crow roast, omelet and all this with vodka and herring! Come visit our light!</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_28">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed for an artifact raid. Treats are on us.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_29">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Loners! Freedom speaking! If you want to live in normal conditions in the Zone and without army obligations like in Duty - move to us! Always glad to see new faces.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_30">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]All our guys - urgently log into the private channel, we are updating security. Don't complain later that "Duty" found out about your raid.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_31">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]If you are on a mission, all info goes to the private channel. Not only our guys read this one, don't blow your cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_32">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Volunteers needed to defend the Barrier! Reward guaranteed. Contact Max or Cap.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_news_33">
    <text>%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Send data on merc movements immediately to my private chat, this is really important.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_0">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Don't clog the channel with nonsense. The fact that you saw a pack of dogs is, of course, wonderful, but it's not worth sharing joy about it - I will block access.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_1">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Support the request for help with exact coordinates. It is in your interests - you won't have to wait while help combs the entire area.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_2">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Put a couple of idiots on ignore. Sick of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_3">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]If I am not on the channel, it doesn't mean you can litter the airwaves.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_4">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Using plugins on the channel is forbidden. Nobody cares what music you are listening to right now and what mood you are in.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_5">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Disabled connection for certain comrades. They won't spout nonsense in the general channel henceforth.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_6">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Don't be like the idiots screaming in the general channel for any reason. I'll take care of them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_7">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]No reason - don't scream to the whole air. Use PM.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_8">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]I have small problems with equipment, and I may disappear sometimes.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_9">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]I repeat, the use of plugins is forbidden. Don't dump messages like "User is now listening..." and other crap here. The channel is not for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_10">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad\n%c[default]Moving by bearing to the helicopter that crashed in the swamps. So far - no one.\n%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]To the private channel, d-dammit!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_11">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave, coming from the northwest, coordinates attached.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_12">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave, coming from the northern ravine.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_13">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad\n%c[default]Observing a mutant wave, coming from the east, presumably - from the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_14">
    <text>%c[orange]Squad\n%c[default]SOS! A pack of dogs is coming straight at us, exact coordinates attached!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_15">
    <text>%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]A pair of helicopters just passed over me heading north. Coordinates attached. Keep heads down, I don't know what their orders are.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_16">
    <text>%c[orange]Basti\n%c[default]We have to do something, we can't just sit and wait! It might be too late right now, but we are obliged to try! Turn it off already...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_17">
    <text>%c[orange]Basti\n%c[default]Recruiting a group for a breakthrough to the Radar! Need four people, preferably in exoskeletons and with good weaponry. I will supply psi-protection artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_18">
    <text>%c[orange]Kulinar\n%c[default]Alert! Spotted a pseudogiant at the entrance to Agroprom! Couldn't kill the beast, so, guys, be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_19">
    <text>%c[orange]Yakut\n%c[default]Attention all! Observing migration of a large herd of pseudo-boars from Army Warehouses towards the Bar! Looks like a controller is leading them, but haven't seen the daddy himself yet. Somebody whistle to Duty, in case they miss this message.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_20">
    <text>%c[orange]Vasya Ninth\n%c[default]Attention, stalker Vovka Beetle! Give back the SVU, moron! I haven't zeroed the scope yet! You see, I didn't take your artifact, means I haven't finished tweaking the gun!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_21">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Everyone! At Wild Territory took Grisha Baldy's PDA off a bandit, filled with unsent SOSs due to network overload. Sorry for the guy. People, don't clog the airwaves with garbage, you might end up in his place. To the especially dense ones I will block the PDA. Sidor, Barkeep and Four-eyes are also aware - they won't help.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_22">
    <text>%c[orange]Basti\n%c[default]Attention all! A helicopter without identification marks crashed into the Swamp, my PDA is catching SOS. The dead are crowding around, can't break through. Those willing to help - knock on my PM. Waiting at the Marble Oak, when approaching send me a message, otherwise fire to kill.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_23">
    <text>%c[orange]Baldy\n%c[default]Bandits have appeared in the Dark Valley again. Not good. We will be eradicating them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_24">
    <text>%c[orange]Mole\n%c[default]Recruiting people for a raid into the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_25">
    <text>%c[orange]Mole\n%c[default]Need two stalkers for a raid into the catacombs.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_26">
    <text>%c[orange]Syak\n%c[default]Need stalkers with experience raiding deep into the Zone. Payment is appropriate. Those interested - knock in PM, we'll discuss the meeting place.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_27">
    <text>%c[orange]Wolf\n%c[default]Fanatic, respond, need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_28">
    <text>%c[orange]Fanatic\n%c[default]Wolf, respond, need to talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_29">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]So... Explaining once and for all - I will not say where the communication center is located.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_30">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]I repeat, passage to the base is strictly by pass or my order.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_31">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]You are drawn to Him. But You are rude, deceitful, selfish. You are unworthy of Him! Only humility and obedience will give You what You want!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_32">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]The Zone is growing. You don't believe it? Look around! Don't you see? It is already inside You! Why go against yourself? Become its friend, not an enemy!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_33">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]He is a reflection of your fears and phobias. He sees and feels You. And He will find You - you cannot hide or run away.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_34">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Nobody understands. Everyone wants to walk the path and get to the CNPP. Only it is a one-way trip. To pave the road to the Sarcophagus with blood and perish there - is that what you want?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_35">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Everything has its term. Look back - there is emptiness. Look forward - there is horror and death. Why feel and see this? After all, you just need to change yourself, start feeling goodness from the Zone, so that all this stops...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_36">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Only the worthy will receive happiness! Do you think that Blowouts are death to all living things? We know how to turn it to our advantage! Become Worthy! Receive Happiness!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_37">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Are you afraid for your life? The Zone can give advice, help...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_38">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Stalker! Surprise your liver - drink water!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_39">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Always the freshest gear, guns and ammo! Direct supply from Duty warehouse. No middlemen. Dark Valley, ask for Zhila. Heh heh.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_40">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Old Russian fun: Order a fight! For birthdays, name days and funerals. Order a fight for a friend! Quality guarantee, on-site visit, video recording. Contact at: Dark Valley, Borov's base.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_41">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Stalkers! Visit the open-air 3D cinema "Brain Scorcher". Entrance is free.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_42">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Boar hooves, flesh eyes, thorn legs... none of this crap is in our vodka! Sidorovich's bunker. Open 24/7, no weekends.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_43">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Effective help in resolving any conflicts. Emergency humanitarian bombings. Agroprom Institute, military base.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_44">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]We wash heads outside and inside, as well as shave and cut hair in the "Monolith" salon. Located in the Sarcophagus, third corridor.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_45">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Are your teeth falling out? Bones aching? Joints twisting? Tell us where the money and the rest of the loot is, and it will all end immediately! Dark Valley, bandit base.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_46">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]I cure constipation. Quickly and efficiently. Diaper as a gift. Contact at: Agroprom Institute underground, controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_47">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Chernobyl Nuclear Power Plant is hiring personnel. Training and internship at the employer's expense in the best Brain Scorcher laboratory! We make Your wishes come true!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_48">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]I'm putting you on the counter. Geiger.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_49">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]We conduct special operations of any kind. Fast, expensive, 100% result. Contact Mertsayushchy or Basti at Cordon, Rookie Village.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_50">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Buying machine guns of all types and modifications. Don't offer miniguns! Misha Machinegun.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_51">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Qualified doctor needed to work with Zone victims. Contact Shura Gynecologist.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_52">
    <text>%c[orange]Arni\n%c[default]First time in the Arena: zombie tightrope walkers, controller fakirs and tushkano sword swallowers! Hurry to see! With every performance there are fewer artists!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_53">
    <text>%c[orange]Arni\n%c[default]If you were hit on one cheek, turn the other - the jaw will pop back into place.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_54">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Remember: the only thing more harmful than vodka is its absence.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_55">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Stalkers! A postman arrived from beyond the Perimeter. Whoever wishes to send word to relatives, hurry stomp to the "100 Rads" bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_56">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]I want to remind everyone again: whoever finds old music recordings on any media - bring them to me. I don't promise money, but we will play what you bring. If quality allows.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_57">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Today, on the occasion of stalker Sanek Jew's birthday, there will be tasty food and strong drinks! Fried potatoes, boar chops, flesh kharcho, Baileys liqueur, Baltika beer, "Buratino" vodka and much more! Gathering in the Bar. Offer is not free and limited!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_58">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Today, on the occasion of stalker Misha Machinegun returning from a long raid, there will be a feast for the whole Bar! Pilaf, fried bloodsucker tentacles, boar cutlets, rotan jelly, Baileys liqueur, as well as various delicacies from the Big Land! Gather in the Bar tonight. The whole party is on the stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_59">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Don't forget: the best remedy for all diseases is simple water. Two drops of water per glass of alcohol, and it takes it all away.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_60">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]If you don't treat a hangover - it passes in a day. If you treat it - in 24 hours.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_61">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]In terms of price/quality ratio, free vodka has no competitors.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_62">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]Snack on something nutritious with vodka. For example, beer.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_63">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]Sometimes life is so bleak,\nThat even tea won't go down the throat.\nOnly beer goes down,\nWith which you chase the vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_64">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]If there is no reason to drink - that is no reason not to drink.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_65">
    <text>%c[orange]Boatswain\n%c[default]When drinking, you need to know the limit. Otherwise you might drink less.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_66">
    <text>%c[orange]Boatswain\n%c[default]Actually I drink very little, only a hundred grams. But after a hundred grams another person wakes up inside me. And that guy, that bastard, drinks like a fish!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_67">
    <text>%c[orange]Boatswain\n%c[default]Red wine is good for health. And health is needed to drink vodka.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_68">
    <text>%c[orange]Max\n%c[default]Fight drunkenness, but before the fight you must have a drink.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_69">
    <text>%c[orange]Wolf\n%c[default]All rookies must come to me. I'll take a look at You, give some tips, throw some small jobs your way.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_70">
    <text>%c[orange]Guide\n%c[default]I don't promise vodka, but we'll have a great walk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_71">
    <text>%c[orange]Doctor\n%c[default]Strelok hasn't been seen for a long time. Do you know where he is?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_72">
    <text>%c[orange]Zhila\n%c[default]Even in the worst person you can find something good, if you search him thoroughly.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_73">
    <text>%c[orange]Zhila\n%c[default]Buy. Sell. Profit.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_74">
    <text>%c[orange]Rat\n%c[default]When you look at Marked One with a knife, it's somehow hard to speak. A feeling that he might not listen to the end.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_75">
    <text>%c[orange]Syak\n%c[default]I had a wonderful dream today. Four loaders were carrying a pile of artifacts to me...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_76">
    <text>%c[orange]Yurik\n%c[default]At the Garbage near the abandoned vehicle lot ran into a pack of pseudodogs. Be careful there, don't step in it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_77">
    <text>%c[orange]Sanek Bandit\n%c[default]A promise to return money in a week means only one thing - a request not to bother with this question for a week.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_78">
    <text>%c[orange]C-Consciousness\n%c[default]We do not know if it will be the end of the world, but the Zone is expanding, and we will monitor it...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_79">
    <text>%c[orange]Shadow of Monolith\n%c[default]Sometimes you really want to put a pistol to your temple. Feel so sick... But the prisoner covers himself from the barrel, begs not to shoot...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_80">
    <text>%c[orange]Mitka Caffeine\n%c[default]Folks, anyone got coffee to spare?\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Are you crazy? What coffee?\n%c[orange]Mitka Caffeine\n%c[default]Well... Just in case... Maybe someone has it...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_81">
    <text>%c[orange]Ivan Scikun\n%c[default]Heard the news: someone wants to break through to the Scorcher again. Scary!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_82">
    <text>%c[orange]Sasha Ficus\n%c[default]Found some junk, round. Beautiful, shimmering... Is it an artifact? Dimples are so smooth, fingers slide, cool... Ow, it lit up!\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Sasha Ficus, Cordon, Vortex.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_83">
    <text>%c[orange]Rafyk\n%c[default]We solve your problems with competitors. Expensive. Ask Ara, yes? We'll be near the Bar.\n%c[orange]Ara\n%c[default]Hey, who was blabbering about me in the Bar? I find out, I stab, yes!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_84">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Sapper\n%c[default]Buying mines, bombs, grenades, rockets. Selling damaged weapons, body armor, scrap metal. Not selling organs, get lost!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_85">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Hamster\n%c[default]When there is plenty to choose from, there is usually nothing to carry it in.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_86">
    <text>%c[orange]Vasya Burnt\n%c[default]Buying the book "1000 ways to quit smoking". For any artifacts and loot. For offers contact: Radar, road to the Scorcher, checkpoint near gasoline barrels. Ask for Vasya Burnt.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_87">
    <text>%c[orange]Vlad Smely\n%c[default]Dammit, zombie bastards! Wounded me badly at Yantar. I fought them off, but didn't manage to stop the bleeding... I see I don't have long left, even the scientists' medkit didn't help... And soon creatures from the Swamp will come to the smell of blood... Damn... Can't feel my legs anymore... Well, at least I'll do a good deed at last... To cleanse my soul at least a little... I trampled the Zone for three years, gathered a lot of valuables... Was planning to leave after this raid. Artifacts and dough there are enough for 20 years of comfortable existence on the Big Land... Arghhh... Made a stash in Pripyat, street... Message interrupted.\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Vlad Smely. Yantar. Extensive blood loss.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_88">
    <text>%c[orange]Gray\n%c[default]Mobile trader ready to deliver any goods to any point in the Zone. Flying out by helicopter, waiting time 1-2 hours. Any items from the Big Land. Prices bite, but the result and waiting time justify all means! Also buying any junk at moderate prices. Write orders in PM. I warn about my appearance over the Zone space via network so no one shoots at my chopper. Who wants to take a risk - prepare to meet large-caliber weaponry.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_89">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]A personal request from me. If anyone is near my shelter and is not short on ammo, please, kill the Snorks in the swamps, they interfere with expeditions in this area!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_90">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]Rookie stalkers! Scientists want to remind you that vodka will not provide such effectiveness in radiation protection as anti-radiation drugs. Remember: by saving a hundred rubles, you won't save your health!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_91">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]After the recent Blowout, communication with the research group at Zaton was interrupted. For any information about the missing group, we are ready to provide a financial reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_92">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]After the recent Blowout, communication with our group at Jupiter was interrupted. If you find any data carriers from this group, science is ready to pay generously for them.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_93">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed to conduct various measurements and lead research groups. High pay, possibility of obtaining a legal pass to the Exclusion Zone. Contact our bunker at Yantar for an interview.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_94">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]Colleague scientists and stalkers! We just discovered the disappearance of a test subject Snork from our laboratory. It was an adult and strong specimen. It will probably return to the swamp again. Be careful!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_95">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Kruglov, come to me. When are you going to take measurements?\n%c[orange]Kruglov%c[default] I am here, Professor.\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Are you slow?\n%c[orange]Kruglov%c[default] Tomorrow.\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] And why not today?\n%c[orange]Kruglov%c[default] You are slow yourself, Professor!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_96">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Petrov\n%c[default]Dangerous mutants, anarchists and bandits will not stop "Duty", when Stalker Petrov is chasing "Duty"! Oh, respected "Duty", forgive me, it's my jubilee today, I relaxed... forgive me...\n%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]Of course, we forgive. As soon as we find you - we forgive immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_97">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Petrov\n%c[default]Stalker Petrov in any condition views "Duty" as a priceless source of fats, carbohydrates and loot. What, didn't turn off the mic!... Well, I'm screwed...\n%c[orange]Stalker Petrov\n%c[default]Need an intermediary for trips to the Bar. I won't be able to go there myself anymore... payment - 20% of sold or gained loot plus payment for funeral and compensation to relatives if they figure me out. Won't offend. Look for me exclusively via SMS in PM, otherwise I won't respond. And won't say where I am, afraid of publicity and "Duty's" revenge. Petrenko, forgive me...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_98">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Borov, stop calling Sidor an old goat on the channel. You're not young yourself, and your hooves are clacking - can hear it even here.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_99">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Reminder: surfing porn sites from your PDAs and laptops is strictly forbidden - it clogs the channel heavily. And anyway - internet is not for this. This is the last warning. All malicious violators will be disconnected forever. And perish alone then, without the ability to call for help - your own fault.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_100">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Alright, gentlemen stalkers. Information about a new squad of unknown affiliation has been confirmed. The network recorded an increased number of stalker deaths in various areas of the Zone. Whoever wants to live, I advise not to poke your nose anywhere further than the Bar without a support group. But even that gives you no guarantee. I spoke - you heard.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_101">
    <text>%c[orange]Sviblov\n%c[default]Freebie, scourge of marauders, where have you disappeared to? What about the goods? Tell it like it is, don't muddy the water, we only live once.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_102">
    <text>%c[orange]Sviblov\n%c[default]All squads, high alert, attacks on stalker camps in the Swamps have become more frequent.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_103">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Who took a crap under my door again?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_104">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]It is dangerous to live and be a trader nowadays. Need people to guard me and my savings.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_105">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]New promotion! With the simultaneous purchase of two Kalashs, eight hundred rounds for them, three Makarov pistols and six mags for each, as well as twelve antirads, eighteen medkits and seven grenades - you get a bandage absolutely free!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_106">
    <text>%c[orange]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]Sherstyuk, respond. The Doctor asked to convey - you have 5 years left maximum. He said you'd understand.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_107">
    <text>%c[orange]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]As my boss used to say, before entering somewhere, it is better to shoot, reload and shoot again, than to shine a flashlight and ask: "Who is there?"</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_108">
    <text>%c[orange]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]Stalkers! The military always has one goal - a new target. Remember that.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_109">
    <text>%c[orange]Kuznetsov\n%c[default]Vodka is evil! Evil is the enemy! And a soldier does not fear the enemy - he destroys him! Private Pres... Perne... Pers-can't-pro-nounce-it-gulov! God gave you a surname... Listen to the combat order: start destroying the enemy!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_110">
    <text>%c[orange]Skryaga\n%c[default]Got hold of some toilet paper. Whoever is tired of burdocks - run here fast, the batch is limited.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_111">
    <text>%c[orange]Skryaga\n%c[default]My parents often beat the foolishness out of me, but I always knew where to get more.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_112">
    <text>%c[orange]Skryaga\n%c[default]Sidorovich, where is my order? It was supposed to arrive yesterday morning, and still nothing. If it doesn't come today, then, with all due respect, I will have to come and pluck the remaining hair from your head. I need this order very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_113">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Is this your Zone? This is not a Zone, but some bullshit. And what's so scary here? I've seen worse beyond the Perimeter, and here we flew more than one kilometer and no sign of danger...\n...What is this! Oh, God, what was that? General, controls failed, we are losing altitude! General, did You see? Did You see?! Motherfucker!! Mommy!!! Save... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_114">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Gnome, get in touch urgently, there is business in Dead City.\n%c[orange]Zhila\n%c[default]Heh-heh, even a Gnome found work in the Zone. Looks like Snow White will show up soon too.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_115">
    <text>%c[orange]Kostya\n%c[default]Eh, we need a good comedian in the Zone. To tell some new jokes... Otherwise, it's all the same, nothing new.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_116">
    <text>%c[orange]Kostya\n%c[default]Just saw a guy carrying a sack of weed to the Freedom base. I think the faction will be out of order for three days.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_117">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]Respected stalkers! Science is ready to accept any artifacts from you at the highest prices! We will pay well even for banal "Jellyfish". Visit our bunker at Yantar!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_118">
    <text>%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]Buying samples of domestic military industrial complex, exoskeletons and gauss rifles! You won't sell for more anywhere else!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_119">
    <text>%c[orange]Skryaga\n%c[default]Buying any foreign guns at the best price! If you are at the Warehouses and with trophies - drop by the light!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_120">
    <text>%c[orange]Syak\n%c[default]Will purchase any quantity of military and scientific armored suits at a good price. Look for me at the Radar.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_121">
    <text>%c[orange]Adrenalin\n%c[default]People, heard about the suits of the elite Monolith troops? Well, the ones that are black? I am very interested in such things, so if you drag me such a specimen in any condition, I will buy it from you at a very high price. You will find me at Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_122">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Stalkers! If you whack a soldier and take his armor, bring it to me. I'll buy it at a good price. And bring artifacts too, so you don't have to walk twice!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_123">
    <text>%c[orange]Kostya\n%c[default]Borov, what are you doing? Your freaks stopped Dikiy at the Garbage, and he was coming from me, on business! In short - give back the player!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_124">
    <text>%c[orange]Doctor\n%c[default]A very smart dog went missing. Druzhok, if you are reading this ad, send an SMS urgently! I prepared very tasty bones for you!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_125">
    <text>%c[orange]Doctor\n%c[default]Friends, is it really that hard not to kill in the Zone? See an animal - go around, why take its life? They are alive, just like you! I beg You...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_126">
    <text>%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Do you like to assert yourself by humiliating and insulting other people? Do you hate people in principle? Join the Bandits! Bandits are the solution to all your problems!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_127">
    <text>%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Well, Dutyers, motherfuckers, are you done showing off? There was a squad, now it's gone, only one sharpened his sneakers, even a bullet didn't catch him. Heh-heh, by the way, that was Bullet, probably ran for help, or to cry into Voronin's vest, heh-heh. We will help your help, and help the help's help, for the boys' amusement, cause there's no need to stick your slippers into the Dark Valley!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_128">
    <text>%c[orange]Yuri Semetsky\n%c[default]My experience shows that usually others die.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_129">
    <text>%c[orange]Yuri Semetsky\n%c[default]Damn, ran into some tailed-horned-scaly-clawed monster! 15 grenades from the underbarrel, and he doesn't care!\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Yuri Semetsky, Jupiter, deathclaw.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_130">
    <text>%c[orange]Yuri Semetsky\n%c[default]Saw some guys in fancy exoskeletons at Jupiter today, had to hide away from sin, seems they didn't notice. So, whoever is going to Jupiter, then... Message interrupted.\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Yuri Semetsky, Jupiter, shot from unknown weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_131">
    <text>%c[orange]Yuri Semetsky\n%c[default]Today I reached Central Pripyat, went into a former kindergarten. Stumbled upon a room with the sign "Director". Hmm, such a sign is better than a dog, who would go there? Oops, the door is opening... Message interrupted.\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Yuri Semetsky, Central Pripyat, controller.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_132">
    <text>%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Zubr, where did you dump the cargo? Do you have brains at all? Now stomp there yourself and pick it up, I'm not going to send guys to slaughter!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_133">
    <text>%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Deception everywhere! Bought a bag of weed from the military, written: "One hundred grams free". I open it - and there is only weed!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_134">
    <text>%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Cook, when will lunch be ready? Probably got drunk with someone again and sleeping, you cattle! Quickly grab your legs in your hands, turpentine on your butt and into the kitchen! If there is no lunch in 5 minutes - I'll tell a familiar controller to code you against drinking, moron!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_135">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]...wherever you go, every time you return to the same place. This damn fog... impossible to get used to... Chepurnoy disappeared, gone for good. Strange. Maybe he found a way out?..</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_136">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]...Sixth day, water ran out... And the colonel went crazy: shot two and put a bullet in his forehead... I am alone now. Alone inside this freaking anomaly... And why did I have to cut off communications with HQ! They could have picked us up, huh? Pension, dacha, fishing - and there would be no ...static... And really, I wonder how it would have turned out? Ah, to hell with it. The Captain ...static... is dead a long time already... And ...static, noise... will go now, soon... to the upper tundra, damn it... to places rich in game... such is justice...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_137">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]... all this is, of course, clear, but don't you find that after the events at the CNPP many will want to know what the deal was. Especially Strelok with his team, loving to stick their nose where even a Burer hasn't looked. Damn, seems the channel opened... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_138">
    <text>%c[orange]Anna\n%c[default]Uncles stalkers! Remember, there are no hopeless situations! There are situations, the exit from which does not suit you!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_139">
    <text>%c[orange]Kotobegemot\n%c[default]For a knife not to rust - it needs to be stored in a large piece of salo (fat).</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_140">
    <text>%c[orange]Kotobegemot\n%c[default]Exchanging a 2x3 carpet for a piece of salo of the same size. Located in the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_141">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]The Zone teaches two things: to drink vodka regularly and to run fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_142">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Intuition is the head's ability to smell with the butt. A very useful quality for every stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_143">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Fighting drunkenness by restricting access to vodka is the same as fighting diarrhea by restricting access to the toilet.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_144">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Remember: a military chopper is not as scary as its drunken crew.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_145">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Stalker, be careful. In the whirlwind of furious attacks, don't smash your face.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_146">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]If you help a stalker in trouble, he will definitely remember you when he gets into trouble again.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_147">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]The Zone is not chess... one checkmate is not enough here.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_148">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]The probability of failure is directly proportional to the stalker's self-confidence and inversely proportional to his experience.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_149">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]The art of going on raids for loot is defined by the ability to use the useless things you took instead of the useful things you forgot.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_150">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Bravery, courage, justice - the first signs of alcohol intoxication.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_151">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]If you want it badly enough - you can fly into space. And if you delay too long - you might not make it to the toilet.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_152">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Your loot not secured by reliable protection is someone else's loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_153">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Rookie - remember: sleep with a rifle, eat with a rifle and go to the toilet with a rifle too!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_154">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Rookies! Carry grenades carefully - let them see you, not remember you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_155">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Don't forget that a mercenary differs from a neutral in that a mercenary will always tell you the truth to your face, but a neutral needs to be drunk first.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_156">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Guys! I got a chunk of salo (fat) by chance, maybe someone has an onion? I hang out at Skadovsk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_157">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Sidor, you bald bastard, you slipped me a defective underbarrel grenade launcher! I shot, and the grenade fell on my foot. Good thing it didn't explode!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_158">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Half-asleep is when you look for your gear in the fridge. Hungover is when you find it there.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_159">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]And I am a Warrior alone in the field!\n%c[orange]Proper Seventy\n%c[default]Flooders - they are like mutants, dangerous and unpredictable...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_160">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Selling soul, buying liver. Waiting for those willing to trade at Skadovsk.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_161">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Sponge Gop, sweatpants. If you see him - shoot him.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_162">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]A stalker is a friend, comrade to a stalker, and sometimes a backpack with interesting loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_163">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]He who doubts the peacefulness of mercenaries will wash with bloody tears!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_164">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]A friend is not the one who drags you drunk out of the Bar, but the one who crawls beside you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_165">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Who has off-topic talk - approach. I dug up a brand new "Kord" here. Tried it on monsters, can't catch up, they scatter too fast.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_166">
    <text>%c[orange]Sherstyuk\n%c[default]Damn, tired of this vodka, but there is no alternative. Although, maybe someone has liqueur or cognac?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_167">
    <text>%c[orange]Sherstyuk\n%c[default]All troubles come from vodka. At best - from cognac. That's why I switched to pure alcohol.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_168">
    <text>%c[orange]Sherstyuk\n%c[default]A hungry soldier is scarier than a chimera. Brothers, don't steal food from the military!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_169">
    <text>%c[orange]Prapor\n%c[default]To everyone! Issuance of equipment and ammunition at the specified hours! Do I have to sleep here or what?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_170">
    <text>%c[orange]Prapor\n%c[default]Ready to buy Flesh eyes for a good price! Come to the checkpoint at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_171">
    <text>%c[orange]Basti\n%c[default]The further into the forest, the more monsters there are.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_172">
    <text>%c[orange]Basti\n%c[default]Information about the appearance of a group of bandits in the Swamps using NVGs, thermal imagers and new generation infrared sights has been confirmed. Be careful, you might not see them through the swamp fog, but you are in full view for them. Based in the church and on the towers. Be more careful in the Swamps!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_173">
    <text>%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]The network is lagging heavily... Sidor is probably downloading porn again. We'll send him a trojan now...\n%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]I'm not downloading anything, been sleeping for a long time, what's wrong with you? Where is the pause button here...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_174">
    <text>%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]Reminder: If I am not online - means I have an SVD in my hands...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_175">
    <text>%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]Reminding everyone! On the third, unknown persons hacked the network and stole dangerous and secret information! For the heads of these suicides I will pay the promised amount plus a camouflage exoskeleton!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_176">
    <text>%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]I repeat: the general channel is not for settling scores! All violators will be temporarily blocked!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_177">
    <text>%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]I want to tell you, stalkers, that there is no perpetual motion machine in the world, but there are perpetual slowpokes.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_178">
    <text>%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]The thought came to me not immediately. The thought came to me not whole. Thoughts travel very long paths to me.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]True is true.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_179">
    <text>%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]Professor, gathered the info, the chopper arrived, moved out to You. Phew, thank god... There is a small forest, dark... And out of this darkness, in silence, these zombified are coming at us. About ten people, all in exoskeletons and with shotguns. Haven't run like that in a long time.\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]When you get there - don't forget to wash your armor.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_180">
    <text>%c[orange]Wesker\n%c[default]Mertsayushchy, when will you close the hole in the network? Sometimes the same messages come 2-3 times!\n%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]And what can I do? The Zone, dammit... It's like a digital echo effect. Can't find the cause.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_181">
    <text>%c[orange]Wesker\n%c[default]Syak, when will you give me the "Goldfish"? You promised a week ago.\n%c[orange]Syak\n%c[default]Now is not the time to think about fish. Think about your soul. Kostya seems to have one, ask around.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_182">
    <text>%c[orange]Resident Evil\n%c[default]Thinking is always useful. And if you also do it wisely...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_183">
    <text>%c[orange]Resident Evil\n%c[default]And at Jupiter it rains. Dirt, slush, darkness and death all around. So good, mmm...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_184">
    <text>%c[orange]Resident Evil\n%c[default]Digging up a lot of loot is bravery, keeping it is wisdom, and skillfully hiding it is art.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_185">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Don't argue with a boor. Just smile softly and silently punch him in the face.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_186">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Warning: I am not the Ministry of Health - I won't warn you.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_187">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]I am that kind of person - I don't hold grudges. I have to write them down.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_188">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]If you can't fly - don't stain the asphalt.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_189">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Don't stand just anywhere - you'll get hit again.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_190">
    <text>%c[orange]Sasha Iter\n%c[default]In the Zone there are three real traders: Skryaga, Petrenko, and Sakharov. All the rest are pathetic speculators. True, Sidor falls out of the general rule here: he is a trader who mainly deals with rookies...\n%c[orange]Syak\n%c[default]Need an experienced stalker to perform one delicate task. Paying double.\n%c[orange]Adrenalin\n%c[default]Paying triple and a good artifact.\n%c[orange]Kulinar\n%c[default]Whatever! Voron and I will chip in for a five-time rate! Just bring proof of completion. We'll discuss everything at the meeting.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_191">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Friends come and go. Enemies accumulate.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_192">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Nothing spoils the target like a direct hit.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_193">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Never hit a man when he's down, because he might get up and hit back. Just shoot him.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_194">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Don't spit in the well - there is an ammo dump there.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_195">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]It is foolish to hope to achieve something global, for example, to establish world peace, to arrange happiness for everyone. But everyone can do some small deed, thanks to which the world will become at least a little better... For example, shoot some bad uncle.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_196">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]CNPP-2 is my favorite place! There is so much stuff there...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_197">
    <text>%c[orange]Proper Seventy\n%c[default]Complex problems always have simple and easy-to-understand wrong solutions.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_198">
    <text>%c[orange]Arhara\n%c[default]If you can't complete the task - that's your problem. The diagnosis of encephalopathy has not been canceled by anyone yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_199">
    <text>%c[orange]Vityaz\n%c[default]Kite, I am Knight. Do you copy? Over.\n%c[orange]Korshun\n%c[default]Knight, I am Kite. Standing near the object. Some strange interference. All equipment except the radio is completely out of order. Half an hour ago repelled an attack of monsters. Completely unknown monsters and... the rest later. We have casualties. Requesting immediate evac. Over... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_200">
    <text>%c[orange]Vadim Shilo\n%c[default]Help! Zombies pinned me down, can't hold them alone.\n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]Send coordinates, soldier!\n%c[orange]Vadim Shilo\n%c[default]Gena... You?..\n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]Shilo! Where are the coordinates? Shilo! Come in!..</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_201">
    <text>%c[orange]Sasha Sivy\n%c[default]Tolik, the boys are wondering... Is it true... Did you really play strip poker with Nimble?\n%c[orange]Tolik\n%c[default]Freaks, go to... Pripyat.\n%c[orange]Sasha Sivy\n%c[default]Ha! We can't get there without your pants!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_202">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]Borov. Everything is done. Where should I put it?\n%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Don't put it anywhere. You already stained all the bags. \n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]As you say. Anything else?\n%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Of course. Check the stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_203">
    <text>%c[orange]Sasha Golden%c[default] Guys, a... scientist showed up here. Says he has info about a special place in the Zone. Says it's some kind of Eldorado. What is Eldorado, guys? And what's so special there?\n%c[orange]Informer%c[default] Where did he get such info? Didn't say?\n%c[orange]Voronin%c[default] Definitely a setup.\n%c[orange]Skryaga%c[default] I heard about Klondike. About Eldorado - no. That's where there is unmeasured gold. Most likely it's not Eldorado, but Klondike itself.\n%c[orange]Sasha Golden%c[default] Naah. He heard about Klondike too - we all heard about it - but this guy says there is also an Eldorado. Anyway, taking the contract. Thanks everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_204">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Aaaaaa! What is this?! Motherfucker, what IS THIS?!... Mommy, take me out of here!.. It's a dream... I am sleeping... none of this exists... it doesn't exist!.. No-o-o!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_205">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Stalker! You bear scars and welts. These are traces of wounds received in battles. But it is also evidence that you are alive, and rewards for what you conquered and won! You live and fight because you want to someday stand before the One for whom you fought so much! And these scars, dear to your heart, will reveal Him to you! Come, He is waiting for you...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_206">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Stalker. At the very moment you take your first step in the Zone, your Mind perceives the entire Path lying before you. And that distant Star that will not let you turn off this Path. And even if sometimes you have nowhere to sleep, sometimes nothing to eat, and dangers are all around - you, like any Chosen One, say in your Soul: "It's nothing. It's all part of the profession. Nobody forced me to go this way. I decided so myself." And therein lies all your Power! You chose your Road yourself! You have nothing to complain about! You have no one to complain to!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_207">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Mayday! Mayday! Mayday! This is Echo Zero Nine! We got two packs in X-Ray One Zero! Request immediate evac! Alpha Zero One, Do you copy?\n%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Roger that, Echo Zero Nine. Negative to evac. Over.\n%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Alpha Zero One, Whiskey Tango Foxtrot! We are getting murdered down here! Need evac ASAP! Out!\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Mercs from abroad arrived again. What did they forget here?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_208">
    <text>%c[orange]Advertisement\n%c[default]Buying "Monolith". Expensive. Well, why not, nobody tried, maybe they will sell.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_209">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]And this pain again... Where else to look? He couldn't have lied...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_210">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Have you never asked yourself: why do we spin around like this? To earn money? But what the hell do we need money for, if all we do is spin around?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_211">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]No matter how difficult the Path to the Goal is, there are always techniques and ways to overcome obstacles. But, already moving along the Path, you may realize that there are difficulties and obstacles that you did not take into account. If you wait for the most favorable moment, you will never move from the spot. And to take such a Step, sometimes a small modicum of Madness is needed. Put this Madness to your service! Do not be afraid! We are all mad to some degree. Just as our entire world is mad!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_212">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Stalker! When the time comes to move to a new battlefield, cast your gaze upon all those you managed to befriend during your Path. Some you taught wisdom, others, on the contrary, taught you, to others you simply told various things, sitting by the fire. Your heart is full of sadness, but you know that you should obey the command of the One to whom you dedicated your struggle. Thank your companions for the company and boldly go further, taking with you unforgettable memories of the traveled segment of the Path...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_213">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Attention! You are surrounded! Resistance is futile! Everyone lay down your weapons! Remove all artifacts from your belt! Deactivate exoskeletons and take off body armor! Come out with your hands up! I repeat...\n%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Lieutenant! You are on an open channel! Switch immediately!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_214">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]You have already experienced fear. You have already lied and betrayed in the past. You have already wandered not on your Path. You have already tormented yourself over mere trifles. You already had to say "yes" when you wanted to say "no". You already had to inflict wounds on those you loved... And you went through all this, but did not lose the Hope to become better than you were! Continue your Path...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_215">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]You are needed where you are right now. Only what is supposed to happen happens. Everything starts on time. And ends too.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_216">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Vasily, stop floundering. Accept everything as it is. Understand, it's not me, it's life. You seemed to settle well in the Swamps too. Why are you... arranging all sorts of sabotage for me here?\n%c[orange]Vasily\n%c[default]Life is made by people. I don't know what sabotage you are talking about. I haven't even come for your soul yet. But that hour will come... just wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_217">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]A scientist from beyond the Perimeter showed up here. Says he's from a secret institute. True, his institute has such a funny name: NIICHAVO. What the hell? A setup?\n%c[orange]Voronin\n%c[default]Definitely a setup. It's from Strugatsky brothers. "Research Institute of Sorcery and Wizardry". What kind of magic is there in the Zone?\n%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]You are ignorant, General. It's the Research Institute of Chernobyl Anomalous Military Equipment. There was one before the first disaster. Terribly classified. And it seems to still exist somewhere underground. Either X-6 or X-4...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_218">
    <text>%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Freeman! Listen, help out! A guy showed up here. Only he is from America, your compatriot. Doesn't speak a word of Russian. Come, work as a translator, eh? If he says something useful - ten percent is yours.\n%c[orange]Freeman\n%c[default]No, Sidor. Me know how your ten percent ending! You look for other.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_219">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]Dudes, who read the latest orientation? A stalker nicknamed "Surovy" is wanted. I fought a chimera here, the bastard ate my PDA, had to get a new one. There seemed to be a six-figure number in the "Price per head" column, no?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_220">
    <text>%c[orange]Vadim Shilo%c[default] Gena, are you online?\n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator%c[default] Shilo?! Alive?!!!\n%c[orange]Vadim Shilo%c[default] Alive, alive. A controller knocked me out with a psi-strike back then, imagine! Apparently, that saved me. The zombies took me for a corpse. The guys died though... But the goods are safe and sound. Where to deliver now?\n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator%c[default] Forget the damn goods! The main thing is you are alive! And I settled everything regarding the goods with the client. The deadlines have passed, they don't even need it anymore sort of. Well, had to persuade someone, I'm used to it. So keep the goods for yourself. It's yours.\n%c[orange]Vadim Shilo%c[default] Thanks, Gena. Nice to hear that from you. Anything else?\n%c[orange]Gena Liquidator%c[default] Yes, meeting at our place.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_221">
    <text>%c[orange]Zhenya Toadstool%c[default] Guys! Is it true they say there are artifacts that gift immortality?\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] They don't gift, they impart. And not immortality. Speaking in scientific language, they optimize biochemical reactions in the body by an order of magnitude, eliminate cell oxidation practically as a phenomenon, accelerate metabolism and do a lot more. That is according to rumors. I haven't seen them myself. You will age just like the rest of us, but much slower. You won't get younger. And how long you will live is unknown. Well, and it won't save you from violent death.\n%c[orange]Zhenya Toadstool%c[default] Thanks, respected one. But are they in the Zone? Do they exist?\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Well, according to rumors, sort of yes. Only where? If you see a stalker with an artifact unknown to you on his belt, ask him.\n%c[orange]Zhenya Toadstool%c[default] Yeah. But who would tell? Everyone hides, saying it's for radiation, for rupture, for all sorts of other crap...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_222">
    <text>%c[orange]Ara\n%c[default]Make your order right now, and as a gift you get a PDA completely free!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_223">
    <text>%c[orange]Fanatic\n%c[default]Experienced stalkers needed to help crush bandits at the Cordon ATP. Also experienced stalkers who can hold this territory against counterattacks of the damn thugs. Wolf and I are planning to set up a transit base and a bar for rookies at the ATP territory. If everything works out - we'll even move Sidorovich there, there is a good bunker for him. Stalkers! Help us, and soon you will be able to not only sit by the fire at Cordon but also drink and eat well in the new bar! Plus, without fear of getting a bullet in the back from bandit scum. All willing - come to the Rookie Village next week.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_224">
    <text>%c[orange]Shura Gynecologist\n%c[default]Found a disfigured corpse in the Unexplored Land today. I've been trampling the Zone for four years, never seen such wounds. The whole body is like cut with a knife, only in straight continuous lines from crown to heels. Cuts are shallow but parallel, and the interval between them is less than a centimeter. The guy clearly died from pain or blood loss, internal organs not damaged, I declare this to you as a former doctor. A monster could hardly do it so precisely. Means it's either a new unknown anomaly or some maniac with good knowledge of the trade. I didn't wait for anyone, ran straight to the Bar to calm nerves with vodka. So look around more often.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_225">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Mockingbird\n%c[default]Look what I wandered into! What a loot, holy crap! How many of them are here? The whole field is covered...\n%c[orange]Kolya Rusty\n%c[default]Mockingbird, where are you? Why are you silent? Vitya, triangulate!\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Gena Mockingbird, Zaton, unknown anomaly.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_226">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]In the Zone, the straight path is not the shortest. The longer the road - the safer it is.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_227">
    <text>%c[orange]Grisha Honest\n%c[default]Trust no one. PDA stolen in the bar, bastards. What kind of people are these? What am I writing from now? Well, I nicked Barin's PDA while he went to the bathroom.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_228">
    <text>%c[orange]Gena Liquidator\n%c[default]Oh, Marked One, another orientation came for you. And do you know how much they are ready to shell out for you? Nah, I think I won't voice it. Who did you manage to annoy so much?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_229">
    <text>%c[orange]Vasya Monkey\n%c[default]Syoma, do you hear me? I found such a fancy stash here...\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Vasya Monkey, Limansk, shot in the head.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_230">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]In the right ear they whisper to you: "you are weak, give me your hand, I will help you!" And in the left ear they whisper to you: "you are weak, give me your hand, I will save you!" Do you see the difference, stalker? So whose side are you on?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_231">
    <text>%c[orange]Mitya Burdock\n%c[default]Guys, wow - a bush with eyes. Come, come here, pretty one... cutie... silly... poor thing...\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Mitya Burdock, Eastern Pripyat, Thorn.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_232">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Planning to open a canteen in one of the buildings in the Bar. Cooks and service personnel needed. Those interested come to "100 Rads" bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_233">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]A rumor passed that there is a tunnel leading from the Bar to Yantar. Everyone possessing useful information on this matter can expect a generous reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_234">
    <text>%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Stalker, tired of sausage and canned meat, but you are not much of a cook? I can offer the book "100 Recipes from Barkeep", finest dishes from handy ingredients, price affordable, exchange possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_235">
    <text>%c[orange]Prapor%c[default] Kostya, woke up? Sobered up? Well what to say... you partied hard day before yesterday.\n%c[orange]Kostya%c[default] And what is it, Comrade Warrant Officer? What happened? Don't remember anything... hic...\n%c[orange]Prapor%c[default] Naturally, you don't remember. Day before yesterday you drank our entire winning from Lyuber all by yourself. Three bottles just like that. From the bottle! Then lined us all up under the barrel of your rifle and forced us to sing songs. Don't remember?\n%c[orange]Kostya%c[default] Don't remember, Comrade Warrant...hic...Officer.\n%c[orange]Prapor%c[default] Exactly... And then put Lyuber in a bent-over pose and forced him to crow like a rooster. And you don't remember that? Slapped his cheeks: sitting wrong, whistling wrong... And you don't remember that? Lyuber is still getting stitches at Doctor's.\n%c[orange]Kostya%c[default] But what happened then?... hic...\n%c[orange]Prapor %c[default] What happened, what happened... It was your birthday, dammit! If not for that, would we tolerate this? Even from you. Oh well. And at the end of all the fun a herd of bloodsuckers flew at the checkpoint. And you locked our guns in the chest in the wagon before that. Tried to shove the key into Bullet's... well, up there. Also don't remember? Oh well. But we enjoyed the spectacle from the wagon, how you beat up four bloodsuckers alone. Yeah... can't drink away talent.\n%c[orange]Kostya%c[default] I want to apologize. To the guys. To everyone.\n%c[orange]Max Lyuber%c[default] It's all good, Koshan. We drank well. Just don't forget, you promised me a small tame jumping pseudogiant for my birthday. A promise is a promise, everyone heard!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_236">
    <text>%c[orange]Professor Volkov\n%c[default]What a view! Do you see, colleague? Do you see? My God, this is... This is... I even struggle to say what beast this is! Look at what... AAAAA!!!!\n%c[orange]Network message\n%c[default]Stalker died: Professor Volkov, Yantar, Thorn.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_237">
    <text>%c[orange]Professor Dmitriev\n%c[default]Respected one, could we go faster? Would like to get there before dark.\n%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]Professor, I've been walking this route for... many years, basically. You can't go fast here. Here it is... what is it called... distortion of space. Did I express myself correctly?\n%c[orange]Professor Dmitriev\n%c[default]How interesting! And did many scientists visit there before me?\n%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]If we get there - you will be the first.\n%c[orange]Professor Dmitriev\n%c[default]First?! Wow! And what does "if we get there" mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_238">
    <text>%c[orange]Sedoy\n%c[default]Does anyone have a Maxim machine gun? Really want to remember my youth...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_239">
    <text>%c[orange]Khimik\n%c[default]What w-w-was that?!\n%c[orange]Prigorshnya\n%c[default]Death... That was death. Well why are you lounging, get up! These are only flowers (the beginning)...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_240">
    <text>%c[orange]Sanka Zhmyev\n%c[default]Damn, seems something is wrong with my PDA. My messages are not sending.\n%c[orange]Vitka Zozo\n%c[default]Everything is fine, they are sending.\n%c[orange]Sanka Zhmyev\n%c[default]How do you know?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_241">
    <text>%c[orange]Zakhar\n%c[default]Kruglov, I beg you, don't write me anything for the next hour. I am hunting.\n%c[orange]Kruglov\n%c[default]I wasn't planning to write anything.\n%c[orange]Zakhar\n%c[default]Kruglov, you...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_242">
    <text>%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]Happy anniversary, sidor! When is the booze-up?\n%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]With a capital letter, please!\n%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]When is the Booze-up?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_243">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Kruglov, imagine - even poltergeists seem smarter than some people!\n%c[orange]Kruglov%c[default] Umm, what are you hinting at?! Maybe let's conduct an experiment and find out?\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Yes, of course! For this we will need a room, various objects or things and an indefinite amount of sweets.\n%c[orange]Kruglov%c[default] I don't quite understand, Professor...\n%c[orange]Sakharov%c[default] Well of course, You are not a poltergeist...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_244">
    <text>%c[orange]Romka Moose%c[default] Genka, are you busy tonight? The guys and I wanted to visit Cook, there is a worthy reason to drink.\n%c[orange]Genka Frail%c[default] No, I am busy today! I am going to hunt the Deathclaw!\n%c[orange]Romka Moose%c[default] Are you crazy? The Deathclaw doesn't exist! It's all tales of drunk veterans in the Bar!\n%c[orange]Genka Frail%c[default] It's not tales! I will prove it to you today. I'll cut off his horn and bring it to you so you can see!\n%c[orange]Romka Moose%c[default] Yeah right. Go ahead. And we will drink to your memory meanwhile.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_245">
    <text>%c[orange]Wesker\n%c[default]Sanya Synoptic, send coordinates of the needed person to my PDA. Catch the encryption.\n%c[orange]Sanya Synoptic\n%c[default]Caught encryption, transmitted coordinates. Pay up at the meeting.\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Wow! Turns out there is a weatherman in the Zone! Using the occasion, can I get tomorrow's weather?</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_246">
    <text>%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Information just arrived that an unknown group of stalkers, consisting of approximately five people, broke through the Monolith defenses at the CNPP and is moving along the station to the east. Also known that these guys took a lot of explosives with them. Targets and identities of stalkers not established yet. Request to everyone: if anyone knows anything about this group, write to me in PM urgently.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_247">
    <text>%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Sick of everything for real. And these flashy show-offs too: we are like stalkers, we are cool...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_248">
    <text>%c[orange]Vasya Tavern\n%c[default]I hate the Zone. Hate mutants, hate bandits who strip you like a sticky note, hate anomalies, hate radiation, hate Blowouts, hate soldiers, hate hucksters. I hate my freaking life!\n%c[orange]General channel\n%c[default]Stalker died: Vasya Tavern, Dark Valley, bullet wound.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_249">
    <text>%c[orange]Shadow of Monolith\n%c[default]Infidels, repent! Your worthless attempts to penetrate our territory are meaningless and doomed to failure! Do not try to stop us on the path of spreading the power of the Great Monolith!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_250">
    <text>%c[orange]Dimon Clumsy%c[default] Guys! Anyone found a PDA? Looks like I drank too much at Freedom base yesterday and lost it, and I have important info there!\n%c[orange]Freedom%c[default] With a cracked glass?\n%c[orange]Dimon Clumsy%c[default] Yes.\n%c[orange]Freedom%c[default] And a corner chewed on one side?\n%c[orange]Dimon Clumsy%c[default] Yes! Yes! That's it!\n%c[orange]Freedom%c[default] No, haven't found it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_251">
    <text>%c[orange]Source undefined\n%c[default]Test subjects demonstrate remarkable ingenuity. What do you think about this, Andrey Ilyich?\n%c[orange]Source undefined\n%c[default]Indeed, amusing behavior... Especially at such radiation doses... Stop! Switch to encrypted channel immediately! What the hell?!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_252">
    <text>%c[orange]Source undefined\n%c[default]Candid, our equipment is acting strangely... All dosimeters and sensors are silent, and Sergey's PDA broke down... Connection is dying here too... What are the orders?\n%c[orange]Source undefined\n%c[default]Get out of there! Get out! Faster, dammit!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_253">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Found the observation center?\n%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Yes, found it. Part of the equipment is still intact. Most cameras disabled, but motion sensors still working... Wait, there is a scheme with indication here... You are here, and... dammit, what is that?! Get out, a group of objects is moving towards you from northern corridors, very fast! Damn, more! In ventilation shafts... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_254">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Colonel, a helicopter with an experimental suppression unit crashed in the Radar area an hour ago. Immediately, I repeat, immediately send a group to the crash site. I don't care about the means. You will be provided with all necessary equipment.\n%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Turn on encryption, damn you! We'll be there in 12 hours.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_255">
    <text>%c[orange]Sakharov\n%c[default]Respected stalker friends! We require a large amount of artifacts for research. We guarantee more than decent payment.\n%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Respecte-ed!.. friends!.. Dressed up, eggheads? Brothers, who nursed you in the beginning, and revived you with vodka, huh? Your thick-headed science? Or Sidorovich? Bring all artifacts to me, as before!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_256">
    <text>%c[orange]Ara\n%c[default]Hey, who was calling me a chump there, huh? Like my uncle said... Measure seven times, stab once!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_257">
    <text>%c[orange]Serega Poet\n%c[default]Here lies a skeleton in the bush. The Zone is not a toilet for a stalker!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_258">
    <text>%c[orange]Max\n%c[default]So. Take a small plastic canister, cut it across into two equal halves and pour water into the bottom one. Then get a piece of foil somewhere, can be from a cigarette pack, and wrap the neck with it. Then... Dammit, I'm writing to the general channel! Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_259">
    <text>%c[orange]Vanya Ratcatcher%c[default] Sidor, do you like cheese?\n%c[orange]Sidorovich%c[default] No.\n%c[orange]Vanya Ratcatcher%c[default] Strange, such a rat, but doesn't like cheese...\n%c[orange]Sidorovich%c[default] Are you crazy, stalker? Fell from the Pine-oak? You come to me to buy loot...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_260">
    <text>%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Cook, What are we gonna eat today?\n%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]Nothing.\n%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Yesterday was nothing too!\n%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]I cooked for two days.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_261">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Yesterday today was tomorrow. Repent, infidels, while there is still time! For tomorrow today will become yesterday.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_262">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Everyone seeks their own Monolith in life.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_263">
    <text>%c[orange]Collector\n%c[default]To everyone who hears me... I am old and dying... time is short... two choppers... I shot them down... but... everything went wrong... I am the last... it was... prototype testing... very powerful... flamethrower... only three copies... one in my hands... whoever manages... pick it up... and also... a letter to my family... in the pocket... this is... a request... I... at Radar... seems... that's... it...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_264">
    <text>%c[orange]Sergey Shaggy\n%c[default]Trust no one. Hid from bandits in the attic, they shout to me: "come out, we won't touch you"... Well, I came out... And they promised...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_265">
    <text>%c[orange]Sashka Fighter\n%c[default]Hey! Anyone brave? To fight me in the Arena? Waiting for a serious opponent, tired of tearing rookies to shreds.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_266">
    <text>%c[orange]Peregar\n%c[default]All stalkers could be different if they weren't so identical. Because for us vodka or machine gun - as long as it knocks you off your feet.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_267">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Life is actually a very bad thing, and many small and commonplace things make it also very long.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_268">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Kalinin's group exists at the ATP. Personnel 7 people. Weapons: SVD, "Vintorez", RPG. I consider using armored vehicles to destroy it inexpedient: terrain is flat - will get burned on approach. I propose to infiltrate this group to destroy from within with two of our agents under the guise of lone stalkers: Lieutenant Mikh...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_269">
    <text>%c[orange]Source unknown\n%c[default]Lukash, soon our squad will assault your base at Army Warehouses. Our commander is Lieutenant Colonel Cherepanov, recon commander. We will be based presumably near the farmstead. Where specifically - don't know yet. Hope you won't offend with payment.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_270">
    <text>%c[orange]Yuri Semetsky\n%c[default]When I stood by the Monolith yesterday, I thought that what is scary is not that I will die and then resurrect, what is scary is that I might like it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_271">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]Haste makes "Springboard" laugh.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_272">
    <text>%c[orange]Kotobegemot\n%c[default]Eh, would love some homemade salo right now! With fried potatoes...</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_273">
    <text>%c[orange]Fenrir\n%c[default]There are many folks in the Zone, but few humans.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_274">
    <text>%c[orange]Kotobegemot\n%c[default]Ehh, damn, yesterday I had a desire to broadcast good news, but thought - I'll do it tomorrow. And today I don't remember what I wanted yesterday. Hmm, sclerosis is starting.\nDidn't consume alcohol yesterday.</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_275">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Stalkers, attention! A new type of zombie appeared. The most dangerous one. They crap and throw it at people. Okay on the suit. But radioactive stuff on the face is somehow unpleasant!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_276">
    <text>%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Holy cow! Got my Viper wet today, had to dry it by the fire. How would I know the ammo inside would explode!</text>
</string>
<string id="mod_news_277">
    <text>%c[orange]Sasha Girl:\n%c[default]Going out to the Swamps. Such beauty... Anomalies jumping around.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Today is a holiday for the girls, today there will be dancing.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_0">
    <text>Marauders, bastards...\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]We guess.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_1">
    <text>A pseudodog attacked, barely shot it!\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Good job.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_2">
    <text>Saw a group of some random guys, presumably "Freedom", heading towards the Bar.\n%c[orange]"Freedom"\n%c[default]Don't blow cover, bastard...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_3">
    <text>A group of five people is moving towards the Barrier, presumably Monolith. Take measures.\n%c[orange]Barrier\n%c[default]Understood. Stoned fanatics, damn them...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_4">
    <text>Help! Military pinned us down at Agroprom in the central complex!\n%c[orange]"Duty"\n%c[default]Why can't you rest... we warned you, there will be a raid.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_5">
    <text>Lukash, mercs are shot, coming home.\n%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]To the private channel, idiots!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_6">
    <text>Two-three-seven, coming home, meet us.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_7">
    <text>Marauders pinned me down, help!\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Attach coordinates, smartass.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_8">
    <text>Heard military comms, they are planning some operation at Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_9">
    <text>Lukash, "Duty" came to the farmstead again. Why?\n%c[orange]Lukash\n%c[default]Sick of them already. What do they need? They'll get it again...\n%c[orange]Petrenko\n%c[default]And those are not ours. Disobeyed direct order of General Voronin and flew out of the faction. So we don't care, do what you want with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_10">
    <text>Need internet access. Is there any in the bar, or do I have to drag myself to Sidorovich?\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Seems Barkeep has it. In principle, you can try going to "Duty" signalmen, they definitely have access.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_11">
    <text>Coming from Yantar with important info, carrying wounded Ruslan Bomber! Guys, might not make it - I'm at the Railroad, and a foursome of mercs is on my tail, pinned at the transition to the Bar...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_12">
    <text>At the Garbage picked up SOS from Zhora Medic! Moving by bearing to Rostok, those willing to pull Zhora out - waiting for messages. Warning - Zhora was taken by the military, no less than ten of them, so it's gonna be hot.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_13">
    <text>To those wishing to purchase a PKM - I can help. Don't come to me with a merry company of more than one person, for I won't believe in good intentions and will shoot like mad dogs. I warned you...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_14">
    <text>Urgently buying four clips for a Gauss! Knock on PM!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_15">
    <text>In the Dark Valley, going by bearing to Kostyan Cat's alarm, ran into a couple of bloodsuckers! Whacked one, the second, bastard, went to the tunnel to Cordon. Warn the rookies there, I can't reach Sidorovich. By the way, Kostyan died, may the earth...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_16">
    <text>Attention all! A herd of zombies coming from Yantar, fuck them sideways. About twenty heads. Know for sure because ran into them myself, barely escaped. Or rather - sixteen now. Tried to lead them to mercenary position, but who knows, maybe they'll push to the Railroad...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_17">
    <text>Selling fresh Snotty Porcupine into good and caring hands. Can find me in the Bar. Will respond in person only after reply in PM. Presence of big money welcomed.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_18">
    <text>Attention all! Spotted mercenaries with heavy weapons in the southeast of Dark Valley! Moving to the Cordon. Those willing to rough up mercs - meeting at the Well, waiting until 3 PM. Without prior message to my PDA will shoot anyone, so for five hundred meters knock on PM.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_19">
    <text>Met the Swamp Doctor... Well, met... He healed me a little, from blind dog bites, but that's not important. Important is that he warned about a Blowout. Says Blowout will happen tomorrow, not in two days as per schedule, so everyone into holes tomorrow!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_20">
    <text>Was making way through military checkpoint at Cordon. Overheard negotiations. According to their forecasts, Blowout in 2 days. Prepare for long sorties so there are shelters on the way!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_21">
    <text>Heh-heh, Zhila, I drove a money client to you, get in touch urgently!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_22">
    <text>Need a stalker, specialist in combination locks, with experience raiding the north of the Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_23">
    <text>I heard the Americans sent one of their supermen to us. Will be interesting to look at him.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_24">
    <text>Don't go into the basements, they are full of creatures! Go around on top!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_25">
    <text>Hemul, blow to the bar urgently, I have business!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_26">
    <text>People! Be careful in the village at the warehouses - there's Burnt Fuzz drifted onto the posts!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_27">
    <text>Hello, heroes, dammit! Stop trying to kick us out of the ATP! If any scumbag hasn't realized yet, this is our territory, and don't fuck with us!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_28">
    <text>Damn! Holy cow, it's full of zombies at Yantar again! Be careful there, people!\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Unique information...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_29">
    <text>Stalkers! Sakharov gives good money for loot! And keeps looking for someone to send to X-16... I'm not risking it... It's highly radioactive there, plus zombies...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_30">
    <text>Attention! If in the village in the Dark Valley they offer you to buy some fancy rifle for 800 rubles - don't believe it, it's a scam!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_31">
    <text>People, don't be total jerks! Found someone's stash with weapons and olives (ammo) by accident? Fine, take it, since you got so lucky! But throw at least something in return! At least an old sawed-off, or a PM with a pack of ammo! Yesterday I was running from a pack of blind dogs, ammo running low. Decided to turn to a stash, replenish ammo. And someone had already dug there thoroughly, took everything. If not for a Duty squad passing nearby, dogs would be tearing me apart in the bushes. Don't be like bandit bastards! Remember, tomorrow you might be in my place.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_32">
    <text>People, if you are planning a trip to the Big Land, or returning from there through the military checkpoint - better rethink. Better crawl an extra kilometer in mud under barbed wire. Soldiers might take money for passage, and then detain "until clarification". And in particularly shitty circumstances might put you against the wall, or shoot in the back, or "forget" to warn about mines. Today I was supposed to meet Senka Valenok from the Big Land, he was carrying goods for me. So he paid, soldiers let him through, and then a burst at the legs and dragged him back. Saw it personally. Probably will pin "illegal entry" with all aggravating circumstances. And could have just whacked him...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_33">
    <text>Found a gun - called Drozd (Thrush). Now that's a beast! Eh, if I found one like that earlier - wouldn't be limping now...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_34">
    <text>Want to express gratitude for good humor on the general channel. Makes life in the Zone much easier. Sometimes it's very nice to read in the dead of night, somewhere in the Forgotten Forest, running from a pack of dogs, about storing a knife in a piece of salo.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_35">
    <text>A group appeared recently, called "Avengers". No different from bandits, except weapons and professionalism. Even wear trench coats like them. So if you see these freaks - shoot without hesitation, otherwise they will put an olive in your head themselves.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_36">
    <text>Old-timers probably remember the "Last Day" faction. There was one, good guys. And then some loner whacked their leader, and the faction vanished as if underground. For a long time nothing was heard of them, but recently I stumbled upon a group of guys in "Last Day" gear at Radar... In short, these are not the guys with whom you could not fear for your back, drink, and have a heart-to-heart. Opened fire to kill immediately, laid down two of my rookies. So if you see these scum - waste them immediately. Although, maybe it's just Monolith looting an old stash... But being on alert with them won't hurt anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_37">
    <text>Dutyers! Saw a well-armed group of bandits near your outpost at the Garbage, coming from Dark Valley. Clearly not taking a stroll there.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_38">
    <text>Barkeep, that guy you ordered, I wasted him. But there were complications. Will you increase the reward?\n%c[orange]Barkeep\n%c[default]Come in, we'll sort it out.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_39">
    <text>Guys, heard that? They say Sidorovich decided to publish a newspaper - called "Zone Herald". And pays decently for news!\n%c[orange]Skryaga\n%c[default]Lying, aren't you? Sidorovich?! To someone?! Paying for such crap?! You are a dreamer!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_40">
    <text>Zhila, your grandmother over the knee! Where are you chilling again?!\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Clear where: probably playing cards with bloodsuckers for suckers again. He has a dream - to latch onto Barkeep's cash register.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_41">
    <text>People, is it true that in the Zone someone manages to ride on pseudogiants along the roads?\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]No, not true. There are no roads in the Zone...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_42">
    <text>Ehh, received a beautiful suit from scientists today! With titanium inserts! A rat will shit itself from effort while gnawing such armor. And break teeth. And die from shame, because with broken teeth and all shitty.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_43">
    <text>So I met a deathclaw. What a monstrosity, mamma mia! And dies somewhat reluctantly. Was in Red Forest, near the stop where bloodsuckers always lived. Changing of the guard or what, heh. Where did he come from anyway? Thought they should only be at Jupiter.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_44">
    <text>Standing... Waiting... Surely someone snitched. Lekha, maybe forget it? Let's go tomorrow, eh?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_45">
    <text>Wow, what a scary monster I just saw! Horror!! Knees still shaking! Anyway, lads, do as you wish, but I now drink on days starting with "S": Saturday, Sunday and... Segodnya (Today)!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_46">
    <text>Eh, Vitalik... Stepped into Fruit Punch. I feel his legs, and there is only a kneecap. Lower, to the feet, legs are like a rubber stick, can tie them in a knot. Hope the doctor does something...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_47">
    <text>Guys, I have a toothache. There is no dentist in the Zone, as I understand. What to do?\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Well, basically, there is one way. Come to the Bar around eleven, and down some anesthesia. And then throw a bottle at someone... should knock the tooth out.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_48">
    <text>Why did I drag myself here? I've been here only three days, and already lost my PM and walk around all beaten and tired! How do you live here??? Somebody!!! Lead me back out of the Zone!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_49">
    <text>However you plan, however you try - the Zone will always do everything differently. Will mess it up and won't ask your name, the bitch.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_50">
    <text>You should have seen this, such beauty! Gonna go clos... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_51">
    <text>Semyon, coming out on your path, dragging Byvaly (Experienced), he got scorched by Zharka (Burner). Meet us, or we won't bring him alive!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_52">
    <text>Selling a crowbar. Behind "100 Rads" bar, in the evening.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_53">
    <text>Be careful with abandoned military equipment in the Zone! Soldiers, cunning bastards, can put a tripwire in such places that wouldn't occur to a normal stalker! Roma Crab crashed like that. I told him not to climb into that damn APC. But no, wanted to ride the Zone with a breeze! Started the engine, and as soon as he moved - something exploded, so hard that all wheels fell off the box. Little left of Roma, couldn't even bury him properly... Eh, gonna go drink, so he rests well. And he was such a careful stalker...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_54">
    <text>Misha Machinegun, did you do something crazy somewhere by chance? Cause people were asking about you here, asking all sorts of questions...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_55">
    <text>Syoma, I found Petrovich... Or rather, only his legs... At Radar, two steps from the barbed wire. Hit by a chopper or something, everything around is plowed up...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_56">
    <text>Yesterday my buddy and I drank two bottles of "Buratino" each and went hunting dogs. That's fun, I tell you! Only can't find the buddy... Will have a hangover cure now and go look again.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_57">
    <text>Recently saw a rookie who came to the Zone with a bicycle. Plans to ride around here on it, weirdo!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_58">
    <text>I heard here that Sakharov can get a Gauss rifle. Is it true, or are they lying?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_59">
    <text>Imagine, yesterday in Dark Valley found a 12.7mm casing. Wonder who is roaming here with such a gun?!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_60">
    <text>Brothers, I bought an awesome detector from Sakharov! Not cheap, of course, but marks anomalies! Yesterday was returning from the swamp at night in the dark, couldn't see anything, like a blind dog, and this thing saved me big time - got out alive and unharmed!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_61">
    <text>Brother stalkers! Sitting, looking at the Institute through binoculars - a new batch of military arrived! Combing everything here again, may the Zone eat them! Advise not to shine near Agroprom for a couple of days!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_62">
    <text>Discovered unknown mutants at the Wild Territory. Careful there.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_63">
    <text>Sold trophy guns to Sidorovich here... Seems he shortchanged me, the old fart... People! Better go to Barkeep!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_64">
    <text>Yesterday met my long missing partner, and he doesn't recognize me, started shooting at me! Had to shoot him... Damn, people, be careful with psi-emission! Shooting at your former colleagues is damn hard!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_65">
    <text>Rumor has it that a controller lives in the Agroprom underground, maybe even more than one... Stalkers, experienced guys went there yesterday - and didn't return! Seems it really is fishy there...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_66">
    <text>Yesterday at Yantar there was impenetrable fog - zombies barely visible through it... Don't repeat my mistakes - it is very dangerous there in the fog!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_67">
    <text>Heh! Time to quit drinking vodka, and go for artifacts. Who is with me?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_68">
    <text>At the Warehouses, where the mercenary outpost is, a corpse went missing. Killed four, but there are three bodies. Devices show three too. Where could he put... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_69">
    <text>Some random loser is wandering in the Dark Valley. But his gun is cool. If anyone loots him - I'll buy that gun.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_70">
    <text>Was at the Warehouses, found a box full of medals for courage. Who were they going to award them to?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_71">
    <text>Who has "Tetris" - let me play for a couple of days.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_72">
    <text>Marauders, bastards - destroyed all of Pripyat... It's a pity, I grew up there...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_73">
    <text>Marble bloodsucker behaves interestingly - after being shot at, holds its side, like it's wounded...\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]And you offer it a medkit. You might just become the pack leader!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_74">
    <text>Found someone's pistol in a stash - killer thing, turned out to be. One shot - one kill.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_75">
    <text>Met a deathclaw after all. At night, in the Red Forest. Tell me, which puddle is less radioactive, to wash my pants?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_76">
    <text>Thanks, Mitya... You pulled me out... I heard you order me to lie down, but I was really scared. When it got hot, I completely lost my head. I am very afraid of pain... Damn, it hurts so much! Need to smear it with something. Zharka (Burner), damn it...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_77">
    <text>Beautiful twins appeared at the Cordon! Only they smoke, and girls shouldn't smoke!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_78">
    <text>...I am absolutely sure that in the vast majority of cases we are hammering nails with microscopes...\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]Shhh! Scientists are working, don't disturb.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_79">
    <text>Came to the Garbage, but Voron is not there. Tell me who he is drinking with, I need him very much.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_80">
    <text>Cigarettes ran out... What a day! Everything is wrong since morning!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_81">
    <text>No laughing! I am scared... The Zone is joking with me again. Walking at night, admiring the full moon. Yawned, closed eyes, open eyes - no moon! Cre-e-e-py!!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_82">
    <text>People! Maybe someone has fishing line and hooks by chance? I know there are no fish in the Zone, but was walking past a swamp just now, and really wanted to sit on the bank with a fishing rod... Would give a "Soul" for tackle...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_83">
    <text>E-e-e-h! Would love to ride a bike right now! Remember childhood! Does anyone know where to get one?\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]True words: the Zone will never run out of idiots...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_84">
    <text>Night descended... The Bloodsucker Village is already snoring mightily... But I am on alert with paper in hands... what if they noticed me after all?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_85">
    <text>Don't know, hic, who Budmo is, hic, but yesterday with Kotobegemot we drank so much for him... hic-hic.\n%c[orange]Mertsayushchy\n%c[default]I'll cut your PDA network for a day - you'll have time to find out.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_86">
    <text>Why was the anomaly "Sosnodub" (Pine-oak) named exactly that?\n%c[orange]Wesker\n%c[default]Because "Dubosos" (Oak-sucker) - doesn't sound very good.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_87">
    <text>Comrades, tell me, who upgrades the Pecheneg? Dolgovyazy refuses for some reason...\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]That's cause you boys don't know how to ask! You gotta do it like this: come to him, grab the Pecheneg by the barrel, and with the buttstock across the back - whack! He takes it immediately and even yells: - No need for an extra barrel, I already have one!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_88">
    <text>Fenrir, hello, brother. You alive there? Cause someone is walking around here, asking about you. I started to worry. Maybe give him... the ice hole treatment?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_89">
    <text>Went hunting fleshes here at night... And really none around. Apparently, hid in their holes.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_90">
    <text>Can teach how to properly show your heels (run away) in an unclear situation. Who is interested, waiting for SMS in PM.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_91">
    <text>Exchanging ten dog tails for one pseudodog tail. Offers in PM.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_92">
    <text>Lost a dog. Name: Professor Kruglov. Whoever meets him, don't kill. He is mine...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_93">
    <text>Pseudodog missing. Distinctive features: no ear, missing one eye, torn off paw, broken jaw and no tail. Don't shoot by accident. Answers to the name "Lucky". To the finder - a good artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_94">
    <text>Eh, it's good when you and your comrades take down a pack of mutants! And excellent if on the first try!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_95">
    <text>Warehouses. Semi-ruined village. Walking, scared. The atmosphere here is wrong somehow...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_96">
    <text>Walking through the Zone for an hour, another, and I feel something is wrong. Fifth hour walking and suddenly I remember - where is the rifle? Daaamn, left it in the bar! Getting old, apparently.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_97">
    <text>Walking through the Zone for an hour, another, and I feel something is wrong. Fourth hour walking and suddenly I remember - where are the monsters? Haven't met a single one! Aaa, what the... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_98">
    <text>People, I ask you from the bottom of my heart - don't shoot at fleshes immediately, take a closer look. After the second liter I look so much like them...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_99">
    <text>Seasoned stalkers say it's better to lose a beloved girlfriend than a bag of bolts. Remember this.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_100">
    <text>Kolyan, shoot, shoot already! Ptui damn it, got away. Call that a romantic: "runs beautifully, runs beautifully"! And now what: do I chase him beautifully across the whole zone? Oops, looks like I didn't turn off the microphone...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_101">
    <text>Big deal, a dog barked from under a bush, and he runs immediately. I would never abandon armor, let alone pants...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_102">
    <text>These bandits are proud! I send them gifts from the underbarrel, and nobody picks them up, everyone just scatters.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_103">
    <text>People, save me! I am at Yanov on the roof of one wagon, near the bridge. Ammo consists of two loaves of bread and two bottles of vodka. Not enough to kill myself...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_104">
    <text>Kitty-kitty, psst, psst. Come here, sweetie... Oh, crap, ugh, ugh bastard, shoo, shoo, oh-crap-crap, mommy!!!... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_105">
    <text>Whoever forgot the path to Tuzla, knock on PM, I'll point the direction.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_106">
    <text>Zakhar, get in touch, have a topic for conversation regarding your order.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_107">
    <text>Serega, well where is your messenger? Did you send him through the fourth reactor or what? If the messenger isn't here in an hour, you can shove your package where a bloodsucker hasn't stuck its tentacles!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_108">
    <text>I have information that Duty lost its special forces squad in the Eastern Pripyat area. Moreover, from message fragments, it can be said they met some super-guys in super-gear. Contact with the squad was lost already in the third minute of battle, and the guys were super-pros, not some riffraff.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_109">
    <text>Borov, listen, we dug up an artifact yesterday, washed it down with the guys, and in the morning my nose is blue... I didn't understand for real, is it from the artifact or from vodka?\n%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]Ask something like that again, idiot - and it will be from my boot.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_110">
    <text>Bubulyuka, say something funny, cause it's kinda boring!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_111">
    <text>Yesterday saw a flight of helicopters pass over Agroprom towards the Swamps. Circled near the path to Agroprom, then rushed to the bridge, where Tuzla is. And then suddenly lightning, crackling, howling, grinding, and a huge flash, like from a nuclear explosion. When I blinked it away - no helicopters, no military - nothing. And dead silence... Even deader than usual in the Zone. Thought about going there, to take a look, but it was getting towards evening, and a stroll in the Swamps is quite something... And now I sit and think - to hell with it! Other enthusiasts will be found, my skin is dearer to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_112">
    <text>Looking for a partner for a trip to Yantar and Agroprom. Loot split equally. Write in PM.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_113">
    <text>People! Can anyone lend some money for a week, about fifteen grand? Cards, damn them...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_114">
    <text>People! I really saw a skeletonized man in the forest! In an ushanka hat and with an axe! Seemed I didn't drink anything... There he is, f... Connection interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_115">
    <text>Hooray! Got hold of a Bengal Soul, can you imagine? A Soul!!! Wow, I'll live now! Get myself armor, a Vintar... And then on a raid again! Hmm... Will buy crap to climb into the deepest crap. Nah screw it, better send money to Mashka!\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]At least one is starting to get it...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_116">
    <text>Where is this blonde Carlson-trader? We had a deal! What kind of person is this...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_117">
    <text>Guys, help out. I pressed something on my PDA while drunk, something about ministry of defense here... Now it says - launch some rockets and a map of America. What do I press?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_118">
    <text>What the... Who nicked my loot at the Wild Territory, under the wagon wheel? Return it nicely, cause I'll find you anyway!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_119">
    <text>Max, need cigarettes? Dug up a whole box, Belomor!\n%c[orange]Max\n%c[default]Opa! Come on, come on, I'll take it all, bring it faster, don't stop anywhere, don't give to anyone, don't talk to anyone, RUN BRING IT!!!! Okay! Combat readiness! Moving out in threes to meet him, god forbid he wets the cigarettes!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_120">
    <text>That's it. Farewe...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_121">
    <text>Things are really bad for Khimik and Prigorshnya... Sold their armored car, begging, mostly on the outskirts. And what stalkers they were in the past! Did so many things!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_122">
    <text>People, has anyone seen Borland? Have business with him, for a good sum. Borland, if you are reading this message - respond in PM!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_123">
    <text>Who can give coordinates of Kombat and Topol? Have a small proposal for them, but they don't respond at all... Whoever sees them - tell them I was looking. Will be grateful!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_124">
    <text>Know about SBU special forces, called "Alpha"? Well, based on this special forces they created a unit specifically for work in the Zone. Real beasts! Eight people were walking with me to Agroprom, and these bastards attacked from ambush at the tunnel. Looks like I was the only one to escape, they laid down my partners there, at the fork... Armed and protected - very well! Clearly some top-secret military developments. So if you see such guys in the distance - run away. And if you see them close - pray. Now I'm afraid to even stick my nose out of the stash, they clearly don't leave witne... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_125">
    <text>By the way, seen a lot of new exoskeletons appeared? With military, with Monolith, someone else too. Monolith guys don't even have an exoskeleton, but some kind of tank. Unloaded a whole clip from "Vintorez" into one - didn't care! Barely escaped, they run in this robe - very fast! Would be nice to get at least one like that... Although no, then anyone would want to unscrew your head for the suit. Forget it...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_126">
    <text>Is it true they say blind dogs don't bite Blind (Slepoy)? Or does he only know how to tell jokes about dutyers and conduct investigations?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_127">
    <text>Saw a group of zombie girls at Yantar. No, not those grannies who wheeze and call for "sooooony". Normal women, their suits are specially for women... Where did they come from? Fancy that, haven't seen a single live girl in the Zone, but zombie girls wander in groups! No, don't think anything like that... I satisfied them, like all other zombies - with a Kalash to the forehead. But still, where do they come from? Poor women...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_128">
    <text>By the way, people, seen Ugryumy (Gloomy)? Well, that guy who used to roam mostly on the outskirts, armed only with a PB and a sawed-off. Roamed for a very long time, sold loot to Barkeep, didn't get into any beefs, didn't shine anywhere. But one day he snapped and decided with his comrade, Skromny (Modest), and some four-eyes to rush to the Monolith. Don't know anything about Skromny, but saw Ugryumy recently at the warehouses, in the bloodsucker village. He was an unsociable guy anyway, but now he completely closed up, doesn't even drink with anyone. Don't know if he reached the Monolith, but the Zone changed him greatly... Since he joined Freedom, although previously didn't recognize factions at all.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_129">
    <text>The Zone is changing... Became much more dangerous than before. Remember, previously chimeras were only seen at the CNPP and in Pripyat, and now recently they whacked one such beast right at the Garbage. At Cordon they saw several bloodsuckers, a pair of giants and a group of zombies. And now, as paths opened from the Swamps, some unreal creatures are coming from there. Recently a pack of rotans attacked the rookie village. If not for Basti and his team, the dead would be countless. And if such crap is happening on the outskirts, what is happening in the northern regions? And at Zaton and Jupiter surroundings, where nothing is properly scouted yet? Must be unreal horror there! Screw it, better not go on long raids until everything settles down.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_130">
    <text>People, is it true that Slavka Bullfinch picked up some girl recently? Walks around now, coaching her, teaching wisdom. Seems she's from beyond the Perimeter. Will have to ask Sidor or Fanatic. Eh, would be nice to get at least a glimpse!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_131">
    <text>People, found a Niva at the Garbage, almost new and not radioactive! In joy rushed to Dark Valley, and got stuck there in the swamp under the bridge. Whoever can - help pull it out! Promise to give rides as reward, if it's on my way. Sitting in the hangar at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_132">
    <text>Looking for partners for a trip to Radar and Pripyat. Ammo and food on me. Located in the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_133">
    <text>In Dark Valley stumbled upon a large military detachment, about forty people. Well, sort of a detachment... Mostly, all soldiers were in pieces. Don't know who shredded them there, but clearly someone very serious. And no bodies except military were there. And even scavengers didn't have time to pull up... Anyway, looted only a couple of corpses, and as soon as dogs appeared on the horizon, bolted from there. Because such a mountain of meat will soon attract someone bigger than blind dogs, and I only have one life.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_134">
    <text>Looking for a partner for a raid in more or less safe places - Cordon, Garbage, Agroprom. Find me in the Rookie Village.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_135">
    <text>Looking for a heavy weapons group for trips to the Cave and Labyrinth. Will be at Agroprom near Adrenalin until tomorrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_136">
    <text>Looking for a partner for terrain reconnaissance in the Swamps. Wear lighter armor so as not to get stuck there. Guns for swamp wildlife on me. Until tomorrow hanging out in the Bar, then going to Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_137">
    <text>People! Bandits captured my buddy Dimka Rezanoy (Cut)! Whoever can, help me rescue him! Misha Machinegun already replied, Oleg Rhubarb and Sanya Serviceman are coming from Cordon. Need a couple more people badly! Will wait at the farm in the south of Dark Valley until noon. As a reward will tell about a stash with good artifacts. Just hurry, otherwise bandits will stab Dimka!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_138">
    <text>Semyonich, look, another truck is coming from the center of the Zone! Meet it... Opa! No, no need to meet it anymore. Hit a Vortex, yeah. And debris flew into a Burner. No, no traces left... Damn, while I was crawling, the microphone turned on. Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_139">
    <text>The only ticket you can buy in the Zone is a one-way ticket. Remember this, and never look into the ticket offices of Pripyat! Such scum lives there sometimes that a bloodsucker will seem like a cutie.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_140">
    <text>Recently at the Swamps stumbled upon a semi-flooded dugout from World War II times. And guns there - countless! No, of course, mostly everything rusted, but about 10 weapon units - in perfect condition. 2 Mosin rifles, 3 Schmeissers, 1 PPSh and something else, I'm not very good with vintage weapons. If anyone wants to buy for their collection - write in PM. For an additional fee will give coordinates of this dugout. Maybe someone wants to dig in this old stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_141">
    <text>People, who can suggest a good gun for 5.56 caliber? Cause I have money, not very good with guns, and the old M-16 is getting tired of being capricious.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_142">
    <text>Saw Swamp Doc today... Imagine what he did: sitting on rocks and sewing tentacles back onto a bloodsucker! The sucker grunts, but hardly twitches. Doctor, when he saw me - said I should stomp far away from here, since I have no health problems. No, well I can understand how Doc determined from a distance that I'm fine. Can even understand why he was sewing tentacles to the sucker - Zone old-timers have their quirks. But what fool managed to cut off tentacles from a bloodsucker while it lay unconscious?! And didn't make a control shot! And the sucker recovered, and when it woke up... That was a surprise. Probably like a cat that got... Well, those... sterilized, basically. And Doc really heals everyone.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_143">
    <text>Military are reinforcing their checkpoints. Something serious is coming, probably. Be more careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_144">
    <text>People, advise not to walk in Pripyat at night. Some rustling, moans, child's crying heard in the distance, ghosts in windows... Today entered a playground, and there are sounds as if children are playing... Swing squeaking, laughter... Don't remember how I got to the stash, ran like I never ran in my youth. And didn't drink or smoke anything before that... And it's not a controller, that one would just burn brains completely. That's it, I'm never setting foot in Pripyat again! This city is alive, I tell you for sure!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_145">
    <text>Monoliths are reinforcing their checkpoints. Probably waiting for someone tough. Be more careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_146">
    <text>People, from whom can I buy a silencer for a shotgun? Heard about such things, but never saw one. Like to work on beasts with large caliber guns, but loud shot sound is not always suitable. Approached Adrenalin - he doesn't have it. I have a Benelli. Paying with loot for information!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_147">
    <text>Rumor has it that somewhere in northern regions several transport choppers crashed. Don't know why they went there, but I have info that on one of the choppers were several crates with RPO-A (Flamethrowers). Where the info is from - don't even ask. Those places are untrodden, hardly anyone managed to dig in those crates. So whoever finds it first - good job! Don't thank for info, I'm not setting foot in northern regions anyway.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_148">
    <text>The fact that the Zone, mutants and all sorts of anomalies arose due to the military and scientists - everyone knows already. And whoever believes in aliens - is a total cretin. But that's not the point. The point is that these bastards continue to conduct experiments on the Zone and its spawns! Anomalous weapons, anomalous body armor, all sorts of other anomalous crap based on artifacts. And they conduct these experiments not in the Zone, but on the Big Land, in their best research institutes. Smell where I'm going? And if these assholes have something go wrong again, and we see a new Zone somewhere in Kiev, or Moscow? That's catastrophe! More people will die than when the Chernobyl Zone formed. And nothing can be done. These thick-headed eggheads never think about consequences...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_149">
    <text>Ummhmmwhen I was stiiiilll a huuuman, puttt didn't remembeeerr whaat didn't remembeeerr whereeeargh. Seeeemed liiike a treeee waaas, and a maaan sitting... Arghaaarrrr! Stttop, soooldier, sooooldier, ssstop... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_150">
    <text>Found someone's stash - controllers pinned me down, can't fight off! Brothers, help out! Can find me in Central Pripyat. Part of the loot from the stash to whoever helps!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_161">
    <text>Thinking: I'll dump the loot, save up some cash and open my own business. Something Zone-themed. Souvenirs, maybe. Want to immortalize this place, this Zone brought so much grief to people.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_162">
    <text>People, tell me, where can one wash up in the Zone? Cause last week I washed my gear in a lake... and now it's not a lake there, but a swamp.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_163">
    <text>I don't like blind dogs. Bastards, they don't even look you in the eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_164">
    <text>Never buy meat pies from Barkeep. After all, it is the Zone. Normal dogs are not found here...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_165">
    <text>A good shooter is one whose gun speaks only on business! I do not submit to infidels! Only Monolith! Only HIM!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_166">
    <text>Heard there is an abandoned German bunker in the Forgotten Forest. True or are they lying?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_167">
    <text>Stumbled upon a wild cat lair today. Parents went hunting, and only kittens remained inside. I sort of forgot that it's not home around, but Pripyat, stuck my nose in there, wanted to feed them some sausage... So these kittens almost made sausage out of me! There were about twenty of them, didn't see them all in the dark. All pounced on me at once, and they weigh more than three kilos each! And climbing on me like on a tree, trying to claw at the face. I barely managed to close the SSP-99 visor. And their claws sure can't tear that suit! I was bashing them for a long time, cause they really restricted movement. Just as I quieted the last one - parents returned. Well, I blew the daddy's head off with the shotgun immediately, but the mommy got away. Will take revenge, what do you think? Seems like a dumb beast, but then again maybe not...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_168">
    <text>Does anyone know where Strelok went?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_169">
    <text>Ready to swear, five minutes ago at Cordon saw a crowd of mutants on the hill, two dozen, no less. Now - not a soul, not even any tracks left. And didn't seem to drink before going out...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_170">
    <text>Heard somewhere that a team of stalkers appeared, sort of gathering to go to the center of the Zone. Whoever knows any info about them - drop it in PM, want to join.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_171">
    <text>Fun stuff. On the way to Sidor, not far from the ATP, saw a bandit take a leak into an "Electro". Right in the forehead, eh... Not even coals remained.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_172">
    <text>People, do you hear these sounds? As if someone is about to atta... A-a-a! Get away! Get away, beast! Bitch! Hel... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_173">
    <text>Thanks to the dummy who made a stash in the stove pipe at Cordon. The vodka was excellent!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_174">
    <text>Damn! These sleeping bags are so uncomfortable! Tomorrow going to express everything to Sidor!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_175">
    <text>Sidor, open up, bastard! You sold me damp ammo, misfire every second shot! Open up, or I'll take the door out!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_176">
    <text>Stumbled upon a corpse yesterday at Army Warehouses... Neutral stalker seemingly, nothing special. Only a skeleton left, clothes and things almost decomposed. And here is what's interesting: on his weapon was an inscription engraved: to such and such, for merits, year 2015. Hell knows, maybe they messed up the date?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_177">
    <text>Guys, I found an artifact here. A cobblestone is a cobblestone - nothing remarkable, doesn't radiate. However, glows a bit from inside and weighs almost nothing. What is this crap?\n%c[orange]Vasya Rusty\n%c[default]Exactly, crap. Where are you?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_178">
    <text>Who is this Semetsky guy? Sick of his messages already! Does he write them only to me? I meet him - I'll kick his ass!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_179">
    <text>Holy cow... Walking yesterday calmly at the Garbage, avoiding anomalies, and bam - like caught a concussion, stunned, eyes swimming... Well, I came to, look around - already at Army Warehouses. Checked PDA - only eight minutes passed! How is this possible?!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_180">
    <text>Anyone good with safes? Found one in the bushes. Rusty, true, but a grenade doesn't take it, bastard.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_181">
    <text>Visited Cordon today... Eh, what times come to mind... Nostalgia!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_182">
    <text>Guys, standing at Yantar right now, looking into the water... Shimmering, reflecting clouds, rays shining through there, among all sorts of garbage fry are peeking through... And the bottom. Pulls me to itself.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]What's with you, brother, first time under psi-emission? Rays he says... Run from there!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_183">
    <text>Brothers! Yesterday near twilight was returning from a raid and stumbled upon some strange radio traffic... Some stalkers asking for help, saying they are stuck in an anomaly, can't get out... Has anyone heard of such a nightmare?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_184">
    <text>Brothers, who is recently from Cordon - how is Sidor there? Haven't heard about him for a long time.\n%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]What would happen to him, that huckster? Everything as usual - alive and well, ripping off rookies, pushing all sorts of junk to them... Nothing new...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_185">
    <text>Guitar broken, damn, to splinters and into the fire so it doesn't go out. Lost count already how long we are sitting here. Three of us, were walking from Army Warehouses, and then bam - and unclear where we are. Now can't get out. Wilderness all around, connection catches damn nothing, not a single soul. Tried to get out - walking as if in circles. And anyway... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_186">
    <text>Brothers... Hel... [static] ... p... Stuck in ...geon ...rome... [static] ... g... broken, very as... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_187">
    <text>Running recently through Pripyat, evening, dark already. Jump out from around the corner and bang my forehead into a zombie in a purple shirt. Then he growled something in a guttural voice, and I went completely cold and hair stood up on my head. Very scary.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_188">
    <text>Do you know which mutants are the most dangerous? You'll say, Venom or Deathclaw? Naah, not correct. I'll tell you. The most dangerous are flies and mosquitoes that plague zombies have! Capable of ruining even the coolest exoskeleton quickly, and how they drink blood, ooo, bloodsuckers smoke nervously on the sidelines!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_189">
    <text>Sanek, hello! I am near the Sarcophagus, and I am a Monolithian now, check it out! Entering the hangar now, I already see two guards... Hey, hello bros, glory to Monoli...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_190">
    <text>Shtyr, it's me. Listen to the scheme. Yesterday stumbled upon a dog lair at the Garbage behind the swamp, and a few zombies were hanging out nearby. Sat quietly on the side, dumped into general channel that I allegedly found a "Sleepy Ball" artifact and gave coordinates of the lair. In a couple of hours stalkers arrived, several people - and straight to the mutts. They shredded everyone, and zombies helped too, I finished off a couple of zombies and collected loot from the losers, not bad loot at all. Check out what I came up with!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_191">
    <text>Today met Gena Sapper with a mine taped to his leg with duct tape. Explained that he stepped on it by accident. Now walks around with it like that. What a laugh! If you meet the grief-sapper, don't get close to him - might blow up.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_192">
    <text>People, you won't believe it! Today saw through binoculars how military pinned some rookie down at Cordon. So he pulled out some artifact and started shooting through it from a PM. So from those shots military were thrown back ten meters. Wish I had such an artifact... And what is most interesting, didn't even search the corpses. Just moved somewhere to the Garbage...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_193">
    <text>Half an hour ago observed how a pseudogiant at Agroprom walked up to a "Vortex" and lay down near it. And it somehow immediately weakened. Grass around it straightened up. Apparently, he takes energy from it. So much for a dumb beast. Actually sucks anomalies dry. So, if you see a sleeping giant by an anomaly, better scram quietly.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_194">
    <text>Bandits have gone completely crazy. Yesterday a rookie came out of the hangar. Walked about 50 meters away. Bandits stopped him right there. Good thing he managed to send SOS to our guys. But still, by the time we ran up, they took all the loot and forced him to run between anomalies. Well, we shot them all. But this won't last long. In short, need to end them. And where do so many of them come from...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_195">
    <text>Today observed how a boar flew into some strange "Electro". So it flashes with all red lightning and strikes not to the sides, but straight up. I probed everything there with a bolt later and found nothing. And only charred remains left of the boar. And who knows where the anomaly went. Either crawled to another place, or dissipated. In general, be careful and keep a bolt ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_196">
    <text>People! Who knows, suggest how best to treat holes from "Electro" electric arrows? For an effective method will gift a slightly worn Berill-5M.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_197">
    <text>Urgently buying "Nut" artifact. Paying expensively. Find me in Dead City.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_198">
    <text>Wow, so many beasts bred in the Forgotten Forest! Wanted to go for artifacts with the boys, so many beasts were at the entrance that used up all ammo. Didn't dare go further. But at least harvested from the carcasses, cut off hooves and other parts.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_199">
    <text>Is it true that a Death Truck flew into an anomaly at Cordon? They say there are even survivors... Who knows, share info. Painfully interesting.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_200">
    <text>Today two of us were walking through Dark Valley and ran into a bandit in a jacket. Only the pistol didn't penetrate him. Had to shoot buckshot. And only when I took the jacket off him, understood what the deal was. Underneath was another one just like it.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_201">
    <text>Was recently in Forgotten Forest and can't understand how Krest survives there alone? Tons of beasts, and he is alone!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_202">
    <text>Today found someone's stash. And in it some strange ammo - called "Isomorph". Who knows what kind of thing this is?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_203">
    <text>Wonder if anyone in the Zone can attach a grenade launcher to a PPSh? Cause I like it painfully much. And want a launcher too...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_204">
    <text>Heard about the stalker-controller? Guys in the Bar told me. A controller took a stalker by the brains, but didn't kill him, set a condition instead: will give you, says he, my ability - you will take Dutyers under control and bring them to me. Well, the stalk agreed, and who wouldn't? Otherwise... you understand. Such a stalker approaches a Duty checkpoint, asks for a smoke, and then bam - and no checkpoint! Although as for me, all these are ta... continuing now, wait a bit, someone is coming to me... ouch, head aches somewhat, will finish writing la...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_205">
    <text>Listen! Finding charred remains for the umpteenth time! Does someone have a flamethrower in the Zone?!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_206">
    <text>Wow, guys! Isomorphs are hardcore! Last round in the barrel was an isomorph. And it actually stopped that beast! Hands shaking until now. It really saved my life, brothers. Where to get more of these? Where do they make them at all?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_207">
    <text>People, I was drinking with a stalker here. So he said in all seriousness that there are talking wolves in the Zone. What kind of mutants are these? Or is he lying? Maybe hallucinated?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_208">
    <text>Dudes, where to get some fancy gun. And with a signature like. Well like a personalized one. Huh? Nephew is coming to the Zone soon, want to make a gift.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_209">
    <text>Anomaly capsules are the thing! Threw around yourself and can sleep calmly even in an open field. No bastard will sneak in! Well, if that bastard is not a human, of course.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_210">
    <text>Guys, what can be carried from here beyond the Perimeter? Well, to sell with profit.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]You survive first. To the Perimeter.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_211">
    <text>Traders are evil. Always asking for some favor. Religion doesn't allow simply selling, or what? Don't need money anymore?\n%c[orange]Sidorovich\n%c[default]Did you understand yourself what you said? Actually, money is the real evil! Beyond the Perimeter they long replaced religion for people. They have only money in their heads there, nothing more important left in life! Just to saw off some dough somewhere, to buy a new trinket.\n%c[orange]Borov\n%c[default]That's it, Ostap got carried away. Speaking in verses...\n%c[orange]Dimak\n%c[default]He is right, no matter how you spin it. And hucksters in the Zone, by the way - and not only them, to be honest - are the most fair: to get something from them, you have to sweat. And how did you want it? Everything fair and square. But the reward can be such that no money would be enough to buy it. True, that is how you negotiate. Face-control, understand? So don't cast aspersions on our hucksters...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_212">
    <text>SOS! Help! Tushkanos pinned us down at Agroprom! Can't get out ourselves. Brothers, help urgently, otherwise all seven of us will lie here!!!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_213">
    <text>Found an interesting zombie about a month ago at Radar. I gave him canned food, and he tossed me some artifact. Only went there the other day and didn't find him. Sad...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_214">
    <text>Sakharov got arrogant! Brought him two "Jellyfish" and a "Droplet". And he says he won't buy them. Says he has plenty already! Old beetle...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_215">
    <text>By the way, about stashes: took one from a guy for a bottle and told him at the end: "what I find - half is yours". Found, split equally, approach him - and he doesn't want to take it... Forgot, probably.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_216">
    <text>We have no ammo, sitting with Edik on a large boulder. About 100 meters away noticed some man in a black raincoat, decided to move to him... Damn, while I was writing, he hacked Edik with an axe, I bolted and am sitting near a crashed helicopter. Urgent hel... Message interrupted.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_217">
    <text>Found out that Sidor gives out diapers. Took one just in case, it's free anyway. Thought, maybe it will be useful. Just walked into Forgotten Forest - was useful immediately.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_218">
    <text>Yea-ah... Not the same wildlife in the Zone anymore... Walking just now from Bar to Garbage, look, a controller sitting under a tree. Legs stretched out, blissful face, warming in the sun - pure cat, just doesn't purr. Think I'll take a photo, since such luck! Approaching quietly, click - here he gets up, approaches so slowly - and bam, punches me in the nose! And grumbles: can't make out words, but clear he doesn't approve. While I was shaking my head, chasing redness from eyes, controller turned, walked away to bushes further and sat down again. Stood a bit more and went on. And you say - beast, beast...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_219">
    <text>Cook turns out to be a philosopher! Yesterday blurted out... such a thing! Think even Monolith prayer would be easier to figure out and understand the meaning than in what he said yesterday!\n%c[orange]Cook\n%c[default]Don't be offended, I was simply sober...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_220">
    <text>So, Messer, butt doesn't ache? Ha-ha-ha! That boar headbutted you nicely, flew a couple meters!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_221">
    <text>Rumor has it Monolithians are not such fanatics as they seem. Maybe they are just pumped with some drugs. Catch a bum on the Big Land, process him and send him here. And he defends his "Monolith". Just who needs all this? Hell understands, figures out... Or maybe it's all fiction...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_222">
    <text>A couple of days ago was in Limansk. And found some documents there. And in them written that there is some installation that affects people's consciousness. Not like Radar burns everything out, but specifically changes the mind. There you go! Maybe we walk under such too, just don't notice...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_223">
    <text>They say, a couple of weeks ago there was a breakthrough in the Cordon area. And rumor has it that mutants broke through to the Perimeter on some armored truck through the minefield. And a human was driving. Of course, many were laid down, but some broke out beyond the Perimeter and broke into the nearest village. So they destroyed that village to zero along with people. Eh, Zone, Zone. What are you doing...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_224">
    <text>A story happened to me today. In general, found an artifact. Such bluish, glows a little. Haven't seen such before and didn't have gloves on me. So decided to take it directly with a container, luckily no anomalies nearby. Put container on it, closed lid, and started moving container to myself. So artifact floated through it and stayed in place. No matter how much I struggled there, nothing came of it.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_225">
    <text>All military are dumb freaks!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_226">
    <text>Who is Semetsky? Why does he die constantly?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_227">
    <text>Damn! Sidor, bastard! Bought a new shotgun from him a week ago, and today it exploded right in hands. Good thing I stayed alive... Once I get to "Monolith" - will wish for Sidorovich to vanish!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_228">
    <text>Found a typewriter in a toilet yesterday. Wonder who is such a poet there?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_229">
    <text>Wonder if one can trade vodka for a BTR from Kuznetsov?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_230">
    <text>I want Sidor to have "Bumblebees" at the price of a diaper!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_231">
    <text>Fang! Haven't seen you for a long time. Since the moment you dragged me on yourself away from those black dogs. Want to say thank you and everything is fine with me.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_232">
    <text>Heard the other day Freedomers caught a controller and got him dead drunk. And were catching hallucinations all night... And then in the morning controller had a wild hangover. Had to shoot the poor guy, so he wouldn't suffer...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_233">
    <text>Is it true there are two labs on Radar? Painfully interesting, tell, who knows.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_234">
    <text>Attention everyone! Was in Pripyat, ran into Monolithians. And were in some strange suits, seemingly painfully fancy. Be careful.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_235">
    <text>Oh darn! Had a stash in Forgotten Forest. Came today, and there is a "Carousel". And what to do now?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_236">
    <text>Guys, found an old photo album in Limansk. Who is interested - write in PM, will discuss.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_237">
    <text>Hey, Kulinar! When will you invite for pilaf? Boasting so much, but still nothing...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_238">
    <text>Yesterday was in Forgotten Forest and found corpses of three vagrants. And what is most terrible, all three have heads torn off. Ghastly sight!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_239">
    <text>Wow! Today saw on Yantar how an exoskeleton walked by itself! Give a tooth, it was empty!</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_240">
    <text>At Cordon on the farm three fleshes settled. Walk together. So together that it feels like they are a family.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_241">
    <text>Saw a group in Red Forest. They shot zombies and then started with friends, telling truth, not to drink vodka, but to booze.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Yeah we believe. What fool would drink vodka, when it can be boozed.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_242">
    <text>Went to Yantar. Beautiful landscape there. Small lake, hills, factory and zombies pressing. Idyll...</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_243">
    <text>Stumbled upon a flesh today. So I kicked it in the eye! Died instantly. Looks like reached the brain.\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]You walk on stilettos or what?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_244">
    <text>Went to Garbage with the boys today. Just familiar hills appeared, and local dogs already greeting us.\n%c[orange]Stalker Bubulyuka\n%c[default]With bread and salt?</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_245">
    <text>Damn! Filthy mutts, pinned me in a ravine and running around. One jumped, hovered for five seconds probably, until I shot its head. Heh-heh.\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Dogs flying, probably means rain.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_246">
    <text>when i went out of roockie village i went to look for bloodsucker here i saw someone runing after boar and kil him i quietly sneaked up and shoot him in eye he jumped on me i barley got knife and stabed him and went to vilage to rest\n%c[orange]Potap\n%c[default]Let's stop smoking garbage. Otherwise cutting your channel.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_uniq_247">
    <text>Damn! Can't understand this Voron at all. He has some own anomalous philosophy. Brought him a SIG-modification - doesn't take it. Put in stash, came in a day or two - same thing. Turned out, it was slightly broken and had to spend a repair kit. And before the bag of weed was a normal man!</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_0">
    <text>"Springboard"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_1">
    <text>"Burner"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_2">
    <text>"Vortex"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_3">
    <text>"Fruit Punch"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_4">
    <text>"Electro"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_5">
    <text>Shrapnel wound, apparently there was a heavy firefight</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_6">
    <text>Boar</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_7">
    <text>Dog</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_8">
    <text>Pseudodog</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_9">
    <text>Bloodsucker</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_10">
    <text>Tushkanos</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_11">
    <text>Not clear what happened, the guy was simply torn apart</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_12">
    <text>Looks like a radiation burn</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_13">
    <text>Slashed all over, don't know what beast that was</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_14">
    <text>Head shot through</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_15">
    <text>Arm torn off in one of the anomalies. Died due to blood loss</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_16">
    <text>Terrible mess instead of legs. Seems stepped into "Fruit Punch"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_17">
    <text>Chest shot through</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_18">
    <text>Shot in the heart, and then in the head - control shot. Mercenaries, apparently...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_19">
    <text>Bloody streak on concrete, shreds of suit, smashed PDA. That's all...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_20">
    <text>Someone was chasing him. Flew into an anomaly</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_21">
    <text>Blood coming from nose and ears. Looks like consequences of radiation poisoning</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_22">
    <text>No wounds. Very strange death</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_23">
    <text>Hit a "Burner". Dropped PDA shortly before, otherwise I couldn't identify him</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_24">
    <text>Splashed on the ground. "Fruit Punch"</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_25">
    <text>He didn't even know what junk he carried in the backpack. Died of radiation. Radioactive artifacts</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_26">
    <text>Suit intact, mess inside. Don't know what the matter is</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_27">
    <text>Marauders</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_28">
    <text>Ran into marauders</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_29">
    <text>Leg shot through. Couldn't return to his own, died of blood loss</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_30">
    <text>Guy pale as death. Neat through hole in the chest...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_31">
    <text>Damaged respiratory system, inhaled radioactive junk</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_32">
    <text>Body thoroughly eaten. Looks like blind dogs</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_33">
    <text>Everything here covered in some slimy junk. Disappeared without a trace, only found boiled PDA around the corner. Don't know what that was...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_34">
    <text>Leg slashed to the bone, died of blood loss</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_35">
    <text>Open fracture. Couldn't leave, lay for a couple of hours, then something thoroughly ate him...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_36">
    <text>Shot at point-blank range from sawn-off. Apparently, it was a marauder ambush... bastards</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_37">
    <text>Shot in the back of the head</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_38">
    <text>Noticed a bloodsucker leaning over the body. When killed the beast and approached, guy wasn't breathing</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_39">
    <text>Strange burns all over the body. Doesn't look like "Burner"...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_40">
    <text>Lacerated wound on chest. Don't know exact circumstances of death</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_41">
    <text>Found PDA next to body. Don't know why voice recorder turned on, but nothing on recording except half an hour of screams. Not a scratch on the guy. Devilry...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_42">
    <text>Found slashed body. Knife lying nearby and trembling slightly. What was happening here, can't imagine...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_43">
    <text>Skeleton polished to shine in untouched gear. Rats?</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_44">
    <text>Gnawed to bones. Rats</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_45">
    <text>Both arms broken, neck twisted. Damn, who did him like that...</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_46">
    <text>Smashed skull</text>
</string>
<string id="dead_reason_47">
    <text>Shoulder stitched with a burst. No bandages, died of blood loss</text>
</string>

<string id="news_1">
    <text>Yes Stalker, not your day today. Your bet didn't play... Your winning - zero tugriks.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_2">
    <text>Winning 500 rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_3">
    <text>Winning one thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_4">
    <text>Winning 5 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_5">
    <text>Winning 10 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_6">
    <text>Winning 15 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_7">
    <text>Winning 20 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_8">
    <text>Winning 25 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_9">
    <text>Winning 50 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_10">
    <text>Winning 100 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_11">
    <text>Winning 200 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_12">
    <text>Winning 300 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_13">
    <text>Winning 400 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_14">
    <text>Winning 500 thousand rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="news_15">
    <text>Jackpot Stalker! Your winning 1 million rubles.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_1">
    <text>Stalker, they were asking about you regarding the debt here...\nYou should drop by, pay the debt - only pennies left.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_2">
    <text>Ay-ya ya-yay, Stalker, the deadline has passed,\nand you are not rushing to pay the debt. Come on hurry up.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_3">
    <text>And what does this mean, Stalker? Were you given a deadline?\nGiven. Deadline passed - blow here with money.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_4">
    <text>So-so, Stalker, means we like to play, but not pay debts.\n Not good. Even contrary - bad. Need to tear arms off for this. Understood everything?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_5">
    <text>Strelok, you became totally insolent. Why the hell, asking, you are not bringing the debt?\nGuys came here, promised to cut you into a British flag, and feed the remains to fleshes. Come to me quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_6">
    <text>I don't understand something, how did we agree?\nDebt for three days - and no "but I couldn't, sorry".\nDo what you want, but return the debt immediately. Otherwise - curtains for you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_7">
    <text>Stalker, come to the Bar urgently.\nYou are awaited... with dough. Otherwise blame yourself - the axe is already sharpened.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_8">
    <text>You are such a beast, Stalker - you, bitch, are setting me up by not giving money back.\nIf you don't return the debt by evening - entrance to my shop will be closed to you forever.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_9">
    <text>Last Chinese warning to you, guy:\nall deadlines passed, and you didn't even lift a finger.\nYou are screwed now if you don't return the dough.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_10">
    <text>That's it, respected one - you are a corpse.\nI hired mercenaries. They are already looking for you.</text>
</string>