<string id="stalker_story_1">
    <text>So we're climbing into that hangar. Dust everywhere, cobwebs - right up to the ceiling, detectors spewing complete nonsense, saying there's nobody around, and we don't exist either. We went to take positions around the perimeter: Sanyok up front, we're covering... And then - CRASH! A beam, a huge iron rusty one under the ceiling, breaks loose - and down! How Sanyok dodged it, he doesn't know himself, but this thing stuck right where he was standing. Well, he fell and rolled away, didn't get up at all, just started shooting while lying down! The rest got scared too, idiots, and started shooting into thin air. Then Sanyok started yelling something about a creature in the corner. I look - I don't see any creature... Anyway, things went south, not an operation but a complete mess... bordello... We started walking through these ruins; walked for about five minutes - carefully, so as not to end up under those beams again. And it's crazy, just crazy: one guy or another keeps seeing things, they start spraying half-mags at empty spots. And two guys really had bad luck: one was walking on flat floor and suddenly fell into a pit, the second got hit across the back by a falling door. Well, at that point we really got fired up - it's clear that some creature is having fun! We turned on psi-protection, threw a gas grenade in every corner - and waited to see who shows up, fingers on triggers. We're waiting... And the creature, as it turned out later, was airborne or something... While we were all acting like fools downstairs, it was quietly sitting under the ceiling having fun, the bitch... We figured it out late, and that was almost by accident. This bastard loosened a couple more beams - half the roof came down. Right on us... crushed four guys flat on the spot... That's when we got it! When Sanyok heard rustling above, he just fired a burst on reflex - most useful reflex ever! Well, the screeching started! We jumped up too, fired from all barrels... The creature fell from above with such screams that our ears were ringing. Well, then we vented: some hit it with rifle butts, some just stomped on it. Sanyok, he pulled out a knife to cut its guts out more painfully... The commander, of course, had trouble pulling everyone off, otherwise we'd have been scraping that bitch off the floor with spoons...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_1_name">
    <text>About the Creature in the Hangar</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_10">
    <text>Have you heard about the Guide? The very first of the stalkers. First one to start going into the Zone. Still alive to this day. They say he'll guide you to any point. Another thing is, finding him is problematic - he doesn't post flyers with his address... And he doesn't agree to guide just anyone either. Takes a lot of cash, but if you found him and made a deal, be sure - he'll get you where you need to go, guaranteed. That's who I'd like to talk to. He's probably seen what's behind the radar...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_10_name">
    <text>The Super-Guide</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_11">
    <text>Showing off and having cash are two different things... What, thought you get money for free here? Hell no! For free you'll only get eaten by some mutant, or shot by soldiers... Gotta think. Think there, and even better here. Complete idiots don't last long here. Doesn't work, without brains... Anyway, here's what happened. Three of us - me, Bruiser and Chain, rest in peace - were going through the service yard - cutting through, basically. We see some bandit walking. So we hid. And he passes by us - doesn't notice. Small guy, but dragging a sack - damn heavy. And his rifle's hanging cleverly: at any moment he could fill us with lead. Well, Bruiser tells me: "Let's feel out this moron, see what he's got?" And I tell him: "Quiet, you idiot! Better watch where he's dragging his loot". So... Then the moron vanished somewhere - we didn't even understand how. Well, we wait. He climbed out after about twenty minutes. While he was dusting himself off, Chain quietly came up from behind and blew half his head off with a shotgun. They started looting the body with Bruiser: he had a nice vest, and should have had a wallet... I went to take a leak - my boys always give me my share, I'm in on it for life. Then it EXPLODED!.. Anyway, that sucker wasn't simple: he rigged something clever to blow up if someone tried to take off his vest. I got out of there fast - not many people will show up at gunshot and explosion... I came back a month later. Of Chain, Bruiser and the moron - not even a bone left. Completely wiped. Anyway, I figured out where he dove into the ruins, and went there myself... Well, I went through three rooms - nothing! Then I see a pile of beds stacked in the corner. What the hell are so many cots doing there? Anyway, I started clearing them out. Cleared them. I look, holy mother, a hatch! I lift the lid, shine my flashlight. Hot damn! I'm in paradise!.. Well, what was there - my business... I didn't end up at a loss. But if I'd listened to them - I'd be dead long ago or still running around broke, begging... Like some people...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_11_name">
    <text>Hatch to Paradise</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_12">
    <text>They say there's one group of guys... Sometimes they're called shamans, sometimes druids. They say they don't carry any electronic equipment - closer to nature, they say, and all that... Well, they say the Zone reacts more strongly to electronics... to all kinds of electromagnetic radiation... and sics monsters on you. According to them, the Zone is a living organism. Can't go into it with devices - a proper person will manage without any extra gear. Though they carry rifles with them, the bastards... Why not try teeth and claws... On the other hand, they don't die in the Zone all that often. They don't kick the bucket more often than us... So maybe they figured it out right... Though they supposedly enter the Zone more from the Belarusian side... Would be good to get a look at them... and check how many artifacts they've got in their pockets...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_12_name">
    <text>Story About Combat Druids</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_13">
    <text>You know what that bandit told me in the bar? That there's supposedly one mutant here that plays with people's minds. Makes them see what isn't there. Even makes them fight each other. And the bastard himself sits in the bushes and laughs. Those who figure out what's happening in time have a chance to survive. And those who don't - get buried. Scary stuff, damn it... Though with our job, you see all kinds of scary things every day...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_13_name">
    <text>Mind Player</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_2">
    <text>Near the factory, you've seen those metal constructions with pipes sticking out? Well, if you haven't been there, I'll explain. There's this maze of pipes and platforms. You go in, and it's like entering another dimension. Everything's rusty, creaking, dripping. And the echo - like in a church. We were told there's good loot there. We went to check it out as a five-man team. Found a couple of crates, started looking through them. Suddenly we hear this howling. We look - can't see anything. Then again, closer. We spread out to cover each other. And then we see it - something's moving in the pipes above. Fast, you can barely make it out. We started shooting - it's dodging, the bastard. Then it jumped down and ran. We chased it. It led us into a dead end. Stands there, staring at us. We approach - it suddenly screams and charges! We barely managed to bring it down. It was some kind of hybrid. Half-human, half... I don't even know what. Since then I don't go near those pipes.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_2_name">
    <text>In the Pipe Maze</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_3">
    <text>I'm telling you, Controller is the worst. You can fight dogs, even chimera can be handled if you're smart. But Controller - that's pure hell. He gets into your head and that's it. You start seeing things that aren't there. Or worse - you stop seeing what's actually there. I had a buddy, experienced guy, been in the Zone for five years. Met a Controller once. When we found him, he was sitting in a corner, eyes glassy, muttering something. We dragged him out, but he never came back to normal. Lived another month, then one night just got up and walked into an anomaly. Didn't even scream. That's what Controller does to you. So if you see one - run. Don't try to be a hero. Heroes with Controllers don't last long.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_3_name">
    <text>Meeting a Controller</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_4">
    <text>Want to know why we avoid the Brain Scorcher? I'll tell you. A group went there once. Eight guys, all experienced. Took psi-protection, everything they needed. Went to explore what's behind it. None of them came back. A month later, one was found wandering near the Barrier. Completely out of his mind. Just laughed and cried. Couldn't say a word normally. Just kept drawing something on the ground - circles and lines. The scientists took him, tried to treat him. Nothing helped. He lived for another year and died. And the rest - no one knows. Maybe they're still wandering around there. Or maybe they're dead. Either way, I'm not going near that place. Money's not worth losing your mind over.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_4_name">
    <text>About the Brain Scorcher</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_5">
    <text>You want artifacts? I'll tell you where to look. But first, listen to what happened to me. I was hunting for artifacts near the factory. Found a good anomaly, started circling it. Threw bolts, checked with detector. Everything seemed fine. Reached in to grab an artifact - and got pulled in! Good thing I was tied with a rope to a pipe. My partners pulled me out. But while I was in there... I saw things. Things you can't describe. Like I was in another world. Everything was different colors, shapes moved on their own. And the silence - deafening silence. When they pulled me out, I couldn't talk for two days. And now sometimes at night I see those shapes. So yeah, hunt for artifacts. But be careful. Very careful. Because the Zone doesn't forgive mistakes. And sometimes it doesn't forgive even when you do everything right.</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_5_name">
    <text>Artifact Hunter</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_6">
    <text>So... I remember someone asked me about something yesterday, and I forgot... Ah, remembered. So, there are curious folks wondering why only our eggheads are poking around the Zone, while foreigners don't even show their noses, even though there's material here for three thousand Nobel Prizes... So, I'll answer point by point. First of all, why would they come here themselves when they can give our guys a grant with such conditions that they'll bring you everything you need on a silver platter? And secondly, they actually have been here, and a lot. It's just the last two years that foreigners are afraid to go into the Zone... they had one major screwup. Now they just buy materials and information. They pay pretty well, so many loners work for them, and marauders too... What, haven't heard about this story? You're kidding! The whole Zone was up in arms, and you're like you fell from the sky. Anyway, it was a big insertion. About thirty scientists alone from half the world... all luminaries, of course, this and that... They prepared seriously: threw money around like crazy, equipment - mountains of it. Took a platoon of military specialists for protection, a trio of guides from our guys, loaded onto shielded armored personnel carriers and set off. What... They came back a week later... twelve people on a beat-to-hell APC. Came out at the wire near the Dead Forest, and marauders were already waiting for them there... Yeah... They don't care where people escaped from... Killed almost everyone. Only three got past the perimeter - two of ours and one egghead. The guy went seriously crazy from the impressions... Well, they quickly grabbed him by the collar - and off to treatment. Now he's writing a book about the Zone. Our guys are okay - experience helped. Though... they probably went crazy in their own way too: one went to the radar and disappeared, and the second went to the Big Land. Well, the Zone took the rest. Have you heard about Town-32? That's where they got caught. At first everything seemed quiet... well, within limits... They were filming-measuring there, collecting samples, poking anomalies with instruments... And then they started going mad. Mass madness. People slowly started losing it. The one of ours who retired told me... Some started tearing their throats out with their nails, some smashed their heads against walls, and some just - barrel in mouth, and... And then the beasts came. Those who were still sane barricaded themselves in a house. Can you imagine? Outside is night and all the local creatures, and inside people are losing their minds one after another. In short, by morning those who could still think somehow broke out. They drove back straight, without roads; even hit a couple of anomalies... Made it to the Dead Forest... And of those who stayed there, no one was ever found. The guys just say that in those parts there was a sharp increase in Controllers. Yeah... So since then nobody goes to Town-32, and you can't lure a foreigner into the Zone for anything...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_6_name">
    <text>Chronicles of Globalist Eggheads</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_7">
    <text>So here's what I wanted to say. When the Duty guys were taking that pseudogiant, I was right there! I just happened to be in those parts! My truck's right front wheel blew: bolts sheared off on a bump. And completely out of spare parts. I cursed properly, then thought, let me go to the factory, I'll find what I need. Well, it was a kilometer walk, there and back - half an hour's work! And I'd been there before... Suddenly I see Duty! And not just a patrol, but like fifty of them! Well, I think, holy crap!.. Stayed right where I was and dove into the bushes. "If they spotted me and start combing through, - I think, - that's the end of me". Laid down in a ditch and trying not to breathe. And then shooting! I only heard shooting like that with such bursts once in my life... when they took the First Base - old-timers, remember? Anyway, I'm lying there, listening with both ears... It's going boom, and then it really CRASHES!.. After about five minutes it dies down, and nobody seems to be coming my way. Well, I got some guts, stood up a bit and looked through binoculars. And these guys quickly pull out of the workshop... all beat up, dragging a bunch of their dead and a pseudogiant on a tarp... just scraps left of the pseudogiant... Dragged off to a gully. Then I hear - engines roared, and the sound left. I waited a bit more - seems like nobody's there. I went inside. Well, obviously after Duty you won't find much! But it's interesting! This, I tell you, was something! They almost shot through the walls. Beams lying across the floor, a piece of roof collapsed. Shells up to your knees - a real shooting range. Blood, bits and pieces... Didn't find anything useful though - just two full mags and a rifle lying there, pinned by a beam, couldn't pull it out... About the bolts, I naturally forgot... Went back to the truck, thought for five minutes, took one bolt off each of the other wheels... well, and drove slowly... If I'd gone out there half an hour earlier... Yeah...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_7_name">
    <text>Duty's Illusion</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_8">
    <text>Yeah, so I got all the way to the outskirts of Pripyat. Well, decided to scout around first. Found a higher point - there was a big boiler room with a chimney. Well, went in carefully... seems like everything's okay - dust lying around, no tracks... Climbed into the firebox and crawled: there were steps inside the chimney. Climbing normally, even the soot doesn't stain anymore - it's petrified... Carefully stick my head out... Beautiful! Half the city laid out before me! Pulled out binoculars and looking around... (short pause) Well, and then... Was about to climb back down, and then a thought flashes: what's happening right under my nose, and I didn't look! Lean over the edge a bit, look one way, then the other... Oh boy! Would've been screwed! A dwarf's walking around the inner courtyard! Main thing is, I almost climbed down! And good thing he doesn't see me yet. But I can't take his head off: AKS is on my back, and the chimney's too narrow, can't turn around. With the PM under my arm, fat chance - it's like fifty meters there, plus the height difference... in short, if I don't hit right away - and I won't - then it's definitely curtains. I sit and think. Well, and watch what he's doing. And he's doing something strange. First he was briskly, with enthusiasm, rummaging in a pile of junk - only pieces flying left and right. And then suddenly froze right where he stood. Like he was listening. Well, then total chaos started. The trash in that pile started moving by itself. The dwarf quickly jumped back, stood up straight, put his hands to his head, twisted his palms in some clever way... and stuff started FLYING at him! From all sides!.. Metal pieces, bricks, roofing felt, branches... Completely buried him. Well, I think, that's it. Game over for the kitty, won't piss anymore... No way! Two seconds this trash laid there, and then just BURST in all directions! There were pipe scraps there, they stuck right into the concrete fence. The dwarf stood for another half minute, thought about something, then turned around and walked into the building. I caught my breath for another minute. "Well, - I think, - enough's enough, time to get out of here". And then suddenly it started smelling like smoke. And then it got hot. Go to hell! Someone lit a fire down below! In a minute there was nothing to breathe. Somehow crawled to the edge of the chimney, there's no platform, I'm sitting with my legs hanging... But the smoke's still eating my eyes, not enough air... in short, gotta bail urgently! Thank God, I always carried forty meters of rope with me for any emergency... exactly, emergency... Anyway, I folded it in half - it wasn't very thick - somehow fixed it on the chimney, tore my neck scarf in half, wrapped it on my hands without gloves, and climbed down, praying to all the gods... One thought in my head: just don't fall! No safety, nothing, rope's cutting my palms... Well, and of course, by Murphy's Law it was five meters short to the ground. Had to jump. What else could I do? Oh, I crashed! Lucky I didn't break anything... But got scraped up and pulled my right leg - big time! Later thought I tore the ligaments. But then I ran from there so fast I probably would've won a gold medal in running...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_8_name">
    <text>Gray in Pripyat</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_9">
    <text>And I couldn't believe my eyes. I mean, there are beautiful girls, right? But this one was... she was... Perfection. Yes. That's it. Perfection. It felt like the world around her was black and white and blurry, she alone was in color and sharp focus. How she moved! I'd never seen anything like that before. I got a lump in my throat. What does she need this science for! What's she doing here in the Zone?.. Well yeah, in the Zone. It was toward evening... At the bus station, there's a separate nine-story building there. First something flashed in the window on the first floor. I quickly took my rifle off safety and then I see - she's coming out of the entrance... I wanted to rub my eyes - you never know what to expect from the Zone? And she approaches. And I'm standing like a fool, staring... Though I'm keeping my rifle ready - force of habit... Then she noticed me... Smiled... Said hello... And I'm listening and not hearing, just looking at her. She was in a blue jumpsuit, bright like that... But not baggy, almost form-fitting... Her figure - something fantastic! Only then did it dawn on me that I'm not listening at all to what she's saying, I'm standing and smiling ear to ear... She, it turned out, was from a research group. Asked if I could help her. Her! I'd have climbed into an anomaly for her!.. Said she studies these, what are they called... Endemics of the Zone. Well, plants that only grow here. Said she ran away from the guards because with them there's no freedom of action, and came here alone. I don't know. I believed her. Agreed to help her bring something. Came back two days later as agreed. Almost got killed five times while collecting it. Walking, and in my head just one thought: now I'll see her again! And nothing! I didn't even see the house where I met her. That's how it was... But how beautiful she was! She was glowing from inside...</text>
</string>
<string id="stalker_story_9_name">
    <text>Male Loneliness</text>
</string>
<string id="Stories">
    <text>Local Folklore</text>
</string>
