<string id="artefact">
    <text>Obtain an artifact</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1">
    <text>Defend the stalker camp</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Barkeep asked me to defend a stalker camp at the Garbage from a bandit attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_1_text">
    <text>A group of stalkers is coming to me, and I am personally interested in their safe arrival. They stopped not far from the Bar. One repentant criminal element reported almost voluntarily that they are to be attacked soon. So head there and protect their camp from the attack.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2">
    <text>Help stalkers fight off attackers</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Barkeep said that bandits are pressing stalkers at Agroprom. They are holding on, but it is unknown for how long. Need to run there and help them.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_defend_camp_2_text">
    <text>Basically, here is the deal. Recently a group of stalkers went to Agroprom. The last time they were in touch, they said they found something valuable in the underground, but bandits pressed them. They are holding on for now, but can't leave either. Will you help them?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Destroy bandits at the Garbage</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Barkeep asked me to finish off a group of bandits that took a fancy to the Garbage territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>Work, work... what do we have here?.. Aha! So, look: can you whack a bandit gang at the Garbage? Duty screams a lot about law and order, but they never get around to it; truth be told, these bandits are rare scum, they've annoyed everyone, so they won't walk for long. Only the one who makes it first will cut some dough... and drinks are on me, that's for sure.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Destroy mercenaries and bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Remove a group of mercenaries and bandits blocking the passage through the Rostok factory territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>Not far from here, at the Rostok factory, a group of mercenaries settled in. They got along with bandits and now want to close the passage through the factory together. You understand yourself - this is a misunderstanding, it must be solved quickly. Dutyers and some experienced guys already went to educate them, only they haven't been seen coming back yet... So you... check how things are there. I pay nicely.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Destroy mercenaries</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>It's simple: Clear the farmstead of mercenaries.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>There is a small farmstead at the Army Warehouses. It was convenient to meet with the right people there, take-give goods, and all that... you got it. And now mercenaries settled there and don't seem to plan to leave anytime soon. Only this doesn't suit me very well. So, I need the farmstead to become free in the near future. I don't care what happens to the tenants.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4">
    <text>Clear the bandit camp</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
    <text>Destroy the bandit camp in the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_4_text">
    <text>Bandits in the Wild Territory. We cannot allow these scum to breed unsanitary conditions right next to the Bar. Their camp must be cleared.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5">
    <text>Destroy the dog lair</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
    <text>Destroy the lair of mutant dogs in the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_5_text">
    <text>Several of our guys went on an expedition, one returned. All torn up, bloody, glassy eyes. Most likely ran into dogs. There is a whole pack of them. So, find their lair and kill every last one.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6">
    <text>Bandits at Agroprom</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
    <text>Destroy a group of bandits at Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_6_text">
    <text>I remember, somehow in '94 racketeers stuck to me: come on, pay up. Ooh, I suffered back then, I had a restaurant. There was no justice for them back then! And suddenly I find out that this same gang is now operating at Agroprom, collecting percentages for finding artifacts! But here my arms are long. I even know where exactly they settled. Be kind, punish them.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7">
    <text>Destroy the snork lair</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_descr">
    <text>Destroy the snork lair in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_eliminate_camp_7_text">
    <text>Yes... It seems those who say the Zone is expanding are right. Several snorks were spotted in the Dark Valley, they weren't seen there before. Well, some people started to panic here. Duty promised to destroy the snorks, but they just can't get around to it. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Find "Meat Chunk"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Get "Meat Chunk" - an artifact that helps healing.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>Recently some holy rollers stopped by, left an order for a "Meat Chunk". You know yourself, they have an interest in this healing artifact... rotten miracle workers, damn it! Ye-eah... So do you take it? In principle, I don't force you.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find "Crystal Thorn"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Find the artifact "Crystal Thorn".</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>"Slime"?.. No, not that. "Crystal Water"?.. No, wrong again... Phew! "Crystal Thorn", oh right! So, look: a collector ordered the artifact "Crystal Thorn". Will pay well for the work. Do you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Find "Night Star"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Find the artifact "Night Star" - help the domestic military-industrial complex.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>Need the artifact "Night Star". Unfortunately, it doesn't grant wishes - verified, but it can enrich you quite well. Scientists give good money for it. They say they are crafting something military based on it... Well, so what?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Find "Flash"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Find the artifact "Flash".</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>The task is simple, and the payment is good. Need to find the artifact "Flash". Don't even ask who ordered it and why. Do you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5">
    <text>Find "Goldfish"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_descr">
    <text>Find the artifact "Goldfish".</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_artefact_5_text">
    <text>Strelok, do you know the fairy tale about the Golden Fish? There, there! Also many jokes about it. So, there is an old man who wants to catch it. Basically, need the unique artifact "Goldfish". External customer. Will you help?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1">
    <text>Find a psi-suit</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Search somewhere in the abandoned laboratories of the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_1_text">
    <text>There was a time when laboratories in the Dark Valley worked: kept looking for how to protect brains from psi-emission. Only they worked too slowly, yes... So, it seems there was one successful attempt after all, and a suit is lying around somewhere there, in which you can even kiss a controller... Aha, even so. If you drag this thing to me, I won't forget it.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2">
    <text>Find the foreigner's gun</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2_descr">
    <text>Need to find the "Desert Eagle" of the vanished foreigner.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_2_text">
    <text>A foreigner appeared in our parts... Was his name Gordon, or something? Moreover, by all habits - an experienced stalker, only somehow strange, silent... Well okay, that's not the point. Still, he vanished somewhere in the Zone. And he had one very interesting thing - a "Desert Eagle". I'd like to look at it closer...</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3">
    <text>Find "Vintorez"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3_descr">
    <text>Find a modified "Vintorez" in the Radar area.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_find_item_3_text">
    <text>So, such a story happened here. A guy rushed in - pockets bulging with money! Started hiring people for his company, not the experienced ones, but the flashy ones, buying equipment in packs... I had a tuned "Vintorez" - a miracle, not a gun - so like a fool I sold it to him. Didn't lose money, won't lie... Only this whole company quickly got covered somewhere in the Radar area. Well, pity the people, of course... But others will know now: you can't pave a road through the Zone with just dough. Yes, so I still pity that "Vintorez" - such a gun and rotting somewhere! Find it, eh? Good fee is on me!</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill a serviceman</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Need to finish off an unknown serviceman.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>I need you to deal with one military guy... and don't ask who he is, and why the hell I need it! Just do the deed. Well? Can I rely on you?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill a stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Finish off one of the stalkers.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>You know, there are people about whom you'd never say anything bad... You trust them, right? Rely on them like on yourself... Only suddenly you find out that he is some son of a bitch so cunning and lying that... Anyway, there is a serious matter: need to settle scores with one guy for everything. Do it, and the rest is on me.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill a stalker from "Monolith"</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Find the trader's former friend and help him die.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>Once I had a friend... unbelievable, right? Eh... and we came to the Zone together, when none of this even existed. And what didn't we do, where didn't we climb... yes, we were young, reckless... Only it was always not enough for him. He wanted to go to the center of the Zone and pulled me, but I refused - and rightly so... We quarreled badly then, and he left alone... Only they tell me they saw him there... he stands for "Monolith" now. So here is the thing, Strelok... I ask you as a human - find him, and... basically, so he doesn't suffer, he must be already... He was like a brother to me, understand?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Kill Vampire</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Find and kill the stalker nicknamed Vampire.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>That's it, this guy got to me!.. I'm talking about Vampire; do you know him or not? Ooh, bastard! He sucks not blood from people, but luck. Whoever goes with him - everyone dies, only he is alive and healthy! Fifth time already! In short, something unclean here. There is a strong desire to lay flowers on this Vampire's grave... Well, do you agree?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill Sparrow</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>Find Sparrow and avenge the death of another stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>Nobles, damn it!.. Pushkins with Lermontovs!.. As if idiots walking under anomalies and bullets every day wasn't enough, they also took duels into fashion! No, just imagine: we had a dispute here... no one even remembers what about. Only these two idiots decided to spill blood. And here you go: one went and died... what a stalker he was! and the second - Sparrow is his name - quickly bailed, because I myself would have put a bullet in his guts at the first opportunity. Find him. I'm sure he hasn't managed to get out of the Zone yet. Will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1">
    <text>Get a flesh eye</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Find a flesh eye for Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>Soon we have a holiday, and there will be a festive dinner, and some local gourmets in especially high spirits (won't point fingers) will definitely want to try my signature dish - flesh eyes in pork sauce. That is, in their own juice with mayonnaise. Anyway, need the eye of this beast and quickly.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2">
    <text>Get a boar hoof</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Find a boar hoof for Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="barmen_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Did you know we are harvesting horns and hooves? It's a big rarity now. Excellent decorations are made from local mutated hooves, I know a jeweler, he is interested. So go ahead, find a boar hoof, and money will arrive in your pocket.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1">
    <text>Defend Duty outpost</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Defend Duty outpost at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_defend_lager_1_text">
    <text>So, you surely met our guys at the Garbage. They are something like an external cordon there, protecting the Bar from mutants coming from the Dark Valley. Information arrived that a large pack of boars is approaching them right now. Help them beat off the wave of mutants, I won't remain in debt.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Destroy zombies</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>At Yantar destroy zombified Dutyers.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>Recently we sent a group to Yantar. Unfortunately, no one from the group returned. I was reported that near the mobile laboratory of scientists at Yantar several zombified stalkers from the group were seen. We cannot allow them to remain in this terrible state. Find and destroy what they have become.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10">
    <text>Remove a dog pack</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_descr">
    <text>Remove a dog pack at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_10_text">
    <text>We, of course, do not assign tasks to stranger stalkers. On the other hand, this task is simple, so there is no sense in chasing our guys. So, listen. Need to clear a small lair of beasts at the Garbage. One of our groups is already working there, so in case of trouble there is somewhere to retreat. On the other hand, it is desirable that there are no troubles, because there are few beasts - no more than a dozen. Most likely dogs: a migration of a sufficiently large pack was recently noticed in this area. You can proceed to the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11">
    <text>Destroy a stalker camp</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_descr">
    <text>Destroy a stalker camp at Agroprom.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_11_text">
    <text>There is one delicate matter, but our guys cannot be involved in its execution in any way. It is unprofitable for our allies to have neutrals present at the factory near Agroprom Research Institute. The task is this: clear the industrial zone from the presence of stalkers, whoever they are and whatever factions they belong to. Is everything clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12">
    <text>Destroy a mercenary squad</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_descr">
    <text>Destroy a mercenary squad at the Rostok factory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_12_text">
    <text>So, the task is this: need to destroy a squad of snipers of the mercenary faction. Situation: these snipers hold the upper floor of the construction complex. Estimated quantity: not less than two, not more than five. Armed, apparently, with sniper rifles. Advice: don't meddle with them during the day.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13">
    <text>Clear the bandit base</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_descr">
    <text>Clear the main bandit base in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_13_text">
    <text>It is necessary to conduct a raid on the main bandit base and destroy the maximum amount of enemy manpower. It's in the Dark Valley. Where the unfinished scientific center is. Enemy strength: about thirty militants; armed with light automatic weapons, pistols, shotguns. Is everything clear?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14">
    <text>Destroy snorks</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_descr">
    <text>Clear tunnels of snorks in the Yantar sector.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_14_text">
    <text>This time we'll have to do some cleaning. Tunnels in the Yantar sector are simply bursting with snorks: there are about a dozen of them there. Yes, now you can't sit out a storm there, like before...</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy a flesh pack</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy a flesh pack in the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>We recorded the movement of a large pack of beasts... Very nasty pig-like mutants, which everyone calls fleshes. Now they are in the Garbage area. All our people are busy, but these beasts must be destroyed. The work is specific, we will pay.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3">
    <text>Destroy pseudodogs</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_descr">
    <text>Clear a pseudodog lair at the Army Warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_3_text">
    <text>Our allies reported the discovery of a monster lair in the territory near the military warehouses. Presumably, a pack of pseudodogs. We have no need to make noise there right now, so this is a task for a neutral. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4">
    <text>Destroy a mercenary outpost</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_descr">
    <text>Not far from the military warehouses destroy a mercenary outpost.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_4_text">
    <text>Recently the activity of mercenary groups increased, several attacks on scientists, researchers of the Zone were made. This cannot be left unpunished. Need to perform a small punitive operation. Object - mercenary outpost near the military warehouses, behind the abandoned village.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5">
    <text>Mercenaries in the Wild Territory</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_descr">
    <text>Destroy mercenaries in the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_5_text">
    <text>A group of scientists plans to conduct research in the Wild Territory. But recently it's unsafe there, mercenaries became active. Ensure that there are no more mercenaries in the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6">
    <text>Kill bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_descr">
    <text>Kill bandits who infiltrated the Wild Territory.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_6_text">
    <text>I'll be brief. Bandits bypassed our outposts at the Bar and are now in the Wild Territory. They need to be eliminated.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7">
    <text>Destroy a controller</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_descr">
    <text>Destroy a controller at Yantar.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_7_text">
    <text>To perform this task, it is necessary to possess special skills. Scientists informed us that at Yantar near the entrance to the underground laboratory (in the central building) they spotted a controller. Controllers are very dangerous, but I am sure you will handle it.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8">
    <text>Destroy Freedomers</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_descr">
    <text>Clear the abandoned village at the Army Warehouses of Freedomers.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_8_text">
    <text>In the abandoned village at the Army Warehouses the activity of Freedom patrols increased. Clear the village of militants. After completion, a special reward awaits you.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9">
    <text>Destroy bandits</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_descr">
    <text>Destroy bandits at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_eliminate_lager_9_text">
    <text>The operational situation is unfavorable, bandits are concentrating in the Garbage and Dark Valley area. The best solution will be to strike two preemptive blows simultaneously! Our fighters will take care of the Valley, you get the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1">
    <text>Find a modified rifle</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Near military warehouses obtain a sample of modified rifle LR300.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_find_item_1_text">
    <text>Someone is helping mercenaries. Just recently they started walking with assault rifles modified for sniper fire. You understand yourself, a dangerous toy. I am interested in such a gun. Gratitude will be adequate, do not doubt.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Neutralize Poker</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Neutralize the bandit Poker.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>Object's nickname - Poker. One of the most cruel bandit leaders, a bastard and rapist... His head is clearly not in order: rumor has it, he earned some rare disease in the Zone. Now he often has total memory lapses, and when he comes to, doesn't remember where he is and who. Nevertheless, always armed and very aggressive. Presumed location: Dark Valley. Ready for the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item">
    <text>Find Dutyer's weapon</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_descr">
    <text>Dutyer asks to find his weapon somewhere in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="drunk_dolg_find_item_text">
    <text>Well, had to screw up like that. What does the Zone do to brains. Nerves seem strong, never feared anything, and then this. Still have this howl in ears. Everything went as usual. There was a sortie to the Dark Valley, sat with Krivoy in ambush covering the main group, and then as I heard the howl, such horror seized. Damn, I don't even remember how I ended up at Cordon. When returned to base, Voronin almost shot me on the spot: he just issued me an improved gun for good service, so to speak. And here... I panicked and bolted, so apparently left it there. If you could bring it to me, because where am I now without a normal weapon.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Clear snork lair</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>At Yantar destroy a snork lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>I want to offer you a small sum of money, which you will receive if the snorks inhabiting the swamps stop distracting me and my colleagues. Sometimes during experiments, it's simply impossible to concentrate.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy wild dog lair</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>In the Wild Territory clear a dog lair.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>In the Wild Territory there is a lair of mutant dogs, I want you to go and clear it. These mutants are dangerous for our expeditions. I know zoologists won't support me, but here, agree, is not a zoo. Such creatures spread rabies, plague and God knows what else.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Bring "Fireball"</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Fireball" for scientists to research.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>We managed to obtain an artifact in laboratory conditions! This is a breakthrough! Now the whole world will hear about our successes. And Nobel Prize is just around the corner! This is a unique artifact - "Pellicle". Its main quality is protection from chemical burns. Want me to gift it to you in the name of science? However, one request - in return I need the artifact "Fireball", know such? Unique thermal properties of its surface require detailed study.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find "Gravi"</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Deliver artifact "Gravi" for scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>We came close to understanding the nature of gravity, in fact, very soon we will be able to create a new generation of engines on antigravity basis, and, quite possibly, the road to stars will open for us. For this we need the artifact "Gravi".</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Get "Jellyfish"</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Artifact "Jellyfish" is needed by scientists for research.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>Our research complex is on the threshold of discovering the secret of space and time. Possibility of teleportation is not fiction! "Vortex" is an anomaly that compresses space, and not just gravitationally affects objects, as some of my fossilized theoretical opponents think, sitting in warm research institutes, diligently chewing chalk. Their glasses will fog up when they find out what results science can achieve in field conditions! Get me the artifact "Jellyfish", please.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Get "Moonlight"</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Provide scientists at Yantar with "Moonlight".</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>We urgently need materials to continue research in the field of energy. You see, we learned to generate electricity using artifacts. True, efficiency is not high enough yet. We achieved best results with artifact "Moonlight". Bring us a sample for further experiments.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5">
    <text>Get "Urchin"</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_descr">
    <text>Scientists need artifact "Urchin" to improve suits.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_artefact_5_text">
    <text>You probably know that our suits possess the best protection from radiation. The secret is that we impregnate them with essence from a special, quite rare, artifact. For manufacturing the next batch of suits we need such an artifact. You call it "Urchin".</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1">
    <text>Bring a unique suit</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Bring an unusual suit from underground laboratory X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_find_item_1_text">
    <text>We have business for you. We recently hired a stalker to penetrate inside the laboratory. Even then I noticed his unusual suit, it gave off tangible heat. The stalker said this suit heals wounds by itself. Basically, the stalker didn't return from the laboratory. No! Don't think we have anything to do with it! And his suit is probably still lying there. I would with pleasure receive it for study.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring a snork foot</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Getting a snork fragment in these parts is not a problem.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>We met Semenov when I was reading lectures on genetics at the university, and he was my student. So I became his scientific supervisor. Back then we were only slightly opening the veil of secrecy of genome modification. What am I about? Ah, yes. For genetic research we will need samples of fresh muscle tissue cells of a snork. For gene material you will have to go to the swamps. There is a hypothesis that snorks as a species are a new step of human evolution. To know for sure, need a DNA sample!</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2">
    <text>Get a flesh eye</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Find a flesh eye for eggheads.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Good news, young man: we have a very interesting task for you! I think you, as a thinking personality possessing sufficient life experience, will appreciate the whole revolutionary nature of my colleagues' idea. The fact is that research showed: eyes of creatures called in common parlance flesh, are equipped - are you listening carefully - with olfactory receptors! Thus, they not only see with eyes, but also smell with them! We are preparing for an operation to transplant this eye to one of... our volunteer assistants. I believe a real furor awaits us! But we need a donor organ. Will you help us?</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3">
    <text>Get a boar hoof</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_descr">
    <text>Bring a boar hoof to scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_3_text">
    <text>Greetings to you... uh... wanderer! Glad you decided to visit us: we just need a person to participate in a very important experiment. Colleague Benter wants to try to cook something edible from local fauna for a practical experiment on researching the influence of mutated protein on human organisms. For now we decided to stop on boars. We need a ham. Boar leg, you understand? If you take this case, I ask you, choose a well-fed individual.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4">
    <text>Find a pseudodog tail</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_descr">
    <text>Provide scientists with a pseudodog tail for experiments.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_4_text">
    <text>Hello, colleague! We still can't solve the mechanism of amazing properties observed in pseudodogs, so decided to change the vector of our search. This time we start from the end... Why are you smiling? What makes you so... ah, yes. I seem to understand. You see, young man, we need the tail of this creature, located at the end... yes, at the end of the body. We were not talking about reproductive organs of this mammal at all! For them, possibly, you will have to take a walk next time.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5">
    <text>Get a bloodsucker jaw</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_descr">
    <text>Get a bloodsucker jaw for scientists.</text>
</string>
<string id="ecolog_monster_part_5_text">
    <text>Oh, stalker, glad to see you! Listen... You have already encountered bloodsuckers in your travels, right? If not, we would like for this to happen. As soon as you can, bring us the lower jaw of a representative of this species - and with all, so to speak, cutlery. Unfortunately, can't initiate you into details of the experiment... possibly, it will negatively affect the stability of your psyche. We will wait.</text>
</string>
<string id="eliminate_lager">
    <text>Camp destruction</text>
</string>
<string id="find_item">
    <text>Find an item</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1">
    <text>Beat off mercenary attack</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Help stalker camp fight off attackers near military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_1_text">
    <text>There is a group of stalkers, living near military warehouses. Normal guys, understand that the Zone is a place of freedom, that laws are generally not applicable here, and one must just live right, by own morality. And so they are thinking now whether to join us or not, yes. Need to help them fight off mercenaries, huh? And we'll throw you some equipment.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2">
    <text>Defend the Barrier</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Defend the Barrier near military warehouses from monsters.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_defend_lager_2_text">
    <text>Monsters are pushing from the Scorcher side again. Help the guys at the Barrier to fight off. I guarantee a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Destroy military camp</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Destroy military camp near Agroprom Research Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>Military is systematically seizing the Zone. We need to slow down this process, otherwise the Zone will turn into a scientific-research zoo. One of the military camps is located near "Agroprom" Research Institute. If you manage to clean this place, it will help at least slow down the seizure of the Zone by military.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Destroy mercenary outpost</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Clear mercenary outpost near warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>Listen. The deal is that we need to deal with the mercenary outpost. Could have left them alone, they know how to shoot well... only they became insolent beyond measure - climbing onto our territory, trying to bribe my people. Time to teach them a lesson. How about it, will you do it?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Destroy Duty group</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>Clear Duty fighter group at Rostok factory.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>How about hunting a little? A squad of Duty cleaners appeared at Rostok factory. There is a good chance to arrange a surprise for them. Duty constantly sends out their guys to run after monsters, and under the noise kill anyone they don't like. Need to destroy this group, otherwise soon Duty will finally hook onto the factory. Shouldn't be many people there: three-four veterans plus a couple of rookies.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3">
    <text>Bring a bulletproof vest</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3_descr">
    <text>Bring a new model army bulletproof vest.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_find_item_3_text">
    <text>Some of the military got new model bulletproof vests. Inner lining of these things is impregnated with some healing ointment, or something... basically, shallow wounds heal like on a dog. And imagine what luck: recently a dozen soldiers in such vests rushed to Yantar, and six returned on their own feet and three more on their shoulders. Get it? One remained there. If you get his vest, we'll figure it out and make such for ourselves too.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill Duty security chief</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Kill the Duty security chief, trying to do it as quietly as possible.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>It would be good if the Duty security chief quietly disappeared. Then they will have a little mess, and I can infiltrate several guys into their faction. Or even, what the hell... okay, won't get my hopes up ahead of time. I advise you to process the client from afar and quietly, without raising noise.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill Captain Ivantsov</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Kill the assistant of the Duty leader, Captain Ivantsov.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>The task is difficult, I warn you immediately, but it is worth it. Need to punish Ivantsov - there is such a henchman of this Duty commander. Engaged in the dirtiest work: punitive expeditions, raids... If you knew how many of our guys he hanged! Time to deal with this trash once and for all. If you decide to do it, I advise you to arm yourself well first thing.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill Colonel Petrenko</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Kill Colonel Petrenko - one of the founding fathers of the Duty faction.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>Colonel Petrenko... I don't know if you heard this name, met him or not, but it would be good for you to meet. This man is one of the founders of Duty and one of our most terrible enemies. Try to make your conversation end quickly... for him. Can you handle it?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Destroy a neutral</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Find and destroy a neutral stalker.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>There is a man, hanging around nearby here. He pulled such a trick, he shot one of ours once. And such things cannot be forgiven. Taking the case? We'll pay, don't worry.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill a Duty commander</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>Destroy one of the Duty commanders.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>I pay for the head of anyone from Duty leadership! Kill him - come back for the reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6">
    <text>Kill Scarecrow</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_descr">
    <text>Kill the stalker nicknamed Scarecrow.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_6_text">
    <text>We destroy monsters, only for us it is a question of survival, not profit. Mutant populations are not so numerous; besides, they are also living beings, so we cannot allow their complete destruction. Some individuals do not understand this. A clear example: there is a stalker, called Scarecrow. He got his nickname not just like that, but because he got the hang of making stuffed animals for sale from these poor fellows. We warned him, only to no avail. Will you do a good deed for Mother Earth?</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7">
    <text>Kill Barin</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_descr">
    <text>Kill the stalker nicknamed Barin.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_kill_stalker_7_text">
    <text>Boor, sycophant, hypocrite, coward... he is also stalker Barin. As you see, a man of wonderful spiritual qualities, which helped him climb into the upper echelons of Duty. Now he deals with providing the faction with supplies and food, although from time to time he still participates in raids. Need to get rid of him... especially since almost all Duty connections regarding supplies are tied specifically to Barin.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1">
    <text>Boar for dinner</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Bring a boar leg.</text>
</string>
<string id="freedom_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>We have a festive dinner planned here in honor of Bob Marley's birthday. You, brother, get us a tastier boar leg, eh? Or better two! Jah won't forget you!..</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager">
    <text>Destroy bloodsucker lair</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_descr">
    <text>Clear bloodsucker lair in the village near military warehouses.</text>
</string>
<string id="hunter_eliminate_lager_text">
    <text>Have you met a bloodsucker? Horror, right? And I recently went to the village near military warehouses, thought to get rich with artifacts. And imagine - I see a bloodsucker, a black one, all in scars. Sitting over a corpse, doesn't see me. I got scared and ran away from there... I ran in vain, he heard me and chased me, and immediately such a howl rose around... then I realized he wasn't alone. I think they have a lair there. If you could drive them away from there, I would give you one rare artifact that I found a couple of days ago.</text>
</string>
<string id="kill_stalker">
    <text>Kill a stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker">
    <text>Destroy the traitor</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>Baldy asks to kill a stalker who ran away with very rare artifacts.</text>
</string>
<string id="lisiy_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>I recently went for artifacts with one stalker, searched near the Scorcher itself. Found so much, even found a couple of artifacts I've never seen before at all, even in photographs. So this son of a bitch set me up. At the last overnight stay he slipped away somewhere and stashed the most expensive artifacts. And also told me lies, like, they disappeared themselves. And a couple of days ago I saw one of those very rare artifacts at Barkeep's. And such anger took me... Anyway, stalker, if you can find him - give him a lead greeting from me. Or maybe you'll find out where his stashes are and find the second artifact. It's worth it, believe me.</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker">
    <text>Kill a master stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>For killing each master, the mercenary is ready to pay well. The fewer masters, the easier for mercenaries.</text>
</string>
<string id="mercenary_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>We are not interested in having walking tanks wandering the Zone: heavily armed stalkers in exoskeletons. Work becomes only harder and more dangerous from this. And the fewer of them - the better for us. Kill one such - get a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="monster_part">
    <text>Obtain a monster body part</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker">
    <text>Destroy Freedom fighter</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_descr">
    <text>One stalker, a former Dutyer, who knew a lot of information about important objects in Pripyat, recently defected to Freedom, need to kill him before he blabs too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="petrenko_kill_stalker_text">
    <text>Listen here. We have maps of Pripyat. Not modern ones, but old, military ones, made in the early nineties. The most important thing on them is the designation of all military objects: underground warehouses, bomb shelters. Now there is little use from this, of course, but if we suddenly find a road to Pripyat - this information will become priceless. The problem is this. One of the officers defected to Freedom, and he knew about this information. Anyway, need to destroy him before he blabs too much.</text>
</string>
<string id="return_for_reward">
    <text>Return for reward</text>
</string>
<string id="return_for_reward_bring">
    <text>Bring the promised item to the customer</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item">
    <text>Find an improved suit</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item_descr">
    <text>Nimble told about a bandit stash where they hid loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="shustriy_find_item_text">
    <text>While sitting in captivity, heard bandits talking about their stash where they put loot. Heard they hid a cool jacket there, and the next day some monster took a fancy to their stash for itself. So fancied it that they are afraid to go there now. Bring me the suit, be a friend, and I'll pay you.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_has_no_job">
    <text>Can't offer anything right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_ask">
    <text>And what do you want to talk about?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_complete">
    <text>Well done, deserved a reward!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_job_what">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_barman_list_job">
    <text>Look what we have today:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1">
    <text>Cover Duty squad</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Cover Duty squad from bandit attack in Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_defend_camp_1_text">
    <text>Still, I finally managed to hammer into the thick heads of Dutyers that it's high time to clear the Garbage from bandits... And Duty will expand its territory, and my regular clients will be spoiled less often. Well, anyway, the thing is that Duty command decided to cut off the influx of bandits from the Dark Valley for a start. They sent out, you know, a barrier squad and discovered that bandits are not happy about this. Who would have thought! So what I'm getting at - would you help the fighters consolidate at the entrance to the Dark Valley, eh? I will reward worthily.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_has_no_job">
    <text>No tasks right now.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_ask">
    <text>What do you want to discuss?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_complete">
    <text>Good job! Task completed.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_job_what">
    <text>Listening.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_dolg_list_job">
    <text>There are tasks:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_drunk_dolg_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_has_no_job">
    <text>Sorry, nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_ask">
    <text>Regarding which task would you like to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_complete">
    <text>You handled the task perfectly! Allow me to present you a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_job_what">
    <text>I am listening to You.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_ecolog_list_job">
    <text>I can offer you the following:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1">
    <text>Destroy bandit camp</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_descr">
    <text>Clear bandits at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_1_text">
    <text>Recently bandits multiplied like dirt, preventing honest people from trading... So: blow to the Garbage - I was informed that these scum settled not far from the vehicle graveyard. You'll sort it out on the spot - everyone will thank you, well and a worthy reward from me won't be delayed. Agreed?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2">
    <text>Bandit camp at ATP</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy bandits at the factory.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_2_text">
    <text>Bandits clustering at ATP again. Already guessed what the task will be? Then... legs in hands - and forward. As soon as you pass our common hot greeting to them, come back - I will reward. Deal?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3">
    <text>Bandits near Agroprom Institute</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_descr">
    <text>Destroy bandits near Agroprom Institute.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_3_text">
    <text>A bandit squad appeared under the institute at Agroprom, preventing my diggers from collecting junk... Solve the problem - something will be due from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4">
    <text>Clear the area</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_descr">
    <text>Destroy mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_4_text">
    <text>There is a matter, not very heavy. They want to bring a foreign tourist to me here. He threw some money to my pals to look at the Zone. Well and where they will lead him, need to clean the area from mutants. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5">
    <text>Eliminate two bandits at the Garbage</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_descr">
    <text>Make the passage to one of the best places in the Zone free.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_5_text">
    <text>Recently one of the best places in the Zone became inaccessible for lovers of the beautiful. At the Garbage... Uh-huh, exactly at the Garbage there is a nook in which you forget about dirt, about money, about blood... Or rather, used to forget. Because now two dirty ugly mugs sit there, threatening to bleed anyone who doesn't pay them for visiting this edge. Eliminate them, I have nowhere to lead tourists.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6">
    <text>Kill bloodsucker</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_descr">
    <text>Destroy bloodsucker in the Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_eliminate_camp_6_text">
    <text>They say military left the Dark Valley. And after that monsters poured out from all cracks. Stalkers already saw a bloodsucker there, moreover an unusual one - it's not afraid of open spaces. Basically, when the rumor reaches scientists, they will definitely want to research this bloodsucker. And I want to be the person who sells the corpse to scientists. Your task is to kill the bloodsucker, and then I take everything on myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Find "Jellyfish"</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Jellyfish".</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>One person from the Big Land ordered "Jellyfish" from me. Work is not dusty, and money not big, but you'll turn around quickly. Agree!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Find "Stone Flower"</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Find artifact "Stone Flower".</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>There is a task for "Stone Flower". From jewelers, by the way. So let's not upset beautiful ladies, eh? Get it - fee and a bottle on me, to drink for their health...</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Find "Night Star"</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Find "Night Star" - a rare and expensive artifact.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>There is one little task... somewhat unpleasant. Seems from the military - they are engaged in developing new means of protection. So, an order came for "Night Star". This is a rare artifact, it can protect from bullets quite well... So do you take it? Paying well!..</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Find "Meat Chunk"</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Find wound healing artifact "Meat Chunk".</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>There is an order for an artifact, need one that can heal wounds, called "Meat Chunk"! They have a clinic or something. Get it - get money yourself and help people.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1">
    <text>Find improved Fort 12</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1_descr">
    <text>Last known owner - commander of the checkpoint under the ruined bridge.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_find_item_1_text">
    <text>Eh, such a stupid fashion for fancy weapons started, no one wants to shoot from ordinary ones anymore, even rookies!.. Basically, there is an order for one improved gun. According to rumors, the commander of the military, who collect money for passage under the bridge, has a Fort 12 with a fat magazine. Will you get it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_has_no_job">
    <text>No work right now...</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_ask">
    <text>What do you want to discuss?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_complete">
    <text>Well, good job, good job! Work for an A - hold the earnings.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_job_what">
    <text>What is it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_freedom_list_job">
    <text>Here look what we have:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_hunter_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_nothing">
    <text>No, nothing. Another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_completed">
    <text>I completed this task.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_job_refuse">
    <text>I refuse to perform this task.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1">
    <text>Kill bandit leader</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_descr">
    <text>Most likely to find him at the Garbage.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_1_text">
    <text>You'll have to finish off one handsome guy - he is one of the main ones among bandits. Recently bandits by his order intercepted my courier and gutted him to zero, and conversation is short with those who touch my people... Anyway, do the deed - I won't remain in debt. So how about it, take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2">
    <text>Kill trader stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_descr">
    <text>Destroy a stalker... Yes, not the best job of all.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_2_text">
    <text>I had some disagreements with one trader. Well, he doesn't want to work with me, to hell with him! Only won't allow spreading vile rumors. Basically, need to end him, so others don't get loose. So they know who is the boss here...</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3">
    <text>Kill rookie stalker</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_descr">
    <text>Finish off a rookie stalker, who, maybe, isn't a rookie at all.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_3_text">
    <text>There is one here, keeps hanging around, pretends to be a rookie, only he is somehow strange... Anyway, if he disappears unnoticed, it will be a good favor to me. Understand what I mean?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4">
    <text>Kill Demon</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_descr">
    <text>Eliminate one of Sidorovich's trade competitors</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_4_text">
    <text>Demon, aka Oleg Gusarov... former special forces. As long as he didn't meddle in other people's business, I had no complaints about him - a loner is a loner. Only someone told me here, Demon is gathering people to crush Cordon under himself and rake in the transfer of loot from the Zone. And this is already a serious problem, and it needs to be solved quickly. Taking the order?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5">
    <text>Kill Father Diodor</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_descr">
    <text>Kill the man preaching in the Zone against artifact collection and trading them.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_5_text">
    <text>I always said: business and religion are two parallel occupations, they can't even intersect closely, and in each other's affairs no-no!.. Only this father, God forgive, Diodor... hmm... well, he can't understand this simple truth. Keeps raving that gathering artifacts, and especially trading them corrupts people to the sinful path not only in the Zone, but in the whole world... well and all in such spirit. He, you understand, calls to destroy artifacts altogether - huh?! Just imagine what he thought up!.. Worst thing, some start falling for the ravings. I approached this Diodor in every possible way, and he keeps bending his line. The deal is: you send him upstairs for an audience... got it, yes? And I give you some solid artifact. So, shake hands?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6">
    <text>Kill "sales representative"</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_descr">
    <text>Kill "sales representative". Trader watches his reputation.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_kill_stalker_6_text">
    <text>Imagine, some weirdo hangs around nearby, introduces himself as my sales representative, uses my reputation, you see, and then pushes substandard goods! Broken guns, falling apart armor, expired canned food... I already had a couple of showdowns with dissatisfied people here. In short, I need a person who will communicate with the "sales representative". Up to substandard condition.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_lisiy_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_mercenary_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring bloodsucker jaw</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Bloodsucker tooth attracts luck? Let's see if the bloodsucker gets lucky.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>Heard the belief that a bloodsucker tooth attracts luck? As if anomalies let go of one who wears such a tooth on the neck, and artifacts come into hands themselves? Basically, it's all bullshit, but there are blockheads who believe and are ready to pay good money. Bring a bloodsucker jaw, I'll pay you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2">
    <text>Get pseudodog tail</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Drag in a pseudodog tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>Winter is coming. And what do women in the Big Land like to wear in winter? Correct! They like to wear furs. So a new fashion started, to make various accessories from pseudodog tails. The fur there is somewhat special! In short, there is an order for such a tail. Will you take it?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_petrenko_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_reward_job">
    <text>I am about the task.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_abandon">
    <text>These tasks are not interesting to me.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_no">
    <text>Another time.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_yes">
    <text>I take it.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_job_reward">
    <text>What do I get for this?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_seek_new_job">
    <text>I need work. Anything in mind?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the small fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_shustriy_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_trader_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_wolf_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_zastava_commander_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1">
    <text>Destroy boar lair</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_descr">
    <text>Clear boar lair next to Wolf's stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_1_text">
    <text>Um, my friend and I had a stash not far from here exactly behind the ATP, trees grow thicker there... Recently boars made a lair there. And it turns out we can't get to our stash now. Help - kill the boars, and I will thank you for myself and for my friend.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2">
    <text>Destroy mutants at the farm</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_descr">
    <text>Wolf asks to clear the farm from mutants.</text>
</string>
<string id="wolf_eliminate_lager_2_text">
    <text>Although this is the border of the Zone, it's hard for rookies even here. Bandits are half the trouble, they at least understand human language. But mutants - it's very bad with them. Set up a lair at the abandoned farm, occupied the only good place for a transit camp. If you can clear the farm of mutants - something is due from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager">
    <text>Clear dog lair</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_descr">
    <text>Near the southern outpost at the Bar a pack of dogs settled.</text>
</string>
<string id="zastava_commander_eliminate_lager_text">
    <text>Despite our efforts, some monsters still break through from the Garbage side. Yes, you probably saw yourself the pack of dogs to the south of us. Kill them - get a reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="defend_lager">
    <text>Camp defense</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1">
    <text>Bring "Slime".</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Slime" for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_1_text">
    <text>Strelok, scientists ordered one quite rare artifact from us: "Slime". Finding it will not be simple. So if you take it, I'll reward normally.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2">
    <text>Bring "Slug".</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Slug" for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_2_text">
    <text>Strelok! Scientists ordered an artifact from us again. But, true, now artifact "Slug". Conditions same: find the needed artifact, get some stuff.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3">
    <text>Bring "Crystal".</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Crystal" for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_3_text">
    <text>Help out, Strelok! Scientists sat on the neck again! Give them artifact "Crystal"! And where to get it? Find it - I won't remain in debt. Reward corresponding!</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4">
    <text>Bring "Battery".</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4_descr">
    <text>Get artifact "Battery" for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_find_artefact_4_text">
    <text>Opa, Strelok! Just in time! Just have business for you. There is an order for one artifact. Sakharov lately became completely insolent, demands only the best, and good artifacts don't just lie on the road. Basically, need to find artifact "Battery". Bring it, won't regret. Will pay generously.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2">
    <text>Bring cat tail.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2_descr">
    <text>Get cat tail for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_2_text">
    <text>There is something in mind, yes... A request for a local cat tail arrived from the "Big Land". From a familiar artist. He visited us once to "paint a place full of decadent charm". We, of course, didn't let him out of the territory, but what there was, he painted notably. So, he claims that from the wool of these very cats very decent pile for brushes is obtained. I, of course, understand, dangerous business, these beasts don't roam alone, but... money is money. And you seem not a rookie anymore. So how about it, Strelok, will you take such a thing?</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1">
    <text>Bring tushkano head.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1_descr">
    <text>Get tushkano head for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_1_text">
    <text>Work, you say? There is work. Here Sakharov invited one foreign tourist to the zone. Well, it's customary. Need some souvenir from the Zone for this tourist. So, you bring me a tushkano head, and my guys will make a stuffed animal from it. We'll shove it to this tourist as a souvenir.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3">
    <text>Bring poltergeist eye.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3_descr">
    <text>Get poltergeist eye for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_3_text">
    <text>Greetings, stalker. Basically, a poltergeist eye was urgently needed on the "Big Land". Preferably undamaged. I know, Strelok, that you are an experienced stalker, seen a lot, so, I think, you will cope with such a task. Reward is worthy. Well, and if you don't want to, say immediately. Won't force.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4">
    <text>Bring chimera claw.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4_descr">
    <text>Get chimera claw for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_4_text">
    <text>Tasks, you say? There is a task and just in your line. Met chimeras in the Zone? Here, look how this beast looks. What am I leading to... Work appeared. Good, monetary. Need, means, a claw from this beauty for us. So how about it, like the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5">
    <text>Bring controller hand.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5_descr">
    <text>Sviblov needed a controller hand for some reason.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_5_text">
    <text>Ahem... Strelok? Could you get me a controller hand? You see, lately my headaches worsened, migraine tortured. So, Sakharov threw me a recipe here. Well, all ingredients are present, but no controller hand. You get it for me, please. And I will settle with you well.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6">
    <text>Bring pseudogiant hand.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6_descr">
    <text>Get pseudogiant hand for Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="nebo_monster_part_6_text">
    <text>There is a task and not an easy one. Will have to sweat. Ready, you say? Basically, scientists made an order for a pseudogiant hand. What, you say? Leg? And the devil knows what it is! Basically, what he walks with. Enterprise is serious, pays very well. But note, pseudogiant is an extremely dangerous beast. I already sent two, they barely crawled back. And you are a serious stalker, know your capabilities. What do you say?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_has_no_job">
    <text>Nothing at the moment.</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_ask">
    <text>About which task do you want to talk?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_complete">
    <text>Task completed... and here is the fee!</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_job_what">
    <text>And what's with the task?</text>
</string>
<string id="tm_nebo_list_job">
    <text>There is something:</text>
</string>
<string id="first_talk_charon">
    <text>I'll talk to Charon. Perhaps he will have tasks for me.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_need_stalker_infidels">
    <text>I need to help clear CNPP-2 of "infidels" who have penetrated the territory. We cannot allow just anyone to walk around the territory of the Chernobyl NPP. Then talk to Solomon and report to Charon.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_snork_leg_feet">
    <text>Find 8 snork feet for one of Solomon's guards.</text>
</string>
<string id="dyak_help_sexton">
    <text>On the way to Pripyat, I was stopped by Deacon - a former bandit who was lucky enough to find the light of the Monolith. He asked me to help clear the territory of "infidel" military. I'm on my way anyway, so I must help my brothers.</text>
</string>
<string id="mathon_naem_mercs">
    <text>I must help my brothers clear the central square of Pripyat from mercenary forces. Talk to Makhon and Charon afterwards.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_spy_interrogate">
    <text>This spy will regret deciding to step on holy ground! Need to interrogate him, and then talk to Deacon.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_help_ghost">
    <text>I need to rescue an "infidel" named Ghost from the clutches of mercenaries, and then escort him to a safe place. Also worth telling everything to Paramedic.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_help_paramedic">
    <text>Talk to Paramedic.</text>
</string>
<string id="haron_talk_charon">
    <text>Return to Charon.</text>
</string>
<string id="doc_talk_paramedic">
    <text>Meet and talk to Paramedic.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_kill_ghost">
    <text>I received an order to kill Ghost. Well, I'm surprised I wasn't assigned to do this earlier.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_zachita_ghost">
    <text>That's how fate turned! Need to get to Ghost and help him fight back.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_lucash_help_seize">
    <text>Freedomers asked me to help retake the base from the military. Most likely I'll have to sweat, as there are decent amount of soldiers there. \nIt is important that Lukash and Cap remain alive, otherwise everything will be in vain. Perhaps it will be easier if I mow down at least part of the military before the Freedom squad arrives.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_vstrecha_meet">
    <text>Meet and talk to Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_osvedomitel_find">
    <text>Snitch asked me to find a "special" folder at the Freedom base. What's in it - I don't need to know. It should be well hidden, so I'll have to crawl around.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_krovosos_super">
    <text>Sviblov told that a local bloodsucker is terrorizing his squad. It has eaten so much that they haven't been able to kill it yet, and it still hangs around somewhere in the far part of the base. Sviblov asked to kill it and drag it to him so he can make a stuffed animal out of it. What an idea - to put such a monstrosity somewhere for beauty.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_predatel_catch">
    <text>A rat appeared in Sviblov's squad. It is not yet clear who exactly, but Sviblov has a plan: He told everyone in the squad that he organized a stash. I need to take a position by the rocks, and meet the reptile there. Then need to tell Sviblov about the meeting.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_help_lefty">
    <text>Bes needed another gun to storm the mercenary base. Heard that Lefty should be there, so there is my interest here too.</text>
</string>
<string id="sveeblov_lab_x10">
    <text>Find documents and a flash drive in laboratory X-10, and take them to Sviblov.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_need_outfit_lefty">
    <text>Lefty doesn't mind working for Lukash, but requested a whole mercenary scientific suit for it. What demands! Will have to slash mercs, take the suit off a corpse and repair it if needed. Heard that Borov has the same one for sale.</text>
</string>
<string id="lucash_need_levsha_lefty">
    <text>Lukash asked me to find Lefty and persuade him to join Freedom. Not an easy task, but the reward will be appropriate.</text>
</string>
<string id="saha_help_prince">
    <text>Met a stalker in the Bar, called Sakhaty. He told that bandits locked his buddies in prison... Do bandits have a prison? Anyway, need to talk to Prince, and we'll see from there.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_speak_meet">
    <text>Meet and talk to Bes.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_zadan_prince">
    <text>Wow, the story with these friends of Sakhaty got twisted! Had to agree to search for Prince's gun. He agreed to release Sakhaty's friends in exchange for the weapon and money. \nWhat a sly one, this Sakhaty! Dumped everything on me. Hope the reward will be generous, otherwise I'll definitely punch him.</text>
</string>
<string id="dolg_leader_help_duty">
    <text>Need to help Sergeant Plichko from Duty kill bandits. Then report to General Voronin about the results.</text>
</string>
<string id="semeckii_treasure_seven">
    <text>There are rumors that Semetsky, the Legend of the Zone, has a rich stash! Rumors are supported by a map fragment that was divided into several parts. Maybe it's just a tale, but I can't miss such an opportunity. After all, if Semetsky is truly immortal, surely he managed to collect a lot of interesting things!</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_dolg_force">
    <text>I need to find Zheka, Prince's debtor. He should be at the Garbage. Kill him or spare him - doesn't matter. The main thing is to get the money by any means and give it to Prince.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_plan_grass">
    <text>Prince asked me to find a bag of "grass" for him. It should be lying somewhere on the territory of the army warehouses... He said that if I can't find it myself, scientists might help with the search. But they will surely ask for something in return for info.</text>
</string>
<string id="agro_varayg_one_laps">
    <text>Varyag throws a challenge: Need to go through four circles of hell through the Agroprom underground with only a knife. As far as I heard, not a single stalker has been able to do this yet.</text>
</string>
<string id="bes_patron_demon">
    <text>Need to help Bes exchange with Colonel Petrenko from Duty: Two modified rifles in exchange for a crate of ammo.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_racia_radio">
    <text>Sobolev gave me a radio station, through which he will be able to talk to an old friend. Heavy, damn it! When I'm in the Red Forest, will need to pass the station to Zakhar. Sure he will be very glad.</text>
</string>
<string id="doronin_help_dorodina">
    <text>A traitor appeared among scientists - Docent Dorodin. Sakharov said that Dorodin knows too much, and is ready to sell their joint works for good money. Need to get to the Dark Valley and take a good position where I can quickly eliminate him without unnecessary noise. I was also warned that another scientist will be with him. According to Sakharov, he doesn't play a big role in all this, so he can be left alive. However, they will be in identical suits with Dorodin, so it depends on luck.</text>
</string>
<string id="dan_zombi_clear">
    <text>Dan asked to get rid of zombies, which became too many on the territory, next to X-16. They don't let security and scientists sleep with their howling and screams, so Dan didn't spare a grenade launcher for me! With it, the business should go both faster and more fun.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_snork_clear">
    <text>Too many mutants bred next to X-18. General Voronin asked me to deal with them.</text>
</string>
<string id="voronin_nychka_bandits">
    <text>General Voronin needs the contents of a bandit stash. According to him, there is a bandit nicknamed Zhila, who doesn't mind assisting. Need to meet with him and chat about the stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="esc_tolik_find_tolik">
    <text>I must find Tolik and talk to him.</text>
</string>
<string id="volk_podmoga_loner">
    <text>Wolf's group needs help. Need to find loner stalkers, they should help.</text>
</string>
<string id="derevna_stalker_bandits">
    <text>Bandits went completely nuts - occupied the Rookie Village! Need to help retake it, and then talk to Wolf.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_art_heart">
    <text>Kruglov told about a rare artifact called "Controller's Heart". One can find such only with the help of a special detector. Search should start from Agroprom, somewhere in the swamp.</text>
</string>
<string id="informator_trade_semeckii_crystal">
    <text>Turned out that Snitch heard about Semetsky's map. Moreover, he is ready to help me with the search for the remaining fragments! Not for free, of course: In exchange for fragments he asked to bring Bengal Crystal Soul. Not such a big price for the stash of the Zone Legend! Just need to cook it.</text>
</string>
<string id="kruglov_case_voronin">
    <text>I need to take the case for General Voronin, and then talk to Kruglov.</text>
</string>
<string id="knyaz_abakan_abakan">
    <text>Prince asked me to get a special Abakan with an integrated collimator. Seems General Voronin gave me a similar one...</text>
</string>
<string id="mil_klyak_help_fang">
    <text>Mercenaries attacked Fang. Need to help him fight them off, and then talk.</text>
</string>
<string id="freeman_turist_guide">
    <text>Turned out that rumors about the foreigner are true: Barkeep asked me to walk with the foreigner, whose name is Freeman. Walk with him around the neighborhood near the Rookie Village, and then return back and talk to Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_detec_artifacts">
    <text>Lefty agreed to fix the broken anomaly detector. According to him, it should track anomalies and show them. But for this will require getting "Mica", "Crystal", "Goldfish", "Soul", "Ruby Spring" and "Flash".</text>
</string>
<string id="fanat_recept_artifact">
    <text>Fanat asked me to find 2 "Gold Chunk" artifacts for him. They are rare, so more often found in the north. Although sure that one can find closer too, if searching well.</text>
</string>
<string id="barman_speech_talk">
    <text>What the hell?! In the stash where Borov's courier's PDA was supposed to lie, turned out to be a trap! Good that it was crappy, otherwise would have definitely remained without hands. Need to return to Borov and tell about what happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_about_pda_meet">
    <text>Need to meet and talk to Ghost.</text>
</string>
<string id="monach_pda_destroy">
    <text>I needed to enter a house, in the bloodsucker village, but something didn't allow doing it, "spitting" me out. Turned out that a whole family of poltergeists settled in the village! What attracted them here? Doesn't matter. Need to kill them to enter the house without problems.</text>
</string>
<string id="about_graf_dialog_talk">
    <text>Need to meet and talk to Count.</text>
</string>
<string id="tsezar_second_dialog_pda">
    <text>Caesar handed me a PDA and documents that need to be taken to Count.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_four_dialog_fang">
    <text>Something serious is brewing. I must give the PDA to Fang and talk to him. Very important information should be stored in the PDA.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_outfit_dialog_lefty">
    <text>Need to bring Lefty the artifact "Fiery Soul".</text>
</string>
<string id="antikvar_first_dialog_antiques">
    <text>Find and bring 3 bottles of vodka to Antiquarian.</text>
</string>
<string id="bar_help_attack">
    <text>Need to fight off the mercenary attack on the bar.</text>
</string>

<string id="arc_haron_burer">
    <text>Charon gave a task to clear the lower floors from a Burer family. Says there should be about six of them there. And also necessary to find and return to Charon one device - "Decoder", which these beasts stole.</text>
</string>
<string id="arc_ohran_konservy">
    <text>One of the guards asked to bring him five cans of food. Promised to thank well.</text>
</string>
<string id="arc_ohran_pda">
    <text>One of the guards asked to bring him five PDAs. "Infidels" should have such.</text>
</string>
<string id="tri_keysa">
    <text>Solomon asked to find three cases on the territory of CNPP-2. He put marks on these cases in my PDA. Seems there shouldn't be big problems finding the first two, but regarding the location of the third case Solomon said that need to use teleports. There is a mark for this case too, but on which of the upper levels of the Sarcophagus to search for it, that is a question for now.</text>
</string>
<string id="bunker_nechist">
    <text>Charon sends to clear the Control Bunker from evil spirits. The entrance to the Bunker is somewhere not far from the first teleports.</text>
</string>
<string id="lekarstva_doctor">
    <text>Charon sends to Pripyat to pick up medicine from Doctor or his courier. Said to search somewhere in the stadium area.</text>
</string>
<string id="konservy_gastronom">
    <text>Solomon asked to find a crate with canned food in Pripyat, in the grocery store. I heard there is more than one grocery store in Pripyat. Will have to search. Besides this, he asked to find a container with medicines on the CNPP territory. To find this container, need to talk to Deacon first - he is the commander of the patrol squad at the CNPP.</text>
</string>
<string id="naemniki_pripyat">
    <text>Mercenaries occupied the base in Pripyat. I must get to Pripyat and meet with Makhon's group. We will definitely banish these "infidels"! \nCharon warned that Makhon is an important member of the brotherhood. He must not die during the assault.</text>
</string>
<string id="shema_bunker">
    <text>Necessary to go to CNPP again, into the Sarcophagus, and then into the Monolith Control Bunker for underground communication schematics for Ghost. He should show me the passage from Pripyat to the Swamps.</text>
</string>
<string id="posylka_solomon">
    <text>Solomon asked to send a package to the Big Land. For this need to talk to the trader at the Cordon named Barkeep.</text>
</string>
<string id="barier_zahvat">
    <text>Need to capture the Barrier at Warehouses, knocking out the military from there. Cap must remain alive. The task will be completed when Cap takes his place at the Barrier. Need not to lose sight of him.</text>
</string>
<string id="diggery_habar">
    <text>Snitch sends to carry loot to diggers at Radar: 5 medkits (ordinary), 5 sticks of sausage, 5 bottles of vodka and 5 cans of food. Everything must be transferred to them safe and sound.</text>
</string>
<string id="tolik_help">
    <text>Met stalker Tolik when ended up at the Cordon. Should help him get to the stalker camp at the abandoned factory near the bridge at the Cordon. Turned out that Cordon is full of mutants now, and he definitely won't cope alone.</text>
</string>
<string id="oruzhie_novichkam">
    <text>Wolf has a stash where six sets of guns and ammo lie, as well as a PDA. Need to bring the PDA to Wolf and distribute weapons to rookies.</text>
</string>
<string id="varyag_pogovoryt">
    <text>Need to find a stalker nicknamed Varyag somewhere at Agroprom and find out from him about documents from laboratory X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="stvol_na_baze_svobody">
    <text>Need to get a modified RG-6 grenade launcher for Petrenko at the Freedom base, converted for NATO M-209 round. Looks like will have to negotiate with the guard of the Freedom arsenal.</text>
</string>
<string id="trava_dlya_ohrannika">
    <text>To negotiate with the arsenal guard, need to get some grass for him. Seems again will have to go bowing to Prince at the Bar.</text>
</string>
<string id="infa_x-18">
    <text>Need to go to laboratory X-18, which is in Dark Valley, find at least some information for Fang there.</text>
</string>
<string id="infa_sidoru">
    <text>Fang asked to carry the laptop to Barkeep at the Cordon, which I brought him from X-16, and the Monolith flash drive from X-18.</text>
</string>
<string id="k_doctoru">
    <text>Well, go to Pripyat again! Need to find Paramedic, he needs help. Again these mercenaries, and Monolith... Won't go through Radar for sure, too dangerous path. Sidorovich said that Doctor can show the road to Pripyat, so will go visit an old acquaintance.</text>
</string>
<string id="v_bunker">
    <text>Paramedic said that I need to go to the Control Bunker once more. Apparently, in such a short time something very bad for all of us happened and need to find at least some opportunity to prevent the threat. There is no concrete information, so I will have to act according to the situation.</text>
</string>
<string id="valet_help">
    <text>Cross asked to help his pal nicknamed Jack. He got into a mess not far from the checkpoint at the Cordon. Need to find him somewhere there, before soldiers grab him, and help get out from the checkpoint.</text>
</string>
<string id="lapsha_nayti">
    <text>Need to find stalker Lapsha and kill him. For this one bro promised to give transmutation recipe "Giant's Little Brother". Lapsha, he says, was seen at the Garbage, not far from the transition to Dark Valley.</text>
</string>
<string id="infa_kuryer">
    <text>One person was supposed to come to Borov, a courier from the center with important information, and disappeared. No news from him for the second day already. Says that last time he was in touch from Dark Valley. In short, need to go to General Voronin, no one but him can help find the courier or what's left of him. In any case, need to try to find and bring Borov the information that the courier was carrying.</text>
</string>
<string id="proveryt_fabriku">
    <text>To find the trace of the missing courier, need to go to the abandoned factory, for reconnaissance. Voronin sent his people there recently, but they didn't return. Apparently, bandits killed them... Feel like will have to shoot again.</text>
</string>
<string id="pogovoryt_lukash">
    <text>Well. Information that the courier carried for Borov is gone. Now need to go to Pripyat to Ghost for a copy that might have been preserved with him. But no one from locals knows the road to Pripyat. There is hope that Freedomers might know the road. In short, need to go to Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="konteyner_radar">
    <text>For Lukash to tell how to pass to Pripyat, need to bring a container from Radar for him. Says a helicopter crashed there recently, on which scientists were transporting something. This something is in a metal container, and the container is highly radioactive. Well, nothing to be done. Will have to go to Radar into the dead forest, look for this glowing box and carry it to Lukash.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_pogovoryt">
    <text>Need to talk to Mervin. Charon said that he can be found here, in the Sarcophagus, next to the "Monolith".</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_pervoe">
    <text>Need to find the first manuscript with main commandments of the "Monolith" brotherhood and return back to Mervin with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_vtoroe">
    <text>Need to find the second manuscript with main commandments of the "Monolith" brotherhood and return back to Mervin with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_gostinitsa">
    <text>Charon sends to Mervin again. This time he is waiting for me in the hotel, in Pripyat, in room #26.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_tretye">
    <text>Need to find the third manuscript with main commandments of the "Monolith" brotherhood and return back to Mervin with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_chetvyortoe">
    <text>Need to find the fourth manuscript with main commandments of the "Monolith" brotherhood and return back to Mervin with it.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervin_pyatoe">
    <text>Need to find the fifth manuscript with main commandments of the "Monolith" brotherhood and then go to the Sarcophagus to Charon.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_doc1">
    <text>Not far from the Bar, outside its territory, a chopper fell not so long ago. Where the chopper itself crashed - unknown. Somewhere there, at the end of this road, they just dropped boxes from it, which should still be lying there. Need to find this place and bring everything valuable that survived from there, so mercenaries don't get it. Most importantly, there should be accompanying documents in a fireproof case.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_prince">
    <text>Need to find Prince's stash at Warehouses, somewhere in a ravine, near a rusty helicopter. Take the gun from there and carry to Prince. Prince is hiding at Radar, somewhere in an abandoned tunnel, where the blocked entrance to the old bunker is. There was also a small military base there before.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_doc2">
    <text>Need to find the second part of documents for Count. Place where to search for docs, at the old checkpoint, practically behind the territory of warehouses. It's not far from the bloodsucker village there. Also Prince said that several boxes survived, some weapon should remain safe there. Mercs didn't manage to take it - rushed in pursuit of him. If I find anything, can take for myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_tsezar">
    <text>Count sends to meet Caesar at Yantar, in the scientists' bunker. Preliminary need to find Caesar's three flash drives with mercenary codes so he can decrypt the obtained information. Flash drives lie in three stashes on the Bar territory, somewhere in the inner courtyard.</text>
</string>
<string id="graf_doc3">
    <text>Necessary to find the third part of documents for Count at Yantar, in the outer courtyard of laboratory complex X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="hleb_skryage">
    <text>Skinflint asked to bring him 10 loaves of rye bread, which only one person nicknamed Baker bakes in the Zone. To find Baker, need to go to trader Sidorovich, who lives on the territory of Glubokoe station, and ask him about Baker.</text>
</string>
<string id="keys_skryage">
    <text>Skinflint asked to find out about the fate of a courier named Shuttle, who was carrying an important package for him from the Big Land. He disappeared a few days ago in the Wild Territory. Shuttle was last in touch three days ago. Since then neither hide nor hair from him. Have to find Shuttle or what's left of him. And most importantly, return the case with the package to Skinflint. Last time Shuttle was in touch from Rostok. This is uninhabited Wild Territory. People disappear there constantly. Said he looked for a place for a halt for the night in some secluded spot and that's it, after that disappeared. Will have to dig through entire Rostok, but find the case and some information about Shuttle.</text>
</string>
<string id="meshki_muka">
    <text>Need to find five sacks of flour for Baker in the bloodsucker village at Army Warehouses. Sacks, most likely, were dragged by bloodsuckers to different secluded places. Will have to search carefully.</text>
</string>
<string id="yaschik_pekar">
    <text>Need to find and bring Baker's box with spare parts for the stove from Agroprom to Baker. Where Baker hid the box, he himself doesn't remember exactly now. Says, made his way at night along the edge of the swamp, through reeds in the northern direction, and put it somewhere there. Thought, later soon returns and picks it up, but that's how it all turned out. Where he was carried from Agroprom now. In short, need to search more carefully in the swamp area.</text>
</string>
<string id="inkognito_agro">
    <text>Pathfinder sent to Agroprom to Incognito, who waits in a secret place somewhere in catacombs. Need to find the blocked entrance to catacombs not far from the northern building, and then Incognito will open the entrance.</text>
</string>
<string id="likvidator_nayti">
    <text>Need to get one very rare artifact for Pathfinder, called "Liquidator". Its only and main property is that when thrown on the ground, it destroys all known anomalies within a radius of 15 meters. This is a reusable artifact. It might be with a group of stalkers calling themselves "Railwaymen". Their leader is a stalker nicknamed Lector. To find these guys, need to go through a secret path that starts at the Rostok factory. Few know about this path. Need to look for it near the concrete fence, opposite the unfinished three-story building, right behind rails and wagons, between metal cabins. This path is one way only, will have to find the way back myself.</text>
</string>
<string id="lektor_help">
    <text>Lector asked in exchange for artifact "Liquidator" to help him: find a missing group of three people, led by Sledgehammer. These couriers carried 10 boxes of Antizombin and a Blowout Detector device. Need to look for them in a small forest, which is behind railway tracks, not far from the Railwaymen base. If cross behind the tracks and keep towards the wire mesh fence, so can get into that forest. Need to search every bush there, but find guys or what's left of them. And most importantly, bring what Lector asks.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_kabany">
    <text>Zveroboy reported where artifact "Liquidator" can be found and asked to help in one matter: destroy superboars at Rostok by the tunnel, which is not far from the transition to Yantar. In proof of completed work, necessary to bring Zveroboy three superboar hooves.</text>
</string>
<string id="zveroboy_shlemy">
    <text>Zveroboy asks to find and bring him three protective helmets of mercenaries. Need to look for them at Yantar, not far from the main entrance to laboratory complex X-16. Helmets are somewhere in the garage area, maybe a bit further. In the area where the pipe was laid, also can be. In short, will have to thoroughly climb all corners there. For this work promised to give a unique assault rifle, taken from a captured mercenary.</text>
</string>
<string id="potapov_mini">
    <text>Mechanic Potapov asked to find 7 parts of the manual for creating item 62, aka Gauss Rifle. \n\nOne part of the manual should be with the military in a stash on the Checkpoint territory at Cordon. The remaining six parts of the manual need to be taken from corpses of six stalkers, who "stole" this manual from under the very nose of the military, penetrating to their Base. \n\nUnfortunately, out of six daredevils no one survived. \nOne, having met with a small group of familiar stalkers, ran into a pack of hungry pseudodogs with them somewhere at the "Garbage". \nSecond decided to take cover in Agroprom undergrounds, perished there. \nThird climbed for some reason into laboratory X-18, which is in "Dark Valley". He didn't come out from there. \nFourth disappeared somewhere in the forest at Radar. He contacted, apparently before death itself, said he is hiding in some rocks. \nFifth reached as far as Pripyat. His trail is lost somewhere in the hotel area. \nSixth... He was chased longer than others. Wounded. He then sat out for some time with scientists at Yantar. Then, as wounds healed, went for scientists, as a sign of gratitude for treatment, to perform some task in laboratory X-16. But didn't return from there already, disappeared somewhere in labyrinths of X-16.</text>
</string>
<string id="lazarev_kvest">
    <text>Kruglov asks to find out what happened to lab assistant Lazarev, who left recently to Agroprom to the swamp, to conduct tests of a new device there, fixing the level and dynamics of anomalous activity growth. Second day no rumors from Lazarev, probably something happened.</text>
</string>
<string id="vypolzen_kvest">
    <text>Colonel Petrenko set a task to destroy Marsh Crawlers in Dark Valley at the swamp under the bridge. They say these beasts are very tenacious and shouldn't approach them close.</text>
</string>
<string id="izlom_kvest">
    <text>Lukash asks to clear the abandoned military checkpoint at Army Warehouses from a Fractures family. These monsters are extremely treacherous, though slow. Need to be extremely careful with them. Checkpoint in the western part of Warehouses, not far from bloodsucker village.</text>
</string>
<string id="solomon_pda">
    <text>Solomon asks to find his PDA, which he dropped in the eastern part of CNPP-2. Says that it won't be difficult to find - it lies somewhere on the asphalt path.</text>
</string>
<string id="doctor_rukzak">
    <text>Necessary to find a hidden backpack on Lenin Square, in the very center of Pripyat. In it, according to Paramedic, lie in special containers ampoules of "Adulin" - a powerful biochemical agent, which protects human psyche from various psi-influences for a long time. The backpack with its contents needs to be brought to Paramedic.</text>
</string>
<string id="snorki_kvest">
    <text>Necessary to destroy a pack of snorks in Pripyat, in the ferris wheel area.</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_vstrecha">
    <text>Need to meet with Illusionist, he waits in the hotel. Need to go up to the second floor, and there will wait in one of the rooms. I don't remember such a stalker...</text>
</string>
<string id="fokusnik_first">
    <text>Damn! How did he find me? Illusionist turned out to be Mervin, who is clearly not happy that I left the brotherhood. In exchange for freedom and things, he ordered me to kill Paramedic.</text>
</string>
<string id="mervina_ubity">
    <text>I'll have to kill Mervin to rid myself and others of danger. And then, can pick up my things and weapon from Ghost. He knows where Mervin's stash is and Paramedic will ask him to go there and take everything that Sorcerer stole from me.</text>
</string>
<string id="prizrak_dinamit">
    <text>Didn't expect this from Ghost. Is he seriously proposing me to go like this, without gear, and find dynamite? Oh I'll remember this to him...</text>
</string>

<string id="prizrak_suvenir">
    <text>Before crossing from Pripyat to Swamps, need to return to Ghost. He forgot to pass something from Doctor.</text>
</string>
<string id="levsha_find_groza">
    <text>To secure himself, Lefty requested "Groza" from me. Whole, so not a scratch, and also without any modifications.</text>
</string>

<string id="disk_svalka">
    <text>Need to bring Dan three disks with very valuable information. Disks were lost about five years ago, after the failure of the first scientific expedition to the Zone. Disks with results of analyses and observations of animal mutation were carried by two military from scientists' security, but ran into hungry mutants and were forced to flee, dropping all their equipment. The place where special forces dropped the backpack with provisions, in which lay the disks too, by their description looks most like the territory we now call Garbage. Landmark on terrain where to search - it's somewhere in ravines behind one of the garbage piles.</text>
</string>
<string id="klondayk_art">
    <text>To find out how to find artifact klondike, need to bring Lector one artifact - "Controller's Heart".</text>
</string>
<string id="snake_art">
    <text>To find artifact klondike in Dark Valley, need to find artifact "Snake Eye". As Lector said, can find it in the forest at Radar, not far from a small gap in barbed wire fence between two boulders.</text>
</string>
<string id="amulet_art">
    <text>Need to find five magic protective Amulets and sixth (catalyst) to catalyze the Charm, possessing unique protective properties taken from each of the five ordinal "progenitors" and doubled in degree of protection. \n\nDescription of Amulets (work only on belt): \n"Chimeron" - first order. 10% protection from electroshock and 10% protection from rupture. Slightly radioactive. \n\n"Dragon" - second order. 10% protection from burns, including chemical. Slightly radioactive. \n\n"Avalon" - third order. 10% protection from explosions and 10% bulletproofness. Slightly radioactive. \n\n"Sarkon" - fourth order. 15% protection from radiation. True, along with this, resistance to electroshock somewhat decreases. \n\n"Garganon" - fifth order. 15% protection from telepathic influence. Slightly radioactive. \n\n"Catalon" - Amulet-catalyst. Slightly radioactive. If placed together with collected amulets of all five previous orders on the belt, then a process of magical catalysis will occur and instead of six amulets one Amulet-Charm will appear, possessing doubled protective properties of all five ordinal amulets and with all this completely not radioactive. \n\nAs Wanderer said, one of the amulets was with an old digger who died somewhere in the center of Pripyat. Another amulet was with his partner who perished somewhere in catacombs of laboratory X-16. And another amulet was with some scammer whom bloodsuckers tore in the village at Army Warehouses. Nothing is known about other amulets.</text>
</string>
<string id="maroder_outfit">
    <text>To return my weapon and all things that marauders took away, need to find two protective armored suits SKAT-11M at Peacekeepers base and bring them safe and sound to Razuvaev - leader of the marauder gang. These suits should be searched for in the house at the entrance to the base. A mark is set on it. To not incur suspicion and anger of Peacekeepers, should get out of the base secretly - find another exit.</text>
</string>
<string id="maloy_mg">
    <text>Necessary to find a small gang of teenage marauders and pass them a proposal from Leila. Presumed location of marauders camp is marked on the map. In the end necessary to find out about marauder leader and agree so they leave the city.</text>
</string>