<string id="ls_header">
    <text>Tip</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_1">
    <text>To avoid dangerous situations, avoid being overweight. \nDon't forget to store loot in stashes, which can be backpacks, or sell items you don't need.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_2">
    <text>Hunting mutants is not only entertainment but also a way to earn money from trophies.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_3">
    <text>In rainy weather, if you are wearing a suit with a helmet, raindrops will interfere with your vision. You can wipe the helmet by pressing [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWIPE_MASK$$%c[default]] or disable this option in the graphics settings.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_4">
    <text>Over time, you will get tired and need rest. If you ignore fatigue, the consequences can be extremely dire.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_5">
    <text>The Zone territory is also patrolled from the air. If a faction has a helicopter, its members can request air support during combat.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_6">
    <text>To avoid pointing your weapon at neutral stalkers' faces without putting it away, you can lower it to the patrol position by pressing [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_WPN_LOWERED$$%c[default]].</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_7">
    <text>Repair kits for weapon and equipment care will help you maintain your gear in good condition when there is no opportunity or funds to visit a technician.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_8">
    <text>Backpacks can be found or bought, after which they can be used to create a personal stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_9">
    <text>To avoid digging into your backpack every time, use quick slots. \nTo view slot contents and keys assigned to quick slots, hold the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SCORES$$%c[default]].</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_10">
    <text>Some weapon models have an additional sight installed. Switch between the main and additional sight with the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWITCH_SCOPE$$%c[default]].</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_11">
    <text>Some weapon models are equipped with a laser designator and a tactical flashlight. Toggle them with keys [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_LASER_ON$$%c[default]] - laser designator, [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_FLASHLIGHT$$%c[default]] - tactical flashlight.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_12">
    <text>Successfully completing tasks given by faction members will also improve their attitude towards you. \nEvery time your standing with a faction increases, its traders will be happy to provide you with a wider assortment.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_13">
    <text>Don't forget about the encyclopedia in your PDA. Perhaps you will find exactly what you are looking for there. \nAdditionally, you can move freely with the PDA in your hands - this is quite convenient if you need to check the location of mission targets in real time.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_14">
    <text>Most accepted tasks can always be cancelled. But don't forget that nobody likes that, and they will treat you with disdain.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_15">
    <text>The Zone is an amazing and at the same time dangerous place, where you never know what might be waiting for you behind the bushes. \nTherefore, stalkers, fearing for their own lives, prefer to check the thickets with a burst of automatic fire to ensure there is no enemy or mutant.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_16">
    <text>Depending on the player's actions, reputation can constantly change, taking one of the possible levels: \nvile, terrible, very bad, bad, neutral, good, very good, excellent, superb.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_17">
    <text>When you are standing, you are an easy target, so flank, flank this riffraff.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_18">
    <text>Don't forget to ask stalkers about available work. The fact that they are not important characters doesn't mean they aren't ready to offer you some dirty work.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_19">
    <text>Contrary to popular belief, no mask or helmet can stop you from eating food and drinking beverages.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_20">
    <text>In the Zone, even a friend can stab you in the back... However, those whom you really helped may still repay you with gratitude, for example, by sharing a recipe or a stash.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_21">
    <text>If you want to reach a specific place but don't know the way yet, later someone might need something in that territory and share the path with you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_22">
    <text>Do not rush to sell PDAs found on corpses; they might be useful to you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_23">
    <text>Do not overlook that all data about your condition is available on your watch screen. \nTo inspect the watch, press and hold the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_WATCH$$%c[default]].</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_24">
    <text>During rain, as well as at night, it is much easier to avoid unwanted attention. However, in the dark, there is also a high chance of running into the Zone's nocturnal inhabitants.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_25">
    <text>It is never redundant to compare prices at traders to stock up with minimum overpayment. \nAs a rule, medics and bartenders offer medicines and food at a much lower price than other traders.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_26">
    <text>When encountering an armed enemy, try to take cover as soon as possible, and then wait for the moment when your opponent stops shooting.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_27">
    <text>If the game has become too difficult, you can always adjust the game difficulty in the corresponding settings section in the main menu.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_28">
    <text>Some stalkers believe in the existence of the Wish Granter, others, on the contrary, deny the very possibility. \nHowever, there are those who believe the tall tales but stick to two simple truths: \n“free cheese is only found in a mousetrap” and “everything has its price”.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_29">
    <text>If you are experiencing strong hunger, your stamina is depleted faster.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_30">
    <text>Hunting trophies are best sold to scientists. Moreover, they might even ask you to obtain something specific for a much larger reward.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_31">
    <text>Always carry a flashlight, or better yet - invest in a night vision device. Who knows what might be lurking in the darkness ten steps away from you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_32">
    <text>It is always worth picking up found ammo - you never know what weapon might be useful next time. So why spend money on ammo later? \nAnd if you are sure that the ammo won't be useful to you, it always makes sense to sell it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_33">
    <text>Remember that artifacts are a stalker's bread and butter. After blowouts, stalkers try to check territories for artifacts first thing. As they say, you don't snooze in the big Zone.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_34">
    <text>Don't forget to turn off your flashlight when you are sneaking up on someone.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_35">
    <text>Even the most trained soldier will get tired as a dog after a whole day of firefights and multi-kilometer marathons. It is always worth paying attention to fatigue, hunger, and sleep.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_36">
    <text>Pistols weigh little, and their maintenance is an extremely easy and cheap process. Doesn't this make them a good backup weapon?</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_37">
    <text>As your reputation increases, traders will offer increasingly difficult tasks to complete.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_38">
    <text>It is not necessary to sell every found artifact, as their properties can help you obtain even more anomalous formations.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_39">
    <text>If things go south, it makes sense to retreat. This will not only save your life but also save your money that you would otherwise spend on repairs and treatment.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_40">
    <text>During firefights, it makes sense to stay in cover until you hear your enemy reloading. \nHowever, remember that an experienced fighter might prefer not to risk it, but simply throw a grenade into your cover.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_41">
    <text>Always keep something with you to stop bleeding. A medic can save you, of course, provided you don't bleed out on the way to him. Besides, he will charge you for his services. And you could have just stocked up on bandages beforehand.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_42">
    <text>Don't forget to use a suppressor - even if it doesn't hide your location, it will definitely buy you some time before you are pinpointed.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_43">
    <text>Most young stalkers prefer to hunt for artifacts in the southern regions of the Zone, however, all experienced ones know that the best places are in the north. \nBut only a small number of unprepared stalkers manage to survive in such harsh and hostile conditions.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_44">
    <text>There are many alternatives to anti-radiation drugs in the Zone, a number of which also have strong additional effects.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_45">
    <text>Remember that it is impossible to make friends with everyone. \nThere will always be a stalker or a faction that won't appreciate your zeal and desire to help others, especially their enemies. \nAnd fanatical and criminal elements don't even need a special reason for this.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_46">
    <text>When encountering a controller, always try to position yourself so that there is a visual obstacle between you and the mutant: a tree, a building, a concrete fence, etc. \nHe won't be able to use his psi-strike if he doesn't see you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_47">
    <text>Try to always keep a psi-injector with you. In case of a sudden meeting with a controller - it will save your life.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_48">
    <text>Stimulants are an excellent replacement for medkits, as their speed of use and effectiveness are much higher than field kits.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_49">
    <text>It always makes sense to carry at least one pack of armor-piercing ammo. \nMutants may not wear armor, but stalkers are a different conversation.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_50">
    <text>Always carry a backup weapon. \nA pistol and a sawed-off shotgun can save your life when things suddenly take a sharp turn.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_51">
    <text>Even years later, some corners of the Zone still harbor dangerous knowledge that faction representatives or traders will definitely be interested in. \nSome lucky ones even claim that their gratitude won't keep you waiting long.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_52">
    <text>To move all items in a selected inventory slot at once, hold the SHIFT key and double-click on them.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_53">
    <text>AP ammo negatively affects weapon condition but has greater penetration power.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_54">
    <text>Found a good trophy weapon, but it is broken? Do not despair! There is always an opportunity to repair it.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_55">
    <text>Listen to the anomalies around you. If you don't see them - it doesn't mean they aren't there.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_56">
    <text>It is always worth carrying energy drinks or specialized medical drugs that increase stamina. \nPerhaps they don't seem particularly valuable right now, but a sudden blowout can quickly convince you otherwise.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_57">
    <text>It is always worth carrying as few items as possible in your backpack, less weight - more loot.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_58">
    <text>Being a cunning and selfish stalker might turn out to be an economically profitable business, but in the end, those who hate you will want to get rid of you.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_59">
    <text>Not everyone in the Zone trusts digital technologies. Some stalkers still use paper to record important information and more. \nPerhaps you can even learn something new!</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_60">
    <text>There is a large number of unique weapon models in the Zone, but unfortunately, not all stalkers have enough technical skills and weapon knowledge to master their disassembly.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_61">
    <text>Over more than 12 years of the Zone's existence, stalkers have studied most of its territories and are no longer distracted by constantly having maps open in front of their faces. \nNevertheless, some, due to developed habit, still keep them at the ready.</text>
</string>
<string id="ls_tip_62">
    <text>Don't bother the developer with every little thing, ask Google your question first. Nerve cells and my time do not regenerate, internet traffic regenerates every month!</text>
</string>