<string id="barman_govorit_talk_article">
    <text>Meet and talk to the Barman.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_new_talk_again_article">
    <text>Meet and talk to the Barman.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_pismo_letter_article">
    <text>After interrogating Yarofeev, I had more questions than answers. I told everything to the Barman, let him think. He asked me to deliver a letter to Sidorovich, the trader from the Peacekeeping Corps. He should be in the village. \nAccording to him, Sidorovich might know something about Magomet's whereabouts. Magomet was acquainted with my Brother, so it will be useful to meet this trader. The Barman also gave me a pass to the Peacekeeper territory so they'd let me through without any problems.</text>
</string>

<string id="barman_strelka_meet_article">
    <text>Talk to the Barman.</text>
</string>

<string id="baza_mir_peacekeepers_article">
    <text>Talk to Colonel Brown and meet the assault group. Need to help the Peacekeepers regain control of their base, which was captured by mutants. After the cleanup, it wouldn't hurt to return to Brown and report.</text>
</string>

<string id="brat_nayti_find_brother_article">
    <text>I must find my brother. I don't care if I have to tear the Zone apart. I must talk to everyone if necessary.</text>
</string>

<string id="demon_vstrecha_talk_article">
    <text>Met with the leader of the "Drifters", Leila. A hot one, but she won't give up the Forester's stash for free. Their faction is located in the same building where the Forester hid supplies for a rainy day. Will have to cooperate and find Demon. He will tell me what to do.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc_karina_talk_article">
    <text>Talked with Karina. She's staying with the Doctor, will help him with his work. Happy for the old man, now he won't have to manage everything alone. Need to talk to him too.</text>
</string>

<string id="doc_vodyanoy_find_article">
    <text>Some crazy stuff is happening: the Doc places a transmitter in the Southern part of the Swamps, and every time it either gets thrown somewhere or broken. The Doctor is already desperate, asked me to go and check what's going on. \nAnd who could he have pissed off?</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_kostolom_article">
    <text>The Swamp Doctor told me a Creature has settled in the Swamps. Even the guys from the checkpoint are afraid of it, don't want to send their squad. \nIt can't be tamed in any way, and it's also terrorizing the Swamp Doctor: scaring his patients, killed Murka's kittens... Since the Doc asked for help, it means this Creature has no place in his preserve. Need to kill it.</text>
</string>

<string id="doctor_kostolom_meet_article">
    <text>Meet the Swamp Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="dolg_attak_bar_article">
    <text>Everything's ready. Me and the guys figured out what's what, Borov's map helped a lot with that. Now I need to go with the squad and help retake the Bar. They asked me to start first and shoot the guards at the entrance, then play it by ear. The main thing is that Plichko doesn't die.</text>
</string>

<string id="eda_lesnik_article">
    <text>The scientists gave the medicine, but they themselves are short on food. The Forester said he has a rainy-day stash hidden in the Dead City. Need to go there and retrieve a crate of provisions from the Forester's secret stash. The old man made the stash in the School building, on the first floor.</text>
</string>

<string id="fabrika_mir_oldmill_article">
    <text>A group of Peacekeeper scouts went missing on the territory of the abandoned antenna. It's unlikely anyone is still alive there, but there's a weak signal. Need to go and check what happened there, then report to General Smith.</text>
</string>

<string id="foster_poisk_save_article">
    <text>Corporal Foster, who was delivering documents to the checkpoint, has gone missing. They tried to find him, but without success. The Peacekeepers hope that an experienced digger like me can find the corporal and help him if he's still alive. Well, gotta help the guys. It'll be a plus to my reputation with the Peacekeepers, and that definitely won't hurt. \nDespite the failure, the Peacekeepers managed to mark the approximate search area. Need to look for the corporal there.</text>
</string>

<string id="graf_poisk_talk_article">
    <text>Didn't expect to hear such a story. Turns out, there's a place for love even in the Zone: They told me that Leila has a sister named Karina. She was first with Dan, then with Sviblov... Well, well! Because of this, distrust arose between the guys, and Dan sent Sviblov to the Radar. I need to talk to Sviblov and find out more about Karina. He should tell me where the passage to the Dead City is.</text>
</string>

<string id="grek_ohota_hunters_article">
    <text>Talked with Greek. Agreed to go together. He told me not to stick my neck out, as boars are dangerous creatures, they can easily gut you with their tusks. Need to shoot them all, then talk to everyone.</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_vstrecha_talk_article">
    <text>I was told to go and meet Grig. He's a former guide, has been many places. Maybe he's heard something about my brother? Also, Grig should know about the passage to Pripyat.</text>
</string>

<string id="grig_zamery_article">
    <text>Need to help the Drifters test a device. For this, I'll first meet a person on the bridge, then escort him to an abandoned village in the Swamps. He'll take measurements and set up the device, after which we'll return to the base. If I complete the task, Grig will show the way from the Swamps to the Forest.</text>
</string>

<string id="groza_tankista_article">
    <text>The tankist asked me to find his unique gun - an anomalous "Groza" (Thunderstorm), which he lost in the X-18 lab in the Dark Valley. Should search on the lower tier of the lab. In return, he promised to tell where I can find a bio-radar - a special device that will display mutant markers for me.</text>
</string>

<string id="hvosty_art_article">
    <text>Grig promised to tell about the passage to Pripyat if I collect 10 dog tails for him. What does he need them for? No idea. But I need to get to Pripyat, so I'll have to do it. Grik said blind dogs can be found outside the city, in the ravines.</text>
</string>

<string id="kapitan_vstrecha_captain_article">
    <text>I can't believe it! After all I've been through, I finally found my Brother! \nTurns out, all this time he's been working for the Duty faction. Became an excellent Guide you can rely on. We have so much to discuss!</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_doc_discuss_article">
    <text>Karina and I ended up in different places. Judging by the signal, she already managed to reach the Doctor.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_nayti_talk_article">
    <text>Karina should be somewhere in the Red Forest. She was supposed to be led along a safe route, but something went wrong. Maybe the Forester has heard something about her? Finally going to meet an old friend.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_perehod_meet_article">
    <text>Karina decided she's had enough adventures. I can perfectly understand her, given the circumstances she recently found herself in. It was decided to go to the Swamps to see the Doc.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_poisk_talk_article">
    <text>Sviblov said that before her disappearance, Karina visited her sister. Need to meet the Atamansha again and find out from her where Karina could have gone.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_pomosch_find_article">
    <text>The hunters gave me a tip: They saw a girl in the company of two old women... Where did they even come from? Will have to introduce them to the Forester. \nAccording to the tip, they were heading towards the tunnel. Marked this spot on the map.</text>
</string>

<string id="karina_poshli_corpse_article">
    <text>No one will believe me! Met with the old women who were with the girl, and they turned out to be controllers! Don't know how, but I managed to shoot them before going crazy myself. \nKarina managed to stay sane. Now need to go and look for the Guide's corpse. He should have had a PDA with the needed passage.</text>
</string>

<string id="karta_bar_map_article">
    <text>The plan to capture the Bar is ready. Just need to take the map to Sergeant Plichko. He's in charge of the assault and should tell about the next steps.</text>
</string>

<string id="leila_vstrecha_leila_article">
    <text>As soon as I entered the Dead City, I was met with a gun pointed at me. Seems I'm starting to get used to it. The guy said he'd lead me to the base, but if I stray too far from him - he'll shoot me without a second thought. Better play along and follow him.</text>
</string>

<string id="lekarstvo_lesniku_medicine_article">
    <text>The old man took a turn for the worse. Need to find medicine, and as soon as possible. He told me that an associate professor from Yantar was carrying it. I need to find out if he's okay and where the medicine for the Forester is now.</text>
</string>

<string id="les_dobratsya_cabin_article">
    <text>My head hurts... I clearly remember there was a tour, and then... What happened? I woke up in some building, found by a local hermit. He started threatening me, asking questions. Good thing he didn't shoot me, his shotgun barrel kept flashing before my eyes. Something in my story made him believe me... I need to follow the Forester to his dwelling in the Forest. He'll show me the way.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_cats_forester_article">
    <text>Well, I had to run around the Swamps. Hunt the local Swamp Creature, help with measurements. Need to drop by the old man's place, rest and dry my feet.</text>
</string>

<string id="lesnik_hunters_talk_article">
    <text>Rested at the Forester's, told him about my adventures. Also asked about the path to the Army Warehouses, but he doesn't know it. Gave me a lead on the local Hunters, specifically on Sutuly (Stooped One). Says he's a seasoned hunter who knows these places like the back of his hand.</text>
</string>

<string id="mandra_article">
    <text>Need to bring the Forester a Mandrake root. Can find it in an old, abandoned mine. The Forester said something about the Mandrake's wild scream when you pull it from the ground (now even his plants are screaming...). Ugh, I have a feeling something nasty's coming.</text>
</string>

<string id="mandra2_art_article">
    <text>Need to find 3 Mandrake roots in an abandoned mine in the northwestern part of the Red Forest. The Forester said scientists pay a lot of money for them, and I'll definitely need it. And why do stalkers collect artifacts if you can sell roots?</text>
</string>

<string id="mg_voyna_zombies_article">
    <text>A Zombie Apocalypse has started in the Dead City! As soon as I got to the city, I received a distress signal from the Drifters. A big wave of zombies appeared, need to shoot them all. \nWhen I'm done, need to drop by Leila's.</text>
</string>

<string id="monolit_pogovority_crystal_article">
    <text>Is it really... my brother? Still can't believe I made it here. Hope he remembers me even in this state.</text>
</string>

<string id="ohotniki_karina_talk_article">
    <text>The Forester hasn't seen the girl, but pointed me towards the Hunters. They comb the whole Forest and really might have noticed something.</text>
</string>

<string id="pobeg_chaes_article">
    <text>I failed to save him... When I finished with the squad, the Drifter was already lying there bleeding out. \nI had to leave, as time was running out. The Drifter managed to tell me about the exit from CHAES-2 to Pripyat. It should be in one of the teleports. Probably should be... Again I'll have to go into these damned teleports. It's the only way to finally get out of here.</text>
</string>

<string id="pro_magometa_article">
    <text>Sidorovich said Magomet can be found somewhere in the Dead City, on the outskirts. He has a "meet-up" scheduled there with some stalker. Need to hurry, because Magomet should know about my brother's group.</text>
</string>

<string id="semeckiy_nayti_article">
    <text>Need to find Yuri Semetsky to find out from him what really happened to my brother. As Magomet said, Semetsky was heading to the Sarcophagus to carry out some mission there.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_cognak_five_article">
    <text>Whew, what a mess. First letters to deliver, now booze. What have I gotten myself into?</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_pismo_letter_article">
    <text>Deliver a letter to the Barman from Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidor_vernutsya_talk_article">
    <text>Need to talk to the trader Sidorovich.</text>
</string>

<string id="sidr_mayor_talk_article">
    <text>Need to go to Cordon and talk to the Barman. I've heard he has influential connections. Maybe he's heard something about my brother?</text>
</string>

<string id="sled2_pomosch_help_article">
    <text>Damn! The Pathfinder has been attacked, he's surrounded on all sides. I must get to him as soon as possible!</text>
</string>

<string id="smith_brown_find_article">
    <text>Smith sent me to talk to Colonel Brown. They've got trouble: a corporal recently went missing. Colonel Brown should know more about this.</text>
</string>

<string id="sutuly_grek_talk_article">
    <text>Sutuly said he doesn't know anything about my brother. Too bad. I was hoping that since he's so experienced, maybe he met him sometime. \nAnyway, the Hunters are willing to show me the path to the Army Warehouses if I help them hunt boars. Need to check my gear and talk to Greek, he's in charge of the hunt.</text>
</string>

<string id="sverhprovodnik_article">
    <text>Need to find the "Superconductor" artifact so the Pathfinder opens the Secret Path from the Army Warehouses to the Swamps via the Dead City. One catch: finding this artifact is extremely difficult. It appears for a short period, sometime between 1 and 2 AM. If you don't find it during that time, the artifact disappears. Will have to scour the Warehouses really fast, possibly for more than one day... And to find this artifact, you only have three, maximum four days.</text>
</string>

<string id="swamp_grig_meet_article">
    <text>I need to return to the Forest, but I don't know the path there. The Doc suggested that Grig should know where it is. Need to meet and talk to him. He and his squad have set up an outpost here, in the Swamps.</text>
</string>

<string id="vano_dialog_find_article">
    <text>Not sure it's a good idea, but still decided to help the drunk, the Baker's assistant. His name is Vano, and he asked me to find mines in the swamp.</text>
</string>

<string id="vas_dovesti_camp_article">
    <text>Met this associate professor. Turns out, on the way he ran into mutants and had to leave the supplies right there. Don't think anything's left of them: the mutants probably weren't against a snack. Me and Vasilyev will have to go to the scientists' bunker at "Yantar". Can get new supplies for the Forester there, and also try to find out something about my brother.</text>
</string>

<string id="vas_dovesti_yantar_article">
    <text>Damn! As soon as we got out of the Forest, we came out onto swamps teeming with zombified and who knows what else. Need to shoot all the abominations as quickly as possible, then continue towards the scientists' bunker. Must remember to talk to everyone, because someone might know where my brother went.</text>
</string>

<string id="vasiliev_nayti_article">
    <text>Poor old man, taken down without medicine and food. Need to find Associate Professor Vasilyev. He was supposed to bring supplies, but hid somewhere on the outskirts of the Forest because of mutants... Why even send this associate professor if he can't even defend himself?</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_talk_talk_article">
    <text>Damn! When Voronin said my Brother was here, I... Words can't describe how happy I was. But it turned out he confused him with Captain Sobelev. \nNo, I won't give up! I will definitely find my Brother, even if I have to run all over the Zone. The good news is that this "fake" Captain turned out to be an old friend of Zakhar's.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_vstrecha_bar_article">
    <text>Victory! Me and the Duty guys managed to retake the Bar territory from the bandits. The only bad thing is that Borov managed to escape... Well, no matter. Doubt he'll show his face here now. \nNow need to help Voronin get to the place. Maybe some bandits have holed up nearby and will be waiting for us.</text>
</string>

<string id="voronin_vstrecha_meet_article">
    <text>Meet General Voronin, commander of Duty.</text>
</string>

<string id="zahar_voda_find_article">
    <text>Zakhar asked me to find a container he had to abandon near the bridge.</text>
</string>

<string id="zapiska_voronin_letter_article">
    <text>Deliver a letter to General Voronin.</text>
</string>

<string id="zapiska_voronin2_letter_article">
    <text>Deliver another letter to General Voronin.</text>
</string>

<string id="zapiska_voronin3_letter_article">
    <text>Deliver a letter to Sidorovich at Cordon.</text>
</string>

<string id="zombi_dom_article">
    <text>I hadn't even recovered from the encounter with the mutants from the Red Forest when Demon from the Drifters faction asked me to clear a whole five-story building of Zombies... Does he think I'm some kind of Rambo? Said his guys busted their asses, and I can prove myself. At least he gave me armor and a gun. The building is the last one, located next to the corner five-story building with the collapsed roof. Need to be careful and not let the Zombies get too close.</text>
</string>
