<string id="tutorial_watch">
    <text>
        \n
        A wristwatch is fastened to your hero's wrist.\n
        Several operating modes are available:\n
        The first mode displays the current in-game time.\n
        The second mode displays health level and status indicators.\n
        The third mode displays the hero's radiation exposure and background radiation.\n

        To examine the indicators in detail, hold down the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_WATCH$$%c[default]].\n
        To switch modes, press the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_WATCH_MODE$$%c[default]].\n
        Keys can always be changed in the control settings.
        \n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="tutorial_headlamp">
    <text>
        \n
        The hero's flashlight is equipped with several operating modes:\n
        Low beam - a wide beam to illuminate the space around you.\n
        High beam - a focused beam to illuminate distant objects.\n
        To switch modes, hold down the flashlight key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_TORCH_SWITCH$$%c[default]].
        \n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="tutorial_backlight">
    <text>
        \n
        Some optical scopes have reticle illumination.\n
        To toggle the illumination state, press the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWITCH_MARK_COLOR$$%c[default]].\n
        The key can always be changed in the control settings.
        \n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="tutorial_collimsight">
    <text>
        \n
        Reticle adjustment is available on collimator and holographic sights.\n
        Settings are saved separately for the weapon + sight combination.\n
        To change the reticle type, press the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWITCH_MARK$$%c[default]].\n
        To change the reticle color, press the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWITCH_MARK_COLOR$$%c[default]].\n
        The key can always be changed in the control settings.
        \n
    </text>
</string>

<string id="tutorial_raindrops">
    <text>
        \n
        During rain, drops accumulate on the helmet visor, impairing visibility.\n
        To wipe the visor, press the key [%c[yellow]$$ACTION_SWIPE_MASK$$%c[default]].\n
        The key can always be changed in the control settings.\n
        Also, the rain drop effect on the visor can be disabled in the graphics settings.
        \n
    </text>
</string>